<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2682251-A1" country="EP" doc-number="2682251" kind="A1" date="20140108" family-id="48703178" file-reference-id="315735" date-produced="20180822" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146585965" ucid="EP-2682251-A1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2682251</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-13173508-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154848157" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>13173508</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20130625</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP180844618" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>13173508.6</doc-number><date>20130625</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140548510" ucid="US-201213542013-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>201213542013</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120705</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989316611" load-source="docdb">B29C  53/04        20060101AFI20131002BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2032823358" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B23Q   3/04        20130101 LI20150802BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2032826224" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B29C  53/04        20130101 LI20150803BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2032827264" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B23Q   3/02        20130101 LI20150802BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2092283402" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B21D  19/12        20130101 LI20150212BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2092283445" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B29K2995/0008      20130101 LA20150212BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2092286873" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B21D  11/20        20130101 FI20150212BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2092288239" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B29K2105/256       20130101 LA20150212BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2092291344" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B29C  53/02        20130101 LI20150212BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132362528" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Verfahren und Vorrichtung zur Herstellung eines eckigen Flanschs</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132362529" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Method and apparatus for forming an angled flange</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132362530" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Procédé et appareil pour former une bride coudée</invention-title><citations><patent-citations><patcit mxw-id="PCIT242945635" load-source="docdb" ucid="JP-2003251714-A"><document-id format="epo"><country>JP</country><doc-number>2003251714</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20030909</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="A" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT242945636" load-source="docdb" ucid="JP-2010274457-A"><document-id format="epo"><country>JP</country><doc-number>2010274457</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20101209</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="A" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit></patent-citations><non-patent-citations><nplcit><text>None</text><sources><source mxw-id="PNPL45211957" load-source="docdb" name="APP"/></sources></nplcit></non-patent-citations></citations></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919544170" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>BOEING CO</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919521857" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>THE BOEING COMPANY</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919012488" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>The Boeing Company</last-name><iid>100235575</iid><address><street>100 North Riverside Plaza</street><city>Chicago, IL 60606-2016</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919538018" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>DIXON ROBERT D</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919507642" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>Dixon, Robert D</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919006203" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Dixon, Robert D</last-name><address><street>7015 Lower Ridge Road</street><city>Everett, WA Washington 98203</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919015994" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Boult Wade Tennant</last-name><iid>101370347</iid><address><street>Verulam Gardens 70 Gray's Inn Road</street><city>London WC1X 8BT</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549912631" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS549755391" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549912633" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549832522" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549831431" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549760987" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549755392" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549912634" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549760988" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549761025" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549826097" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549832523" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549842050" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549912635" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549761026" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549912636" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549755397" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549831432" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549761027" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549842051" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549761028" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549832524" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549754528" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549832525" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549832530" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549754537" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS549754538" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549755398" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549826102" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549831433" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549832532" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549755399" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549832533" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS549831438" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549842052" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549826103" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549831439" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS549754539" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states><ep-extended-states><ep-extended-state-data><country>BA</country></ep-extended-state-data><ep-extended-state-data><country>ME</country></ep-extended-state-data></ep-extended-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA128674019" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p id="pa01" num="0001">A method and apparatus comprising a structure and a locking magnet. The structure comprises a retaining portion and a magnetic portion. The retaining portion of the structure is configured to receive a first section of a workpiece such that a second section of the workpiece is positioned at an angle relative to the magnetic portion of the structure. The magnetic portion of the structure is positioned at a first side of the workpiece. The locking magnet is configured to exert an attractive force that causes the magnetic portion of the structure to move towards the second section of the workpiece when the locking magnet is positioned at a second side of the workpiece.
<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="78" he="115" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA128738301" lang="EN" source="EPO" load-source="docdb"><p>A method and apparatus comprising a structure and a locking magnet. The structure comprises a retaining portion and a magnetic portion. The retaining portion of the structure is configured to receive a first section of a workpiece such that a second section of the workpiece is positioned at an angle relative to the magnetic portion of the structure. The magnetic portion of the structure is positioned at a first side of the workpiece. The locking magnet is configured to exert an attractive force that causes the magnetic portion of the structure to move towards the second section of the workpiece when the locking magnet is positioned at a second side of the workpiece.</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES63960007" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001"><b>BACKGROUND INFORMATION</b></heading><heading id="h0002"><b>1. Field:</b></heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present disclosure relates generally to forming flanges on parts, and in particular, to forming angled flanges on parts. Still more particularly, the present disclosure relates to a method and apparatus for bending a workpiece to form an angled flange.</p><heading id="h0003"><b>2. Background:</b></heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">Different types of objects may be formed using a part having a flange. As used herein, a "flange" may be a protruding ridge, a rim, a collar, a rib, or some other type of extension on a part. In some cases, the flange on a part may be angled with respect to another portion of the part. This type of flange may be referred to as an "angled flange".</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">Different types of tools may be used to form an angled flange on a part. For example, without limitation, various tools may be used to bend the flange on a part relative to the rest of the part to form an angled flange. The angled flange may be formed at some selected angle relative to the rest of the part. The tools used to form these angled flanges may be referred to as "bend tools". In some cases, these bend tools may be used to hold the part with the angled flange at selected angles relative to the rest of the part, while the part is cured, heated, hardened, or processed in some other manner.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">However, some currently available bend tools may be heavier and/or larger than desired. Transporting these heavy tools to various locations for use with different parts may be more difficult than desired. Further, using these types of bend tools on a moving line or an assembly line in a manufacturing facility may be more difficult than desired.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">The increased weight and size of these currently available bend tools may increase the energy needed to perform heating and/or curing operations during manufacturing and fabrication. For example, without limitation, when placed in an oven or an autoclave, a bend tool may block heat and/or draw heat away from the part being held by the bend tool. Further, as the size of the bend tool increases, the energy needed to heat the bend tool also increases.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">Additionally, some currently available bend tools may only be configured for use with a particular type of part. Consequently, using part-specific bend tools to form an object comprised of multiple parts that require angled flanges may be more expensive than desired. Therefore, it would be desirable to have a method and apparatus that takes into account at least some of the issues discussed above, as well as other possible issues.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p><heading id="h0004"><b>SUMMARY</b></heading><p id="p0007" num="0007">According to an aspect of the present disclosure there is provided an apparatus that includes a structure comprising a retaining portion and a magnetic portion in which the retaining portion of the structure is configured to receive a first section of a workpiece such that a second section of the workpiece is positioned at an angle relative to the magnetic portion of the structure and the magnetic portion of the structure is positioned at a first side of the workpiece, and a locking magnet configured to exert an attractive force that causes the magnetic portion of the structure to move towards the second section of the workpiece when the locking magnet is positioned at a second side of the workpiece.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">Advantageously the first section of the workpiece bends relative to the second section of the workpiece when the magnetic portion of the structure moves towards the second section of the workpiece and the second section of the workpiece remains in a substantially fixed position relative to the magnetic portion of the structure. Preferably the apparatus includes a positioning system configured to hold the second section of the workpiece in the substantially fixed position while the magnetic portion of the structure moves towards the second section of the workpiece. Preferably the apparatus includes a rigid elongate member, wherein the retaining portion of the structure is configured to receive both the rigid elongate member and the first section of the workpiece. Preferably the apparatus includes the retaining portion of the structure is configured to receive both the rigid elongate member and the first section of the workpiece such that the first section of the workpiece remains substantially planar when the first section of the workpiece bends relative to the second section of the workpiece. Advantageously the apparatus includes a clamping magnet associated with the magnetic portion of the structure, wherein the attractive force exerted by the locking magnet when the locking magnet is positioned at the second side of the workpiece causes the clamping magnet to move towards the second section of the workpiece until the magnetic portion of the structure contacts a surface of the second section of the workpiece. Advantageously the retaining portion of the structure comprises a slot configured to receive the first section of the workpiece when the retaining portion is placed over the first section of the workpiece. Preferably the slot is configured to receive the first section of the workpiece and a rigid elongate member. Preferably the apparatus further includes a holding magnet located in the slot of the retaining portion of the structure and configured to hold the rigid elongate member in the slot. Advantageously a groove on the first side of the workpiece separates the first section of the workpiece from the second section of the workpiece. Preferably the workpiece is a flange configured to bend relative to the second section of the workpiece at the groove to form an angled flange when the magnetic portion of the structure moves towards the second section of the workpiece and the second section of the workpiece remains in a substantially fixed position relative to the magnetic portion of the structure. Advantageously the structure is one structure in a group of structures and the locking magnet is one locking magnet in a group of locking magnets and wherein the group of structures and the group of locking magnets form a bending<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> system. Advantageously the workpiece comprises a flexible material in which the flexible material comprises at least one of a composite material, a flexible metal material, a flexible metal alloy, and a silicone material.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">According to a further aspect of the present disclosure there is provided a bending system that includes a group of structures in which each structure in the group of structures comprises a retaining portion and a magnetic portion in which the retaining portion of the each structure has a slot configured to receive a first section of a workpiece such that a second section of the workpiece is positioned at an angle relative to the magnetic portion of the each structure and the magnetic portion of the each structure is positioned at a first side of the workpiece; a group of locking magnets configured to exert a group of attractive forces, a group of clamping magnets in which each clamping magnet in the group of clamping magnets is associated with the magnetic portion of a corresponding structure in the group of structures and in which the group of attractive forces exerted by the group of locking magnets when the group of locking magnets is positioned at a second side of the workpiece causes the group of clamping magnets to move towards the second section of the workpiece while the second section of the workpiece remains in a substantially fixed position until the magnetic portion of the each structure contacts a surface of the second section of the workpiece in which the first section of the workpiece bends relative to the second section of the workpiece to form an angled flange when the magnetic portion of the structure moves towards the second section of the workpiece, and a rigid elongate member, wherein the slot is configured to receive both the rigid elongate member and the first section of the workpiece such that the first section of the workpiece remains substantially planar when the first section of the workpiece bends relative to the second section of the workpiece.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">According to still a further aspect of the present disclosure there is provided a method for bending a workpiece, the method includes receiving a first section of the workpiece within a retaining portion of a structure, positioning a second section of the workpiece at an angle relative to a magnetic portion of the structure, and positioning the magnetic portion of the structure at a first side of the workpiece.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">Advantageously the steps of positioning the second section of the workpiece at the angle relative to the magnetic portion of the structure and positioning the magnetic portion of the structure at the first side of the workpiece are performed in response to receiving the first section of the workpiece within the retaining portion of the structure. Advantageously the method further includes holding the second section of the workpiece in a substantially fixed position relative to the magnetic portion of the structure. Preferably, the method further includes exerting, by a locking magnet positioned at a second side of the workpiece, an attractive force that causes the magnetic portion of the structure to move towards the second section of the workpiece. Preferably the step of exerting, by the locking magnet positioned at the second side of the workpiece, the attractive force that causes the magnetic portion of the structure to move towards the second section of the workpiece comprises exerting, by the locking magnet positioned at the second side of the workpiece, the attractive force<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> that causes a clamping magnet associated with the magnetic portion of the structure to move towards the second section of the workpiece until the magnetic portion of the structure contacts a surface of the second section of the workpiece. Preferably the method further includes bending the first section of the workpiece relative to the second section of the workpiece in response to the magnetic portion of the structure moving towards the second section of the workpiece while the second section of the workpiece remains in the substantially fixed position. Preferably the step of receiving the first section of the workpiece within the retaining portion of the structure comprises receiving a rigid elongate member and the first section of the workpiece within a slot in the retaining portion of the structure. Preferably the step of receiving the rigid elongate member and the first section of the workpiece within the slot in the retaining portion of the structure comprises receiving the rigid elongate member and the first section of the workpiece within the slot in the retaining portion of the structure, wherein the rigid elongate member is configured to keep the first section of the workpiece substantially planar when the first section of the workpiece bends relative to the second section of the workpiece. Preferably the method further includes holding the rigid elongate member within the slot of the retaining portion of the workpiece using a holding magnet.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">According to yet a further aspect of the present disclosure there is provided a method for forming an angled flange, the method including receiving a rigid elongate member and a first section of a workpiece within a slot in a retaining portion of each structure in a group of structures such that a second section of the workpiece is positioned at an angle relative to a magnetic portion of the each structure and the magnetic portion of the each structure is positioned at a first side of the workpiece, holding the second section of the workpiece in a substantially fixed position relative to the magnetic portion of the each structure in the group of structures, positioning a group of locking magnets at a second side of the workpiece, exerting, by the group of locking magnets, a number of attractive forces configured to cause a clamping magnet associated with the magnetic portion of the each structure to move towards the second section of the workpiece until the magnetic portion of the each structure contacts a surface of the second section of the workpiece, and bending the first section of the workpiece relative to the second section of the workpiece at a groove in the workpiece in response to the magnetic portion of the each structure moving towards the second section of the workpiece in which the rigid elongate member keeps the first section of the workpiece substantially planar when the first section of the workpiece bends relative to the second section of the workpiece.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">The features and functions can be achieved independently in various embodiments of the present disclosure or may be combined in yet other embodiments in which further details can be seen with reference to the following description and drawings.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></p><heading id="h0005"><b>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</b></heading><p id="p0014" num="0014">The novel features believed characteristic of the illustrative embodiments are set forth in the appended claims. The illustrative embodiments, however, as well as a preferred mode of use, further objectives and features thereof, will best be understood by reference to the following detailed description of an illustrative embodiment of the present disclosure when read in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, wherein:
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001"><b>Figure 1</b></figref> is an illustration of a fabrication environment in the form of a block diagram in accordance with an illustrative embodiment;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002"><b>Figure 2</b></figref> is an illustration of a front isometric view of a workpiece in accordance with an illustrative embodiment;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003"><b>Figure 3</b></figref> is an illustration of a front isometric view of a structure for a bending system in accordance with an illustrative embodiment;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003"><b>Figure 4</b></figref> is an illustration of a back isometric view of a structure in accordance with an illustrative embodiment;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004"><b>Figure 5</b></figref> is an illustration of a front isometric view of a bending system in accordance with an illustrative embodiment;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005"><b>Figure 6</b></figref> is an illustration of a front isometric view of a bending system placed over a workpiece in accordance with an illustrative embodiment;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0006"><b>Figure 7</b></figref> is an illustration of a cross-sectional side view of a structure attached to a workpiece in accordance with an illustrative embodiment;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0007"><b>Figure 8</b></figref> is an illustration of a cross-sectional side view of a structure attached to a workpiece and a locking magnet positioned relative to the workpiece in accordance with an illustrative embodiment;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0008"><b>Figure 9</b></figref> is an illustration of a back isometric view of a group of locking magnets positioned on a second surface of a workpiece in accordance with an illustrative embodiment;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0009"><b>Figure 10</b></figref> is an illustration of a front isometric view of a bending system holding an angled section of a workpiece in place in accordance with an illustrative embodiment;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0010"><b>Figure 11</b></figref> is an illustration of a front isometric view of a part with an angled section in accordance with an illustrative embodiment;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0011"><b>Figure 12</b></figref> is an illustration of an isometric view of a bin structure for an overhead bin for an aircraft in accordance with an illustrative embodiment;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0012"><b>Figure 13</b></figref> is an illustration of a process for forming an angled section on a workpiece in the form of a flowchart in accordance with an illustrative embodiment;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0013"><b>Figure 14</b></figref> is an illustration of an aircraft manufacturing and service method in the form of a block diagram in accordance with an illustrative embodiment; and<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></li><li><figref idrefs="f0013"><b>Figure 15</b></figref> is an illustration of an aircraft in the form of a block diagram in accordance with an illustrative embodiment.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0006"><b>DETAILED DESCRIPTION</b></heading><p id="p0015" num="0015">The different illustrative embodiments recognize and take into account different considerations. For example, without limitation, the different illustrative embodiments recognize and take into account that it may be desirable to have a bend tool that may be used on a moving line or an assembly line in a manufacturing facility. Further, the different illustrative embodiments recognize and take into account that it may be desirable to have a bend tool that is less expensive than some currently available bend tools. Still further, the different illustrative embodiments recognize and take into account that having a bend tool that can be used to bend flanges of varying lengths to form angled flanges may be desirable.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">Thus, the different illustrative embodiments provide a method and apparatus for bending a workpiece. In one illustrative embodiment, an apparatus may comprise a structure and a locking magnet. The structure may comprise a retaining portion and a magnetic portion. The retaining portion of the structure may be configured to receive a first section of a workpiece such that a second section of the workpiece is positioned at an angle relative to the magnetic portion of the structure. The magnetic portion of the structure may be positioned at a first side of the workpiece. The locking magnet may be configured to exert an attractive force that causes the magnetic portion of the structure to move towards the second section of the workpiece when the locking magnet is positioned at a second side of the workpiece.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">With reference now to <figref idrefs="f0001"><b>Figure 1</b></figref><b>,</b> an illustration of a fabrication environment in the form of a block diagram is depicted in accordance with an illustrative embodiment. In <figref idrefs="f0001"><b>Figure 1</b></figref><b>,</b> fabrication environment <b>100</b> may be an example of one environment in which bending system <b>102</b> may be used to bend workpiece <b>104.</b> Bending system <b>102</b> may also be referred to as a bending tool or a bend tool in some illustrative examples.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">As depicted, workpiece <b>104</b> may be bent to form part <b>105.</b> In these illustrative examples, part <b>105</b> may be formed for use in manufacturing, assembling, reworking, and/or otherwise forming object <b>106.</b> Object <b>106</b> may be selected from one of any number of different types of objects. For example, without limitation, object <b>106</b> may be selected from one of an overhead bin in an aircraft, a fuselage of an aircraft, a door, a tool, a table, a seat in a seating system, a connection mechanism, a bracket, a duct, or some other type of object. However, in other illustrative examples, workpiece <b>104</b> may be bent to form a new workpiece that will be used to form part <b>105</b> for object <b>106.</b></p><p id="p0019" num="0019">In these illustrative examples, workpiece <b>104</b> may have first side <b>108</b> and second side <b>110.</b> Workpiece <b>104</b> may have first surface <b>112</b> at first side <b>108</b> and second surface <b>114</b> at second side <b>110.</b> As depicted, groove <b>116</b> may be formed on first side <b>108</b> of workpiece <b>104.</b> In particular, groove <b>116</b><!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> may comprise an opening at first surface <b>112</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> that extends towards second surface <b>114</b> of workpiece <b>104.</b></p><p id="p0020" num="0020">Groove <b>116</b> may separate first section <b>118</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> and second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104.</b> In these illustrative examples, first section <b>118</b> and second section <b>120</b> may be substantially planar prior to any bending of workpiece <b>104</b> by bending system <b>102.</b> Bending system <b>102</b> may be used to bend first section <b>118</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> relative to second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> at groove <b>116</b> to form angled section <b>122.</b></p><p id="p0021" num="0021">In one illustrative example, first section <b>118</b> may be referred to as flange <b>124</b> and angled section <b>122</b> may be referred to as angled flange <b>125.</b> In this manner, bending system <b>102</b> may bend flange <b>124</b> at groove <b>116</b> to form angled flange <b>125.</b> In particular, flange <b>124</b> may be bent at angle <b>121</b> relative to second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104.</b></p><p id="p0022" num="0022">In some illustrative examples, groove <b>116</b> may have shape <b>123</b> configured to allow first section <b>118</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> to bend without increasing the stress to which workpiece <b>104</b> is subjected when first section <b>118</b> bends more than desired. Shape <b>123</b> may be, for example, without limitation, a triangular prism shape, a rectangular prism shape, or some other type of shape.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">Of course, in other illustrative examples, groove <b>116</b> may not be present on workpiece <b>104.</b> Instead, bending system <b>102</b> may bend first section <b>118</b> relative to second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> at the interface between first section <b>118</b> and second section <b>120</b> without groove <b>116</b> being present on first side <b>108</b> of workpiece <b>104.</b></p><p id="p0024" num="0024">In these illustrative examples, bending system <b>102</b> may comprise group of structures <b>126,</b> group of clamping magnets <b>127,</b> and group of locking magnets <b>128.</b> As used herein, a "group of" items may mean one or more items. For example, without limitation, group of structures <b>126</b> may be one or more structures, group of clamping magnets <b>127</b> may be one or more clamping magnets, and group of locking magnets <b>128</b> may be one or more locking magnets.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">In some cases, a "structure" in group of structures <b>126</b> may also be referred to as a clamp. In this manner, group of structures <b>126</b> may be referred to as a group of clamps.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">Group of clamping magnets <b>127</b> may be associated with group of structures <b>126.</b> When one component is "associated" with another component, the association may be a physical association in the depicted examples. For example, without limitation, structure <b>130</b> may be an example of a structure in group of structures <b>126</b> and clamping magnet <b>140</b> may be an example of a clamping magnet in group of clamping magnets <b>127.</b> Clamping magnet <b>140</b> may be associated with structure <b>130.</b></p><p id="p0027" num="0027">As used herein, a first component, such as clamping magnet <b>140,</b> may be considered to be associated with a second component, such as structure <b>130,</b> by being secured to the second component, bonded to the second component, mounted to the second component, welded to the second component, fastened to the second component, and/or connected to the second component in some other suitable manner. Additionally, the first component may be connected to the second<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> component using a third component. The first component may also be considered to be associated with the second component by being formed as part of and/or an extension of the second component.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">Depending on the implementation, group of clamping magnets <b>127</b> may be held by, attached to, fastened to, and/or otherwise associated with group of structures <b>126.</b> Group of structures <b>126</b> may be configured to receive first section <b>118</b> of workpiece <b>104.</b> The association of group of clamping magnets <b>127</b> with group of structures <b>126</b> and the configuration of group of structures <b>126</b> may be selected such that group of clamping magnets <b>127</b> is positioned away from first surface <b>112</b> of second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> when group of structures <b>126</b> receives first section <b>118</b> of workpiece <b>104.</b></p><p id="p0029" num="0029">As depicted, group of locking magnets <b>128</b> may exert number of attractive forces <b>129.</b> Group of clamping magnets <b>127</b> may be attracted to number of attractive forces <b>129</b> exerted by group of locking magnets <b>128.</b> This attraction may cause group of clamping magnets <b>127</b> to move towards first surface <b>112</b> of second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> when group of locking magnets <b>128</b> is positioned at second surface <b>114</b> of workpiece <b>104.</b> In particular, group of clamping magnets <b>127</b> may move towards first surface <b>112</b> of second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> in a manner such that first section <b>118</b> bends relative to second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104.</b></p><p id="p0030" num="0030">For example, without limitation, structure <b>130</b> may comprise retaining portion <b>132</b> and magnetic portion <b>134.</b> In these illustrative examples, retaining portion <b>132</b> may be configured to receive first section <b>118</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> such that second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> is positioned at an angle relative to magnetic portion <b>134</b> of structure <b>130.</b></p><p id="p0031" num="0031">In one illustrative example, retaining portion <b>132</b> may have slot <b>138</b> configured to receive and retain first section <b>118</b> of workpiece <b>104.</b> For example, without limitation, retaining portion <b>132</b> may be positioned over first section <b>118</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> such that slot <b>138</b> receives first section <b>118</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> and such that magnetic portion <b>134</b> of structure <b>130</b> is located at first side <b>108</b> of workpiece <b>104.</b> In particular, retaining portion <b>132</b> may be positioned over first section <b>118</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> such that magnetic portion <b>134</b> of structure <b>130</b> is positioned at an angle relative to first surface <b>112</b> of second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104.</b></p><p id="p0032" num="0032">Clamping magnet <b>140</b> may be associated with magnetic portion <b>134</b> of structure <b>130.</b> In one illustrative example, each clamping magnet in group of clamping magnets <b>127</b> may be associated with a magnetic portion of a corresponding structure in group of structures <b>126.</b> Of course, in other illustrative examples, group of clamping magnets <b>127</b> may comprise a single clamping magnet configured to be associated with all of the structures in group of structures <b>126.</b> For example, without limitation, clamping magnet <b>140</b> may be the only clamping magnet in group of clamping magnets <b>127</b> in some cases.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">As depicted, locking magnet <b>142</b> may be an example of one locking magnet in group of locking magnets <b>128.</b> In one illustrative example, each locking magnet in group of locking magnets <b>128</b> may correspond to a clamping magnet in group of clamping magnets <b>127.</b> Of course, in other<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> illustrative examples, group of locking magnets <b>128</b> may comprise a single locking magnet configured to correspond to all of the clamping magnets in group of clamping magnets <b>127.</b> For example, without limitation, locking magnet <b>142</b> may be the only locking magnet in group of locking magnets <b>128.</b></p><p id="p0034" num="0034">In these illustrative examples, locking magnet <b>142</b> may be configured to exert attractive force <b>144.</b> Attractive force <b>144</b> may be one of number of attractive forces <b>129</b> exerted by group of locking magnets <b>128.</b></p><p id="p0035" num="0035">Once first section <b>118</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> has been retained by retaining portion <b>132</b> of structure <b>130,</b> locking magnet <b>142</b> may be positioned relative to second side <b>110</b> of workpiece <b>104.</b> In some illustrative examples, locking magnet <b>142</b> may be positioned on second surface <b>114</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> at second side <b>110</b> of workpiece <b>104.</b></p><p id="p0036" num="0036">Attractive force <b>144</b> exerted by locking magnet <b>142</b> may cause clamping magnet <b>140</b> to move towards second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> when locking magnet <b>142</b> is positioned on second surface <b>114</b> at second side <b>110</b> of workpiece <b>104.</b> The movement of clamping magnet <b>140</b> towards second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> may be relative to the movement between clamping magnet <b>140</b> and second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104.</b></p><p id="p0037" num="0037">Additionally, attractive force <b>144</b> exerted by locking magnet <b>142</b> may cause clamping magnet <b>140,</b> and thus, magnetic portion <b>134</b> of structure <b>130,</b> to move towards first surface <b>112</b> of second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> until magnetic portion <b>134</b> contacts first surface <b>112.</b> In these illustrative examples, attractive force <b>144</b> exerted by locking magnet <b>142</b> may cause clamping magnet <b>140</b> and locking magnet <b>142</b> to remain in substantially locked positions against first surface <b>112</b> and second surface <b>114,</b> respectively, of second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104.</b> In other words, locking magnet 142 may be configured to lock clamping magnet <b>140,</b> and thereby structure <b>130,</b> into a locked position relative to workpiece <b>104.</b></p><p id="p0038" num="0038">The movement of magnetic portion <b>134</b> of structure <b>130</b> towards second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> may be a rotation of magnetic portion <b>134</b> about axis <b>145</b> through structure <b>130.</b> In one illustrative example, axis <b>145</b> may extend through retaining portion <b>132</b> of structure <b>130.</b> More specifically, axis <b>145</b> may extend through an end or edge of slot <b>138</b> in retaining portion <b>132</b> of structure <b>130.</b></p><p id="p0039" num="0039">The rotation of magnetic portion <b>134</b> of structure <b>130</b> towards second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> may cause first section <b>118</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> to bend relative to second section <b>120</b> when second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> remains in a substantially fixed position relative to magnetic portion <b>134</b> of structure <b>130.</b></p><p id="p0040" num="0040">In these illustrative examples, positioning system <b>148</b> may be configured to hold second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> in a substantially fixed position while magnetic portion <b>134</b> of structure <b>130</b> rotates towards second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104.</b> Positioning system <b>148</b> may take a number of different forms. In one illustrative example, positioning system <b>148</b> may be a clamping system. In<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> another illustrative example, positioning system <b>148</b> may be a rigid structure configured to hold second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> in a substantially fixed position.</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">In some illustrative examples, slot <b>138</b> may be configured to receive and retain rigid elongate member <b>150</b> in addition to first section <b>118</b> of workpiece <b>104.</b> Rigid elongate member <b>150</b> may take various forms. Rigid elongate member <b>150</b> may take the form of, for example, without limitation, a rod, a beam, a stiffening structure, an elongate part, a rib, a plate, or some other type of rigid elongate member.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">Rigid elongate member <b>150</b> may be comprised of a magnetic material in one illustrative example. In this example, holding magnet <b>152</b> may be associated with slot <b>138.</b> Slot <b>138</b> may be configured to receive rigid elongate member <b>150</b> and holding magnet <b>152</b> may be configured to hold rigid elongate member <b>150</b> in place within slot <b>138.</b> In this manner, rigid elongate member <b>150</b> may be magnetically attached to retaining portion <b>132</b> of structure <b>130</b> within slot <b>138</b> by holding magnet <b>152.</b> Depending on the implementation, rigid elongate member <b>150</b> may be magnetically attached to retaining portion <b>132</b> prior to retaining portion <b>132</b> being placed over first section <b>118</b> of workpiece <b>104.</b></p><p id="p0043" num="0043">In other illustrative examples, rigid elongate member <b>150</b> may be associated with first section <b>118</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> on second surface <b>114</b> of workpiece <b>104.</b> For example, without limitation, rigid elongate member <b>150</b> may be fastened to first section <b>118</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> by fasteners. In this manner, slot <b>138</b> may receive both rigid elongate member <b>150</b> and first section <b>118</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> when retaining portion <b>132</b> is placed over first section <b>118.</b></p><p id="p0044" num="0044">As depicted, rigid elongate member <b>150</b> may only be in contact with first section <b>118</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> and may not contact second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104.</b> Rigid elongate member <b>150</b> may be configured to keep first section <b>118</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> substantially planar when first section <b>118</b> bends in response to magnetic portion <b>134</b> of structure <b>130</b> rotating towards first surface <b>112</b> of second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104.</b> In this manner, angled section <b>122</b> may be substantially planar or substantially flat.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045">In one illustrative example, adhesive <b>146</b> may be present inside groove <b>116.</b> Adhesive <b>146</b> may be applied to groove <b>116</b> prior to first section <b>118</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> being bent. After angled section <b>122</b> has been formed, bending system <b>102</b> may hold angled section <b>122</b> at angle <b>121</b> relative to second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> for some selected amount of time to allow adhesive <b>146</b> to harden. Once adhesive <b>146</b> hardens, angled section <b>122</b> may remain substantially at angle <b>121</b> relative to second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> after bending system <b>102</b> is detached from workpiece <b>104.</b></p><p id="p0046" num="0046">In these illustrative examples, workpiece <b>104</b> may be comprised of flexible material <b>154.</b> Flexible material <b>154</b> may be any material configured to bend without causing undesired inconsistencies to form on and/or in workpiece <b>104.</b> Flexible material <b>154</b> may comprise, for<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> example, without limitation, a composite material, a flexible metal material, a flexible metal alloy, a silicone material, and/or other suitable types of flexible materials.</p><p id="p0047" num="0047">In some cases, structure <b>130</b> alone may be unable to bend first section <b>118</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> to form angled section <b>122.</b> For example, without limitation, the number of structures in group of structures <b>126</b> needed to form angled section <b>122</b> may increase as the length of workpiece <b>104</b> increases. Further, the number of structures included in group of structures <b>126</b> may depend on the flexibility of flexible material <b>154.</b> In this manner, bending system <b>102</b> may be adjustable. As one illustrative example, group of structures <b>126</b> may require at least two structures to bend workpiece <b>104.</b> However, in another illustrative example, group of structures <b>126</b> may require at least five structures to bend workpiece <b>104.</b></p><p id="p0048" num="0048">The size and weight of each of the structures in group of structures <b>126</b> may be sufficiently reduced to allow bending system <b>102</b> to be used along a moving line or assembly line in fabrication environment <b>100.</b> Further, the size and weight of each of the structures in group of structures <b>126</b> may be sufficiently reduced to give bending system <b>102</b> a desired level of portability.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">The illustration of bending system <b>102</b> and workpiece <b>104</b> in fabrication environment <b>100</b> in <figref idrefs="f0001"><b>Figure 1</b></figref> is not meant to imply physical or architectural limitations to the manner in which an illustrative embodiment may be implemented. Other components in addition to or in place of the ones illustrated may be used. Some components may be optional. Also, the blocks are presented to illustrate some functional components. One or more of these blocks may be combined, divided, or combined and divided into different blocks when implemented in an illustrative embodiment.</p><p id="p0050" num="0050">In some illustrative examples, adhesive <b>146</b> may not be used inside groove <b>116.</b> Rather, a resin material or some other type of material configured to harden in response to heat and/or pressure may be used inside groove <b>116.</b> In these examples, bending system <b>102</b> may hold angled section <b>122</b> at angle <b>121</b> relative to second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> while heat and/or pressure are applied to workpiece <b>104.</b> For example, without limitation, bending system <b>102</b> may hold angled section <b>122</b> at angle <b>121</b> relative to second section <b>120</b> inside an oven. The size of group of structures <b>126</b> may reduce the possibility of bending system <b>102</b> blocking and/or drawing heat away from workpiece <b>104</b> during heating more than desired.</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">Turning now to <figref idrefs="f0002 f0003 f0004 f0005 f0006 f0007 f0008 f0009 f0010"><b>Figures 2-11</b></figref><b>,</b> illustrations of a process for forming a part with an angled flange are depicted in accordance with an illustrative embodiment. In <figref idrefs="f0002 f0003 f0004 f0005 f0006 f0007 f0008 f0009 f0010"><b>Figures 2-11</b></figref><b>,</b> a flange on a workpiece may be bent at a selected angle to form an angled flange.</p><p id="p0052" num="0052">With reference now to <figref idrefs="f0002"><b>Figure 2</b></figref><b>,</b> an illustration of a front isometric view of a workpiece is depicted in accordance with an illustrative embodiment. In this illustrative example, workpiece <b>200</b> may be an example of one implementation for workpiece <b>104</b> in <figref idrefs="f0001"><b>Figure 1</b></figref><b>.</b> As depicted, workpiece <b>200</b> may have first side <b>202</b> and second side <b>204.</b> Further, workpiece may have first surface <b>206</b> at first side <b>202</b> and second surface <b>208</b> at second side <b>204.</b><!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></p><p id="p0053" num="0053">In this illustrative example, groove <b>210</b> may separate first section <b>212</b> and second section <b>214</b> of workpiece <b>200.</b> First section <b>212</b> and second section <b>214</b> may be examples of implementations for first section <b>118</b> and second section <b>120,</b> respectively, of workpiece <b>104</b> in <figref idrefs="f0001"><b>Figure 1</b></figref><b>.</b> Further, groove <b>210</b> may be an example of one implementation for groove <b>116</b> in <figref idrefs="f0001"><b>Figure 1</b></figref><b>.</b></p><p id="p0054" num="0054">As depicted, first section <b>212</b> and second section <b>214</b> may be substantially planar sections. First section <b>212</b> of workpiece <b>200</b> may also be referred to as flange <b>216</b> on workpiece <b>200</b> in these examples.</p><p id="p0055" num="0055">With reference now to <figref idrefs="f0003"><b>Figure 3</b></figref><b>,</b> an illustration of a front isometric view of a structure for a bending system is depicted in accordance with an illustrative embodiment. In <figref idrefs="f0003"><b>Figure 3</b></figref><b>,</b> structure <b>300</b> may be an example of one implementation for structure <b>130</b> in group of structures <b>126</b> in <figref idrefs="f0001"><b>Figure 1</b></figref><b>.</b> Structure <b>300</b> may be one structure in a group of structures (not shown) for use in a bending system (not shown).</p><p id="p0056" num="0056">As depicted, structure <b>300</b> may comprise retaining portion <b>302,</b> magnetic portion <b>304,</b> and support portion <b>306.</b> Retaining portion <b>302</b> and magnetic portion <b>304</b> may be examples of implementations for retaining portion <b>132</b> and magnetic portion <b>134,</b> respectively, in <figref idrefs="f0001"><b>Figure 1</b></figref><b>.</b> In this illustrative example, support portion <b>306</b> of structure <b>300</b> may be located between retaining portion <b>302</b> and magnetic portion <b>304.</b></p><p id="p0057" num="0057">In this illustrative example, retaining portion <b>302</b> of structure <b>300</b> may have slot <b>308.</b> Slot <b>308</b> may be an example of one implementation for slot <b>138</b> in <figref idrefs="f0001"><b>Figure 1</b></figref><b>.</b> Slot <b>308</b> may be configured to receive and retain first section <b>212</b> of workpiece <b>200</b> in <figref idrefs="f0002"><b>Figure 2</b></figref><b>.</b> As depicted, holding magnet <b>310</b> may be associated with slot <b>308.</b> Holding magnet <b>310</b> may be configured to hold a magnetic member, such as, for example, without limitation, rigid elongate member <b>150</b> in <figref idrefs="f0001"><b>Figure 1</b></figref><b>,</b> in place.</p><p id="p0058" num="0058">Magnetic portion <b>304</b> of structure <b>300</b> may have channel <b>312.</b> Channel <b>312</b> may be configured to receive and hold clamping magnet <b>314.</b> Clamping magnet <b>314</b> may be an example of one implementation for clamping magnet <b>140</b> in <figref idrefs="f0001"><b>Figure 1</b></figref><b>.</b> Channel <b>312</b> of magnetic portion <b>304</b> of structure <b>300</b> may have first opening <b>316.</b> Clamping magnet <b>314</b> may be inserted into channel <b>312</b> through first opening <b>316.</b> As depicted, first opening <b>316</b> may have first diameter <b>318.</b> In this illustrative example, fastener <b>320</b> may be used to keep clamping magnet <b>314</b> in place within channel <b>312</b> of magnetic portion <b>304</b> of structure <b>300.</b></p><p id="p0059" num="0059">With reference now to <figref idrefs="f0003"><b>Figure 4</b></figref><b>,</b> an illustration of a back isometric view of structure <b>300</b> from <figref idrefs="f0003"><b>Figure 3</b></figref> is depicted in accordance with an illustrative embodiment. In <figref idrefs="f0003"><b>Figure 4</b></figref><b>,</b> second opening <b>400</b> of channel <b>312</b> may be seen. Second opening <b>400</b> may have second diameter <b>402.</b></p><p id="p0060" num="0060">Second diameter <b>402</b> of second opening <b>400</b> may be smaller than first diameter <b>318</b> of first opening <b>316</b> in <figref idrefs="f0003"><b>Figure 3</b></figref><b>.</b> In particular, channel <b>312</b> may have lip <b>404</b> at second opening <b>400.</b> Lip <b>404</b> may be configured to reduce the possibility of clamping magnet <b>314</b> slipping out of channel <b>312</b> through second opening <b>400</b> when clamping magnet <b>314</b> is positioned relative to a locking magnet (not shown) exerting an attractive force.<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --></p><p id="p0061" num="0061">With reference now to <figref idrefs="f0004"><b>Figure 5</b></figref><b>,</b> an illustration of a front isometric view of a bending system is depicted in accordance with an illustrative embodiment. In <figref idrefs="f0004"><b>Figure 5</b></figref><b>,</b> bending system <b>500</b> may be an example of one implementation for bending system <b>102</b> in <figref idrefs="f0001"><b>Figure 1</b></figref><b>.</b> As depicted, bending system <b>500</b> may include structure <b>300</b> from <figref idrefs="f0003"><b>Figure 3</b></figref><b>,</b> as well as structures <b>502, 504, 506,</b> and <b>508.</b></p><p id="p0062" num="0062">Structures <b>300, 502, 504, 506,</b> and <b>508</b> may form group of structures <b>510.</b> Group of structures <b>510</b> may be an example of one implementation for group of structures <b>126</b> in <figref idrefs="f0001"><b>Figure 1</b></figref><b>.</b></p><p id="p0063" num="0063">In this illustrative example, structures <b>502, 504, 506,</b> and <b>508</b> in group of structures <b>510</b> may be implemented in a manner similar to structure <b>300.</b> For example, without limitation, structure <b>502</b> may have retaining portion <b>512,</b> magnetic portion <b>514,</b> and support portion <b>516.</b> Further, retaining portion <b>512</b> may have slot <b>518</b> and magnetic portion <b>514</b> may have channel <b>520.</b> Additionally, structure <b>504</b> may have retaining portion <b>522,</b> magnetic portion <b>524,</b> and support portion <b>526.</b> Further, retaining portion <b>522</b> may have slot <b>528</b> and magnetic portion <b>524</b> may have channel <b>530.</b></p><p id="p0064" num="0064">Structure <b>506</b> may have retaining portion <b>532,</b> magnetic portion <b>534,</b> and support portion <b>536.</b> Further, retaining portion <b>532</b> may have slot <b>538</b> and magnetic portion <b>534</b> may have channel <b>540.</b> Structure <b>508</b> may have retaining portion <b>542,</b> magnetic portion <b>544,</b> and support portion <b>546.</b> Further, retaining portion <b>542</b> may have slot <b>548</b> and magnetic portion <b>544</b> may have channel <b>550.</b></p><p id="p0065" num="0065">In this illustrative example, clamping magnet <b>314</b> associated with structure <b>300</b> may be one clamping magnet in group of clamping magnets <b>552</b> associated with group of structures <b>510.</b> Group of clamping magnets <b>552</b> may be an example of one implementation for group of clamping magnets <b>127</b> in <figref idrefs="f0001"><b>Figure 1</b></figref><b>.</b> In this illustrative example, group of clamping magnets <b>552</b> may include clamping magnets <b>554, 556, 558,</b> and <b>560</b> in addition to clamping magnet <b>314.</b></p><p id="p0066" num="0066">Clamping magnets <b>554, 556, 558,</b> and <b>560</b> may be associated with structures <b>502, 504, 506,</b> and <b>508,</b> respectively, in a manner similar to the manner in which clamping magnet <b>314</b> is associated with structure <b>300.</b> In particular, clamping magnets <b>554, 556, 558,</b> and <b>560</b> may be held within channel <b>520</b> of structure <b>502,</b> channel <b>530</b> of structure <b>504,</b> channel <b>540</b> of structure <b>506,</b> and channel <b>550</b> of structure <b>508,</b> respectively. Further, fasteners <b>562, 564, 566,</b> and <b>568</b> may be used to hold clamping magnets <b>554, 556, 558,</b> and <b>560,</b> respectively, in place similar to the manner in which fastener <b>320</b> is used to hold clamping magnet <b>314</b> in place within channel <b>312</b> of structure <b>300.</b></p><p id="p0067" num="0067">As depicted, rigid elongate member <b>570</b> may be magnetically attached to group of structures <b>510.</b> For example, without limitation, rigid elongate member <b>570</b> may be comprised of a magnetic material. Rigid elongate member <b>570</b> may be inserted into slot <b>308</b> of retaining portion <b>302</b> of structure <b>300</b> and held in place within slot <b>308</b> by holding magnet <b>310</b> (not shown in this view) from</p><p id="p0068" num="0068"><figref idrefs="f0003"><b>Figure 3</b></figref><b>.</b> Similarly, rigid elongate member <b>570</b> may be held within slot <b>518</b> of structure <b>502,</b> slot <b>528</b> of structure <b>504,</b> slot <b>538</b> of structure <b>506,</b> and slot <b>548</b> of structure <b>508,</b> respectively, by holding magnets (not shown in this view) within these slots.</p><p id="p0069" num="0069">Turning now to <figref idrefs="f0005"><b>Figure 6</b></figref><b>,</b> an illustration of a front isometric view of bending system <b>500</b> from <figref idrefs="f0004"><b>Figure 5</b></figref> placed over workpiece <b>200</b> from <figref idrefs="f0002"><b>Figure 2</b></figref> is depicted in accordance with an illustrative<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> embodiment. In <figref idrefs="f0005"><b>Figure 6</b></figref><b>,</b> bending system <b>500</b> may be placed over first section <b>212</b> of workpiece <b>200.</b></p><p id="p0070" num="0070">In particular, group of structures <b>510</b> may be placed over first section <b>212</b> of workpiece <b>200</b> to attach retaining portion <b>302</b> of structure <b>300,</b> retaining portion <b>512</b> of structure <b>502,</b> retaining portion <b>522</b> of structure <b>504,</b> retaining portion <b>532</b> of structure <b>506,</b> and retaining portion <b>542</b> of structure <b>508</b> to first section <b>212</b> of workpiece <b>200.</b> These retaining portions of group of structures <b>510</b> may be attached to first section <b>212</b> of workpiece <b>200</b> such that slot <b>308</b> of structure <b>300,</b> slot <b>518</b> of structure <b>502,</b> slot <b>528</b> of structure <b>504,</b> slot <b>538</b> of structure <b>506,</b> and slot <b>548</b> of structure <b>508,</b> receive first section <b>212</b> of workpiece <b>200.</b></p><p id="p0071" num="0071">Further, group of structures <b>510</b> may be placed over first section <b>212</b> of workpiece <b>200</b> such that magnetic portion <b>304</b> of structure <b>300,</b> magnetic portion <b>514</b> of structure <b>502,</b> magnetic portion <b>524</b> of structure <b>504,</b> magnetic portion <b>534</b> of structure <b>506,</b> and magnetic portion <b>544</b> of structure <b>508</b> are positioned at first side <b>202</b> of workpiece <b>200.</b> In particular, the magnetic portions of group of structures <b>510</b> may be angled relative to first surface <b>206</b> of workpiece <b>200</b> such that these magnetic portions are located away from first surface <b>206</b> of workpiece <b>200.</b></p><p id="p0072" num="0072">With reference now to <figref idrefs="f0006"><b>Figure 7</b></figref><b>,</b> an illustration of a cross-sectional side view of structure <b>300</b> attached to workpiece <b>200</b> is depicted in accordance with an illustrative embodiment. A cross-sectional side view of bending system <b>500</b> attached to workpiece <b>200</b> in <figref idrefs="f0005"><b>Figure 6</b></figref> taken along lines <b>7-7</b> in <figref idrefs="f0005"><b>Figure 6</b></figref> is depicted in <figref idrefs="f0006"><b>Figure 7</b></figref><b>.</b></p><p id="p0073" num="0073">As depicted, second section <b>214</b> of workpiece <b>200</b> may be positioned at angle <b>700</b> relative to magnetic portion <b>304</b> of structure <b>300.</b> In this illustrative example, retaining portion <b>302,</b> magnetic portion <b>304,</b> and support portion <b>306</b> may not be moveable with respect to each other. In this manner, rotation of magnetic portion <b>304</b> in a particular direction may cause rotation of retaining portion <b>302</b> in the same direction.</p><p id="p0074" num="0074">Consequently, rotation of magnetic portion <b>304</b> in the direction of arrow <b>704</b> about axis <b>706</b> through retaining portion <b>302</b> of structure <b>300</b> may cause retaining portion <b>302</b> to also rotate in the direction of arrow <b>704.</b> This rotation of structure <b>300</b> may cause first section <b>212</b> of workpiece <b>200</b> to bend at groove <b>210</b> when second section <b>214</b> is held in a substantially fixed position relative to magnetic portion <b>304</b> of structure <b>300.</b></p><p id="p0075" num="0075">In this illustrative example, adhesive <b>702</b> may be applied to groove <b>210</b> of workpiece <b>200.</b> Adhesive <b>702</b> may be used to hold first section <b>212</b> in a bent position when first section <b>212</b> is bent relative to second section <b>214</b> of workpiece <b>200.</b></p><p id="p0076" num="0076">With reference now to <figref idrefs="f0007"><b>Figure 8</b></figref><b>,</b> an illustration of a cross-sectional side view of structure <b>300</b> attached to workpiece <b>200</b> and a locking magnet positioned relative to workpiece <b>200</b> is depicted in accordance with an illustrative embodiment. In this illustrative example, locking magnet <b>800</b> may be positioned on second surface <b>208</b> of workpiece <b>200</b> at second side <b>204</b> of workpiece <b>200.</b> Locking<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> magnet <b>800</b> may be one locking magnet in a group of locking magnets (not shown) that may be positioned on second surface <b>208</b> of workpiece <b>200.</b></p><p id="p0077" num="0077">When locking magnet <b>800</b> is positioned on second surface <b>208,</b> locking magnet <b>800</b> may exert attractive force <b>802.</b> Clamping magnet <b>314</b> (not shown in this view) from <figref idrefs="f0003"><b>Figure 3</b></figref> held within magnetic portion <b>304</b> of structure <b>300</b> may be attracted to locking magnet <b>800</b> in response to attractive force <b>802.</b> This attraction may cause clamping magnet <b>314</b> (not shown in this view) and magnetic portion <b>304</b> of structure <b>300</b> to move towards second section <b>214</b> of workpiece <b>200.</b></p><p id="p0078" num="0078">In <figref idrefs="f0007"><b>Figure 8</b></figref><b>,</b> clamping magnet <b>314</b> (not shown in this view) and magnetic portion <b>304</b> of structure <b>300</b> have rotated in the direction of arrow <b>704</b> about axis <b>706</b> through retaining portion <b>302</b> of structure <b>300</b> towards first surface <b>206</b> of workpiece <b>200</b> from the positions of clamping magnet <b>314</b> and magnetic portion <b>304</b> in <figref idrefs="f0006"><b>Figure 7</b></figref><b>.</b> As depicted, clamping magnet <b>314</b> (not shown in this view) and magnetic portion <b>304</b> of structure <b>300</b> may be rotated in the direction of arrow <b>704</b> until magnetic portion <b>304</b> is in contact with first surface <b>206</b> of workpiece <b>200.</b></p><p id="p0079" num="0079">Attractive force <b>802</b> exerted by locking magnet <b>800</b> may cause clamping magnet <b>314</b> (not shown in this view) and locking magnet <b>800</b> to remain in locked positions against first surface <b>206</b> and second surface <b>208,</b> respectively, of workpiece <b>200.</b> In other words, attractive force <b>802</b> may cause clamping magnet <b>314</b> to be pulled up against first surface <b>206</b> and locking magnet <b>800</b> to be pulled up against second surface <b>208</b> opposite each other.</p><p id="p0080" num="0080">In this illustrative example, rotation of clamping magnet <b>314</b> (not shown in this view) and magnetic portion <b>304</b> of structure <b>300</b> towards first surface <b>206</b> of workpiece <b>200</b> may cause first section <b>212</b> of workpiece <b>200</b> to bend at groove <b>210</b> in workpiece <b>200.</b> First section <b>212</b> of workpiece <b>200</b> may bend such that first section <b>212</b> takes the form of angled section <b>806.</b> Angled section <b>806</b> may be referred to as angled flange <b>808.</b> Angled section <b>806</b> may have angle <b>810</b> relative to second section <b>214</b> of workpiece <b>200.</b></p><p id="p0081" num="0081">With reference now to <figref idrefs="f0008"><b>Figure 9</b></figref><b>,</b> an illustration of a back isometric view of a group of locking magnets positioned on second surface <b>208</b> of workpiece <b>200</b> is depicted in accordance with an illustrative embodiment. In this illustrative example, group of locking magnets <b>900</b> may be positioned on second surface <b>208</b> of workpiece <b>200.</b> As depicted, group of locking magnets <b>900</b> may include locking magnet <b>800</b> from <figref idrefs="f0007"><b>Figure 8</b></figref><b>,</b> as well as locking magnets <b>902, 904, 906,</b> and <b>908.</b></p><p id="p0082" num="0082">When group of locking magnets <b>900</b> is positioned on second surface <b>208</b> of workpiece <b>200,</b> magnetic portion <b>304</b> (not shown in this view) of structure <b>300,</b> magnetic portion <b>514</b> (not shown in this view) of structure <b>502,</b> magnetic portion <b>524</b> (not shown in this view) of structure <b>504,</b> magnetic portion <b>534</b> (not shown in this view) of structure <b>506,</b> and magnetic portion <b>544</b> (not shown in this view) of structure <b>508</b> from <figref idrefs="f0004"><b>Figure 5</b></figref> may rotate towards first surface <b>206</b> of workpiece <b>200</b> such that first section <b>212</b> of workpiece <b>200</b> bends to form angled section <b>806.</b><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></p><p id="p0083" num="0083">In this illustrative example, rigid elongate member <b>570</b> may be configured to keep angled section <b>806</b> substantially planar when first section <b>212</b> bends. In other words, rigid elongate member <b>570</b> may keep angled section <b>806</b> substantially planar or flat.</p><p id="p0084" num="0084">With reference now to <figref idrefs="f0009"><b>Figure 10</b></figref><b>,</b> an illustration of a front isometric view of bending system <b>500</b> holding angled section <b>806</b> of workpiece <b>200</b> in place is depicted in accordance with an illustrative embodiment. As depicted in <figref idrefs="f0008"><b>Figure 9</b></figref><b>,</b> bending system <b>500</b> may hold angled section <b>806</b> of workpiece <b>200</b> at angle <b>810</b> relative to second section <b>214</b> of workpiece <b>200.</b></p><p id="p0085" num="0085">Angled section <b>806</b> may be held at angle <b>810</b> for a selected amount of time until adhesive <b>702</b> (not shown in this view) from <figref idrefs="f0006"><b>Figure 7</b></figref> hardens. In some illustrative examples, heat and/or pressure may be applied to workpiece <b>200</b> while bending system <b>500</b> holds angled section <b>806</b> of workpiece <b>200</b> at angle <b>810</b> to harden adhesive <b>702</b> (not shown in this view) from <figref idrefs="f0006"><b>Figure 7</b></figref><b>.</b></p><p id="p0086" num="0086">With reference now to <figref idrefs="f0010"><b>Figure 11</b></figref><b>,</b> an illustration of a front isometric view of a part with an angled section is depicted in accordance with an illustrative embodiment. As depicted, bending system <b>500</b> from <figref idrefs="f0004 f0005 f0006 f0007 f0008 f0009"><b>Figures 5-10</b></figref> may be removed from workpiece <b>200.</b> Once angled section <b>806</b> has been formed, workpiece <b>200</b> may be referred to as part <b>1100.</b> Part <b>1100</b> may be configured for use in an overhead bin (not shown in this view) for an aircraft.</p><p id="p0087" num="0087">The illustrations of workpiece <b>200</b> in <figref idrefs="f0002"><b>Figure 2</b></figref> and <figref idrefs="f0004"><b>Figures 5</b></figref><b>-10,</b> structure <b>300</b> in <figref idrefs="f0003"><b>Figures 3</b>-<b>4,</b></figref> bending system <b>500</b> in <figref idrefs="f0004 f0005 f0006 f0007 f0008 f0009"><b>Figures 5-10</b></figref><b>,</b> and part <b>1100</b> in <figref idrefs="f0010"><b>Figure 11</b></figref> are not meant to imply physical or architectural limitations to the manner in which an illustrative embodiment may be implemented. Other components in addition to or in place of the ones illustrated may be used. Some components may be optional.</p><p id="p0088" num="0088">Further, the different components shown in <figref idrefs="f0002 f0003 f0004 f0005 f0006 f0007 f0008 f0009 f0010"><b>Figures 2-11</b></figref> may be combined with components in <figref idrefs="f0001"><b>Figure 1</b></figref><b>,</b> used with components in <figref idrefs="f0001"><b>Figure 1</b></figref><b>,</b> or a combination of the two. Additionally, some of the components in <figref idrefs="f0002 f0003 f0004 f0005 f0006 f0007 f0008 f0009 f0010"><b>Figures 2-11</b></figref> may be illustrative examples of how components shown in block form in <figref idrefs="f0001"><b>Figure 1</b></figref> may be implemented as physical structures.</p><p id="p0089" num="0089">With reference now to <figref idrefs="f0011"><b>Figure 12</b></figref><b>,</b> an illustration of an isometric view of a bin structure for an overhead bin for an aircraft is depicted in accordance with an illustrative embodiment. In this illustrative example, bin structure <b>1200</b> may be a part for an overhead bin (not shown) for an aircraft (not shown). In particular, bin structure <b>1200</b> may be connected to a bin receptacle to form an overhead bin in an aircraft.</p><p id="p0090" num="0090">As depicted, bin structure <b>1200</b> may be formed using part <b>1202</b> and part <b>1204.</b> In this illustrative example, part <b>1202</b> may have angled flange <b>1206</b> and part <b>1204</b> may have angled flange <b>1208.</b></p><p id="p0091" num="0091">Angled flange <b>1206</b> and angled flange <b>1208</b> may be formed using bending system <b>1210</b> and bending system <b>1212.</b> Bending system <b>1210</b> and bending system <b>1212</b> may be examples of two different implementations for bending system <b>102</b> in <figref idrefs="f0001"><b>Figure 1</b></figref><b>.</b> As depicted, bending system <b>1210</b> may include group of structures <b>1214</b> and bending system <b>1212</b> may include group of structures <b>1216.</b><!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></p><p id="p0092" num="0092">In this illustrative example, rigid elongate member <b>1218</b> may keep angled flange <b>1206</b> substantially planar when bending system <b>1210</b> forms angled flange <b>1206.</b> Rigid elongate member <b>1218</b> may be magnetically attached to group of structures <b>1214</b> prior to forming angled flange <b>1206.</b> Further, rigid elongate member <b>1218</b> may be considered part of bending system <b>1210.</b></p><p id="p0093" num="0093">In a similar manner, rigid elongate member <b>1220</b> may keep angled flange <b>1208</b> substantially planar when bending system <b>1210</b> forms angled flange <b>1208.</b> However, rigid elongate member <b>1220</b> may be associated with part <b>1204.</b> In this illustrative example, rigid elongate member <b>1220</b> may be part of bin structure <b>1200.</b> In this manner, rigid elongate member <b>1220</b> may not be considered part of bending system <b>1212.</b></p><p id="p0094" num="0094">As depicted, both bending system <b>1210</b> and bending system <b>1212</b> may be used at the same time during the assembly of bin structure <b>1200.</b> Further, bending system <b>1210</b> and bending system <b>1212</b> may be left attached to part <b>1202</b> and part <b>1204,</b> respectively, while other operations are performed on bin structure <b>1200.</b> These operations may include, for example, without limitation, a number of assembly operations, a number of finishing operations, a number of fastening operations, and/or other types of operations.</p><p id="p0095" num="0095">The illustration of bin structure <b>1200,</b> part <b>1202,</b> part <b>1204,</b> bending system <b>1210,</b> and bending system <b>1212</b> in <figref idrefs="f0011"><b>Figure 12</b></figref> is not meant to imply physical or architectural limitations to the manner in which an illustrative embodiment may be implemented. Other components in addition to or in place of the ones illustrated may be used. Some components may be optional.</p><p id="p0096" num="0096">Further, the different components shown in <figref idrefs="f0011"><b>Figure 12</b></figref> may be combined with components in <figref idrefs="f0001"><b>Figure 1</b></figref><b>,</b> used with components in <figref idrefs="f0001"><b>Figure 1</b></figref><b>,</b> or a combination of the two. Additionally, some of the components in <figref idrefs="f0011"><b>Figure 12</b></figref> may be illustrative examples of how components shown in block form in <figref idrefs="f0001"><b>Figure 1</b></figref> may be implemented as physical structures.</p><p id="p0097" num="0097">With reference now to <figref idrefs="f0012"><b>Figure 13</b></figref><b>,</b> an illustration of a process for forming an angled section on a workpiece in the form of a flowchart is depicted in accordance with an illustrative embodiment. The process illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0012"><b>Figure 13</b></figref> may be implemented using bending system <b>102</b> in <figref idrefs="f0001"><b>Figure 1</b></figref><b>.</b> In particular, this process may use bending system <b>102</b> to bend workpiece <b>104</b> to form angled section <b>122</b> in <figref idrefs="f0001"><b>Figure 1</b></figref><b>.</b></p><p id="p0098" num="0098">The process may begin by attaching rigid elongate member <b>150</b> to the retaining portion of each structure in group of structures <b>126</b> (operation <b>1300).</b> In other words, in operation <b>1300,</b> rigid elongate member <b>150</b> may be received within the retaining portion of each structure in group of structures <b>126.</b></p><p id="p0099" num="0099">In one illustrative example, rigid elongate member <b>150</b> may be magnetically attached within a slot in the retaining portion of each structure in group of structures <b>126</b> in operation <b>1300.</b> For example, without limitation, rigid elongate member <b>150</b> may be magnetically attached to retaining portion <b>132</b> of structure <b>130</b> within slot <b>138</b> of retaining portion <b>132.</b> In particular, holding magnet<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> <b>152</b> may be used to hold rigid elongate member <b>150</b> within the retaining portion of each structure in group of structures <b>126.</b></p><p id="p0100" num="0100">Next, group of structures <b>126</b> with rigid elongate member <b>150</b> may be positioned over first section <b>118</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> such that first section <b>118</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> is received within the slot of the retaining portion of each structure in group of structures <b>126</b> (operation <b>1302).</b> In this illustrative example, second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> may be positioned at an angle relative to the magnetic portion of each structure in group of structures <b>126</b> in response to operation <b>1302</b> being performed. Further, the magnetic portion of each structure in group of structures <b>126</b> may be positioned at first side <b>108</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> in response to operation <b>1302</b> being performed.</p><p id="p0101" num="0101">Second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> may be held in a substantially fixed position relative to the magnetic portion of each structure in group of structures <b>126</b> (operation <b>1304).</b> Operation <b>1304</b> may be performed using, for example, without limitation, positioning system <b>148.</b></p><p id="p0102" num="0102">Group of locking magnets <b>128</b> may be positioned at second side <b>110</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> (operation <b>1306).</b> Group of locking magnets <b>128</b> may exert number of attractive forces <b>129</b> that may be configured to cause a clamping magnet associated with the magnetic portion of each structure in group of structures <b>126</b> to move towards second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> (operation <b>1308).</b></p><p id="p0103" num="0103">For example, without limitation, attractive force <b>144</b> exerted by locking magnet <b>142</b> positioned on second surface <b>114</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> may cause clamping magnet <b>140</b> associated with magnetic portion <b>134</b> of structure <b>130</b> to rotate towards first surface <b>112</b> of workpiece <b>104.</b> Clamping magnet <b>140</b> and magnetic portion <b>134</b> of structure <b>130</b> may rotate until magnetic portion <b>134</b> comes into contact with first surface <b>112</b> of second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104.</b></p><p id="p0104" num="0104">First section <b>118</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> may bend relative to second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> in response to the magnetic portion of each structure in group of structures <b>126</b> moving towards second section <b>120</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> (operation <b>1310),</b> with the process terminating thereafter. In operation <b>1310,</b> first section <b>118</b> may bend at groove <b>116</b> in workpiece <b>104.</b> Further, rigid elongate member <b>150</b> may keep first section <b>118</b> of workpiece <b>104</b> substantially planar when first section <b>118</b> bends during operation <b>1310.</b></p><p id="p0105" num="0105">The flowcharts and block diagrams in the different depicted embodiments illustrate the architecture, functionality, and operation of some possible implementations of apparatus and methods in an illustrative embodiment. In this regard, each block in the flowcharts or block diagrams may represent a module, segment, function, and/or a portion of an operation or step. For example, one or more of the blocks may be implemented as program code, in hardware, or a combination of the program code and hardware.</p><p id="p0106" num="0106">When implemented in hardware, the hardware may, for example, take the form of integrated circuits that are manufactured or configured to perform one or more operations in the flowcharts or block diagrams. For example, one or more of the operations in <figref idrefs="f0012"><b>Figure 13</b></figref> may be implemented using a robotic system.<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --></p><p id="p0107" num="0107">In some alternative implementations of an illustrative embodiment, the function or functions noted in the blocks may occur out of the order noted in the figures. For example, in some cases, two blocks shown in succession may be executed substantially concurrently, or the blocks may sometimes be performed in the reverse order, depending upon the functionality involved. Also, other blocks may be added in addition to the illustrated blocks in a flowchart or block diagram.</p><p id="p0108" num="0108">Illustrative embodiments of the disclosure may be described in the context of aircraft manufacturing and service method <b>1400</b> as shown in <figref idrefs="f0013"><b>Figure 14</b></figref> and aircraft <b>1500</b> as shown in <figref idrefs="f0013"><b>Figure 15</b></figref><b>.</b> Turning first to <figref idrefs="f0013"><b>Figure 14</b></figref><b>,</b> an illustration of an aircraft manufacturing and service method in the form of a block diagram is depicted in accordance with an illustrative embodiment. During pre-production, aircraft manufacturing and service method <b>1400</b> may include specification and design <b>1402</b> of aircraft <b>1500</b> in <figref idrefs="f0013"><b>Figure 15</b></figref> and material procurement <b>1404.</b></p><p id="p0109" num="0109">During production, component and subassembly manufacturing <b>1406</b> and system integration <b>1408</b> of aircraft <b>1500</b> in <figref idrefs="f0013"><b>Figure 15</b></figref> takes place. Thereafter, aircraft <b>1500</b> in <figref idrefs="f0013"><b>Figure 15</b></figref> may go through certification and delivery <b>1410</b> in order to be placed in service <b>1412.</b> While in service <b>1412</b> by a customer, aircraft <b>1500</b> in <figref idrefs="f0013"><b>Figure 15</b></figref> is scheduled for routine maintenance and service <b>1414,</b> which may include modification, reconfiguration, refurbishment, and other maintenance or service.</p><p id="p0110" num="0110">Each of the processes of aircraft manufacturing and service method <b>1400</b> may be performed or carried out by a system integrator, a third party, and/or an operator. In these examples, the operator may be a customer. For the purposes of this description, a system integrator may include, without limitation, any number of aircraft manufacturers and major-system subcontractors; a third party may include, without limitation, any number of vendors, subcontractors, and suppliers; and an operator may be an airline, a leasing company, a military entity, a service organization, and so on.</p><p id="p0111" num="0111">With reference now to <figref idrefs="f0013"><b>Figure 15</b></figref><b>,</b> an illustration of an aircraft in the form of a block diagram is depicted in which an illustrative embodiment may be implemented. In this example, aircraft <b>1500</b> is produced by aircraft manufacturing and service method <b>1400</b> in <figref idrefs="f0013"><b>Figure 14</b></figref> and may include airframe <b>1502</b> with plurality of systems <b>1504</b> and interior <b>1506.</b> Examples of systems <b>1504</b> include one or more of propulsion system <b>1508,</b> electrical system <b>1510,</b> hydraulic system <b>1512,</b> and environmental system <b>1514.</b> Any number of other systems may be included. Although an aerospace example is shown, different illustrative embodiments may be applied to other industries, such as the automotive industry.</p><p id="p0112" num="0112">Apparatuses and methods embodied herein may be employed during at least one of the stages of aircraft manufacturing and service method <b>1400</b> in <figref idrefs="f0013"><b>Figure 14</b></figref><b>.</b> In one illustrative example, components or subassemblies produced in component and subassembly manufacturing <b>1406</b> in <figref idrefs="f0013"><b>Figure 14</b></figref> may be fabricated or manufactured in a manner similar to components or subassemblies produced while aircraft <b>1500</b> is in service <b>1412</b> in <figref idrefs="f0013"><b>Figure 14</b></figref><b>.</b> As yet another example, one or more apparatus embodiments, method embodiments, or a combination thereof may<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> be utilized during production stages, such as component and subassembly manufacturing <b>1406</b> and system integration <b>1408</b> in <figref idrefs="f0013"><b>Figure 14</b></figref><b>.</b></p><p id="p0113" num="0113">For example, without limitation, bending system <b>102</b> in <figref idrefs="f0001"><b>Figure 1</b></figref> may be used to form and/or rework parts for aircraft <b>1500</b> during one or more of component and subassembly manufacturing <b>1406,</b> system integration <b>1408,</b> routine maintenance and service <b>1414</b> and other stages during the processes of aircraft manufacturing and service method <b>1400</b> in <figref idrefs="f0013"><b>Figure 14</b></figref><b>.</b> For example, without limitation, bending system <b>102</b> in <figref idrefs="f0001"><b>Figure 1</b></figref> may be used to form one or more parts for an overhead bin for aircraft <b>1500</b> in <figref idrefs="f0013"><b>Figure 15</b></figref><b>,</b> such as bin structure <b>1200</b> in <figref idrefs="f0011"><b>Figure 12</b></figref><b>.</b></p><p id="p0114" num="0114">One or more apparatus embodiments, method embodiments, or a combination thereof may be utilized while aircraft <b>1500</b> is in service <b>1412</b> and/or during maintenance and service <b>1414</b> in <figref idrefs="f0013"><b>Figure 14</b></figref><b>.</b> The use of a number of the different illustrative embodiments may substantially expedite the assembly of and/or reduce the cost of aircraft <b>1500.</b></p><p id="p0115" num="0115">Thus, the different illustrative embodiments may provide a method and apparatus for bending a flange to form an angled flange for a part. The different illustrative embodiments may provide a bending system, such as bending system <b>102</b> in <figref idrefs="f0001"><b>Figure 1</b></figref><b>,</b> configured to form angled flange <b>125</b> for part <b>105.</b> Bending system <b>102</b> may have a size and weight configured for portability and for use on a moving line or an assembly line. Further, bending system <b>102</b> may have a size and weight that allow bending system <b>102</b> to be used inside a curing system, an oven, or an autoclave without drawing heat away from workpiece <b>104</b> in amounts outside of selected tolerances.</p><p id="p0116" num="0116">Additionally, the number of structures used in group of structures <b>126</b> for bending system <b>102</b> to form angled flange <b>125</b> may be adjusted based on the length of workpiece <b>104.</b> In this manner, a single bending system <b>102</b> may be used with different sizes of workpieces.</p><p id="p0117" num="0117">The description of the different illustrative embodiments has been presented for purposes of illustration and description, and is not intended to be exhaustive or limited to the embodiments in the form disclosed. Many modifications and variations will be apparent to those of ordinary skill in the art. Further, different illustrative embodiments may provide different features as compared to other illustrative embodiments. The embodiment or embodiments selected are chosen and described in order to best explain the principles of the embodiments, the practical application, and to enable others of ordinary skill in the art to understand the disclosure for various embodiments with various modifications as are suited to the particular use contemplated.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56983064" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --><claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>An apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a structure (130) comprising a retaining portion (132) and a magnetic portion (134) in which the retaining portion (132) of the structure (130) is configured to receive a first section (118) of a workpiece (104) such that a second section (120) of the workpiece (104) is positioned at an angle (121) relative to the magnetic portion (134) of the structure (130) and the magnetic portion (134) of the structure (130) is positioned at a first side (108) of the workpiece (104); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a locking magnet (142) configured to exert an attractive force (144) that causes the magnetic portion (134) of the structure (130) to move towards the second section (120) of the workpiece (104) when the locking magnet (142) is positioned at a second side (110) of the workpiece (104).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The apparatus of claim 1, wherein the first section (118) of the workpiece (104) bends relative to the second section (120) of the workpiece (104) when the magnetic portion (134) of the structure (130) moves towards the second section (120) of the workpiece (104) and the second section (120) of the workpiece (104) remains in a substantially fixed position relative to the magnetic portion (134) of the structure (130).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The apparatus of claim 2 further comprising:
<claim-text>a positioning system (148) configured to hold the second section (120) of the workpiece (104) in the substantially fixed position while the magnetic portion (134) of the structure (130) moves towards the second section (120) of the workpiece (104).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The apparatus of claim 2 or 3 further comprising:
<claim-text>a rigid elongate member (150), wherein the retaining portion (132) of the structure (130) is configured to receive both the rigid elongate member (150) and the first section (118) of the workpiece (104), and wherein the retaining portion (132) of the structure (130) is configured to receive both the rigid elongate member (150) and the first section (118) of the workpiece (104) such that the first section (118) of the workpiece (104) remains substantially planar when the first section (118) of the workpiece (104) bends relative to the second section (120) of the workpiece (104).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The apparatus of any preceding claim further comprising:
<claim-text>a clamping magnet (140) associated with the magnetic portion (134) of the structure (130), wherein the attractive force (144) exerted by the locking magnet (142) when the locking magnet (142) is positioned at the second side (110) of the workpiece (104) causes the clamping magnet (140) to move towards the second section (120) of the workpiece (104) until the magnetic portion (134) of the structure (130) contacts a surface (112) of the second section (120) of the workpiece (104).</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The apparatus of any preceding claim wherein the retaining portion (132) of the structure (130) comprises:
<claim-text>a slot (138) configured to receive the first section (118) of the workpiece (104) when the retaining portion (132) is placed over the first section (118) of the workpiece (104), wherein the slot (138) is configured to receive the first section (118) of the workpiece (104) and a rigid elongate member (150); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a holding magnet (152) located in the slot (138) of the retaining portion (132) of the structure (130) and configured to hold the rigid elongate member (150) in the slot (138).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The apparatus of any preceding claim, wherein a groove (116) on the first side (108) of the workpiece (104) separates the first section (118) of the workpiece (104) from the second section (120) of the workpiece (104), and, wherein the first section (118) of the workpiece (104) is a flange (124) configured to bend relative to the second section (120) of the workpiece (104) at the groove (116) to form an angled flange (125) when the magnetic portion (134) of the structure (130) moves towards the second section (120) of the workpiece (104) and the second section (120) of the workpiece (104) remains in a substantially fixed position relative to the magnetic portion (134) of the structure (130).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The apparatus of any preceding claim wherein the structure (130) is one structure (130) in a group of structures (126) and the locking magnet (142) is one locking magnet (142) in a group of locking magnets (128) and wherein the group of structures (126) and the group of locking magnets (128) form a bending system (102).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The apparatus of any preceding claim wherein the workpiece (104) comprises a flexible material (154) in which the flexible material (154) comprises at least one of a composite material, a flexible metal material, a flexible metal alloy, and a silicone material.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>A method for bending a workpiece (104), the method comprising:
<claim-text>receiving a first section (118) of the workpiece (104) within a retaining portion (132) of a structure (130);</claim-text>
<claim-text>positioning a second section (120) of the workpiece (104) at an angle (121) relative to a magnetic portion (134) of the structure (130); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>positioning the magnetic portion (134) of the structure (130) at a first side (108) of the workpiece (104).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>The method of claim 10, wherein the steps of positioning the second section (120) of the workpiece (104) at the angle (121) relative to the magnetic portion (134) of the structure (130) and<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> positioning the magnetic portion (134) of the structure (130) at the first side (108) of the workpiece (104) are performed in response to receiving the first section (118) of the workpiece (104) within the retaining portion (132) of the structure (130).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>The method of claim 10 further comprising:
<claim-text>holding the second section (120) of the workpiece (104) in a substantially fixed position relative to the magnetic portion (134) of the structure (130).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>The method of claim 12 further comprising:
<claim-text>exerting, by a locking magnet (142) positioned at a second side (110) of the workpiece (104), an attractive force (144) that causes the magnetic portion (134) of the structure (130) to move towards the second section (120) of the workpiece (104), said exerting comprises:
<claim-text>exerting, by the locking magnet (142) positioned at the second side (110) of the workpiece (110), the attractive force (144) that causes a clamping magnet (140) associated with the magnetic portion (134) of the structure (130) to move towards the second section (120) of the workpiece (104) until the magnetic portion (134) of the structure (130) contacts a surface (112) of the second section (120) of the workpiece (104).</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>The method of any preceding claim further comprising:
<claim-text>bending the first section (118) of the workpiece (104) relative to the second section (120) of the workpiece (104) in response to the magnetic portion (134) of the structure (130) moving towards the second section (120) of the workpiece (104) while the second section (120) of the workpiece (104) remains in the substantially fixed position.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>The method of claim 14, wherein the step of receiving the first section (118) of the workpiece (104) within the retaining portion (132) of the structure (130) comprises:
<claim-text>receiving a rigid elongate member (150) and the first section (118) of the workpiece (104) within a slot (138) in the retaining portion (132) of the structure (130) wherein the step of receiving comprises</claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving the rigid elongate member (150) and the first section (118) of the workpiece (104) within the slot (138) in the retaining portion (132) of the structure (130), wherein the rigid elongate member (150) is configured to keep the first section (118) of the workpiece (104) substantially planar when the first section (118) of the workpiece (104) bends relative to the second section (120) of the workpiece (104); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>holding the rigid elongate member (150) within the slot (138) of the retaining portion (132) of the workpiece (104) using a holding magnet (152).</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16671366" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="158" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="158" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3,4"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="165" he="220" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --><figure id="f0004" num="5"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="165" he="228" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --><figure id="f0005" num="6"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="165" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --><figure id="f0006" num="7"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="165" he="225" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --><figure id="f0007" num="8"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="165" he="225" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --><figure id="f0008" num="9"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="165" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --><figure id="f0009" num="10"><img id="if0009" file="imgf0009.tif" wi="165" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --><figure id="f0010" num="11"><img id="if0010" file="imgf0010.tif" wi="165" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --><figure id="f0011" num="12"><img id="if0011" file="imgf0011.tif" wi="165" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --><figure id="f0012" num="13"><img id="if0012" file="imgf0012.tif" wi="165" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="36"> --><figure id="f0013" num="14,15"><img id="if0013" file="imgf0013.tif" wi="161" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><search-report-data><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="158" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="159" he="233" type="tif"/></search-report-data><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
