<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2417915-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2417915" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="42931476" file-reference-id="316852" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146588466" ucid="EP-2417915-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2417915</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-11177071-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154850658" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>11177071</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20110810</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP175458631" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>11177071.5</doc-number><date>20110810</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140549253" ucid="GB-201013470-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>GB</country><doc-number>201013470</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20100811</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20131105</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989325731" load-source="docdb">A61B  17/02        20060101AFI20121016BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989325732" load-source="docdb">A61B  17/17        20060101ALI20121016BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1702771998" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61B2090/061       20160201 LA20180127BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1702771999" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61B2019/545       20130101 LA20160317BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1957314753" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61B  17/72        20130101 LI20160317BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1957316557" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61F2002/4658      20130101 LA20160317BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1957316771" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61B  17/025       20130101 LI20160321BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1957318427" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61B  17/1675      20130101 LI20160317BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1957319969" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61B  17/1764      20130101 FI20160321BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2049530959" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61B2017/0268      20130101 LA20150605BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2049538428" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61B  17/155       20130101 LA20150605BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370031" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Bandspanner und Bohrerführung</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370032" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Ligament balancer and drill guide</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370033" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Équilibreur de ligament et guide-foret</invention-title></technical-data><related-documents><relation type="division-into"><child-doc ucid="EP-12192969.9"><document-id load-source="patent-office" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12192969.9</doc-number><date>20121116</date></document-id></child-doc><parent-doc ucid="EP-11177071-A"><document-id load-source="patent-office" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>11177071</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20110810</date></document-id><parent-grant-document ucid="EP-2417915-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2417915</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date></document-id></parent-grant-document></parent-doc></relation></related-documents><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919513488" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>BIOMET UK HEALTHCARE LTD</last-name><address><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919506566" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>BIOMET UK HEALTHCARE LIMITED</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919504902" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>HUTCHISON NICHOLAS WILLIAM</last-name><address><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919538468" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>Hutchison, Nicholas William</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919023240" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Hutchison, Nicholas William</last-name><address><street>Warwick House Patterdown</street><city>Chippenham, Wiltshire SN15 2NR</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919517333" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>LLOYD RUSSELL</last-name><address><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919522898" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>LLOYD, RUSSELL</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919023235" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>LLOYD, RUSSELL</last-name><address><street>73 Sedgebrook Road Liden</street><city>Swindon, Oxfordshire SN3 6EZ</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919514181" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>MURRAY DAVID WYCLIFFE</last-name><address><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919544449" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>MURRAY, DAVID WYCLIFFE</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919023236" load-source="patent-office" sequence="3" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>MURRAY, DAVID WYCLIFFE</last-name><address><street>Cuddesdon House Cuddesdon</street><city>Oxford, Oxfordshire OX44 9HB</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919504070" load-source="docdb" sequence="4" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>DODD CHRISTOPHER ALEXANDER</last-name><address><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919514151" load-source="docdb" sequence="4" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>DODD, CHRISTOPHER ALEXANDER</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919023238" load-source="patent-office" sequence="4" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>DODD, CHRISTOPHER ALEXANDER</last-name><address><street>1 Tackley Place</street><city>Oxford, Oxfordshire OX2 6RR</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919023239" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Biomet UK Healthcare Limited</last-name><iid>101261783</iid><address><street>Waterton Industrial Estate</street><city>Bridgend South Wales CF31 3XA</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919023237" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Giles, Ashley Simon</last-name><iid>100036177</iid><address><street>Haseltine Lake LLP Lincoln House, 5th Floor 300 High Holborn</street><city>London WC1V 7JH</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549924147" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS549893239" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549924148" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549785809" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549785882" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549880105" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549880110" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549803038" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549924149" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549924150" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549870489" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549785810" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549785811" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549803039" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549924151" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549803048" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549880111" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549785883" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549924152" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549785812" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549924153" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549803049" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549893240" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549785817" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549803050" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549893245" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS549893246" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549785818" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549785884" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549785819" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549870498" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549803051" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549870499" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS549785820" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549875592" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549785889" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549785890" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS549924154" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63960887" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to tools for use in knee surgery and particularly to a ligament balancer and a drill guide for a knee. The closest prior art is <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US5860980A"><text>US-A-5860980</text></patcit>, which defines the preamble of claim 1.</p><heading id="h0001"><b>Background</b></heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">When a knee joint becomes damaged or diseased, it is known to replace all or part of the knee joint with a prosthesis. A common form of prosthesis comprises a femoral component, which is attached to a distal end of a femur, and a tibial component, which is attached to a proximal end of a tibia. The femoral and tibial components may articulate directly or may be separated by a meniscal bearing component. The femoral component also articulates with a patella, which is secured in position by a quadriceps tendon and a patellar ligament.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">The articulation of a natural knee joint is stabilised by the action of medial and lateral collateral ligaments and anterior and posterior cruciate ligaments. Where possible, all of these ligaments are retained when a prosthesis is implanted, although in practice it is often necessary to remove at least the posterior cruciate ligament. It is desirable for tension in the knee ligaments after surgery to be balanced throughout the range of motion of the knee.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">The most complex component of a knee prosthesis is the femoral component, as it carries not only the condylar bearing surfaces, but also the patella bearing surface, which extends along an anterior face of the distal femur. Conventional femoral components require resection of the distal end surface of the femur and the anterior and posterior faces of the femur. They also usually require two chamfered cuts to be made at the distal end of the femur anteriorly and posteriorly. The positioning of the femoral cuts determines the position and orientation of the implanted femoral component, and hence the bearing surfaces which it carries. The correct positioning of the femoral cuts is vitally important therefore to ensuring equal tension in the ligaments after surgery.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">It is known to use surgical jigs to guide the positioning of the femoral cuts. Correct placing of a jig to ensure balancing of the ligaments with the knee in flexion is complicated by the presence of the patella. The patella is conventionally either everted<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> or subluxed in order to provide sufficient space for the surgical jig. However, this means that the substantial force exerted via the patella and patellar tendon by the quadriceps mechanism is acting out of its normal alignment. With the patella out of position, this force acts to skew the joint either laterally or medially, making balancing of the remaining ligaments extremely difficult.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">Owing, at least in part, to the complicated nature of balancing ligaments with the knee in flexion, flexion balancing conventionally comprises attempting to replicate in flexion a previously measured and balanced extension gap.</p><heading id="h0002"><b>Summary of invention</b></heading><p id="p0007" num="0007">According to a first aspect of the present invention, there is provided a ligament balancer for a knee according to claim 1.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">The first and second guide holes may be aligned along an axis that is substantially parallel to the movement axis of the balancer.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">The ligament balancer may further comprise a tibial location plate which may be rigidly connected to the first guide portion. The tibial location plate may be integrally formed with the first guide portion. The tibial location plate may define a tibial location plane which may be substantially perpendicular to the movement axis of the ligament balancer.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">The ligament balancer may further comprise at least one tibial spacer which may be removably connected to the tibial location plate.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">The tibial spacer may be removably connected to the tibial location plate by cooperating attachment means formed on the tibial spacer and tibial location plate.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p><p id="p0012" num="0012">The cooperating attachment means may comprise a recessed groove and projecting rib. The recessed groove may be formed on the tibial location plate, with the corresponding projecting rib formed on the tibial spacer plate.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">The tibial location plate attachment means may be located on a face of the tibial location plate that is remote from the second guide portion and remainder of the ligament balancer, so as to be adjacent to a tibia when the balancer is in use.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">The ligament balancer may further comprise a plurality of tibial spacer plates, each one of which may be operable for removable connection to the tibial location plate, and each one of which may have a different thickness.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">The ligament balancer comprises an intramedullary rod which may be rigidly connected to the second guide portion. The intramedullary rod may be integrally formed with the second guide portion.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">The ligament balancer may further comprise a drive mechanism operating between the first and second guide portions. The drive mechanism may be a pinion drive.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">At least one of the first and second guide portions may comprise a post that extends substantially parallel to the movement axis of the balancer and carries a rack, the post being received within an opening which may be formed on the other of the first and second guide portions.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p><p id="p0018" num="0018">According to a second aspect of the present invention, there is provided a surgical kit of parts comprising a ligament balancer of the first aspect of the present invention and a drill guide for a knee, comprising first and second connected arms, each arm comprising at least two guide openings extending there through, the guide openings being spaced longitudinally along each arm, longitudinal axes of the first and second arms intersecting at a predetermined angle.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">The at least two guide openings on each of the first and second arms may be located along the longitudinal axes of the respective arms.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">At least one of the openings may comprise a slot extending along a longitudinal axis of an arm.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">At least one of the openings may comprise a hole centred on a longitudinal axis of an arm.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">The longitudinal axes of the first and second arms may intersect at 90 degrees.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></p><p id="p0023" num="0023">The first and second arms together may define a drill guide plane, and the guide openings may extend through the first and second arms along axes that are substantially perpendicular to the drill guide plane.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">One of the arms may comprise a reference arm and the other of the arms may comprise a drilling arm.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">The present invention may be used in a method of locating a cutting block on a distal femoral surface as part of a knee replacement procedure, comprising determining the anterior/posterior location of the cutting block solely from a measured extension gap of the knee.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">The method may comprise: measuring the extension gap of the knee, selecting a guiding instrument corresponding to the measured extension gap, and using the guiding instrument to mark a location for the cutting block in the anterior/posterior direction. The guiding instrument may guide a marking tool in marking the location.<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></p><p id="p0027" num="0027">The guiding instrument may comprise a standard part and a changeable part, and selecting the guiding instrument may comprise selecting the changeable part that corresponds to the measured extension gap. The guiding instrument may comprise a ligament balancer according to the first and/or second aspects of the present invention and the changeable part may comprise a tibial spacer plate.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">Marking a location for the cutting block may comprise drilling a marking hole. Alternatively, marking a location may comprise drilling a mounting hole for the cutting block.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">A method of balancing knee ligaments may comprise: placing the knee joint in flexion, inserting an intramedullary rod into the medullary canal of the femur; and moving the intramedullary rod away from the tibia until the femur begins to rotate about the intramedullary rod.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">A method of locating a cutting block on a distal femoral surface as part of a knee replacement procedure may comprise balancing the knee ligaments, drilling marker holes into the distal femoral surface, referencing the marker holes to position a drill guide, drilling mounting holes through the drill guide, and mounting the cutting block on the distal femoral surface via the mounting holes.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">Balancing the knee ligaments may comprise placing the knee joint in flexion, inserting an intramedullary rod into the medullary canal of the femur; and moving the intramedullary rod away from the tibia until the femur begins to rotate about the intramedullary rod. The patella may be placed in its anatomical position before the joint is distracted by moving the intramedullary rod away from the tibia.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">Balancing the knee ligaments may be conducted using a ligament balancing instrument. The marker holes may be drilled through the ligament balancing instrument. The ligament balancing instrument may be a ligament balancer according to the first and/or second aspects of the present invention. The ligaments may be<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> allowed to become out of balance once the marker holes have been drilled. The drill guide may be a drill guide according to the third aspect of the present invention.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">Referencing the marker holes to position a drill guide may comprise inserting pins into the marker holes and mounting the drill guide on the pins.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">The marker holes may be aligned along a marking axis that intercepts a mounting axis along which the mounting holes are aligned. The marking axis may intersect the mounting axis at substantially 90 degrees. Each mounting hole may be displaced from the marking axis in substantially the same direction.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">The present invention may also be used in a method of attaching a cutting block to a distal femoral surface as part of a knee replacement procedure, the method comprising:
<ol><li>(a) performing distal femoral and proximal tibial resections;</li><li>(b) measuring the resulting joint gap with the knee in extension;</li><li>(c) placing the knee in 90 degrees of flexion;</li><li>(d) inserting an intramedullary rod of a surgical instrument into the medullary canal of the femur;</li><li>(e) moving the intramedullary rod of the surgical instrument away from the proximal tibial surface until the femur begins to rotate about the intramedullary rod;</li><li>(f) drilling mounting holes for the cutting block into the distal femoral surface; and</li><li>(g) mounting the cutting block via the drilled mounting holes.</li></ol></p><p id="p0036" num="0036">The surgical instrument may comprise a ligament balancer according to the present invention.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">Step (c) may comprise adjusting soft tissues to balance the joint and/or achieve a rectangular joint gap. Step (c) may also comprise selecting an appropriate tibial spacer plate for the ligament balancer based upon the measured extension gap.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">Step (f) may comprise drilling through guide holes on the surgical instrument.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">Step (f) may comprise:
<ol><li>(i) drilling marker holes through the ligament balancer;</li><li>(ii) removing the ligament balancer and mounting a drill guide via the marker holes; and<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></li><li>(iii) drilling mounting holes through the drill guide.</li></ol></p><p id="p0040" num="0040">At least part of step (f) may be conducted while the femur is in the position attained at the end of step (e).</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">Step (f)(i) may be conducted with the patella in its anatomical position.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">The drill guide may comprise a drill guide according to the third aspect of the present invention.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">Step (e) may be conducted with the patella in its anatomical position.</p><heading id="h0003"><b>Brief description of drawings</b></heading><p id="p0044" num="0044">For a better understanding of the present invention, and to show more clearly how it may be carried into effect, reference will now be made, by way of example, to the following drawings, in which:-
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> is a perspective view of an extension gauge for a knee.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figures 2</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0002">3</figref> are perspective views of a ligament balancer for a knee.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 4</figref> is a perspective view of a drill guide.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 5</figref> is a perspective view of a knee sizer.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0004"><b>Detailed description of embodiments</b></heading><p id="p0045" num="0045">The ligament balancer and drill guide of the present invention are suitable for use in a knee replacement procedure. An extension gauge and knee sizer may also be used as part of the same knee replacement procedure.</p><p id="p0046" num="0046">With reference to <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>, an extension gauge 1 comprises a tibial location plate 2, a substantially parallel femoral location plate 4, a handle 5, a drive mechanism 6, that moves the tibial and femoral location plates relative to each other, and a referencing scale (not shown). The drive mechanism comprises a threaded post 3 extending from<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> the tibial location plate 2, in a direction substantially perpendicular to the plane of the plate 2, and a cooperating nut that is received on the threaded post 3 and contained between bifurcated arms 9, 11 extending from the femoral location plate 4. Rotation of the nut 7 causes translation of the nut 7 and femoral location plate 4 along the threaded post 3.</p><p id="p0047" num="0047">In use, the extension gauge 1 is employed following resection of the distal femoral and proximal tibial surfaces. The gauge 1 is inserted into the knee joint space via the handle 5 with the knee in extension. The tibial and femoral location plates 2, 4 are then separated using the drive mechanism 6 until each plate 2, 4 rests against the corresponding resected surface of the tibia or the femur. The collateral ligaments may then be adjusted so that the extension gap between the resected surfaces is rectangular, the planar faces of the location plates 2, 4 fully engaging the resected bone surfaces of the tibia and femur. The size of the balanced extension gap may then be read from the scale on the extension gauge.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048">With reference to <figref idrefs="f0001">Figures 2</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0002">3</figref>, a ligament balancer 10 comprises a tibial location plate 12, a first guide portion 14 integrally formed with the tibial location plate 12, a second guide portion 16 and an intramedullary (IM) rod 18 integrally formed with the second guide portion 16. The first and second guide portions 14, 16 extend in a plane that is substantially perpendicular to the plane of the tibial location plate 12 and the plane in which the axis of the IM rod 18 extends. The second guide portion 16 is also integrally formed with a mounting post 20 which extends away from the second guide portion 16 to be received in an opening 24 on the first guide portion. A hex pinion drive 22 acts between the mounting post 20 of the second guide portion 16 and the first guide portion 14 to enable controlled separation of the tibial location plate 12 / first guide portion 14 and the IM rod 18 / second guide portion 16. Guide holes 26, 28 extend through the first and second guide portions 14,16 respectively, so that the guide holes 26, 28 may be separated as the first and second guide portions 14, 16 are separated using the hex pinion drive 22. The guide holes 26, 28 are aligned along an axis A that is perpendicular to the plane of the tibial location plate 12. As illustrated particularly in <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 3</figref>, the guide holes 26, 28 are displaced away from the axis of the IM rod 18 such that the axis A along which the guide holes 26, 28 are aligned is displaced from the IM rod in a direction that is perpendicular to the axis of alignment A of the guide holes. A lower (as viewed in the figures) surface of the tibial location plate<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> tibial spacer plate 34. The lower surface of the tibial location plate 12 is that surface which is distant from the IM rod 18 and the remainder of the balancer 10. A plurality of tibial spacer plates 34 is provided, each having a different thickness t. Further detail of the ligament balancer 10 is provided in the discussion of an operative technique below.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">With reference to <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 4</figref>, a drill guide 40 comprises a first, or reference, arm 42 and a second, or drilling, arm 44 that is rigidly connected to the reference arm 42. The arms 42, 44 are connected at a fixed angle α of 90 degrees so as to form a T shape that defines a guide plane of the tool 40. Guide openings extend through each of the arms 42, 44 along the longitudinal reference axis 46 of the reference arm 42 and the longitudinal drilling axis 48 of the drilling arm 44. The reference arm 42 comprises a first guide opening in the form of a reference hole 50 and a second guide opening in the form of a reference slot 52. The drilling arm 44 comprises two guide openings in the form of drill holes 54, 56. Each of the guide openings extends through the drill guide in a direction perpendicular to the plane of the drill guide. The reference slot 52 additionally extends longitudinally within the plane of the drill guide along the reference axis 46. The drill guide 40 acts as a translation guide, enabling holes to be drilled through the guide openings 54, 56 on the drilling arm 44 in a fixed special relation to existing input holes, registered by the reference arm 42 through the interaction of pins inserted into the input holes and extending into the reference hole 50 and reference slot 52. The reference slot 52 on the reference arm 42 allows for varying separation in the input holes to be accommodated.</p><p id="p0050" num="0050">In use, pins are inserted into the above mentioned input holes and the drill guide 40 is mounted on the pins via the reference hole 50 and reference slot 52 in the reference arm 42. Holes can then be drilled through the drill guide holes 54, 56 in the drilling arm, with the drilling direction being at 90 degrees to the plane of the drill guide. The newly drilled holes are aligned on an axis that is at 90 degrees to the axis aligning the input holes, which corresponds to the reference axis 46 of the drill guide 40, when the drill guide is mounted on the input holes via the pins. The vertical (as viewed in <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 4</figref>) location of the newly drilled holes is determined by the vertical (as viewed in <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 4</figref>) location of the lower of the input holes, that which corresponds to guide hole 50 on the reference arm 42.</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">With reference to <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 5</figref>, an Anterior/Posterior (A/P) sizer 60 comprises a body 61, mounting posts 62, 64 extending from the body 61, a stylus 66 mounted on the body 61<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> and reference means 68 marked on the body 61. In use, the A/P sizer 60 is mounted in appropriate holes in a distal femoral surface via the mounting posts 62, 64 and the stylus 66 is used, in combination with the reference means 68, to measure the size of the anterior portion of a femur.</p><p id="p0052" num="0052">An operative technique for total knee replacement that employs the above described instruments is as follows:<br/>
i) The distal femoral and proximal tibial cuts are made to the femur and tibia respectively in a conventional manner.<br/>
ii) The leg is placed in extension and the extension gap is measured using the extension gauge 1. The collateral ligaments are adjusted to ensure that the gap is rectangular with equal tension in the ligaments.<br/>
iii) The knee is placed in 90 degrees of flexion.<br/>
iv) The measured extension gap is used to determine the requirement for and correct size of tibial spacer 34 to be attached to the tibial location plate 12 of the ligament balancer 10. Table 1 demonstrates how the measured extension gap is correlated to the required tibial spacer.
<tables id="tabl0001" num="0001"><table frame="all"><title><b>Table 1</b></title><tgroup cols="2"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="43mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="47mm"/><thead><row><entry align="center" valign="top"><b>Measured Extension Gap</b></entry><entry align="center" valign="top"><b>Tibial Spacer Plate Required</b></entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry align="center">10 mm</entry><entry align="center">No spacer required</entry></row><row><entry align="center">12 mm</entry><entry align="center">Size 12 spacer required</entry></row><row><entry align="center">14 mm</entry><entry align="center">Size 14 spacer required</entry></row><row><entry align="center">16 mm</entry><entry align="center">Size 16 spacer required</entry></row><row><entry align="center">18 mm</entry><entry align="center">Size 18 spacer required</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></tables>
v) The patella is everted or subluxed, the medullary canal of the femur is opened and the IM rod 18 of the ligament balancer 10 is inserted into the medullary canal until the second guide portion 16 is flush with the resected distal femoral surface.<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> -->vi) The patella is returned to its anatomical position, resting over the second guide portion 16 in the region of area B on <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 3</figref>.<br/>
vii) The ligament balancer 10 is opened using the hex pinion drive 22, separating the tibial location plate 12/ first guide portion 14 and the IM rod 18 / second guide portion 16 until ligament slack is taken up. The extent to which ligament slack has been taken up can be assessed by observation of the femur. At the point at which ligament slack is completely taken up, the femur begins to rotate about its longitudinal axis and hence about the IM rod 18. The ligament balancer 10 is therefore opened until the femur begins to rotate on the IM rod 18. It will be appreciated that the flexion gap is not measured, neither is it forced to assume a predetermined magnitude, the balancer 10 is simply opened until the slack is taken up. Use of the tibial spacer plates 34 ensures that the ligament balancer 10 is not required to open a great distance, even with a relatively large joint space, meaning the ligament balancer 10 can remain relatively small and compact.<br/>
viii) With ligament slack taken up, at the point where the femur is just beginning to rotate on the IM rod 18, pin holes are drilled through the guide holes 26, 28 in the first and second guide portions 14, 16 of the balancer 10 into the resected femoral surface. It will be appreciated that the anterior/posterior location of the lower guide hole 26, and hence the drilled lower pin hole, is determined by the presence and size of tibial spacer 34, and hence by the measured extension gap, in combination with the fixed geometry of the balancer 10. It will also be appreciated that the anterior/posterior separation of the guide holes 26, 28 is not important; the important feature is that the drilled pin holes guided by them are in "vertical" anterior/posterior alignment on the femur at the point at which the ligaments are correctly tensioned, that is the point at which the femur just begins to rotate about the IM rod 18. The lateral separation of the guide holes 26, 28 away from the IM rod 18 ensures that the pin holes can be drilled with the patella in place, and thus with the forces of the joint acting in their anatomical directions. The guide holes 26, 28 are a suitable distance away from the patella, when it is in place over the region B of the ligament balancer 10, that the pin holes may be safely drilled through the guide holes 26, 28 without risking damage to the patella or surrounding soft tissues.<br/>
ix) The patella is again everted or subluxed and the ligament balancer 10 is removed from the joint space.<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> -->x) Pins are inserted into the two drilled pin holes in the resected femoral surface and the drill guide 40 is mounted onto the pins via the reference hole 50 and the reference slot 52 in the reference arm 42.<br/>
xi) Mounting peg holes are drilled through the two unoccupied drill guide holes 54, 56 on the drilling arm 44 of the drill guide 40. The drill guide 40 ensures that the two new peg holes are orthogonal to the vertical (as seen in <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 4</figref>) anterior/posterior axis defined by the two pin holes drilled using the ligament balancer 10. The newly drilled peg holes are thus aligned with the horizontal (as seen in <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 4</figref>) medial/lateral axis when the knee is correctly balanced. The vertical (as seen in the Figures) anterior/posterior location of the newly drilled peg holes is determined by the anterior/posterior location of the lower ligament balancer guide hole 26, hence by the measured extension gap, in combination with the fixed geometry of the drill guide 40. The combined effect of the ligament balancer 10 and drill guide 40 is that the position of the eventual horizontally aligned (as seen in the Figures) mounting peg holes is determined with the patella in place. The horizontally aligned peg holes cannot be directly drilled with the patella in place because the patella is in the way, but by using the drill guide 40 and the vertically aligned pin holes that are drilled using the ligament balancer 10 with the patella in place, the eventual location of the horizontally aligned peg holes is fixed while the patella is in place and the knee is accurately balanced.<br/>
xii) The drill guide 40 and pins are removed and the A/P sizer 60 is mounted via the mounting posts 62, 64 on the horizontally aligned mounting peg holes drilled through the drill guide 40. The stylus 66 references off the anterior portion of the femur to size the femur and thus establish what size of cutting block should be employed to make the remaining anterior, posterior and chamfered cuts to the femur.<br/>
xiii) The A/P sizer 60 is removed and the appropriate size cutting block is mounted in the same horizontally aligned mounting peg holes. It is envisaged that all cutting blocks to be used with this technique would have the same separation between the mounting pegs and the posterior cut guide surface. It is only the separation between the mounting pegs and the anterior cut guide surface that would vary, and it is this separation that is established by the A/P sizer 60.<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> -->xiv) Anterior, posterior and chamfered cuts are made and the operation is continued in a conventional manner.</p><p id="p0053" num="0053">As discussed above, the anterior, posterior and chamfered cuts made to the distal femur determine the final position of the femoral component, and their correct positioning is therefore of fundamental importance to ensuring post operative performance of the prosthetic joint. The position of these cuts is determined by the location at which a cutting block is mounted on the resected surface of the distal femur. Cutting blocks are conventionally mounted via two mounting peg holes which are aligned substantially in the medial/lateral direction on the resected distal femoral surface with the knee in 90 degrees of flexion. Determining the appropriate position for these peg holes is extremely challenging, as their correct position can only truly be determined with all the ligaments that exert forces on the joint in their correct anatomical positions, and yet the mounting peg holes will in inevitably need to be located in very close proximity to an anatomically located patella.</p><p id="p0054" num="0054">The majority of existing surgical instrumentation designed to assist in locating mounting holes for a femoral cutting block inherently accepts that ligament balancing and drilling of the peg holes cannot be performed with the patella in its anatomical position. Those few instruments that do seek to work with the patella in place look to reduce the size of the instrument, such that it can be accommodated behind the patella. However, the basic functioning of these instruments is conventional.</p><p id="p0055" num="0055">The present invention represents a fundamental departure from the conventional approach to locating the mounting peg holes for a femoral cutting block. The present invention separates the actions of balancing the knee ligaments and drilling the cutting block mounting holes, such that the conditions for each action may be optimised. Thus, with the patella in place, the ligament balancer 10 of the present invention allows the knee ligaments to be accurately balanced. Rather than forcing a flexion gap to match an extension gap, the ligament balancer 10 of the present invention allows a surgeon to recognise when the soft tissues of the knee are in balance, by visually registering the moment at which the femur begins to rotate about its longitudinal axis. Instead of trying to drill the cutting block mounting holes at this time, the ligament balancer 10 instead guides the drilling of two marker holes, that are in correct anterior/posterior alignment when the knee joint is balanced in 90 degrees of flexion. As these holes merely serve a marking or indicating function, they can be located away<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> from the line of action of the patella and thus can be drilled with the patella in place and without risking damage to the patella and its supporting soft tissues. Once the marker holes have been drilled, the final position of the cutting block has effectively been established, and there is no longer any need to maintain the knee ligaments in their balanced condition. The patella can be everted or subluxed and the ligament balancer 10 removed to reveal the resected distal femoral surface with its two marker holes.</p><p id="p0056" num="0056">The relation between the marker holes, drilled with the knee in balance, and the final location of the cutting block mounting holes is fixed by the features of the drill guide 40 of the present invention. This drill guide 40 in effect operates as a translation guide or template, with input reference features and output drilling features in a fixed spatial arrangement. Via the drill guide 40 of the present invention, the more posterior of the marker holes fixes the anterior/posterior location of the cutting block mounting holes, and the alignment of the two marker holes in the anterior/posterior direction fixes the alignment of the cutting block mounting holes in the medial/lateral direction.</p><p id="p0057" num="0057">The drill guide 40 of the present invention comprises two drilling holes 54, 56, through which the cutting block mounting holes are drilled, that are a fixed distance d from the posterior reference hole 50 in the anterior/posterior direction (when the drill guide is in position on a distal femoral surface). The cutting block mounting holes are thus drilled at an anterior/posterior level that is the fixed distance d above the posterior marking hole. The anterior marking hole provides an alignment axis that marks the precise anterior posterior axis at which the knee is balanced. The reference slot 52 in the drill guide 40 accommodates considerable variation in location of the anterior marker hole, as it is the axis that this hole defines in combination with the posterior marker hole, rather than the precise location of the anterior marker hole, which is important.</p><p id="p0058" num="0058">In order for the correct femoral cuts to be made, the cutting block mounting holes should be aligned along the precise medial/lateral axis at which the knee ligaments are balanced. When the posterior reference hole 50 of the drill guide 40 is aligned with the posterior marker hole (via a pin) and the reference slot 52 of the drill guide 40 is aligned with the anterior marker hole (also via a pin), the reference axis 46 of the drill guide 40 is in alignment with the balanced anterior/posterior axis defined by the marker holes. The drilling axis 48 of the drill guide 40, on which the drilling holes 54, 56 of the guide 40 are located, is thus oriented at 90 degrees to this balanced anterior/posterior axis. In this manner, no matter what the actual orientation of the femur might be at the<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> time of drilling, the cutting block mounting holes drilled through the drill holes 54, 56 of the drill guide 40 will be aligned along the precise medial/lateral axis at which the knee is balanced. It will be appreciated that the drilling of the cutting block mounting holes can therefore be conducted without concern for the balancing of the knee ligaments at the time of drilling, and with the patella safely out of the way. It will further be appreciated that this separation of the ligament balancing and mounting hole drilling operations optimises conditions for both operations, and represents a significant departure from the operation of known instrumentation for guiding the drilling of such holes.</p><p id="p0059" num="0059">The use of tibial spacer plates 32 in the ligament balancer 10 of the present invention enables the ligament balancer 10 to be optimised to the particular joint space in which it must work. In a large joint space, having a large extension gap, a thick tibial spacer plate can be employed, raising the tibial location plate 12 and hence also the guide hole 26 through which the posterior marking hole is drilled. The anterior/posterior location of this hole, and hence of the cutting block mounting holes, is thus matched to the available joint space. In addition, by raising the tibial location plate 12 relative to the femur, the distance by which the tibial location plate 12 and IM rod 18 must be separated is reduced, enabling the ligament balancer 10 to remain compact for working in smaller joint spaces and with the patella in its anatomical position.</p><p id="p0060" num="0060">It will be appreciated that, while specific embodiments of the present invention have been described, these embodiments are not intended to limit the scope of the present invention. Thus, variations to the described embodiments may be contemplated. For example the geometric arrangement of the drill guide 40 may be varied, in order to provide the desired translation relation between input marker holes and drilled mounting holes. In addition, and to the extent physically possible, features described in relation to any one embodiment of the invention may be employed in connection with any other embodiment described herein.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56985401" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Ligament-Balancierungsvorrichtung (10) für ein Knie, umfassend einen ersten Führungsteil (14) mit einem dadurch verlaufenden ersten Führungsloch (26), einen zweiten Führungsteil (16) mit einem dadurch verlaufenden zweiten Führungsloch (28), wobei die ersten und zweiten Führungsteile längs einer Bewegungsachse zueinander beweglich sind, die ersten und zweiten Führungslöcher (26, 28) längs einer Achse ausgerichtet sind, die im Wesentlichen parallel zur Bewegungsachse der Balancierungsvorrichtung (10) ist, die Balancierungsvorrichtung (10) derart ausgelegt ist, dass die Bewegungsachse bei Gebrauch im Wesentlichen parallel zur vorderen bzw. hinteren Achse einer distalen Oberschenkelfläche ist, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die Ligament-Balancierungsvorrichtung (10) zudem einen intramedullären Stab (18) aufweist, wobei die ersten und zweiten Führungslöcher (26, 28) Bohrführungslöcher sind, und die Ausrichtungsachse der Bohrführungslöcher (26, 28) weg vom intramedullären Stab (18) in einer Richtung beabstandet ist, die im Wesentlichen senkrecht zur Ausrichtungsachse der ersten und zweiten Führungslöcher (26, 28) ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Ligament-Balancierungsvorrichtung (10) nach Anspruch 1, zudem umfassend eine Schienbein-Positionierungsplatte (12), die fest mit dem ersten Führungsteil (14) verbunden ist, und mindestens einen Schienbein-Spacer (34), der abnehmbar mit der Schienbein-Positionierungsplatte (12) verbunden ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Ligament-Balancierungsvorrichtung (10) nach Anspruch 2, wobei der Schienbein-Spacer (34) abnehmbar über kooperierende Befestigungsvorrichtungen (30, 32) auf dem Schienbein-Spacer (34) und der Schienbein-Positionierungsplatte (12) mit der Schienbein-Positionierungsplatte (12) verbunden ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Ligament-Balancierungsvorrichtung (10) nach Anspruch 3, wobei sich die Befestigungsvorrichtung (30) für die Schienbein-Positionierungsplatte auf einer Seite der Schienbein-Positionierungsplatte (12) befindet, die von dem zweiten Führungsteil (16) und dem Rest der Ligament-Balancierungsvorrichtung (10) entfernt gelegen ist.<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Ligament-Balanderungsvorrichtung (10) nach einem der Ansprüche 2 bis 4, zudem umfassend eine Anzahl Schlenbein-Positionierungsplatten (34), die sich jeweils abnehmbar mit der Schienbein-Positionierungsplatte (12) verbinden lassen, wobei die Schlenbein-Positionierungsplatten (34) unterschiedlich dick sind.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Ligament-Balancierungsvorrichtung (10) nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, zudem umfassend einen Treibmechanismus (22), der zwischen den ersten und zweiten Führungsteilen (14, 16) arbeitet.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Ligament-Balancierungsvorrichtung (10) nach Anspruch 6, wobei mindestens einer der ersten und zweiten Führungstelle (14, 16) einen Stab (20) umfasst, der im Wesentlichen parallel zur Bewegungsachse der Balancierungsvorrichtung (10) verläuft und der ein Schraubgewinde oder eine Gewindeschiene trägt, wobei der Stab (20) in einer Öffnung aufgenommen wird, die sich auf der äußeren der ersten und zweiten Führungsteile (14, 16) befindet.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Teilekit, umfassend eine Ligament-Balancierungsvorrichtung (10) nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 7 und eine Bohrführung (40) für ein Knie, wobei die Bohrführung (40) erste und zweite verbundene Arme (42, 44) umfasst, jeder Arm mindestens zwei dadurch verlaufende Führungsöffnungen (50, 52; 54, 56) umfasst, die Führungsöffnungen an jedem Arm entlang längs beabstandet sind, und wobei sich die Längsachsen der ersten und zweiten Arme (42, 44) in einem festgelegten Winkel schneiden.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Teilekit nach Anspruch 8, wobei sich die mindestens zwei Führungsöffnungen (50, 52; 54, 56) auf jedem der ersten und zweiten Arme der Bohrführung auf den Längsachsen der jeweiligen Arme (42, 44) befinden.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Teilekit nach Anspruch 8 oder 9, wobei mindestens eine der Öffnungen (52) in der Bohrführung (40) einen Schlitz umfasst, der an einer Längsachse eines Arms (42) entlang verläuft.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Teilekit nach einem der Ansprüche 8 bis 10, wobei sich die Längsachsen (46, 48) der ersten und zweiten Arme (42, 44) der Bohrführung im Wesentlichen in einem Winkel von 90° schneiden.<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Teilekit nach einem der Ansprüche 8 bis 11, wobei die ersten und zweiten Arme (42, 44) zusammen eine Bohrführungsebene definieren, und die Führungsöffnungen (50, 52; 54, 56) durch die ersten und zweiten Arme (42, 44) an den Achsen entlang verlaufen, die im Wesentlichen senkrecht zur Bohrführungsebene sind.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Teilekit nach einem der Ansprüche 8 bis 12, wobei einer der Arme der Bohrführung einen Referenzarm (42) umfasst, und der andere der Arme einen Bohrarm (44) umfasst, wobei jede der Führungsöffnungen (50, 52) an dem Referenzarm einen Durchmesser oder eine Breite aufweist, der bzw. die im Wesentlichen gleich dem Durchmesser von mindestens einem der Führungslöcher (26, 28) der Ligament-Balancierungsvorrichtung (10) ist, so dass sich die Bohrführung (40) auf Ausrichtungsstiften befinden kann, die in Blindbohrungen passen, welche durch die ersten und zweiten Führungslöcher (26, 28) gebohrt wurden.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Ligament-Balancierungsvorrichtung (10) nach Anspruch 1 bis 7 oder ein Teilekit nach einem der Ansprüche 8 bis 13, wobei der intramedulläre Stab (18) fest mit dem zweiten Führungsteil (16) verbunden ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Ligament-Balancierungsvorrichtung (10) oder ein Teilekit nach Anspruch 14, wobei der intramedulläre Stab (18) einstückig mit dem zweiten Führungsteil herausgearbeitet ist.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56985402" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A ligament balancer (10) for a knee, comprising a first guide portion (14) having a first guide hole (26) extending there through, a second guide portion (16) having a second guide hole (28) extending there through, the first and second guide portions being moveable with respect to each other along a movement axis, the first and second guide holes (26, 28) being aligned along an axis that is substantially parallel to the movement axis of the balancer (10), the balancer (10) being adapted such that, in use, the movement axis is substantially parallel to the anterior/posterior axis of a distal femoral surface, <b>characterised in that</b> the ligament balancer (10) further comprises an intramedullary rod (18), wherein the first and second guide holes (26, 28) are drill guide holes and the axis of alignment of the drill guide holes (26, 28) is spaced away from the intramedullary rod (18) in a direction substantially perpendicular to the axis of alignment of the first and second guide holes (26, 28).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>A ligament balancer (10) as claimed in claim 1, further comprising a tibial location plate (12) rigidly connected to the first guide portion (14), and at least one tibial spacer (34), removably connected to the tibial location plate (12).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>A ligament balancer (10) as claimed in claim 2, wherein the tibial spacer (34) is removably connected to the tibial location plate (12) by cooperating attachment means (30, 32) on the tibial spacer (34) and tibial location plate (12).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>A ligament balancer (10) as claimed in claim 3, wherein the tibial location plate attachment means (30) is located on a face of the tibial location plate (12) that is remote from the second guide portion (16) and remainder of the ligament balancer (10).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>A ligament balancer (10) as claimed in any of claims 2 to 4, further comprising a plurality of tibial spacer plates (34), each one operable for removable connection to the tibial location plate (12), each tibial spacer plate (34) having a different thickness.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>A ligament balancer (10) as claimed in any of the preceding claims, further comprising a drive mechanism (22) operating between the first and second guide portions (14, 16).<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>A ligament balancer (10) as claimed in claim 6, wherein at least one of the first and second guide portions (14, 16) comprises a post (20) that extends substantially parallel to the movement axis of the balancer (10) and carries a screw thread or rack, the post (20) being received within an opening formed on the other of the first and second guide portions (14, 16).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>A kit of parts comprising a ligament balancer (10) as claimed in any of claims 1 to 7 and a drill guide (40) for a knee, the drill guide (40) comprising first and second connected arms (42, 44), each arm comprising at least two guide openings (50, 52; 54, 56) extending there through, the guide openings being spaced longitudinally along each arm, longitudinal axes of the first and second arms (42, 44) intersecting at a predetermined angle.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>A kit of parts as claimed in claim 8, wherein the at least two guide openings (50, 52; 54, 56) on each of the first and second arms of the drill guide are disposed on the longitudinal axes of the respective arms (42, 44).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>A kit of parts as claimed in claim 8 or 9, wherein at least one of the openings (52) in the drill guide (40) comprises a slot extending along a longitudinal axis of an arm (42).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>A kit of parts as claimed in any of claims 8 to 10, wherein the longitudinal axes (46, 48) of the first and second arms (42, 44) of the drill guide intersect at substantially 90 degrees.<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>A kit of parts as claimed in any of claims 8 to 11, wherein the first and second arms (42, 44) together define a drill guide plane, and the guide openings (50, 52; 54, 56) extend through the first and second arms (42, 44) along axes that are substantially perpendicular to the drill guide plane.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>A kit of parts as claimed in any of claims 8 to 12, wherein one of the arms of the drill guide comprises a reference arm (42) and the other of the arms comprises a drilling arm (44), each of the guide openings (50, 52) on the reference arm having a diameter or width which is substantially the same as a diameter of at least one of the guide holes (26, 28) of the ligament balancer (10), so that the drill guide (40) can be<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> located on alignment pins which fit into blind bores which have been drilled through the first and second guide holes (26, 28).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>A ligament balancer (10) as claimed in any of claims 1 to 7 or a kit of part as claimed in any of claims 8 to 13, wherein the intramedullary rod (18) is rigidly connected to the second guide portion (16).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>A ligament balancer (10) or a kit of parts as claimed in claim 14, wherein the intramedullary rod (18) is integrally formed with the second guide portion.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56985403" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Equilibreur de ligament (10) pour un genou, comprenant une première portion de guidage (14) ayant un premier trou de guidage (26) s'étendant à travers celle-ci, une deuxième portion de guidage (16) ayant un deuxième trou de guidage (28) s'étendant à travers celle-ci, les première et deuxième portions de guidage étant déplaçables l'une relativement à l'autre le long d'un axe de mouvement, les premier et deuxième trous de guidage (26, 28) étant alignés le long d'un axe qui est sensiblement parallèle à l'axe de mouvement de l'équilibreur (10), l'équilibreur (10) étant conçu de façon que, en cours d'utilisation, l'axe de mouvement soit sensiblement parallèle à l'axe antérieur/postérieur d'une surface fémorale distale, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> l'équilibreur de ligament (10) comprend en outre une tige intramédullaire (18), où les premier et deuxième trous de guidage (26, 28) sont des trous de guide-foret, et l'axe d'alignement des trous de guide-foret (26, 28) est espacé de la tige intramédullaire (18) dans une direction sensiblement perpendiculaire à l'axe d'alignement des premier et deuxième trous de guidage (26, 28).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Equilibreur de ligament (10) selon la revendication 1, comprenant en outre une plaque de localisation tibiale (12) reliée rigidement à la première portion de guidage (14), et au moins un écarteur tibial (34), relié amoviblement à la plaque de localisation tibiale (12).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Equilibreur de ligament (10) selon la revendication 2, dans lequel l'écarteur tibial (34) est relié amoviblement à la plaque de localisation tibiale (12) par des moyens de fixation coopérants (30, 32) sur<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --> l'écarteur tibial (34) et la plaque de localisation tibiale (12).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Equilibreur de ligament (10) selon la revendication 3, dans lequel les moyens de fixation (30) de la plaque de localisation tibiale se situent sur une face de la plaque de localisation tibiale (12) qui est éloignée de la deuxième portion de guidage (16) et du restant de l'équilibreur de ligament (10).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Equilibreur de ligament (10) selon l'une quelconque des revendications 2 à 4, comprenant en outre une pluralité de plaques d'écartement tibiales (34), chacune actionnable pour une connexion à distance à la plaque de localisation tibiale (12), chaque plaque d'écartement tibiale (34) ayant une épaisseur différente.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Equilibreur de ligament (10) selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, comprenant en outre un mécanisme d'entraînement (22) opérant entre les première et deuxième portions de guidage (14, 16).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Equilibreur de ligament (10) selon la revendication 6, dans lequel au moins une des première et deuxième portions de guidage (14, 16) comprend un montant (20) qui s'étend d'une manière sensiblement parallèle à l'axe de mouvement de l'équilibreur (10) et supporte un filetage de vis ou crémaillère, le montant (20) étant reçu dans une ouverture ménagée sur l'autre des première et deuxième portions de guidage (14, 16).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Kit de pièces comprenant un équilibreur de ligament (10) tel que revendiqué dans l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 7 et un guide-foret (40) pour un genou, le guide-foret (40) comprenant des premier et<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> deuxième bras reliés (42, 44), chaque bras comprenant au moins deux ouvertures de guidage (50, 52 ; 54, 56) s'étendant à travers ceux-ci, les ouvertures de guidage étant espacées longitudinalement le long de chaque bras, les axes longitudinaux des premier et deuxième bras (42, 44) se croisant à un angle prédéterminé.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Kit de pièces selon la revendication 8 , dans lequel les au moins deux ouvertures de guidage (50, 52 ; 54, 56) sur chacun des premier et deuxième bras du guide-foret sont disposées sur les axes longitudinaux des bras respectifs (42, 44).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Kit de pièces selon la revendication 8 ou 9, dans lequel au moins une des ouvertures (52) dans le guide-foret (40) comprend une fente s'étendant le long d'un axe longitudinal d'un bras (42).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Kit de pièces selon l'une quelconque des revendications 8 à 10, dans lequel les axes longitudinaux (46, 48) des premier et deuxième bras (42, 44) du guide-foret se croisent à sensiblement 90 degrés.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Kit de pièces selon l'une quelconque des revendications 8 à 11, dans lequel les premier et deuxième bras (42, 44) définissent ensemble un plan de guide-foret, et les ouvertures de guidage (50, 52 ; 54, 56) s'étendent à travers les premier et deuxième bras (42, 44) le long d'axes qui sont sensiblement perpendiculaires au plan de guide-foret.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Kit de pièces selon l'une quelconque des revendications 8 à 12, dans lequel un des bras du guide-foret comprend un bras de référence (42), et l'autre des bras comprend un bras de forage (44), chacune des<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --> ouvertures de guidage (50, 52) sur le bras de référence ayant un diamètre ou une largeur qui est sensiblement le même qu'un diamètre d'au moins un des trous de guidage (26, 28) de l'équilibreur de ligament (10), de sorte que le guide-foret (40) peut être localisé sur des axes d'alignement qui s'insèrent dans des trous borgnes qui ont été forés à travers les premier et deuxième trous de guidage (26, 28).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Equilibreur de ligament (10) selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 7 ou un kit de pièces selon l'une quelconque des revendications 8 à 13, dans lequel la tige intramédullaire (18) est reliée rigidement à la deuxième portion de guidage (16).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Equilibreur de ligament (10) ou un kit de pièces selon la revendication 14, dans lequel la tige intramédullaire (18) est formée intégralement avec la deuxième portion de guidage.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16672151" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1,2"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="165" he="189" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --><figure id="f0002" num="3,4"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="149" he="226" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --><figure id="f0003" num="5"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="156" he="147" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
