<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2680839-A1" country="EP" doc-number="2680839" kind="A1" date="20140108" family-id="45816006" file-reference-id="252638" date-produced="20180823" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146586822" ucid="EP-2680839-A1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2680839</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-12708479-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154849014" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12708479</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120302</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP220440203" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12708479.6</doc-number><date>20120302</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140547101" ucid="US-201161448626-P" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>201161448626</doc-number><kind>P</kind><date>20110302</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140551288" ucid="US-201161501653-P" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>201161501653</doc-number><kind>P</kind><date>20110627</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140555092" ucid="US-2012027488-W" linkage-type="W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>2012027488</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20120302</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989320641" load-source="docdb">A61K  31/357       20060101AFI20120920BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989321806" load-source="docdb">A61K  39/395       20060101ALI20120920BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989322938" load-source="docdb">A61P  35/00        20060101ALI20120920BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989626389" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">C07K2317/732       20130101 LA20130328BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989628141" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61K2039/505       20130101 LA20130328BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989630955" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">C07K  16/28        20130101 LI20130328BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989640869" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">C07K  16/3069      20130101 LI20130328BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989645768" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61K  39/39541     20130101 LI20130328BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989650353" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">C07K2317/92        20130101 LA20130328BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2104294713" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61K  31/357       20130101 LI20140804BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2104299346" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61K  39/39558     20130101 FI20140731BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132365099" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">GLEICHZEITIGE VERABREICHUNG VON ERIBULIN UND FARLETUZUMAB ZUR BEHANDLUNG VON BRUSTKREBS</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132365100" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">CO -ADMINISTRATION OF ERIBULIN AND FARLETUZUMAB FOR THE TREATMENT OF BREAST CANCER</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132365101" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">CO-ADMINISTRATION D'ÉRIBULINE ET DE FARLETUZUMAB POUR LE TRAITEMENT DU CANCER DU SEIN</invention-title><citations><non-patent-citations><nplcit><text>See references of WO 2012119077A1</text><sources><source mxw-id="PNPL67456167" load-source="docdb" name="SEA"/></sources></nplcit></non-patent-citations></citations></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919517741" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>MORPHOTEK INC</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919534226" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>MORPHOTEK, INC.</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919016335" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Morphotek, Inc.</last-name><iid>100181577</iid><address><street>210 Welsh Pool Road</street><city>Exton, PA 19341</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919543055" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>MALTZMAN JULIA D</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919519338" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>MALTZMAN, Julia, D.</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919012017" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>MALTZMAN, Julia, D.</last-name><address><street>924 Primrose Lane</street><city>Wynnewood, PA 19096</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919012352" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Lock, Graham James</last-name><suffix>et al</suffix><iid>100045167</iid><address><street>Fry Heath &amp; Spence LLP The Gables Massetts Road</street><city>Horley Surrey RH6 7DQ</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="US-2012027488-W"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2012027488</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20120302</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2012119077-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2012119077</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20120907</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549846925" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS549846387" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549846935" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549776763" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549765548" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549860173" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549846388" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549846936" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549860190" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549860191" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549765242" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549776764" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549776777" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549846937" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549860192" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549846942" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549846389" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549765557" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549860193" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549776778" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549860202" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549916707" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549844737" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549916708" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549916709" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549844742" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS549844743" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549765243" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549846394" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549844744" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549860203" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549765244" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549860204" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS549844745" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549846943" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549846395" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549844750" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS549765558" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states><ep-extended-states><ep-extended-state-data><country>BA</country></ep-extended-state-data><ep-extended-state-data><country>ME</country></ep-extended-state-data></ep-extended-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA99830064" ref-ucid="WO-2012119077-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p num="0000">The present invention provides methods for treating a subject having breast cancer by administering (a) eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and (b) farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA100326892" ref-ucid="WO-2012119077-A1" lang="EN" source="national office" load-source="docdb"><p>The present invention provides methods for treating a subject having breast cancer by administering (a) eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and (b) farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA99830065" ref-ucid="WO-2012119077-A1" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><p num="0000">La présente invention concerne des méthodes de traitement d'un sujet atteint d'un cancer du sein par l'administration (a) d'éribuline ou d'un sel pharmaceutiquement acceptable de celle-ci et (b) de farletuzumab ou d'un fragment de liaison à un antigène de celui-ci.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA100326893" ref-ucid="WO-2012119077-A1" lang="FR" source="national office" load-source="docdb"><p>La présente invention concerne des méthodes de traitement d'un sujet atteint d'un cancer du sein par l'administration (a) d'éribuline ou d'un sel pharmaceutiquement acceptable de celle-ci et (b) de farletuzumab ou d'un fragment de liaison à un antigène de celui-ci.</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES51232062" ref-ucid="WO-2012119077-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="2"/>--><p id="p0001" num="0001">CO -ADMINISTRATION OF ERIBULIN AND FARLETUZUMAB FOR THE TREATMENT OF BREAST CANCER </p><p id="p0002" num="0002">Related Applications </p><p id="p0003" num="0003"> This application claims the benefit of the filing date of U.S. Provisional Application</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">Nos. 61/448,626, filed on March 2, 2011, and 61/501 ,653, filed on June 27, 2011. The entire contents of each of the foregoing applications are hereby incorporated herein by reference. </p><p id="p0005" num="0005">Background of the Invention </p><p id="p0006" num="0006"> Breast cancer is the second leading cause of cancer death in women, exceeded only by lung cancer. The chance that breast cancer will be responsible for a woman's death is about 1 in 36 (about 3%). The American Cancer Society estimates that in the United States in 2012, about 39,510 women will die from breast cancer and about 226,870 new cases of invasive breast cancer will be diagnosed in women. </p><p id="p0007" num="0007"> Breast cancer treatments are currently tailored according to cellular protein expression: estrogen receptor/progesterone receptor (ER PR) expressing breast cancers are treated with endocrine therapy, and human epidermal growth factor receptor 2 (HER2) overexpressing breast cancers are treated with treatments including an anti-HER2 agent. Cancers that lack these markers presently have a poor prognosis and typically are still treated with traditional cytotoxic chemotherapy. Thus, there is a need for new and effective treatments for breast cancer, including those that may lack one or more of the foregoing markers (e.g. , "triple negative" breast cancers). </p><p id="p0008" num="0008">Summary of the Invention </p><p id="p0009" num="0009"> The present invention provides methods for treating a subject having breast cancer.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">The methods include administering to a subject suffering from breast cancer a therapeutically effective amount of (a) eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and (b) farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof. </p><p id="p0011" num="0011"> The breast cancer may be an adenocarcinoma; inflammatory breast cancer; metastatic breast cancer; folate receptor alpha expressing or over-expressing breast cancer; HER2 positive breast cancer; or HER2 negative breast cancer. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="3"/>-->
 In some embodiments, the breast cancer is estrogen receptor (ER) negative and progesterone receptor (PR) negative; ER negative and PR positive; ER positive and PR positive; or ER positive and PR negative. </p><p id="p0012" num="0012"> In some embodiments, the breast cancer is triple negative, i.e. , HER2 negative, ER negative, and PR negative. </p><p id="p0013" num="0013"> In some embodiments, the breast cancer is refractory to hormonal therapy, such as tamoxifen or an aromatase inhibitor. </p><p id="p0014" num="0014"> In some embodiments, the breast cancer is ER negative and PR positive; ER positive and PR positive; or ER positive and PR negative, and is refractory to hormonal therapy. </p><p id="p0015" num="0015"> In some embodiments of the invention, the breast cancer is metastatic breast cancer and the subject has previously received at least one chemotherapeutic regimen for the treatment of metastatic disease. </p><p id="p0016" num="0016"> In some embodiments of the invention, the breast cancer is metastatic breast cancer and the subject has previously received at least two chemotherapeutic regimens for the treatment of metastatic disease. </p><p id="p0017" num="0017"> In other embodiments of the invention, the subject previously received </p><p id="p0018" num="0018">chemotherapeutic regimens that comprise administration of an anthracycline or a taxane or both. </p><p id="p0019" num="0019"> In some embodiments, farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof, may be administered intercurrently. </p><p id="p0020" num="0020"> In various embodiments of the invention, eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof, are administered in amounts effective to produce a synergistic anti-cancer effect. </p><p id="p0021" num="0021"> In certain embodiments, tumor growth in the subject is inhibited. </p><p id="p0022" num="0022"> In other embodiments of the invention, administration of eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof, results in tumor regression in the subject. In other embodiments of the invention, administration of eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof, results in complete tumor regression in the subject. </p><p id="p0023" num="0023"> In some embodiments, eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof may be administered to the subject from one to three times about every 14-35 days; or about once every 21-28 days. In one embodiment, eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof is 
<!-- EPO <DP n="4"/>-->
 administered to the subject on day 1 and day 8 of a 21-28 day cycle. In some embodiments, eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof is administered to the subject on day 1 and day 8 of a 21 day cycle. In some embodiments, eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof is administered to the subject on day 1 and day 8 of a 28 day cycle. </p><p id="p0024" num="0024"> In some embodiments, farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof may be administered to the subject from 1-4 times about every 7-28 days. In some embodiments, farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment is administered once during a 21-28 day cycle. In some embodiments, farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof may be administered to the subject on day 1 of a 21-28 day cycle. In some embodiments, farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof may be administered to the subject on day 1 of a 28 day cycle or on day 1 of a 21 day cycle. </p><p id="p0025" num="0025"> In some embodiments of the invention, farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof is administered to the subject immediately after administration of eribulin, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof. </p><p id="p0026" num="0026"> In some embodiments of the invention, farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof is administered to the subject once per week. </p><p id="p0027" num="0027"> Eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof may be administered to the subject in an amount from about 0.5 mg/m<sup>2</sup> to about 3.0 mg/m<sup>2</sup>; an amount from about 1.0 mg/m<sup>2</sup> to about 2.0 mg/m<sup>2</sup>; an amount of about 1.4 mg/m<sup>2</sup>; or an amount of 1.1 mg/m<sup>2</sup>. </p><p id="p0028" num="0028"> In one embodiment, the subject has mild or moderate hepatic impairment, and eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof is administered to the subject in an amount of 1.1 mg/m<sup>2</sup> or 0.7 mg/m<sup>2</sup>, respectively. </p><p id="p0029" num="0029"> In one embodiment, eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof is formulated in a liposomal formulation. In certain embodiments, the liposomal formulation further comprises an ammonium salt. </p><p id="p0030" num="0030"> In some embodiments, farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof may be administered to the subject in an amount from about 1.00 mg/kg to about 4.0 mg/kg once a week; an amount from about 1.0 mg/kg to about 3.0 mg/kg once a week; an amount of about 2.5 mg/kg once a week; or an amount from about 3.00 mg/kg to about 9.00 mg/kg tri-weekly. </p><p id="p0031" num="0031"> In other embodiments, farletuzumab or an antigen binding portion thereof is administered in an amount of about 7.0 mg/kg, about 7.5 mg/kg, about 8.0 mg/kg, or about 8.5 mg/kg. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="5"/>-->
 Eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and farletuzumab or an antigen- binding fragment thereof, may be administered to the subject intravenously. </p><p id="p0032" num="0032"> In one embodiment of the invention, the pharmaceutically acceptable salt of eribulin is eribulin mesylate. </p><p id="p0033" num="0033"> In one embodiment of the invention, eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof, are administered to the subject as a second or later line therapy against the cancer. </p><p id="p0034" num="0034"> In another aspect, the present invention provides methods of treating a subject suffering from breast cancer. The methods include administering to the subject (a) eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof on day 1 and day 8 of a 21-28 day cycle, and (b) farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof on day 1 of the same 21-28 day cycle. In some embodiments, eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof is administered on day 1 and day 8 of a 21 day cycle, and farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof is administered on day 1 of the same 21 day cycle. In some embodiments, eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof is administered on day 1 and day 8 of a 28 day cycle, and farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof is administered on day 1 of the same 28 day cycle. </p><p id="p0035" num="0035"> The methods of the invention may comprise administering a loading dose of farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof. For example, at least one loading dose of farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof may be administered during a first 21- 28 day cycle. In some embodiments, farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof is administered on day 1 and day 8 of the first cycle. For example, farletuzumab or an antigen- binding fragment thereof may be administered on day 1 and day 8 of a first 21 day cycle and on day 1 of subsequent 21 day cycles. </p><p id="p0036" num="0036"> In a further aspect, the invention provides methods of treating a subject suffering from breast cancer. The methods include administering, e.g. , intravenously administering, to the subject eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof on day 1 and day 8 of a 21-28 day cycle, and administering, e.g., intravenously administering, farletuzumab or an antigen- binding fragment thereof on day 1 and day 8 of the first 21-28 day cycle and on day 1 of subsequent 21-28 day cycles. In some embodiments, the cycle is a 21 day cycle. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="6"/>-->
 Brief Description of the Drawings </p><p id="p0037" num="0037"> Figure 1 shows the results of flow cytometric analysis of breast cancer cell lines CAL51, T47D, HCC-1954 and BT474 to determine the expression level of FRa on the cell surface. All lines except BT474 were found to be FRa positive. </p><p id="p0038" num="0038"> Figure 2 depicts a series of graphs showing farletuzumab mediated ADCC on breast cancer cell lines T47D, CAL51, IGROV (ovarian cancer cell line used as positive control), and HCC1954. </p><p id="p0039" num="0039"> Figure 3 shows the sequences of farletuzumab (MORAb-003). Detailed Description of the Invention </p><p id="p0040" num="0040"> The present invention provides methods of treating breast cancer. The methods of the invention generally include administering to a subject suffering from breast cancer a therapeutically effective amount of (a) eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and (b) farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof. </p><p id="p0041" num="0041"> In some embodiments, eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof, are administered in amounts effective to produce a synergistic anticancer effect. </p><p id="p0042" num="0042"> The term "synergistic anticancer effect" as used herein, refers to the inhibition of the growth of a tumor upon administration of the therapies described herein, such that the inhibition of tumor growth is more than additive versus administration of each monotherapy alone. For example, in some embodiments, a synergistic anticancer effect can be measured by differences in the growth of the cancer. In other embodiments, a synergistic anticancer effect can be measured by differences in inhibition of tumor growth and/or tumor regression. A synergistic effect may permit use of reduced amounts of (a) eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof and/or (b) farletuzumab or an antigen binding fragment thereof. </p><p id="p0043" num="0043"> Eribulin is a non-taxane microtubule dynamics inhibitor. Eribulin is a synthetic analogue of halichondrin B, a product isolated from the marine sponge Halichondria okadai. The chemical name for eribulin is l l,15: 18,21 :24,28-Triepoxy-7,9-ethano-12,15-methano- 9H,15H-furo[3,2- ]furo[2',3':5,6]pyrano[4,3¾[l,4]dioxacyclopentacosin-5(4H)-one, 2-[(25")-3- amino-2-hydroxypropyl]hexacosahydro-3-methoxy-26-methyl-20,27-bis(methylene)-,</p><p id="p0044" num="0044">(2R S R,8aS,9S,l0aR,l lS,l2R,l3aR,l3bS,l5S,l8S,2lS,24S,26R,28R,29aS). It has a 
<!-- EPO <DP n="7"/>-->
 molecular weight of 729.9 for the free base and 826.0 for the mesylate salt. Eribulin has the structure of Formula I and eribulin mesylate has the structure of Formula II. </p><p id="p0045" num="0045"><img id="imgf000007_0001" he="110" wi="124" file="imgf000007_0001.tif" img-format="tif" img-content="drawing" orientation="portrait" inline="no"/></p><p id="p0046" num="0046">Eribulin mesylate has been approved for the treatment of patients with metastatic breast cancer who have previously received at least two chemotherapeutic regimens for the treatment of metastatic breast cancer. </p><p id="p0047" num="0047"> As used herein, the term "farletuzumab" or "MORAb-003" refers to an antibody that binds to FRa and includes the following CDRs, as derived from the murine LK26 heavy and light chains: SEQ ID NO:l (GFTFSGYGLS) as CDRH1, SEQ ID NO:2 </p><p id="p0048" num="0048"> (MISSGGSYTYYADSVKG) as CDRH2, SEQ ID NO:3 (HGDDPAWFAY) as CDRH3, SEQ ID NO:4 (SVSSSISSNNLH) as CDRL1, SEQ ID NO:5 (GTSNLAS) as CDRL2 and SEQ ID NO:6 (QQWSSYPYMYT) as CDRL3. Farletuzumab has the amino acid sequences shown in SEQ ID NO:7 and SEQ ID NO:8 in Figure 3, attached herewith. Farletuzumab, and methods of making and using it, are described in U.S. Patent No. 5,646,253, the contents of which are 
<!-- EPO <DP n="8"/>-->
 incorporated herein by reference. Additional anti-FRa antibodies can be used in combination with eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof to treat breast cancer in a subject, including for example, those with mutations in the framework regions as taught in US Patent No. 5,646,253, the contents of which are hereby incorporated by reference. </p><p id="p0049" num="0049"> The term "antibody" as used herein, comprises four polypeptide chains, two heavy (H) chains and two light (L) chains, interconnected by disulfide bonds, as well as any functional (i. e. , antigen-binding) fragment, mutant, variant, or derivation thereof, which retains the essential epitope binding features of an Ig molecule. Such mutant, variant, or derivative antibody formats are known in the art, and include molecules such as Fab fragments, Fab' fragments, F(ab')<sub>2</sub> fragments, Fd fragments, Fabc fragments, Sc antibodies (single chain antibodies), diabodies, individual antibody light chains, individual antibody heavy chains, chimeric fusions between antibody chains and the like. Immunoglobulin molecules can be of any class (e.g. , IgG, IgE, IgM, IgD, and IgA), or subclass (e.g. , IgGl , IgG2, IgG3, IgG4, IgAl and IgA2). </p><p id="p0050" num="0050"> Each heavy chain is comprised of a heavy chain variable region (abbreviated herein as</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">HCVR or VH) and a heavy chain constant region. The heavy chain constant region for IgG, IgD and IgA is comprised of three domains, CHI, CH2 and CH3. The heavy chain constant region for IgM and IgE includes four domains, CHI , CH2, CH3 and CH4. Each light chain is comprised of a light chain variable region (abbreviated herein as LCVR or VL) and a light chain constant region. The light chain constant region is comprised of one domain, CL. The VH and VL regions can be further subdivided into regions of hypervariability, termed complementarity determining regions (CDRs), interspersed with regions that are more conserved, termed framework regions (FR). Each VH and VL is composed of three CDRs and four FRs, arranged from amino-terminus to carboxy-terminus in the following order: FR1, CDR1, FR2, CDR2, FR3, CDR3, FR4. Light chains are classified as either kappa or lambda. Heavy chains are classified as gamma, mu, alpha, delta, or epsilon, and define the antibody's isotype (i.e., class) as IgG, IgM, IgA, IgD and IgE, respectively. </p><p id="p0052" num="0052"> The variable regions of the heavy and light chains contain a binding domain that interacts with an antigen. The constant regions of the antibodies may mediate the binding of the immunoglobulin to host tissues or factors, including various cells of the immune system (e.g. , effector cells) and the first component (Clq) of the classical complement system. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="9"/>-->
 The term "antigen-binding portion or fragment" of an antibody, as used herein, refers to one or more fragments of an antibody that retain the ability to specifically bind to an antigen (e.g. , cell-associated FRa , FRa not bound to a cell). It has been shown that the antigen- binding function of an antibody can be performed by fragments of a full-length antibody. Examples of binding fragments encompassed within the term "antigen-binding portion or fragment" of an antibody include (i) a Fab fragment, a monovalent fragment consisting of the VL, VH, CL and CHI domains; (ii) a F(ab')2 fragment, a bivalent fragment comprising two Fab fragments linked by a disulfide bridge at the hinge region; (iii) a Fd fragment consisting of the VH and CHI domains; (iv) a Fv fragment consisting of the VL and VH domains of a single arm of an antibody, (v) a dAb including VH and VL domains; (vi) a dAb fragment (Ward et al. (1989) Nature 341, 544-546), which consists of a VH domain; (vii) a dAb which consists of a VH or a VL domain; and (viii) an isolated complementarity determining region (CDR) or (ix) a combination of two or more isolated CDRs which may optionally be joined by a synthetic linker. Furthermore, although the two domains of the Fv fragment, VL and VH, are coded for by separate genes, they can be joined, using recombinant methods, by a synthetic linker that enables them to be made as a single protein chain in which the VL and VH regions pair to form monovalent molecules (known as single chain Fv (scFv); see e.g. , Bird et al. (1988) Science 242, 423-426; and Huston et al. (1988) Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 85, 5879-5883). Such single chain antibodies are also intended to be encompassed within the term "antigen-binding portion or fragment" of an antibody. These antibody fragments are obtained using conventional techniques known to those with skill in the art, and the fragments are screened for utility in the same manner as are intact antibodies. Antigen-binding portions can be produced by recombinant DNA techniques, or by enzymatic or chemical cleavage of intact immunoglobulins . </p><p id="p0053" num="0053"> In one embodiment, an antigen-binding portion, fragment or derivative of farletuzumab may include one or more of the CDRs recited above (SEQ ID NOs: 1-6) or may include a variable region light chain selected from the group consisting of LK26HuVK (SEQ ID NO: 13 of US Pat. No 5,646,253), LK26HuVKY (SEQ ID NO: 14 of US Pat. No 5,646,253), LK26HuVKPW (SEQ ID NO: 15 of US Pat. No 5,646,253), and LK26HuVKPW,Y (SEQ ID NO: 16 of US Pat. No 5,646,253); and/or a variable region heavy chain selected from the group consisting of LK26HuVH (SEQ ID NO: 17 of US Pat. No 5,646,253); LK26HuVH FAIS,N 
<!-- EPO <DP n="10"/>-->
 (SEQ ID NO: 18 of US Pat. No 5,646,253); LK26HuVH SLF (SEQ ID NO: 19 of US Pat. No 5,646,253); LK26HuVH 1,1 (SEQ ID NO: 20 of US Pat. No 5,646,253); and LK26KOLHuVH (SEQ ID NO: 21 of US Pat. No 5,646,253). See US Patent No. 5,646,253 and US Patent No. 6,124,106. In another embodiment, an antigen binding portion, fragment, or derivative of farletuzumab may include the heavy chain variable region LK26KOLHuVH (SEQ ID NO: 21 of US Pat. No 5,646,253) and the light chain variable region LK26HuVKPW,Y (SEQ ID NO: 16 of US Pat. No 5,646,253); the heavy chain variable region LK26HuVH SLF (SEQ ID NO: 19 of US Pat. No 5,646,253) and the light chain variable region LK26HuVKPW,Y (SEQ ID NO: 16 of US Pat. No 5,646,253); or the heavy chain variable region LK26HuVH FAIS,N (SEQ ID NO: 18 of US Pat. No 5,646,253) and the light chain variable region </p><p id="p0054" num="0054">LK26HuVKPW,Y (SEQ ID NO: 16 of US Pat. No 5,646,253). </p><p id="p0055" num="0055"> The term "antibody", as used herein, includes polyclonal antibodies, monoclonal antibodies, murine antibodies, chimeric antibodies, humanized antibodies, and human antibodies, and those that occur naturally or are recombinantly produced according to methods well known in the art. </p><p id="p0056" num="0056"> In various embodiments, antibodies of the present invention, for example, </p><p id="p0057" num="0057">farletuzumab, can further exhibit immune effector activity. As used herein, the term "immune effector activity," refers to the ability of antibodies of the present invention to kill cells by antibody-dependent cellular cytotoxicity (ADCC) or complement dependent cytotoxicity (CDC). As well known in the art, ADCC refers to a mechanism of cell-mediated immunity whereby an effector cell (for example, natural killer cells, neutrophils and eosinophils) actively lyses a target cell bound by an antibody, for example, farletuzumab, as part of the humoral immune response. In turn, CDC refers to the binding of antibodies to complement, leading to direct cell toxicity. </p><p id="p0058" num="0058"> The term "subject," as used herein, includes mammals, for example, primates (e.g. , humans, monkeys, chimpanzees), cows, sheep, goats, horses, dogs, cats, rabbits, rats, mice and the like. In some embodiments, the subject is a human. </p><p id="p0059" num="0059"> In one aspect of the invention, methods of treatment are featured that comprise the administration of two or more therapeutic agents (e.g. , (a) eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and (b) farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof). </p><p id="p0060" num="0060"> In some embodiments, the breast cancer is adenocarcinoma, inflammatory breast cancer and/or metastatic breast cancer. In some embodiments, the breast cancer is a HER2 
<!-- EPO <DP n="11"/>-->
 positive or HER2 negative breast cancer. In other embodiments, the breast cancer is a HER2 negative, ER negative and PR negative cancer (i.e. , a triple negative breast cancer). In further embodiments, the breast cancer is a HER2 negative, ER negative and PR positive cancer. In yet further embodiments, the breast cancer is a HER2 negative, ER positive and PR positive cancer. In further embodiments, the breast cancer is a HER2 negative, ER positive and PR negative cancer. In yet further embodiments, the breast cancer is an FRa expressing triple negative breast cancer. FRa expression can be assessed by a variety of methods, for example as described in Example 4 . Standard methods can be used to determine ER, PR and HER2 status. </p><p id="p0061" num="0061"> As used herein, "HER2," which is also known as Neu, ErbB-2, CD340 (cluster of differentiation 340) or pl85, is a protein that is a member of the epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR/ErbB) family. In humans, HER2 is encoded by the ERBB2 gene. </p><p id="p0062" num="0062"> In some embodiments, the breast cancer is endocrine refractory or hormone refractory. The terms "endocrine refractory" and "hormone refractory" refer to a cancer that is resistant to treatment with hormonal therapy, e.g., aromatase inhibitors or tamoxifen. </p><p id="p0063" num="0063"> In some embodiments, the breast cancer is a folate receptor-a expressing or overexpressing cancer. As used herein, the term "folate receptor alpha" (also referred to as FRa, FR-alpha, FOLR-1, FOLR1, or FRA) refers to the alpha isoform of the high affinity receptor for folate. Membrane bound FRa is attached to the cell surface by a glycosyl phosphatidylinositol (GPI) anchor, recycles between extracellular and endocytic compartments and is capable of transporting folate into the cell. FRa is expressed in a variety of epithelial tissues including those of the female reproductive tract, placenta, breast, kidney proximal tubules, choroid plexus, lung and salivary glands. Soluble forms of FRa may be derived by the action of proteases or phospholipase on membrane anchored folate receptors. </p><p id="p0064" num="0064"> As used herein, the terms "FRa not bound to a cell" or "soluble FRa" refer to FRa that is not attached to the cellular membrane of a cell, such as a cancerous cell. In a particular embodiment, the FRa not bound to a cell is unbound to any cell and is freely floating or solubilized in biological fluids, e.g. , urine or serum. For example, the FRa may be shed, secreted or exported from normal or cancerous cells, for example, from the surface of cancerous cells, into biological fluids. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="12"/>-->
 A breast cancer which is an FRa-expressing or overexpressing cancer can be identified by measuring the level of FRa, e.g., soluble FRa, in a sample derived from a subject. The term "sample" as used herein refers to a collection of similar cells or tissue isolated from a subject, as well as tissues, cells and fluids present within a subject. The term "sample" includes any body fluid (e.g., plasma, blood fluids, lymph, gynecological fluids, cystic fluid, urine, ocular fluids, ascitic fluid and fluids collected by bronchial lavage and/or peritoneal rinsing), or tissue or a cell from a subject. In one embodiment, the tissue or cell is removed from the subject. In another embodiment, the tissue or cell is present within the subject. Other subject samples, include tear drops, serum, cerebrospinal fluid, feces, sputum and cell extracts. In one embodiment, the biological sample contains protein molecules from the test subject. In another embodiment, the biological sample may contain mRNA molecules from the test subject or genomic DNA molecules from the test subject. </p><p id="p0065" num="0065"> It will be readily understood by the ordinarily skilled artisan that essentially any technical means suitable for detecting the level of expression of FRa at either the nucleic acid or protein level can be used to detect the level of FRa. </p><p id="p0066" num="0066"> For example, mRNA may be extracted from the sample obtained from the subject and expression of mRNA(s) encoding FRa in the sample may be detected and/or quantified using standard molecular biology techniques, such as PCR analysis. RNA may be extracted from cells using RNA extraction techniques including, for example, using acid phenol/guanidine isothiocyanate extraction (RNAzol B; Biogenesis), RNeasy RNA preparation kits (Qiagen) or PAXgene (PreAnalytix, Switzerland). RNA may be assayed, for example, using microarray analysis, nuclear run-on assays, RNase protection assays (see e.g. , Melton et al., Nuc. Acids Res. 12:7035), in situ hybridization, membrane blot techniques (such as used in hybridization analysis, such as Northern, Southern, dot, and the like), or by detection in microwells, sample tubes, gels, beads or fibers (or any solid support comprising bound nucleic acids). </p><p id="p0067" num="0067"> In one embodiment of the invention, microarrays are used to detect the level of expression of FRa. Microarrays are particularly well suited for this purpose because of the reproducibility between different experiments. Microarrays provide one method for the simultaneous measurement of the expression levels of large numbers of genes. Each array consists of a reproducible pattern of capture probes attached to a solid support. Labeled RNA or DNA is hybridized to complementary probes on the array and then detected by laser scanning. Hybridization intensities for each probe on the array are determined and converted 
<!-- EPO <DP n="13"/>-->
 to a quantitative value representing relative gene expression levels. See, U.S. Pat. Nos. </p><p id="p0068" num="0068">6,040,138, 5,800,992 and 6,020,135, 6,033,860, and 6,344,316, which are incorporated herein by reference. High-density oligonucleotide arrays are particularly useful for determining the gene expression profile for a large number of RNAs in a sample. </p><p id="p0069" num="0069"> In some embodiments, methods for determining the level of expression of FRa in a sample include the process of nucleic acid amplification and/or reverse transcriptase (to prepare cDNA) of, for example, mRNA in the sample, e.g. , by RT-PCR (the experimental embodiment set forth in Mullis, 1987, U.S. Pat. No. 4,683,202), ligase chain reaction (Barany (1991) Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 88: 189-193), self sustained sequence replication (Guatelli et al. (1990) Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 87: 1874-1878), transcriptional amplification system (Kwoh et al. (1989) Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 86: 1173-1177), Q-Beta Replicase (Lizardi et al. (1988) Bio/Technology 6: 1197), rolling circle replication (Lizardi et al., U.S. Pat. No. 5,854,033) or any other nucleic acid amplification method, followed by the detection of the amplified molecules using techniques discussed herein and/or other techniques known to those of skill in the art. These detection schemes are especially useful for the detection of nucleic acid molecules if such molecules are present in very low numbers. In particular aspects of the invention, the level of expression of FRa is determined by quantitative fluorogenic RT-PCR (i.e., the TaqManTM System). </p><p id="p0070" num="0070"> The levels of FRa can also be determined, for example, using any method known in the art for the measurement of protein levels. Such methods include, for example, electrophoresis, capillary electrophoresis, high performance liquid chromatography (HPLC), thin layer chromatography (TLC), hyperdiffusion chromatography, fluid or gel precipitin reactions, absorption spectroscopy, a colorimetric assays, spectrophotometric assays, flow cytometry, immunodiffusion (single or double), Immunoelectrophoresis, Western blotting, radioimmunoassay (RIA), enzyme-linked immunosorbent assays (ELISAs), </p><p id="p0071" num="0071">immunofluorescent assays, and electrochemiluminescence immunoassay (exemplified below), and the like. In a preferred embodiment, the level is determined using antibody-based techniques. Such methods are described in U.S. Provisional patent Application No. </p><p id="p0072" num="0072">61/410,497, filed on November 5, 2010, entitled "Folate receptor alpha as a diagnostic and prognostic marker for folate receptor alpha-expressing cancers," the entire contents of which are incorporated herein by reference. In another embodiment, the level is determined by using immunohistochemical techniques, such as described in Kalli et al. "Folate receptor alpha as a 
<!-- EPO <DP n="14"/>-->
 tumor target in epithelial ovarian cancer," Gynecol Oncol. 2008 March ; 108(3): 619-626, which is incorporated herein by reference. </p><p id="p0073" num="0073"> Antibody-based techniques for the detection of FRa include, without limitation, ELISA, RIA, flow cytometry, immunocytochemistry, tissue immunohistochemistry, Western blot and immunoprecipitation. Anti-FRa antibodies or antigen binding portions thereof for use in these techniques may be generated or may be obtained from commercial sources for use for in vitro or in vivo detection of FRa. Further, FRa may be detected by contacting a biological sample with an anti-FRa antibody or antigen binding portion thereof and detecting the bound antibody or antigen binding portion thereof. The anti-FRa antibody or antigen binding portion thereof may be directly labeled with a detectable label or may be unlabeled. If an unlabeled antibody is used, a second antibody or other molecule that can bind the anti-FRa antibody that is labeled is used to detect antibody bound to FRa. As is well known to one of skill in the art, a second antibody is chosen that is able to specifically bind the specific species and class of the first antibody. For example, if the anti-FRa antibody comprises a human IgG, then the secondary antibody may be a labeled anti-human- IgG antibody. Other molecules that can bind to antibodies include, without limitation, Protein A and Protein G, both of which are available commercially, e.g., from Pierce Chemical Co. Suitable labels for the antibody or secondary molecule include various enzymes, prosthetic groups, fluorescent materials, luminescent materials, magnetic agents and radioactive materials. Examples of suitable enzymes include horseradish peroxidase, alkaline phosphatase, O-galactosidase, or acetylcholinesterase; examples of suitable prosthetic group complexes include </p><p id="p0074" num="0074">streptavidinibiotin and avidin/biotin; examples of suitable fluorescent materials include umbelliferone, fluorescein, fluorescein isothiocyanate, rhodamine, dichlorotriazinylamine fluorescein, dansyl chloride or phycoerythrin; an example of a luminescent material includes luminol; an example of a magnetic agent includes gadolinium; and examples of suitable radioactive material include <sup>125</sup>1, <sup>131</sup>1, <sup>35</sup>S or <sup>3</sup>H. </p><p id="p0075" num="0075"> Anti-FRa antibodies or antigen binding portions thereof may be used to detect a breast cancer which is an FRa-expressing or overexpressing cancer by determining the presence, level, and/or localization of FRa in a biological sample. An anti-FRa antibody or an antigen- binding portion of such an antibody may be used to detect, quantify, and/or localize FRa, for example, in a tissue or on the surface of a cell. A preferred immunoassay for determining the presence and/or localization of FRa, e.g., cell surface levels, is an immunohistochemistry 
<!-- EPO <DP n="15"/>-->
 (IHC)/immunocytochemistry (ICC) assay. Immunohistochemistry and immunocytochemistry procedures are well known in the art. The tissue or cells to be tested may be fixed utilizing any of a variety of fixation conditions which include, without limitation, paraformaldehyde in phosphate buffer, paraformaldehyde in periodate/lysine/phosphate buffer, paraformaldehyde with glutaraldehyde (for Transmission Electron Microscopy), or cold acetone or alcohol (for frozen samples). The tissue also may be embedded in an embedding medium for IHC. </p><p id="p0076" num="0076">Embedding media for immunohistochemistry experiments may include, but are not limited to, paraffin wax or any form of cryomatrix (for frozen samples). To obtain three-dimensional images, it may also be possible to perform immunohistochemistry experiments using a whole- mount preparation. </p><p id="p0077" num="0077"> Suitable IHC assays that may be used to detect FRa expression include those described in, for example, Example 4. When IHC is used to detect FRa expression, in some </p><p id="p0078" num="0078">embodiments, a positive sample is one in which &gt;5 , &gt;10 , &gt;15 , &gt;20 , &gt;25 , &gt;30 , &gt;35 , &gt;40 , &gt;45 , &gt;50 , &gt;55 , &gt;60 , &gt;65 , &gt;70 , &gt;75 , &gt;80 , &gt;85 , &gt;90 , or &gt;95 of tumor cells stain at any intensity (e.g., membrane staining). </p><p id="p0079" num="0079"> An exemplary antibody which may be used to detect FRa is antibody 26B3 (also referred to as 26B3.F2), which was deposited with the American Type Culture Collection (Manassas, VA) under Accession No. PTA-11885 on May 19, 2011. This antibody is described in U.S. Provisional Application Nos. 61/508,444, filed July 15, 2011; 61/604,412, filed February 28, 2012 and 61/604,954, filed February 29, 2012. The entire contents of each of the foregoing applications are hereby incorporated herein by reference. </p><p id="p0080" num="0080"> Antigen retrieval, when necessary, may be accomplished by performing Heat Induced Epitope Retrieval (HIER) or Proteolytic Induced Epitope Retrieval (PIER) or a combination thereof. Antibody penetration of cells or tissues for IHC/ICC, when necessary, may be accomplished using a variety of reagents including, without limitation, Triton X-100, saponin or sodium borohydride. Blocking treatment, if necessary, may be performed by treating cells or tissue with a variety of blocking reagents including, but not limited to, serum albumin. The methods of detection of FRa in a tissue or cell sample are numerous, and may include, without limitation, direct antibody detection, indirect antibody detection, peroxidase anti-peroxidase method, avidin-biotin complex method, labeled streptavidin biotin method or any one of a variety of polymeric signal amplification methods. Other methods of detection include, for 
<!-- EPO <DP n="16"/>-->
 example, nucleic acid-based detection methods or folate-based detection methods (see, e.g. , Muller, C. et al. J. Nucl Med. 2008 Feb; 49(2): 310-317 (use of radiopharmaceuticals as imaging agents)). </p><p id="p0081" num="0081"> In some embodiments, eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof, are administered concurrently, intercurrently, consecutively or concomitantly. As used herein, the term "concurrently" refers to the administration of two active agents, wherein at least a portion of the administration of the two active agents occurs at the same time. As used herein, the term "consecutively" refers to the administration of two active agents, wherein the administration of one active agent occurs within about a day of conclusion of administration of the other active agent. As used herein, the term "concomitantly" refers to the administration of two active agents, wherein administration of one active agent occurs at some point during the dosing regimen of the second active agent. As used herein, the term "intercurrently" refers to the administration of two active agents, wherein administration of the two active agents occurs generally during the same time period (e.g. , over 30 days), but not necessarily at the same time. In some embodiments, eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof, are administered intercurrently, consecutively or concomitantly. In some embodiments, eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof are administered intercurrently. It will be appreciated from the foregoing that the drugs can be administered in any order. </p><p id="p0082" num="0082"> As used herein, the term "therapeutically effective amount" of eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof, refers to an amount effective, at dosages and for periods of time necessary, to achieve the desired therapeutic result. A therapeutically effective amount may vary according to factors such as the disease state, age, sex, and weight of the individual, and the ability of the combination of eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof, to elicit a desired response in the individual. </p><p id="p0083" num="0083"> In some embodiments, eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof is administered from 1-5 times about every 10-40 days, e.g. , from one to three times about every 14-35 days. In some embodiments, eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof is administered about once every 21-28 days. In other embodiments, eribulin or a </p><p id="p0084" num="0084">pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof is administered about twice every 21-28 days. In 
<!-- EPO <DP n="17"/>-->
 some embodiments, eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof is administered on day 1 and day 8 of a 21-28 day cycle. </p><p id="p0085" num="0085"> In some embodiments, farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof is administered once a week. In other embodiments, farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof is administered tri-weekly. In some embodiments, farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof is administered from 1-4 times about every 7-28 days. In some embodiments, farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment is administered once during a 21-28 day cycle. In other embodiments, farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment is administered on day 1 of the 21-28 day cycle. In some embodiments, farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof is administered weekly thereafter. In some embodiments, farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment is administered immediately after the administration of eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof. </p><p id="p0086" num="0086"> In some embodiments, a loading dose of farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof is used. For example, farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof may be administered on day 1 and day 8 of a 21-28 day cycle and on day 1 of subsequent cycles. </p><p id="p0087" num="0087"> In some embodiments of the methods of the invention, farletuzumab or an antigen- binding fragment thereof is administered before eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, e.g. , before the administration of eribulin. One such embodiment is described in Example 5 below. Alternatively, eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof can be administered first, e.g. , before the administration of farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof. </p><p id="p0088" num="0088"> For example, eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof is administered intravenously on day 1 and day 8 of a 21 day cycle and farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment is administered on day 1 of the same 21 day cycle, for example, immediately before or after the intravenous administration of eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof. This 21 day cycle can be repeated in the subject as indicated. For example, it can be repeated for 1-2, 2-5, 10 or more cycles. In some embodiments, a loading dose of farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof is used. For example, farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof may be intravenously administered on day 1 and day 8 of a first 21 day cycle and on day 1 of subsequent cycles. </p><p id="p0089" num="0089"> In some embodiments, administration of eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof and administration of farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof do not 
<!-- EPO <DP n="18"/>-->
 overlap. For example, administration comprises a 21-day cycle, wherein eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof is administered on day 1 of the cycle and wherein farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof is administered once on any one of days 2-16 of the cycle. In some embodiments, administration comprises a 28-day cycle, wherein eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof is administered on days 1 and 8 of the cycle and wherein farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof is administered once on any one of days 15-28 of the cycle. </p><p id="p0090" num="0090"> In some embodiments, the subject receives about 2 to about 50 treatment cycles, e.g., about 3 to about 30 treatment cycles. In some embodiments, the subject is administered about 4 to about 6 treatment cycles. </p><p id="p0091" num="0091"> In some embodiments, eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof is administered in an amount from about 0.1 mg/m<sup>2</sup> to about 5.0 mg/m<sup>2</sup>, e.g. , from about 0.2 mg/m<sup>2</sup> to about 4.0 mg/m<sup>2</sup>. For example, eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof is administered in an amount of about, e.g. , 0.5 mg/m<sup>2</sup> to about 3.0 mg/m<sup>2</sup>, for example, about 0.5 mg/m<sup>2</sup>, about 0.7 mg/m<sup>2</sup>, about 1.0 mg/m<sup>2</sup>, about 1.1 mg/m<sup>2</sup>, about 1.2 mg/m<sup>2</sup>, about 1.3 mg/m<sup>2</sup>, about 1.4 mg/m<sup>2</sup>, about 1.5 mg/m<sup>2</sup>, about 2.0 mg/m<sup>2</sup>, about 2.5 </p><p id="p0092" num="0092"> 2 </p><p id="p0093" num="0093">mg/m<sup>2</sup>, or about 3.0 mg/m<sup>2</sup>. In one embodiment the dose is 1.4 mg/m administered intravenously over 2 to 5 minutes on days 1 and 8 of a 21 -day cycle. In another embodiment, the subject has mild hepatic impairment and the amount is 1.1 mg/m<sup>2</sup> administered intravenously over 2 to 5 minutes on days 1 and 8 of a 21 -day cycle. In another embodiment, the subject has moderate hepatic impairment and the amount is 0.7 mg/m<sup>2</sup> administered intravenously over 2 to 5 minutes on days 1 and 8 of a 21 -day cycle. In yet another embodiment, the subject has moderate renal impairment (creatinine clearance of 30-50 </p><p id="p0094" num="0094"> 2 </p><p id="p0095" num="0095">mL/min) and the amount is 1.1 mg/m administered intravenously over 2 to 5 minutes on days 1 and 8 of a 21 -day cycle. </p><p id="p0096" num="0096"> In some embodiments, farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof is administered in an amount from about 0.5 mg/kg to about 4.00 mg/kg weekly. In some embodiments, farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof is administered in an amount from about 1.00 to about 3.00 mg/kg weekly, e.g., in an amount of about 1.00 mg/kg, 1.25 mg/kg, 1.5 mg/kg, 1.75 mg/kg, 2.00 mg/kg, 2.25 mg/kg, 2.50 mg/kg, 2.75 mg/kg or 3.00 mg/kg weekly. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="19"/>-->
 In some embodiments, farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof is administered in an amount from about 3.00 mg/kg to about 9.00 mg/kg tri-weekly, i.e. , once every three weeks. For example, farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof is administered in an amount of, for example, about 3.00 mg/kg, 3.25 mg/kg, 3.5 mg/kg, 3.75 mg/kg, 4.00 mg/kg, 4.25 mg/kg, 4.50 mg/kg, 4.75 mg/kg, 5.0 mg/kg, 5.25 mg/kg, 5.50 mg/kg, 5.75 mg/kg, 6.00 mg/kg, 6.25 mg/kg, 6.50 mg/kg, 6.85 mg/kg, 7.00 mg/kg, 7.25 mg/kg, 7.50 mg/kg, 7.75 mg/kg, 8.00 mg/kg, 8.25 mg/kg, 8.50 mg/kg, 8.75 mg/kg, or about 9.00 mg/kg, for example, tri-weekly. </p><p id="p0097" num="0097"> In some embodiments, eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof is formulated in a liposomal formulation. For example, in some embodiments, the liposomal formulation further comprises an ammonium salt. See for example, WO 2010/113984. </p><p id="p0098" num="0098"> In some embodiments, tumor growth in the subject is inhibited by at least about 5%, about 10%, about 15%, about 20%, about 25%, about 30%, about 35%, about 40%, about 45%, about 50%, about 55%, about 60%, about 65%, about 70%, about 75%, about 80%, about 85%, about 90%, about 95% or about 100% compared to a suitable control. In some embodiments, administration of eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof, results in tumor regression in the subject. In some embodiments, administration of eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof, results in complete tumor regression in the subject. As used herein, the term "tumor regression" refers to a decrease in tumor size. Regression may be complete or partial. Inhibition of tumor growth or tumor regression may be observed in primary and/or metastatic tumors. </p><p id="p0099" num="0099"> In some embodiments of the methods of the invention, administration of eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof, results in improvement in progression free survival. In other embodiments of the methods of the invention, administration of eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof, results in an improvement one or more clinical outcome variables, such as e.g., objective response rate (ORR): complete response and partial response CR + PR); time to response (TTR); duration of response (DoR); disease control rate (DCR; CR + PR + stable disease [SD]); clinical benefit rate (CBR: CR +</p><p id="p0100" num="0100">PR + durable stable disease [dSD, duration of SD &gt; 12 weeks]). The improvement(s) may be observed relative to any suitable control, e.g. , improvement in a treated individual, or in a 
<!-- EPO <DP n="20"/>-->
 group of treated individuals, compared with a control individual or control group, e.g. , a group treated with eribulin or a pharmacuetically acceptable salt thereof (e.g., eribulin mesylate) and optionally placebo. </p><p id="p0101" num="0101"> In some embodiments, the methods of the present invention further include </p><p id="p0102" num="0102">maintenance therapy with eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, or farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment, or both. </p><p id="p0103" num="0103"> Numerous approaches for administering anti-cancer drugs are known in the art, and can readily be adapted for use in the present invention with eribulin or the pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof, for example, the drugs can be administered together, in a single composition, or separately, as part of a comprehensive treatment regimen and in any order. For systemic administration, the drugs can be administered by, for example, intravenous infusion (continuous or bolus). The modes of administration may be different for each drug administered. Appropriate scheduling and dosing of such administration can readily be determined by those of skill in this art based on, for example, preclinical, studies in animals and clinical studies (e.g. , phase I studies) in humans. In addition, monitoring factors such as blood counts (e.g. , neutrophil and platelet counts) and vital signs in patients can be used, as is well understood in the art. </p><p id="p0104" num="0104"> In some embodiments, subjects treated by the methods of the invention may be premedicated prior to the administration of the eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof and/or farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof. For example, subjects may be premedicated prior to infusion of farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof, e.g. , with acetaminophen, such as about 650-1000 mg of acetaminophen or a clinical equivalent. Subjects may also receive concomitant premedication in the form of primary prophylaxis for hypersensitivity and infusion-related reactions, e.g. , a combination of anti- histamine agents, antipyretics, systemic steroids, and additional supportive measures as required. Subjects may also be premedicated with anti-nausea medications. Subjects may be treated with anti-nausea medications on a regular or as-needed basis while undergoing treatment according to the methods of the invention. </p><p id="p0105" num="0105"> The invention also includes compositions (e.g. , pharmaceutical compositions comprising a pharmaceutically acceptable carrier) that include (a) eribulin or a </p><p id="p0106" num="0106">pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and (b) farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof, optionally in combination with an additional therapeutic agent(s). The drugs in these 
<!-- EPO <DP n="21"/>-->
 compositions preferably are formulated for administration to patients or, alternatively, can be in a form requiring further processing prior to administration. For example, the compositions can include the drugs in a lyophilized form or in a concentrated form requiring dilution. </p><p id="p0107" num="0107">Formulation of drugs for use in chemotherapeutic methods can be carried out using standard methods in the art (see, e.g. , Remington 's Pharmaceutical Sciences (18th edition), ed. A. Gennaro, 1990, Mack Publishing Co., Easton, PA). </p><p id="p0108" num="0108"> Also included in the invention are kits that include eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof. Eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof, can be present in a single container, such as a vial, or can be present in separate containers. Further, the different agents can be present in forms that are ready for </p><p id="p0109" num="0109">administration or forms requiring further formulation (e.g. , lyophilized form). The kits can also include diluents for the agents, instructions for administration of the agents, one or more labels listing the contents of the kits, and/or devices used in agent administration. </p><p id="p0110" num="0110"> The present invention is further illustrated by the following examples, which should not be construed as further limiting. The contents of all figures and all references, patents and published patent applications cited throughout this application are expressly incorporated herein by reference in their entirety. EXAMPLES </p><p id="p0111" num="0111"> Example 1: Expression of Folate Receptor Alpha (FRq) on Breast Cancer Cell Lines </p><p id="p0112" num="0112"> The FRoc expression status and eribulin mesylate IC50 values of four breast cancer cell lines were determined. IGROV-1 cells (ovarian tumor cell line) were used as a positive control for FRa. The cells were collected, washed (centrifuged at 1200 RPM for 5 minutes) and suspended in FACS buffer (cold PBS + 2% FBS). The cells were counted using </p><p id="p0113" num="0113"> Cellometer AutoT4 and added to a 96 well U-bottom plate (at 50,000 cells per well) and centrifuged at 1200 RPM for 5 minutes. The buffer was removed. Farletuzumab (10 μg/mL or 1 μg/mL) diluted in FACS buffer was added to the wells (100 μΕ per well of diluted farletuzumab was added) and incubation on ice was carried out for 1 hour. The plate was washed 3 times with 200 μΕ/well of FACS buffer. Secondary antibody (goat anti-human Ig- FITC from SouthernBiotech at 1: 100) diluted in FACS buffer, ΙΟΟμΕ/well was added. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="22"/>-->
 Incubation on ice was carried out for 1 hour. The plate was washed 3 times with 200 μΕ/well of FACS buffer. 200 μL· FACS buffer was added to each well and FACS analysis was performed using a BD FACS CANTO II flow cytometer (BD Biosciences). The results are provided in Table 1. </p><p id="p0114" num="0114">Table 1: Expression of FRoc, ER, PR, and eribulin mesylate IC50 values in five breast cancer cell lines </p><p id="p0115" num="0115"><img id="imgf000022_0001" he="38" wi="134" file="imgf000022_0001.tif" img-format="tif" img-content="table" orientation="portrait" inline="no"/></p><p id="p0116" num="0116">The cell lines were also analyzed in a second set of experiments using FACS, and FRoc expression status of these cell lines was confirmed. Cells were grown in complete RPMI consisting of RPMI 1640 medium (Invitrogen) with 2 mM L-glutamine, non-essential amino acids, sodium pyruvate, antibiotics, and 10% heat inactivated FBS. TrypLE (Invitrogen) was used to harvest the cells and 1 ml of harvested cells was counted on the ViCell (Bekman Coulter). 5E4 cells were pipetted into 96-well U-bottom assay plate for FACS staining in</p><p id="p0117" num="0117">PBS+2% FBS (FACS buffer) up to 100 μΐ/well. Farletuzumab and isotype control antibodies were added at 10 μg/mL to each well containing cells (except cells only) and mixed gently. After a 60 minute incubation period, cells were washed twice with an additional 150μ1 of FACS buffer. Then cells were resuspended in -100 μΐ FACS buffer with FITC-conjugated Goat anti-human antibody (Southern Biotech lot# F7006-QF20B) incubated 30 min on ice. After two washes in FACS buffer, the cells were resuspended in 200 μΕ FACS buffer and analyzed on an EasyCyte Flow Cytometer (Guava Technologies). Figure 1 shows that FRoc was expressed on the breast cancer cell lines CAL51, T47D and HCC-1954 cells, but not on BT474 cells. </p><p id="p0118" num="0118">Example 2: Farletuzumab Mediated Antibody-Dependent Cell-Mediated Cytotoxicity 
<!-- EPO <DP n="23"/>-->
 To assess whether farletuzumab alone could mediate ADCC to the foregoing breast cancer cell lines (BT474, HCC-1954, T47D andCAL51), the xCelligence platform (Roche) was used. The IGROV-lcell line was used as a positive control. TrypLE (Invitrogen) harvested cells were counted and resuspended at a predetermined optimal cell density based on cell type (HCC-1954, IGROV-1, T47D, BT474 at 40,000 cells/mL, CAL51 at 25,000 cells/mL). 100 μL· of complete RPMI was added to each well of the Eplate 96 (Roche) and a background reading was taken on the xCelligence. 100 μL· of cells were added to each dedicated well on the plate. The plate was then incubated at room temperature for 30 minutes to allow the cells to settle appropriately. The plate was placed in the xCelligence and readings were taken every 10 minutes overnight. In the same time, human PBMCs ("PBMCs") from a verified donor (AllCells) were cultured overnight in complete RPMI supplemented with 2 ng/mL IL-2 (Peprotech). On the following day, 100 μL· of media was removed from each well without disturbing the cell monolayer on the bottom of the well. 50 μL· of diluted antibody in RPMI was added to the well at 4X the final concentration desired. The plate (cells plus antibody) was placed in the xCelligence and allowed to incubate for an hour (while taking readings every 10 minutes). During this time, PBMCs were harvested by scraping and counted. The PBMCs were spun down and resuspended in RPMI so that they can be added at a 20:1 or 10:1 ratio (PBMCS:target cell) depending on the cell type, in 50 μL· per well. After the PBMCs were added to the plate, it was returned to the xCelligence and readings were taken continuously overnight. Percent cytotoxicity was calculated as follows: </p><p id="p0119" num="0119"> % killing=(l-(Cell Index Farletuzumab well/Cell Index complement only well))*100. </p><p id="p0120" num="0120"> To measure ADCC activity, cells were plated at the desired density onto an E-plate and allowed to adhere overnight. The following day, purified farletuzumab was added at the final concentration indicated in Figure 2 (for HCC1954 cells farletuzumab was used at 10 μg/mL) and incubated for 30 minutes. Then, IL-2 (2 ng/mL)-activated PBMCs from normal healthy donors were added at an effectontarget ratio of 20:1. ADCC activity was monitored every 15 minutes. Readouts were taken using the xCELLigence system (Roche). Figure 2 shows the results of the ADCC assay. Farletuzumab exerted moderate and titratable ADCC activities to T47D and CAL51 cells. Farletuzumab at 10 μg/mL could kill -50% of HCC1954 cells by ADCC. Farletuzumab exerted no measurable ADCC activities to FRa negative BT474 cells</p><p id="p0121" num="0121">(data not shown). These results show that farletuzumab, administered alone, can mediate</p><p id="p0122" num="0122">ADCC in FRa expressing breast cancer cell lines. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="24"/>-->
 Example 3: Combination Effect of Eribulin Mesylate and Farletuzumab</p><p id="p0123" num="0123">To evaluate the combination effect of eribulin mesylate (E7389) and farletuzumab- mediated ADCC, HCC-1954 or CAL51 cells were pretreated in tissue culture flasks for four days with eribulin mesylate (E7389) at two concentrations (see Tables 2 and 3 below). </p><p id="p0124" num="0124"> Pretreated cells were harvested at day 4, strained, counted and percentage of cytotoxicity of eribulin mesylate was calculated as follows: </p><p id="p0125" num="0125"> % cytotoxicity=(l-(cell count with eribulin/cell counts w/o eribulin))X100. </p><p id="p0126" num="0126">Cells in suspension were then seeded in Eplate 96 (Roche) as in a regular ADCC assay with farletuzumab and control antibody at one fixed concentration of lC^g/mL. The ADCC assays were conducted as above and percentage of cytotoxicity of farletuzumab was calculated as follows: </p><p id="p0127" num="0127"> % cytotoxicity=(l-(Cell Index farletuzumab well/Cell Index complement only well))X100.</p><p id="p0128" num="0128">The combined effect of eribulin and farletuzumab in the course of the four plus two day assay period is calculated as follows: </p><p id="p0129" num="0129"> % total cytotoxicity=(l-(cell count with eribulin/cell counts w/o eribulin)X(Cell Index farletuzumab well/Cell Index complement only well))X100. </p><p id="p0130" num="0130"> Table 2 shows that farletuzumab ADCC activity alone killed 52% of the HCC-1954 cells. When the same cells were pretreated with eribulin mesylate at the two doses for four days, cell growth was inhibited by 34% and 51% respectively. Farletuzumab mediated ADCC killed 64% and 57% of those pretreated cells, respectively, in the following two days. Taken together, the total cytotoxicity could be calculated as 77% and 79%, respectively, with the two doses of eribulin treatment. In contrast, isotype control antibody added minimum toxicity to eribulin treated cells. </p><p id="p0131" num="0131"> Similarly, Table 3 shows that farletuzumab ADCC activity alone killed 38% of the</p><p id="p0132" num="0132">CAL51 cells. When the same cells were pretreated with eribulin mesylate at the two doses for four days, cell growth was inhibited by 18% and 29% respectively. Farletuzumab mediated ADCC killed 54% and 51% of those pretreated cells, respectively, in the following two days. Taken together, the total cytotoxicity could be calculated as 62% and 65%, respectively, with the two doses of eribulin mesylate treatment. In contrast, isotype control antibody added minimum toxicity to eribulin mesylate treated cells. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="25"/>-->
 Table 2: Combination effect of Eribulin Mesylate ("E7389")and Farletuzumab on HCC1954 cells </p><p id="p0133" num="0133"><img id="imgf000025_0001" he="60" wi="158" file="imgf000025_0001.tif" img-format="tif" img-content="table" orientation="portrait" inline="yes"/></p><p id="p0134" num="0134">Table 3: Combination effect of Eribulin Mesylate (E7389) and Farletuzumab on CAL51 cells </p><p id="p0135" num="0135"><img id="imgf000025_0002" he="60" wi="158" file="imgf000025_0002.tif" img-format="tif" img-content="table" orientation="portrait" inline="yes"/></p><p id="p0136" num="0136">As demonstrated by the foregoing results, eribulin and farletuzumab exerted at least additive cytotoxicity to FRa-expressing breast cancer cells. </p><p id="p0137" num="0137">Example 4: Folate Receptor Alpha Expression and Association with Triple-Negative Forms of Breast Cancer </p><p id="p0138" num="0138"> Immunohistochemistry studies were conducted to assess the expression of FRa by breast cancer tissue samples. Analyses were conducted using tissue microarray (TMA) 
<!-- EPO <DP n="26"/>-->
 samples and formalin-fixed paraffin-embedded (FFPE) histology samples that were stained with a primary mouse monoclonal antibody (26B3) directed to FRa (O'Shannessy et al., Oncotarget 2(12):1227-43 (2011)). </p><p id="p0139" num="0139">Immunohistochemistry </p><p id="p0140" num="0140"> Immunohistochemistry was performed using TMA samples (US Biomax, Inc., catalog # BR1503a; 72 cases, duplicate cores) or FFPE specimens (obtained from the archives of Genzyme Genetics) and a MACH4 Universal HRP-Polymer Detection Kit (Biocare Medical, Concord, CA). FFPE specimens were sectioned at 5μιη onto positively-charged glass slides and heated for approximately 60 minutes at 60 °C. Slides were deparaffinized in 3 sequential baths of xylene for 3min each, transferred to three sequential baths of 100% alcohol for 3 minutes each, followed by three sequential baths of 95% alcohol for 3min each and then rinsed for 5 minutes in deionized (DI) water. Slides were then pretreated in Diva heat-induced epitope retrieval solution (Biocare Medical) diluted 1:10 in DI water and placed inside a pressurized decloaking chamber already filled with 500 mL of DI water. For antigen retrieval, slides were incubated for 15min inside the decloaking chamber in which pressurized incubation reaches a maximum of 125 °C at 16 PSI for 30sec and then cooled for 15min down to 95 °C. After cooling to room temperature, slides were washed in 3 sequential baths of Tris Buffered Saline/0.1% Tween-20® wash buffer (TBST) for 3 minutes each and subsequently placed into Peroxidase- 1 (Biocare Medical) blocking solution for 5 minutes at room temperature. After washing in TBST as above, Background Sniper (Biocare Medical) serum- free universal blocking reagent was applied for 10 minutes at room temperature. For staining, samples were incubated with purified antibody 26B3 or antibody BN3.2 (Leica Microsystems, Buffalo Grove, IL) at 2.5 μg/mL diluted in Antibody Diluent (Dako North America, Inc., Carpinteria, CA) or Universal Negative Control (mouse ready-to-use negative control antibody (Dako, for negative isotype tissue)) for 60 minutes at room temperature. After washing, slides were incubated with MACH4 Mouse Probe Primary Antibody Enhancer for 15 minutes, followed by Polymer-HRP reagent for 20 minutes, developed with a 3,3'-diaminobenzidine tetrahydrochloride (DAB) solution (Dako) for 5 minutes and counterstained with hematoxylin (Dako) for 2 minutes, all incubations being performed at room temperature. Scoring for 
<!-- EPO <DP n="27"/>-->
 staining was performed by a single board-certified pathologist, using customary scoring for intensity and the percent of the tumor stained at each intensity. </p><p id="p0141" num="0141">Statistical Analyses </p><p id="p0142" num="0142"> All statistical analyses were performed using GraphPad (Prizm). </p><p id="p0143" num="0143">Positive Staining Result and Rejection of TMA Samples </p><p id="p0144" num="0144"> A sample (TMA core or FFPE specimen) was considered positive for FRa expression if the percentage of the tumor area considered by the reading pathologist to be positive for membranous staining was greater than or equal to 5% at any intensity. A TMA core was rejected and therefore not included in the analyses if the reading pathologist determined it was either missing entirely (empty core), was composed of necrotic tissue or was deemed to represent normal tissue. Histopathologic diagnosis of cores was made by the reading pathologist. </p><p id="p0145" num="0145">The M-Score - A Semi-Quantitative Staining Algorithm </p><p id="p0146" num="0146"> A metric for staining of each sample was defined as follows: 
<img id="imgf000027_0001" he="13" wi="78" file="imgf000027_0001.tif" img-format="tif" img-content="drawing" orientation="portrait" inline="no"/>
 </p><p id="p0147" num="0147">In the equation, is the percentage of tumor stained at intensity j for patient i and Wj is the absolute value of the intensity. The metric has a theoretical range from zero (no positive staining) to fifty (100% 3+). As such, the M-score is a weighted score of FRa IHC tumor cell membrane staining that captures both the proportion of FRa positive cells and staining intensity. </p><p id="p0148" num="0148"> The M-scores for each patient/sample were averaged over duplicate TMA cores or FFPE specimens, where appropriate. If a determination (core) was void of results, i.e. no tumor or necrotic tissue present, the M-score was assigned to the non-void determinations. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="28"/>-->
 The practical application of the above equation for the M-score is presented below: 
<img id="imgf000028_0001" he="21" wi="132" file="imgf000028_0001.tif" img-format="tif" img-content="table" orientation="portrait" inline="no"/>
 </p><p id="p0149" num="0149">Where x = % of tumor stained with intensity 3+; y = % of tumor stained with intensity 2+; z = % of tumor stained with intensity 1+ </p><p id="p0150" num="0150">The positivity rate for FRa expression was calculated as the proportion of tumors that were stained positive according to the definition of a positive result (&gt;5%tumor cell membrane staining). This procedure was also applied within specific histology subgroups. Differences for mean values were determined using Fisher's exact test or one-way ANOVA with post hoc tests controlling for overall type I error. </p><p id="p0151" num="0151">Experimental Results </p><p id="p0152" num="0152"> Antibody 26B3 was shown to recognize FRa on FFPE sections of various tissues, including breast. The staining pattern of FRa by 26B3 was consistent with a membranous localization, although diffuse cytoplasmic staining was also observed. Cytoplasmic staining was not observed in the absence of membrane staining. </p><p id="p0153" num="0153"> The distribution of histologies present on the breast cancer TMA are shown in Table 4, the majority of the cases represented being identified as invasive ductal carcinoma (IDC). The TMA included two normal breast samples, which were positive for FRa expression as determined by staining with antibody 26B3. Staining in normal breast was restricted to ductal cells with luminal and membrane staining. Two of three fibroadenoma cases (67%), 0/2 cystosarcoma cases (0%) and 1/6 ductal carcinoma in situ cases (17%) were positive for FRa. The single invasive lobular carcinoma (ILC) was negative for FRa staining. Of the 59 IDC samples, 18 (31%) were positive for FRa. Given the small number of positive cases on this TMA a valid analysis of FRa expression relative to stage or grade was not possible; however, it should be noted that the majority of samples were either Tl or T2. FRa expression was shown to associate with ER/PR negative tumors relative to ER/PR positive tumors (p=0.012) 
<!-- EPO <DP n="29"/>-->
 and with triple negative breast cancers (TNBC) (ER/PR+ or Her2+ versus ER/PR/Her2-, p&lt;0.0001). </p><p id="p0154" num="0154"> Table 4: Distribution of FRA (FR ) positivity across histology types - TMA data </p><p id="p0155" num="0155"> FRA positive FRA negative </p><p id="p0156" num="0156"> Tumor Histology N (%) N (%) Total P value* </p><p id="p0157" num="0157">Normal 2 (100%) 0 (0%) 2 </p><p id="p0158" num="0158"> Fibroadenoma 2 (67%) 1 (33%) 3 </p><p id="p0159" num="0159"> Cystosarcoma 0 (0%) 2 (100%) 2 </p><p id="p0160" num="0160"> DCIS - Ductal carcinoma in situ 1 (17%) 5 (83%) 6 </p><p id="p0161" num="0161"> ILC - Invasive lobular 0 (0%) 1 (100%) 1 </p><p id="p0162" num="0162">carcinoma </p><p id="p0163" num="0163"> IDC - Invasive ductal carcinoma 18 (31%) 41 (69%) 59 </p><p id="p0164" num="0164"> Total carcinomas: 21 (30%) 50 (70%) 71 </p><p id="p0165" num="0165"> IDC Molecular subtype </p><p id="p0166" num="0166"> analysis: </p><p id="p0167" num="0167"> ER/PR+ 4 (14%) 24 (86%) 28 -</p><p id="p0168" num="0168">ER/PR- 14 (45%) 17 (55%) 31 J 0.012 </p><p id="p0169" num="0169"> Her2+ 2 (15%) 11 (85%) </p><p id="p0170" num="0170"> Her2- 16 (35%) 30 (65%) 4 <sup>13</sup>6 Ί J 0.307</p><p id="p0171" num="0171">ER/PR/Her2- 12 (67%) 6 (33%) 18 &lt;0.0001 </p><p id="p0172" num="0172"> (ER/PR+ or Her2+ versus ER/PR/Her2-) </p><p id="p0173" num="0173">Tl 3 (43%) 4 (57%) 7 </p><p id="p0174" num="0174"> T2 10 (26%) 29 (74%) 39 </p><p id="p0175" num="0175"> T3 5 (63%) 3 (37%) 8 </p><p id="p0176" num="0176"> T4 0 (0%) 5 (100%) 5 </p><p id="p0177" num="0177"> NO 18 (35%) 33 (65%) </p><p id="p0178" num="0178"> N1/N2** 0 (0%) 8 (100%) <sup>5</sup> 8<sup>1</sup> Ί J 0.092</p><p id="p0179" num="0179">Grade 1 1 (14%) 6 (86%) </p><p id="p0180" num="0180"> Grade 2 12 (36%) 21 (64%) 3 <sup>7</sup>3 Ί J <sup>"</sup>Ί 0.393</p><p id="p0181" num="0181">Grade 3 5 (26%) 14 (74%) 19 0.6465 * P values calculated via 2X2 contingency table analysis using Fisher's exact test. </p><p id="p0182" num="0182"> ** 4/8 (50%) of N1/N2 samples were Her2+ </p><p id="p0183" num="0183"> ER/PR+ indicates ER+/PR+, ER-/PR+ or ER+/PR- ER/PR- indicates ER-/PR-</p><p id="p0184" num="0184">ER/PR/Her2- indicates ER- /PR- / HER2- (triple negative) 
<!-- EPO <DP n="30"/>-->
 Of the 18 FRa positive IDC cases, two (11%) were Her2 positive meaning that the majority (89%) were Her2 negative. These data suggest that FRa positivity tracks more closely with Her2 negativity. Further, of the 18 FRa positive IDC cases, 3 were estrogen receptor (ER) positive and 4 were progesterone receptor (PR) positive, but all ER/PR positive/FRa positive cases were Her2 negative. Additionally, 12/18 (67%) of the FRa positive IDC cases were triple-negative breast cancers (TNBC), suggesting that FRa may be a marker and target for very poor prognosis TNBC molecular subtype. Looking at the TMA as a whole, 2/13 (15%) of all Her2 positive cases were also positive for FRa while 16/46 (35%) of the Her2 negative cases were also FRa positive, supporting the suggestion that FRa expression correlates negatively with Her2 expression. Further, FRa expression appears to identify a new molecular subtype (FRa +) of breast cancer. </p><p id="p0185" num="0185"> The TMA described above was composed primarily of early stage breast cancers: stage I, 6/60 (10%); stage II, 44/60 (73%); stage III, 10/60 (17%). Therefore, to confirm and extend the results obtained on the TMA, 61 FFPE tissue blocks from stage IV (T4) Her2 negative breast cancers with known ER/PR expression ranging from 0-100% positive were assessed. All 61 of these samples were from metastases, not the primary tumor. </p><p id="p0186" num="0186"> FRa expression was detected in 22/61 (36%) of these patients, demonstrating that the percent of FRa positive specimens/tumors determined in early stage disease is retained in late stage metastatic disease in a Her2 negative population (TMA positivity = 35%; stage IV metastatic disease = 36%). Of the 22 FRa positive stage IV metastatic patients, only 3 (14%) showed any positivity for ER/PR with such positivity trending in the low range (up to 30%). As such, 19/22 (86%) FRa positive patients were of the triple negative molecular subtype. These data (Table 5) compare favorably with the data obtained in early stage disease on the TMA where 67% of all FRa positive patients were of the triple negative subtype. </p><p id="p0187" num="0187"> Samples from stage IV metastatic disease were obtained from a number of metastatic sites including lymph node, bone, skin and liver, as well as fluid and fine needle aspirate (FN A) samples obtained primarily from pleura and paracentesis. Several of these 'fluid biopsies' were stained for FRa, suggesting the potential general applicability of the described IHC methodology to multiple sample types. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="31"/>-->
 Table 5: Distribution of FRA(FRa) positivity in HER2 negative (HER2-) molecular subtypes of metastatic breast cancer samples </p><p id="p0188" num="0188"> FRA positive FRA negative </p><p id="p0189" num="0189"> Tumor Molecular N (%) N (%) Total P value* </p><p id="p0190" num="0190"> subtype </p><p id="p0191" num="0191">Total Samples: 22 (36%) 39 (64%) 61 </p><p id="p0192" num="0192"> ER/PR+ 3 (14%) 20 (86%) 23 </p><p id="p0193" num="0193"> ER/PR/Her2- 19 (50%) 19 (50%) 38 0.0054 </p><p id="p0194" num="0194"> (ER/PR+ versus ER/PR/Her2-) </p><p id="p0195" num="0195"> Grade 1 3 (30%) 7 (70%) 10 </p><p id="p0196" num="0196"> Grade 2 11 (28%) 28 (72%) 39 1.0 </p><p id="p0197" num="0197"> (Grade 1 versus Grade 2) </p><p id="p0198" num="0198"> Grade 3 8 (67%) 4 (33%) 12 0.037 </p><p id="p0199" num="0199"> (Grade 1 or 2 versus Grade 3) </p><p id="p0200" num="0200"> *P values calculated via 2x2 contingency table analysis using Fisher's exact test ER/PR+ indicates ER+/PR+, ER-/PR+ or ER+/PR-</p><p id="p0201" num="0201">ER/PR/Her2- indicates ER- /PR- / HER2- (triple negative) </p><p id="p0202" num="0202">Example 5: Efficacy and Safety of Eribulin Mesylate and Farletuzumab Combination Treatment of HER2 Negative Metastatic Breast Cancer </p><p id="p0203" num="0203">A multicenter, randomized, double blind, parallel-group study is carried out to determine the efficacy and safety of eribulin mesylate and farletuzumab combination treatment. Subjects with HER2 negative metastatic breast cancer are randomized to two treatment groups that receive either the combination of (i) eribulin mesylate and farletuzumab (Arm A) or (ii) eribulin mesylate and placebo (Arm B). The following stratification factors are considered: i) previous treatment for metastatic disease (1<sup>st</sup> or 2<sup>nd</sup> line); ii) hormone- receptor phenotype (positive vs negative). </p><p id="p0204" num="0204">Subjects </p><p id="p0205" num="0205"> Subjects are selected based on inclusion and exclusion criteria, including the following: </p><p id="p0206" num="0206"> Inclusion Criteria 
<!-- EPO <DP n="32"/>-->
 The subjects must provide written, informed consent prior to participation. The subjects must be females or males aged &gt;18 years at the time of informed consent. </p><p id="p0207" num="0207"> Subjects must have a HER2-negative metastatic breast cancer (MBC) according to National Comprehensive Cancer Network (NCCN) ver. 1.2012. They must show positive expression of FRa and the presence of measurable disease. </p><p id="p0208" num="0208"> Exclusion Criteria </p><p id="p0209" num="0209"> Subjects with HER2-positive MBC (as per NCCN ver. 1.2012) are excluded. </p><p id="p0210" num="0210">Treatments </p><p id="p0211" num="0211"> Subjects are randomly assigned to receive eribulin mesylate in combination with farletuzumab (arm A) or eribulin mesylate in combination with placebo (arm B). </p><p id="p0212" num="0212"> Eribulin Treatments </p><p id="p0213" num="0213"> Eribulin mesylate is administered at a dose of 1.4 mg/m<sup>2</sup> as an IV infusion over 2-5 minutes on Days 1 and 8 of every 21 -day cycle. Dose reduction and interruption for eribulin- related toxicity is made according to the following instructions: </p><p id="p0214" num="0214">Dose modification on Day 1 of each cycle: </p><p id="p0215" num="0215"> Eribulin mesylate is reduced to 1.1 mg/m<sup>2</sup> on Day 1 of a cycle at the occurrence of the following events: (i) Grade 3 or 4 hematologic toxicities that recovered to Grade 2 within 14 days in the previous cycle and consisted of the following: Grade 4 neutropenia &gt;7 days, Grade 3 or 4 febrile neutropenia and/or infection requiring treatment with antibiotics and/or growth factors, Grade 4 thrombocytopenia, or Grade 3 thrombocytopenia requiring platelet or blood transfusion or both; (ii) Grade 3 or 4 non-hematologic toxicities that recovered to Grade 2 within 7 days, with or without maximal supportive care; (iii) inability to administer eribulin on Day 8 in the previous cycle due to toxicity. </p><p id="p0216" num="0216"> If Grade 3 or 4 hematologic toxicities do not recover to Grade 2 in 14 days, or non- hematologic Grade 3 or 4 toxicities to Grade 2 in 7 days, the subject discontinues treatment with eribulin. However, if the subject is deemed to have clinical benefit, eribulin may be continued. </p><p id="p0217" num="0217"> Dose modification on Day 8 of each cycle: </p><p id="p0218" num="0218"> If hematologic (ANC &lt;1.0 x 109/L (l,000/mm3) or platelet count &lt;75 x 109/L (75,000/ mm3)) or non-hematologic (any &gt;Grade 2 toxicity, except for inadequately treated nausea and/or vomiting) toxicities occur on Day 8 (pre-dose), treatment with eribulin is postponed until recovery to above hematologic values and to &lt; Grade 2 for non-hematologic 
<!-- EPO <DP n="33"/>-->
 toxicities. If recovery occurs on or before Day 15, eribulin mesylate is resumed at a reduced dose of 1.1 mg/m<sup>2</sup> and this will be the new Day 8. </p><p id="p0219" num="0219"> If toxicity has not recovered to the above values on Day 15, the second administration of eribulin in the cycle is omitted. Eribulin mesylate is resumed at a reduced dose of 1.1 mg/m<sup>2</sup> and as scheduled on Day 1 of the next cycle if recovery occurs to above values. </p><p id="p0220" num="0220"> If Grade 3 or 4 hematologic toxicities do not recover to Grade 2 in 14 days, or non- hematologic Grade 3 or 4 toxicities to Grade 2 in 7 days, the subject discontinues treatment with eribulin. However, if the subject is deemed to have clinical benefit, eribulin may be continued. </p><p id="p0221" num="0221">Subsequent dose modifications: </p><p id="p0222" num="0222"> If hematological toxicity (ANC &lt;1.0 x 109/L (l,000/mm3) or platelet count &lt;75 x 109/L (75,000/ mm<sup>3</sup>)) re-occurs despite a dose reduction to 1.1 mg/ m<sup>2</sup>, and the use of hematopoietic growth factors, the dose of eribulin mesylate is further reduced to 0.7 mg/ m<sup>2</sup>. If Grade 3 or 4 non-hematological toxicity re-occurs despite the dose reduction to 1.1 mg/ m<sup>2</sup>, the eribulin mesylate dose is reduced to 0.7 mg/ m<sup>2</sup>. </p><p id="p0223" num="0223"> If Grade 3 or 4 hematologic toxicities do not recover to Grade 2 in 14 days, or non- hematologic Grade 3 or 4 toxicities to Grade 2 in 7 days following a dose reduction to 0.7 mg/m2, the subject discontinues treatment with eribulin. However, if the subject is deemed to have clinical benefit, continuation of eribulin may be considered. </p><p id="p0224" num="0224"> Farletuzumab Treatments </p><p id="p0225" num="0225"> Farletuzumab 7.5 mg/Kg is administered as an i.v. infusion on Day 1 of each 3-week cycle. However for first cycle only, 7.5 mg/Kg of farletuzumab is administered on Dl and D8. In the event of treatment delay, a dose of 2.5 mg/kg maintains adequate farletuzumab levels until resumption of the q/3 weekly dosing. </p><p id="p0226" num="0226"> Farletuzumab or placebo will be administered intravenously using an in-line, low- protein or non-protein binding 0.20 or 0.22 micron filter. Subjects should receive farletuzumab or placebo intravenously initially at 0.4 mL/min and the rate progressed as tolerated to 2 mL/minute. The suggested rate of increase is 0.4 mL/minute every 5 minutes. If 2 mL/minute is well tolerated, subsequent infusions can be started at that rate. If infusion-related adverse effects are encountered, the infusion rate is decreased by at least 50%, and then advanced back to the highest rate that is well tolerated. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="34"/>-->
 Subjects can discontinue for intolerable toxicity of farletuzumab. In the event of one week delay of the eribulin dose, a supplemental farletuzumab dose of 2.5 mg.kg maintains farletuzumab levels until resumption of the treatment. </p><p id="p0227" num="0227"> Farletuzumab is administered before administration of eribulin mesylate. If an indwelling venous access device is used, farletuzumab or placebo is administered via a different lumen than that used for blood collections whenever possible. Whenever possible, farletuzumab or placebo is administered via the most distal lumen of a multi-lumen catheter to reduce the possibility of confounding drug level analyses. </p><p id="p0228" num="0228"> Placebo Treatments </p><p id="p0229" num="0229"> Normal saline is used as placebo. Placebo is administered to the subjects in arm B just as farletuzumab is administered to the subjects in arm A. </p><p id="p0230" num="0230">Concomitant Drug/Therapy </p><p id="p0231" num="0231"> Anti-nausea/vomiting medication is allowed. All subjects are premedicated prior to farletuzumab (or placebo) infusion with acetaminophen 650-1000 mg by mouth or clinical equivalent per clinic routine. Subjects can also receive concomitant premedication in the form of primary prophylaxis for hypersensitivity and infusion-related reactions that may consist of a combination of anti-histamine agents, antipyretics, systemic steroids, and additional supportive measures as required. </p><p id="p0232" num="0232"> In the event of a drug hypersensitivity reaction believed to be associated with test article (farletuzumab or placebo) infusion, subjects can be premedicated for subsequent infusions with antipyretic or histamine receptor blocking medications (e.g., diphenhydramine, etc.), per the clinic routine, in order to reduce the incidence/severity of fluid retention and/or hypersensitivity reactions. In case of allergic reactions, the investigator institutes medically appropriate treatment measures. </p><p id="p0233" num="0233">Assessment Procedures </p><p id="p0234" num="0234"> Screening is conducted within 28 days before the start of study treatment. </p><p id="p0235" num="0235">A positive sample is defined as &gt;5 of tumour cells staining at any intensity by </p><p id="p0236" num="0236">immunohistochemistry (IHC). Subjects are screened for FRa expression by IHC (FFPE or FNA). The trial does not mandate a collection of a new biopsy for screening, so historical or newly obtained tissue sample can be used for FRa characterization. </p><p id="p0237" num="0237"> Tumor assessments consist of radiographic evaluation of the chest, abdomen, pelvis, brain and other areas of known or suspected disease. Standard of care scans that meet protocol 
<!-- EPO <DP n="35"/>-->
 imaging criteria are used as screening/baseline scans if performed within 28 days before randomization. Historic bone scans can be used if performed within 6 weeks (42 days) before randomization. </p><p id="p0238" num="0238">Efficacy Assessments </p><p id="p0239" num="0239"> Tumour assessments are performed based on RECIST 1.1. Efficacy analysis is based upon investigator's assessment. </p><p id="p0240" num="0240"> Response assessments (computed tomography [CT]/magnetic resonance imaging </p><p id="p0241" num="0241">[MRI]) are assessed by the investigator (in conjunction with the site radiologist) and entered onto the appropriate case report form (CRF). All tumour assessment scans are sent to a central imaging core laboratory for independent review. </p><p id="p0242" num="0242">Study Endpoints </p><p id="p0243" num="0243"> Study endpoints may include progression free survival (PFS), defined as the time from the date of randomization to the date of first independently confirmed objective documentation of disease progression, or date of death, whichever occurs first; objective response rate</p><p id="p0244" num="0244">(proportion of subjects who have best objective response of complete response [CR] or partial response [PR]); disease control rate (proportion of subjects who have best objective response of complete response [CR] or partial response [PR] or stable disease [SD]); dlinical benefit rate (proportion of subjects who have best objective response of CR + PR + dSD [dSD, duration of SD &gt; 12 weeks]); overall survival (measured from the date of randomization until date of death from any cause; subjects who are lost to follow-up and the subjects who are alive at the date of data cut-off will be censored at the date the subject was last known alive); </p><p id="p0245" num="0245">duration of response (period from documented response until the time of evidence of progression); time to response (period from the date of randomization until the first documented confirmed response). The study endpoints are analyzed using appropriate analysis sets and statistical methods. </p><p id="p0246" num="0246">Equivalents </p><p id="p0247" num="0247"> Those skilled in the art will recognize, or be able to ascertain using no more than routine experimentation, many equivalents to the specific embodiments of the invention described herein. Such equivalents are intended to be encompassed by the following claims. 
</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM44851196" ref-ucid="WO-2012119077-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><claim-statement><!-- EPO <DP n="36"/>--> CLAIMS </claim-statement><claim id="clm-0001" num="1"><claim-text>1. A method of treating a subject suffering from breast cancer, the method comprising: administering to said subject (a) a therapeutically effective amount of eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and (b) farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0002" num="2"><claim-text>2. The method of claim 1, wherein the breast cancer is an adenocarcinoma. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0003" num="3"><claim-text>3. The method of claim 1, wherein the breast cancer is inflammatory breast cancer. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0004" num="4"><claim-text>4. The method of claim 1, wherein the breast cancer is metastatic breast cancer. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0005" num="5"><claim-text>5. The method of claim 4, wherein the subject has previously received at least one chemotherapeutic regimen for the treatment of metastatic breast cancer. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0006" num="6"><claim-text>6. The method of claim 4, wherein the subject has previously received at least two chemotherapeutic regimens for the treatment of metastatic breast cancer. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0007" num="7"><claim-text>7. The method of claim 6, wherein the subject previously received one or more </claim-text><claim-text>chemotherapeutic regimens comprising administration of an anthracycline or a taxane or both. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0008" num="8"><claim-text>8. The method of any one of the preceding claims, wherein the breast cancer is folate receptor alpha expressing or overexpressing breast cancer. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0009" num="9"><claim-text>9. The method of claim 1 or claim 8, wherein said breast cancer is a HER2 negative breast cancer. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0010" num="10"><claim-text>10. The method of claim 1 or claim 8, wherein said breast cancer is a HER2 positive breast cancer. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0011" num="11"><claim-text>11. The method of claim 9, wherein said breast cancer is ER negative and PR negative. <!-- EPO <DP n="37"/>--> </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0012" num="12"><claim-text>12. The method of claim 9, wherein said breast cancer is ER negative and PR positive; ER positive and PR positive; or ER positive and PR negative. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0013" num="13"><claim-text>13. The method of claim 8, wherein the breast cancer is ER negative, PR negative and HER2 negative breast cancer. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0014" num="14"><claim-text>14. The method of claim 11 or 12, wherein the breast cancer is refractory to a hormonal therapy. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0015" num="15"><claim-text>15. The method of claim 9 or 10, wherein the breast cancer is ER negative and PR positive; ER positive and PR positive; or ER positive and PR negative; and is refractory to a hormonal therapy. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0016" num="16"><claim-text>16. The method of claim 14 or 15, wherein the hormonal therapy is therapy with tamoxifen or an aromatase inhibitor. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0017" num="17"><claim-text>17. The method of claim 1, wherein eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof, are administered intercurrently. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0018" num="18"><claim-text>18. The method of claim 1, wherein tumor growth in the subject is inhibited. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0019" num="19"><claim-text>19. The method of claim 1, wherein administration of eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof, results in tumor regression in the subject. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0020" num="20"><claim-text>20. The method of claim 1, wherein administration of eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof, results in complete tumor regression in the subject. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0021" num="21"><claim-text>21. The method of claim 1, wherein said eribulin or pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof is administered to the subject from one to three times about every 14-35 days. <!-- EPO <DP n="38"/>--> </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0022" num="22"><claim-text>22. The method of claim 1, wherein said eribulin or pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof is administered to the subject at least once every 21-28 days. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0023" num="23"><claim-text>23. The method of claim 22, wherein said eribulin or pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof is administered to the subject on day 1 and day 8 of a 21-28 day cycle. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0024" num="24"><claim-text>24. The method of claim 23, wherein said farletuzumab or antigen-binding fragment thereof is administered to the subject on day 1 of a 21-28 day cycle. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0025" num="25"><claim-text>25. The method of claim 22, wherein said eribulin or pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof is administered to the subject on day 1 and day 8 of a 21 -day cycle. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0026" num="26"><claim-text>26. The method of claim 25, wherein said farletuzumab or antigen-binding fragment thereof is administered on day 1 of a 21 -day cycle. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0027" num="27"><claim-text>27. The method of claim 26, wherein said farletuzumab or antigen-binding fragment thereof is administered to the subject immediately after administration of eribulin, or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0028" num="28"><claim-text>28. The method of claim 26, wherein said eribulin or pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof is administered to the subject after administration of said farletuzumab or antigen- binding fragment thereof on day 1. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0029" num="29"><claim-text>29. The method of claim 23, wherein said farletuzumab or antigen-binding fragment thereof is administered to the subject once per week. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0030" num="30"><claim-text>30. The method of claim 1, wherein said eribulin or pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof is administered to the subject in an amount from about 0.5 mg/m<sup>2</sup> to about 3.0 mg/m<sup>2</sup>. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0031" num="31"><claim-text>31. The method of claim 20, wherein said eribulin, or pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof is administered to the subject in an amount from about 0.7 mg/m<sup>2</sup> to about 2.0 mg/m<sup>2</sup>. <!-- EPO <DP n="39"/>--> </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0032" num="32"><claim-text>32. The method of any one of claims 23-25, wherein said eribulin, or pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof is administered to the subject in an amount of 1.4 mg/m<sup>2</sup>. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0033" num="33"><claim-text>33. The method of claim 23, wherein the subject has mild hepatic impairment, and said eribulin or pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof is administered to the subject in an amount of 1.1 mg/m<sup>2</sup>. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0034" num="34"><claim-text>34. The method of claim 23, wherein the subject has moderate hepatic impairment, and said eribulin, or pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof is administered to the subject in an amount of 0.7 mg/m<sup>2</sup>. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0035" num="35"><claim-text>35. The method of claim 1, wherein said eribulin or pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof is administered to the subject intravenously. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0036" num="36"><claim-text>36. The method of claim 1, wherein said farletuzumab or antigen-binding fragment thereof is administered to the subject in an amount from about 0.5 mg/kg to about 4.0 mg/kg once a week. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0037" num="37"><claim-text>37. The method of claim 36, wherein said farletuzumab or antigen-binding fragment thereof is administered to the subject in an amount from about 1.0 mg/kg to about 3.0 mg/kg once a week. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0038" num="38"><claim-text>38. The method of claim 36, wherein said farletuzumab or antigen-binding fragment thereof is administered to the subject in an amount of about 2.5 mg/kg once a week. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0039" num="39"><claim-text>39. The method of claim 1, wherein said farletuzumab or antigen-binding fragment thereof is administered to the subject in an amount of about 3.00 mg/kg to about 9.00 mg/kg triweekly. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0040" num="40"><claim-text>40. The method of claim 39, wherein said farletuzumab or antigen-binding fragment thereof is administered to the subject in an amount of about 7.50 mg/kg. <!-- EPO <DP n="40"/>--> </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0041" num="41"><claim-text>41. The method of claim 1, wherein eribulin or pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and farletuzumab or antigen-binding fragment thereof, are administered to the subject intravenously. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0042" num="42"><claim-text>42. The method of claim 1, wherein said eribulin or pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, is eribulin mesylate. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0043" num="43"><claim-text>43. The method of claim 1, wherein farletuzumab is administered. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0044" num="44"><claim-text>44. The method of claim 1, wherein eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof, and farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof, are administered to the subject as a second or later line therapy against the cancer. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0045" num="45"><claim-text>45. A method of treating a subject suffering from breast cancer, the method comprising: administering to said subject (a) eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof on day 1 and day 8 of a 21-28 day cycle, and (b) farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof on day 1 of said 21-28 day cycle. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0046" num="46"><claim-text>46. The method of claim 45, further comprising administering to said subject at least one loading dose of farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof during a first 21-28 day cycle. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0047" num="47"><claim-text>47. The method of claim 46, wherein farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof is administered on day 1 and day 8 of said first cycle. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0048" num="48"><claim-text>48. A method of treating a subject suffering from breast cancer, the method comprising: administering to said subject </claim-text><claim-text> (a) eribulin or a pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof on day 1 and day 8 of a 21-28 day cycle, and </claim-text><claim-text> (b) farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof <!-- EPO <DP n="41"/>--> (i) on day 1 and day 8 of a first 21-28 day cycle, and </claim-text><claim-text> (ii) on day 1 of each subsequent 21-28 daycycle. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0049" num="49"><claim-text>49. The method of any one of claims 45-48, wherein said cycle is a 21 day cycle. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0050" num="50"><claim-text>50. The method of any one of claims 45-48, wherein said eribulin or pharmaceutically acceptable salt thereof and said farletuzumab or an antigen-binding fragment thereof are administered intravenously. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0051" num="51"><claim-text>51. The method of any of the preceding claims, wherein a pharmaceutically acceptable salt of eribulin is administered, which is eribulin mesylate. </claim-text></claim></claims><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
