<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2036649-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2036649" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="40149694" file-reference-id="299957" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146588696" ucid="EP-2036649-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2036649</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-08164179-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154850888" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>08164179</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20080911</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140556371" ucid="US-20753408-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>20753408</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20080910</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140547121" ucid="US-97209107-P" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>97209107</doc-number><kind>P</kind><date>20070913</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130807</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989326384" load-source="ipcr">B23K  11/31        20060101AFI20090119BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989652509" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B23K  11/314       20130101 FI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370721" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Universelle Schweisszangenkonfiguration</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370722" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Universal weld gun configuration</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370723" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Configuration de pistolet de soudage universelle</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919537432" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>COMAU INC</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919541971" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>COMAU, INC.</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919527515" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>KILIBARDA VELIBOR</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919517960" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>KILIBARDA, VELIBOR</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919024317" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>KILIBARDA, VELIBOR</last-name><address><street>600 West Brown Street Unit 209</street><city>Birmingham, MI 48009</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919024319" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Comau, Inc.</last-name><iid>101001398</iid><address><street>21000 Telegraph Road</street><city>Southfield, MI 48033</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919024318" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Notaro, Giancarlo</last-name><iid>100024738</iid><address><street>Buzzi, Notaro &amp; Antonielli d'Oulx Via Maria Vittoria 18</street><city>10123 Torino</city><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549804990" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549882988" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549879262" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549787909" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549882989" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549895623" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549872831" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549882994" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549882995" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549789384" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549879263" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549879264" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549872832" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549882996" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549872833" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549895624" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549787910" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549882997" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549879265" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549883002" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549872838" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549804991" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549879270" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549872839" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549804996" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549789389" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549925114" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549789390" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549804997" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549787911" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549789391" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549895629" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549925115" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549879271" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63961115" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><p id="p0001" num="0001">This invention relates to weld guns and more specifically to a single weld gun design that will accommodate both X axis and Y axis weld gun configurations as well as the entire spectrum of weld gun arm orientations from 0 to 90 degrees between the horizontal and vertical configurations.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002">Weld guns typically have a design that is dedicated to a particular axis configuration, most typically an X axis configuration or a Y axis configuration, and typically cannot be converted from one axis configuration to another axis configuration without a substantial tear-up of the gun involving an expenditure oftime and money rendering the conversion impractical. Since many welding applications, including motor vehicle body shop welding applications, require weld guns having a variety of weld gun axes, conventional, dedicated weld gun designs require maintaining a large inventory of various weld axis configurations.</p><heading id="h0001"><u>Summary of the invention</u></heading><p id="p0003" num="0003">The invention relates to a method and apparatus for providing a weld gun that is readily convertible between a plurality of weld gun axes, <b>as set forth in independent claims 1 and 9</b>.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p><p id="p0004" num="0004">Further features of the invention <b>are disclosed in the dependent claims</b>.</p><heading id="h0002"><u>Brief description of the drawings</u></heading><p id="p0005" num="0005">The description herein makes reference to the accompanying drawings wherein like reference numerals refer to like parts throughout the several views, and wherein:
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is a side elevational view showing the invention weld gun outfitted with a horizontal or X axis weld gun configuration;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> is a side elevational view showing the invention weld gun outfitted with a vertical or Y axis weld gun configuration;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> is a perspective view of the invention weld gun showing, for schematic illustrative purposes only, the weld gun outfitted with both a horizontal (phantom line) and vertical (solid line) weld gun configuration;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4</figref> is a side elevational view of the invention weld gun showing, again for schematic illustrative purposes only, the weld gun outfitted with both a horizontal</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 5</figref> is a side elevationel view showing, again for schematic illustrative<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> purposes only, the invention weld gun equipped with both a horizontal (phantom line) and a vertical (solid line) gun configuration, and further illustrating the ability of the gun to accommodate an intermediate (phantom line) weld gun configuration.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0003"><u>Detailed description of the preferred embodiment</u></heading><p id="p0006" num="0006">The invention weld gun includes a weld gun body comprising spaced side plates 10 of generally rectangular configuration interconnected by suitable reinforcing and spacing members 11; a transformer 12 positioned between the side plates between the reinforcing and spacing members 11; an actuator 14 (either hydraulic or pneumatic) pivotally mounted at 15 to an upper region of the weld plates between the weld plates and a weld arm assembly 16.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">The weld arm assembly 16 includes a movable or pivotal arm 18 and a fixed arm 20.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">Pivotal arm 18 includes a first arm segment in the form of spaced bellcranks 22 and a second arm segment 24.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">The bellcranks 22 forming the first arm segment are pivotally secured at their upper ends 22a by a pivot pin 23' to the free end of piston rod 14a of actuator 14 and are pivotally mounted at their lower ends 22b by a pivot pin 23' to a lower region of side plates 10 between the plates.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">Second arm segment 24 comprises a flat bar member having an inboard end 24a fixedly but removably positioned between the intermediate portions 22c of bellcranks 22 utilizing rectangularly spaced bolts or dowels 26. A weld tip 28 is fixedly secured to the outboard end 24b of arm segment 24.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">The inboard end 20a of fixed arm 20 is fixedly secured to and between a lower region of spaced plates 10 utilizing rectangularly spaced bolts or dowels 30. A weld tip 32 is fixedly secured to the outboard end 20b of arm 20.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">A first flexible shunt 34 ofU configuration extends from transformer 12 to arm segment 24 and a second shunt 36 of S configuration extends from transformer 12 to arm 20.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">Shunt 34 includes an inboard end 34a suitably electrically connected to the inboard face 12a of transformer 12 and an outboard end 34b electrically connected to inboard end edge face 24c of arm segment 24 utilizing, for example, an electrically conductive fastener 37.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">Shunt 36 includes an inboard end 36a suitably electrically connected to transformer inboard face 12a and an outboard end 36b electrically connected to inboard end edge face 20c of arm 20 utilizing, for example, an electrically conductive<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> fastener 38.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">With this arrangement, as best seen in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> illustrating a horizontal or X-axis weld gun configuration, arm segment 24 and arm 20 extend horizontally in parallel relation from body 10 and suitable actuation of actuator 14 moves moveable arm 18 about the axis of pin 23 between the solid line position of <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> and the dotted line position of <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> to facilitate an X-axis welding operation with the arm movement facilitated by flexing of the shunt 34.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">To convert the weld gun from the X axis configuration seen in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> to the Y axis configuration seen in <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref>, bolts or dowels 26 and 30 are removed; fastener 37 is loosened to electrically disconnect the outboard end 34b of shunt 34 from end edge face 24c of arm segment 24; fastener 38 is loosened to electrically disconnect the outboard end 36b of shunt 36 from the end edge face 20c of arm 20; arm segment 24 is separated from arm segment 22; arm 20 is separated from body 10; the inboard end 24a of arm segment 24 is secured to body 10 utilizing bolts or dowels 30 with the arm segment extending vertically downwardly with respect to the body 10; fastener 38 is tightened to electrically connect the outboard end 36b of shunt 36 to outside edge 24d of arm segment 24; the inboard end of arm 20 is secured to the intermediate portion 22c of bellcranks 22 utilizing bolts or dowels 26 with the arm extending vertically downwardly with respect to the body 10 in parallel relation to arm segment 24 to position weld tips 28/32 in opposing relation; and fastener 37 is tightened to electrically connect the outboard end 34b of shunt 34 to side edge 20c of arm 20.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">The conversion from X axis configuration to Y axis configuration will be seen to essentially involve interchanging the arm 20 and the arm segment 24 and rotating arm 20 and arm segment 24 90° with respect to their X axis configuration, while turning each arm over to place the weld tips 28/32 in confronting relationship. With this Y axis configuration, suitable actuation of actuator 14 moves arm 20 about the axis of pin 23 between the solid line position of <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref> and the dotted line of <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref>.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">Note that the conversion of the weld gun from an X axis configuration to a Y axis configuration has been achieved by simply removing the bolts or dowels 26/30, disconnecting the shunts, exchanging the arm segment 24 for the arm 20, reconnecting the bolts or dowels, and reconnecting the shunts. The conversion has not required any tear-up of the weld gun and, more specifically, the mounting of the actuator on the body has not been disturbed, the connection of the actuator to the arm segment 22 has not been disturbed, the mounting of the transformer on the body has not been<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> disturbed, and the electrical connection of the shunts to the transformer has not been disturbed.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019"><figref idrefs="f0003">Figures 3</figref>, <figref idrefs="f0004">4</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0005">5</figref> illustrate, for schematic illustrative purposes only, the manner in which the same weld gun body is able to accommodate both a horizontal gun assembly and a vertical gun assembly. <figref idrefs="f0005">Figure 5</figref> further illustrates the manner in which the weld gun design of the invention is able to accommodate not only a horizontal or X axis weld gun configuration and a vertical or Y axis weld gun configuration, but also weld gun configurations positioned at intermediate positions between the X axis and the Y axis configurations. For example, it will be seen that the weld gun arm intermediate configuration seen in <figref idrefs="f0005">Figure 5</figref> can be readily accomplished, without interchanging arm segment 24 and arm 20, simply by customizing the inboard ends of the arm segment 24 and arm 20 to suitably receive the bolts or dowels 26/30 and to suitably mate with the outboard ends of the shunts so that the shunts need not be modified to accommodate any specific weld gun orientation, but rather the same shunts may be used to accommodate all weld gun arm orientations either horizontal, vertical or any position in between.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">The invention will be seen to provide an apparatus and methodology for readily converting a weld gun from an X axis configuration to a Y axis configuration, thereby eliminating the need to maintain a separate inventory of X axis and Y axis weld guns.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">In accordance with the provisions of the patent statutes, the present invention has been described in what is considered to represent its preferred embodiment. However, it should be noted that the invention can be practiced otherwise than as specifically illustrated and described without departing from the scope of the claims.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56986085" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Verfahren zum Bewerkstelligen einer Umkonfiguration einer Schweißzange von einer ersten Schweißzangenachse zu einer zweiten Schweißzangenachse, wobei die Schweißzange einen Körper (10), ein Stellglied (14), ein erstes Armglied (20) mit einer ersten Schweißspitze (32) und ein zweites Armglied (24) mit einer zweiten Schweißspitze (28) umfasst, wobei das Verfahren umfasst:
<claim-text>entfernbares Verbinden der Armglieder (20, 24) der Schweißzange mit dem Rest der Schweißzange, und</claim-text>
<claim-text>während die Armglieder (20, 24) mit einem ersten Winkel in Bezug auf den Rest der Schweißzange konfiguriert sind, um die erste Schweißzangenachse vorzusehen, Entfernen der Armglieder (20, 24) von dem Rest der Schweißzange und Wechseln der Armglieder (20, 24), wobei die gewechselten Armglieder entfernbar mit einem zweiten, anderen Winkel in Bezug auf den Rest der Schweißzange positioniert werden, um die zweite Schweißzangenachse vorzusehen,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei die Konfiguration für die erste Schweißzangenachse und die Konfiguration für die zweite Schweißzangenachse entlang von zueinander orthogonalen Achsen ausgerichtet sind.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, das weiterhin einen Schritt zum Ausbilden des zweiten Armglieds (24) mit einer anderen Länge als das erste Armglied (20) umfasst, derart dass die Schweißspitzen (32, 28) in beiden Schweißzangenachsen nebeneinander positioniert werden können.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, das weiterhin die folgenden Schritte umfasst:
<claim-text>schwenkbares Montieren eines Hebelglieds (22) an dem Körper (10),</claim-text>
<claim-text>Verbinden des Hebelglieds (22) mit dem Stellglied (14), und</claim-text>
<claim-text>fixes, aber entfernbares Verbinden des ersten Armglieds (20) mit dem Körper (10) und des zweiten Armglieds (24) mit dem Hebelglied (22).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 3, das weiterhin die folgenden Schritte umfasst:<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> -->
<claim-text>Verbinden eines Endes (22a) des Hebelglieds (22) mit dem Stellglied (14),</claim-text>
<claim-text>schwenkbares Montieren eines anderen Endes (22b) des Hebelglieds (22) an dem Körper (10), und</claim-text>
<claim-text>entfernbares Verbinden eines von der zweiten Schweißspitze (28) fernen Endes (24a) des zweiten Armglieds (24) mit einer mittleren Position des Hebelglieds (22).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, wobei das entfernbare Verbinden der Armglieder (20, 24) der Schweißzange mit dem Rest der Schweißzange umfasst:
<claim-text>fixes, aber entfernbares Anbringen eines Endes des ersten Armglieds (20a) an dem Körper (10),</claim-text>
<claim-text>Verbinden eines Endes (22a) eines Hebelglieds (22) mit dem Stellglied (14),</claim-text>
<claim-text>schwenkbares Montieren eines anderen Endes (22b) des Hebelglieds (22) an dem Körper (10), und</claim-text>
<claim-text>fixes, aber entfernbares Anbringen eines Endes (24a) des zweiten Armglieds (24) an einem mittleren Teil (22c) des Hebelglieds (22),</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei das Entfernen der Armglieder (20, 24) von dem Rest der Schweißzange und das Wechseln der Armglieder umfassen:
<claim-text>ohne die Verbindung des Hebelglieds (22) mit dem Stellglied (14) zu stören:
<claim-text>Entfernen des ersten Armglieds (20) von dem Körper (10),</claim-text>
<claim-text>Entfernen des zweiten Armglieds (24) von dem Hebelglied (22),</claim-text>
<claim-text>Montieren des zweiten Armglieds (24) an dem Körper (10) anstelle des ersten Armglieds (20), aber mit einem anderen Winkel in Bezug auf den Körper (10), und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Montieren des ersten Armglieds (20) an dem Hebelglied (22) anstelle des zweiten Armglieds (24), aber mit einem anderen Winkel in Bezug auf das Hebelglied (22) und allgemein parallel zu dem zweiten Armglied (24).</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 5, wobei das Verfahren weiterhin einen Schritt zum Ausbilden des zweiten Armglieds (24) kürzer als das erste Armglied (20) umfasst, derart dass die<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> Schweißspitzen (32, 28) in beiden Schweißzangenachsen nebeneinander positioniert werden können.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, das weiterhin umfasst:
<claim-text>Montieren des Stellglieds (14) an dem Körper (10),</claim-text>
<claim-text>Bewerkstelligen einer Bewegung der Schweißspitzen (32, 28) zu Positionen auf gegenüberliegenden Flächen eines Werkstücks, indem das Stellglied betätigt wird, um eine relative Bewegung der Armglieder (20, 24) zu veranlassen, und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Tragen eines Transformators (12) an dem Körper (10),</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei das entfernbare Verbinden der Armglieder (20, 24) mit dem Rest der Schweißzange umfasst:
<claim-text>elektrisches Verbinden eines ersten Endes (36a) eines ersten Nebenschlusses (36) mit dem Transformator (12) und eines zweiten Endes (36b) des ersten Nebenschlusses (36) mit einer ersten Kantenfläche (20c) des ersten Armglieds (20), und</claim-text>
<claim-text>elektrisches Verbinden eines ersten Endes (34a) eines zweiten Nebenschlusses (34) mit dem Transformator (12) und eines zweiten Endes (34b) des zweiten Nebenschlusses (34) mit einer ersten Kantenfläche (24c) des zweiten Armglieds (24),</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei das Entfernen der Armglieder (20, 24) von dem Rest der Schweißzange und das Wechseln der Armglieder umfassen:
<claim-text>Trennen der Armglieder (20, 24) von dem Körper (10),</claim-text>
<claim-text>Trennen der zweiten Enden (36b, 34b) der Nebenschlüsse (36, 34) von den ersten Kantenflächen (20c, 24c) der Armglieder (20, 24),</claim-text>
<claim-text>erneutes Verbinden der Armglieder (20, 24) mit dem Körper (10) mit dem zweiten Winkel zu dem Körper (10),</claim-text>
<claim-text>Verbinden der zweiten Enden der Nebenschlüsse (36b, 34b) mit zweiten Kantenflächen (20d, 24d) der Armglieder (20, 24), die neben den ersten Kantenflächen (20c, 24c), aber mit Winkeln in Bezug auf die ersten Kantenflächen angeordnet sind.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 7, wobei das Wechseln der Armglieder (20, 24) das Wechseln der ersten und zweiten Armglieder vor dem erneuten Verbinden der Armglieder mit dem Körper umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Schweißzange, die einen Schweißzangenkörper (10), einen ersten Schweißarm (20) mit einer ersten Schweißspitze (32), einen zweiten Schweißarm (18) einschließlich eines Armsegments (24) mit einer zweiten Schweißspitze (28), ein Stellglied (14), das an dem Körper (10) montiert ist und betätigt werden kann, um eine relative Bewegung der Schweißarme (20, 18) zu veranlassen, um eine Bewegung der Schweißspitzen (32, 28) zu Positionen an gegenüberliegenden Flächen eines Werkstücks zu bewerkstelligen, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b>:
<claim-text>die Schweißzange Montageaufbauten umfasst, die derart betätigt werden können, dass der erste Schweißarm (20) und das Armsegment (24) an der Schweißzange wahlweise an einer ersten Position montiert werden können, an welcher sie sich allgemein parallel zueinander in einer ersten Richtung relativ zu dem Körper (10) erstrecken, um eine erste Schweißzangenachse zu erzielen, oder an einer zweiten Position, an welcher sie sich allgemein parallel zueinander in einer zweiten, anderen Richtung relativ zu dem Körper (10) erstrecken, um eine zweite, andere Schweißzangenachse zu erzielen,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei die ersten und zweiten Richtungen entlang von zueinander orthogonalen Achsen verlaufen oder eine beliebige andere Ausrichtung zueinander aufweisen.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Schweißzange nach Anspruch 9, wobei:
<claim-text>das Stellglied (14) operativ mit dem zweiten Schweißarm (18) verbunden ist und betätigt werden kann, um den zweiten Schweißarm (18) relativ zu dem ersten Schweißarm (20) zu bewegen, und</claim-text>
<claim-text>die Verbindung des Stellglieds (14) mit dem zweiten Schweißarm (18) unabhängig davon, ob sich der erste Schweißarm (20) und das Armsegment (24) an ihrer ersten Position oder an ihrer zweiten Position befinden, identisch ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Schweißzange nach Anspruch 9, wobei:
<claim-text>das Armsegment (24) ein zweites Armsegment ist,<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>der zweite Schweißarm (18) weiterhin ein erstes Armsegment (22) umfasst, das an einem Ende (22b) schwenkbar an dem Körper (10) montiert ist und an einem anderen Ende (22a) mit dem Stellglied (14) verbunden ist, und</claim-text>
<claim-text>das zweite Segment (24) neben einem Ende (24a) entfernbar mit dem ersten Armsegment (22) zwischen den Enden (22a, 22b) des ersten Armsegments (22) verbunden ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Schweißzange nach Anspruch 11, wobei, wenn sich der erste Schweißarm (20) und das zweite Armsegment (24) an ihren ersten Positionen befinden, sich das zweite Armsegment (24) von dem ersten Armsegment (22) mit einem ersten Winkel erstreckt, und wenn sich der erste Schweißarm (20) und das zweite Armsegment (24) an ihren zweiten Positionen befinden, sich das zweite Armsegment (24) von dem Körper (10) mit einem zweiten, anderen Winkel erstreckt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Schweißzange nach Anspruch 12, wobei der erste Schweißarm (20) fix, aber entfernbar an dem Körper (10) montiert ist und sich an seiner ersten Position von dem Körper (10) mit einem ersten Winkel parallel zu dem zweiten Armsegment (24) erstreckt und sich an seiner zweiten Position von dem ersten Armsegment (22) mit einem zweiten, anderen Winkel parallel zu dem zweiten Armsegment (24) erstreckt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Schweißzange nach Anspruch 9, wobei der Montageaufbau betätigt werden kann, um zu gestatten, dass der erste Schweißarm (20) und das Armsegment (24) gewechselt werden, sodass, um die zweite Schweißzangenachse ausgehend von der Schweißzange in der ersten Schweißzangenachse zu erzielen, das Armsegment (24) anstelle des ersten Schweißarms (20), aber mit einem anderen Winkel relativ zu dem Körper (10) positioniert wird und der erste Schweißarm (20) anstelle des Armsegments (24), aber mit einem anderen Winkel relativ zu dem Körper (10) positioniert wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Schweißzange nach Anspruch 11, wobei das zweite Armsegment (24) kürzer als der erste Schweißarm (20) ist, wobei, um eine andere Schweißzangenachse zu erzielen, ohne die Verbindung des Stellglieds (14) mit dem ersten Armsegment (22) zu stören, das zweite Armsegment (24) von dem ersten Armsegment (22) entfernt werden kann, wobei der erste Schweißarm (20) von dem Körper (10) entfernt und an dem ersten Armsegment (22) anstelle des zweiten Armsegments (24), aber mit einem anderen Winkel in Bezug auf das erste Armsegment (22) montiert wird und wobei das zweite Armsegment (24) an dem Körper (10) anstelle des ersten Schweißarms (20), aber mit einem anderen Winkel in Bezug<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> auf den Körper (10) in einer allgemein parallelen Beziehung zu dem ersten Armsegment (22) montiert wird.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56986086" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A method of facilitating conversion of the weld gun from a first axis gun to a second axis gun wherein the weld gun includes a body (10), an actuator (14), a first arm member (20) carrying a first weld tip (32) and a second arm member (24) carrying a second weld tip (28), the method comprising:
<claim-text>removably connecting the arm embers (20,24) of the gun to the remainder of the gun; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>with the arm members (20,24) configured at a first angle with respect to the remainder of the gun to provide the first axis gun, removing the arm members (20,24) from the remainder of the gun and interchanging the arm members (20,24) with the interchanged arm members removably positioned at a second, different angle with respect to the remainder of the gun to provide the second axis gun,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said first axis gun configuration and said second axis gun configuration are along mutually orthogonal axes.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>A method according to claim 1 including the further step of forming the second arm member (24) of a different length than the first arm member (20) by an extent to allow the weld tips (32,28) to be positioned proximate one another in either axis of the weld gun.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>A method according to claim 1 including the further steps of:
<claim-text>pivotally mounting a bellcrank member (22) on the body (10);</claim-text>
<claim-text>connecting the bellcrank member (22) to the actuator (14); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>fixedly but removably connecting the first arm member (20) to the body (10) and the second arm member (24) to the bellcrank member (22).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>A method according to claim 3 including the further steps of:
<claim-text>connecting one end (22a) of the bellcrank member (22) to the actuator (14);</claim-text>
<claim-text>pivotally mounting another end (22b) of the bellcrank member (22) to the body (22); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>removably connecting an end (24a) of the second arm member (24) remote from the second weld tip (28) to an intermediate location on the bellcrank member (22).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>A method according to claim 1 wherein removably connecting the arm members (20,24) of the gun to the remainder of the gun includes:
<claim-text>fixedly but removably attaching one end of the first arm member (20a) to the body (10);</claim-text>
<claim-text>connecting one end (22a) of a bellcrank member (22) to the actuator (14);<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>pivotally mounting another end of the bellcrank member (22b) on the body (10); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>fixedly but removably attaching one end (24a) of the second arm member (24) to an intermediate portion (22c) of the bellcrank member (22); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein removing the arm members (20,24) from the remainder of the gun and interchanging the arm members includes:
<claim-text>without disturbing the connection of the bellcrank member (22) to the actuator (14):
<claim-text>removing the first arm member (20) from the body (10);</claim-text>
<claim-text>removing the second arm member (24) from the bellcrank member (22);</claim-text>
<claim-text>mounting the second arm member (24) on the body (10) in place of the first arm member (20) but at a different angle with respect to the body (10); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>mounting the first arm member (20) on the bellcrank member (22) in place of the second arm member (24) but at a different angle with respect to the bellcrank member (22), and in generally parallel relation to the second arm member (24).</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>A method according to claim 5 wherein the method includes the further step of forming the second arm member (24) shorter than the first arm member (20) by an extent to allow the weld tips (32,28) to be positioned proximate one another in either axis of the weld gun.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>A method according to claim 1 further comprising:
<claim-text>mounting the actuator (14) on the body (10);</claim-text>
<claim-text>facilitating movement of the weld tips (32,28) to positions on opposite faces of a work piece by operating the actuator to impart relative movement to the arm members (20,24); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>carrying a transformer (12) with the body (10);</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein removably connecting the arm members (20,24) to the remainder of the gun includes:
<claim-text>electrically connecting a first end (36a) of a first shunt (36) to the transformer (12) and a second end (36b) of the first shunt (36) to a first edge face (20c) of the first arm member (20); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>electrically connecting a first end (34a) of a second shunt (34) to the transformer (12) and a second end (34b) of the second shunt (34) to a first edge face (24c) of the second arm member (24); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein removing the arm members (20,24) from the remainder of the gun and interchanging the arm members includes:<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> -->
<claim-text>disconnecting the arm members (20,24) from the body (10);</claim-text>
<claim-text>disconnecting the second ends (36b,34b) of the shunts (36,34) from the first edge faces (20c,24c) of the arm members (20,24);</claim-text>
<claim-text>reconnecting the arm members (20,24) to the body (10) at the second angle to the body (10);</claim-text>
<claim-text>connecting the second ends of the shunts (36b,34b) to second edge faces (20d.24d) of the arm members (20.24) that are proximate the first edges faces (20c.24c) but at angles with respect to the first edge faces.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>A method according to claim 7 wherein interchanging the arm members (20.24) includes interchanging the first and second arm members prior to reconnecting the arm members to the body.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>A weld gun comprising a weld gun body (10), a first weld arm (20) carrying a first weld tip (32), a second weld arm (18) including an arm segment (24) carrying a second weld tip (28), an actuator (14) mounted on the body (10) and operative to impart relative movement to the weld arms (20,18) to facilitate movement of the weld tips (32,28) to positions on opposite faces of a work piece, <b>characterized in that</b>:
<claim-text>the gun includes mounting structures operative to allow the first weld arm (20) and the arm segment (24) to be selectively mounted on the gun in a first position in generally parallel relation to each another and extending in a first direction relative to the body (10) to achieve a first weld gun axis and a second position in generally parallel relation to each other and extending in a second, different direction relative to the body (10) to achieve a second, different weld gun axis,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said first and second directions are along mutually orthogonal axes or along any directions in between.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>A weld gun according to claim 9 wherein:
<claim-text>the actuator (14) is operatively connected to the second weld arm (18) and is operative to move the second weld arm (18) relative to the first weld arm (20); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the connection of the actuator (14) to the second weld arm (18) is identical, irrespective of whether the first weld arm (20) and the arm segment (24) are in their first position or their second position.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>A weld gun according to claim 9 wherein:
<claim-text>the arm segment (24) comprises a second arm segment;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second weld arm (18) further includes a first arm segment (22)<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> pivotally mounted at one end (22b) thereof on the body (10) and connected to another end (22a) thereof to the actuator (14); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second segment (24) is removably secured proximate one end (24a) thereof to the first arm segment (22) intermediate the ends (22a,22b) of the first arm segment (22).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>A weld gun according to claim 11 wherein, with the first weld arm (20) and the second arm segment (24) in their first positions, the second segment (24) extends from the first arm segment (22) at a first angle and in the second positions of the first weld arm (20) and the second arm segment (24), the second arm segment (24) extends from the body (10) at a second, different angle.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>A weld gun according to claim 12 wherein the first weld arm (20) is fixedly but removably mounted on the body (10) and in its first position extends from the body (10) at a first angle in parallel relation to the second arm segment (24) and in its second position extends from the first arm segment (22) at a second different angle in parallel relation to the second arm segment (22).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>A weld gun according to claim 9 wherein the mounting structures are operative to allow the first weld arm (20) and the arm segment (24) to be interchanged so that, to achieve the second weld gun axis with the weld gun in the first weld gun axis, the arm segment (24) is positioned in place of the first weld arm (20) but at a different angle relative to the body (10) and the first weld arm (20) is positioned in place of the arm segment (24) but at a different angle relative to the body (10).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>A weld gun according to claim 11, wherein the second arm segment (24) is shorter than the first arm (20) whereby, to achieve a different weld axis without disturbing the connection of the actuator (14) to the first arm segment (22), the second arm segment (24) may be removed from the first arm segment (22), the first arm (20) removed from the body (10) and mounted on the first arm segment (22) in place of the second arm segment (24) but at a different angle with respect to the first arm segment (22), and the second arm segment (24) mounted on the body (10) in place of the first arm (20) but at a different angle with respect to the body (10) in generally parallel relation to the first arm segment (22).</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56986087" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Procédé pour faciliter la conversion du pistolet de soudage d'un pistolet de premier axe à un pistolet de second axe, dans lequel le pistolet de soudage comprend un corps (10), un actionneur (14), un premier élément de bras (20) portant une première pointe de soudage (32) et un second élément de bras (24) portant une seconde pointe de soudage (28), le procédé comprenant les étapes consistant à :
<claim-text>raccorder de manière amovible les éléments de bras (20, 24) du pistolet au reste du pistolet; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>avec les éléments de bras (20, 24) configurés selon un premier angle par rapport au reste du pistolet pour fournir le pistolet de premier axe, retirer les éléments de bras (20, 24) du reste du pistolet et interchanger les éléments de bras (20, 24) avec les éléments de bras interchangés positionnés de manière amovible selon un second angle différent par rapport au reste du pistolet pour fournir le pistolet de second axe,</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel ladite configuration de pistolet de premier axe et ladite configuration de pistolet de second axe sont le long d'axes mutuellement orthogonaux.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, comprenant l'étape supplémentaire consistant à former le second élément de bras (24) avec une longueur différente du premier élément de bras (20) selon une étendue qui permet aux pointes de soudage (32, 28) d'être positionnées à proximité l'une de l'autre dans chaque axe du pistolet de soudage.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, comprenant les étapes supplémentaires consistant à:
<claim-text>monter de manière pivotante un élément de levier coudé (22) sur le corps (10);</claim-text>
<claim-text>raccorder l'élément de levier coudé (22) à l'actionneur (14); et</claim-text>
<claim-text>raccorder de manière de fixe mais amovible le premier élément de bras (20) au corps (10) et le second élément de bras (24) à l'élément de levier coudé (22).</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 3, comprenant les étapes supplémentaires consistant à:
<claim-text>raccorder une extrémité (22a) de l'élément de levier coudé (22) à l'actionneur (14);</claim-text>
<claim-text>monter de manière pivotante une autre extrémité (22b) de l'élément de levier coudé (22) sur le corps (10); et</claim-text>
<claim-text>raccorder de manière amovible une extrémité (24a) du second élément de bras (24) à distance de la seconde pointe de soudage (28) à un emplacement intermédiaire sur l'élément de levier coudé (22).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, dans lequel l'étape consistant à raccorder de manière amovible les éléments de bras (20, 24) du pistolet au reste du pistolet comprend les étapes consistant à:
<claim-text>fixer de manière fixe mais amovible une extrémité du premier élément de bras (20a) sur le corps (10);</claim-text>
<claim-text>raccorder une extrémité (22a) d'un élément de levier coudé (22) à l'actionneur (14);</claim-text>
<claim-text>monter de manière pivotante une autre extrémité (22b) de l'élément de levier coudé (22) sur le corps (10); et</claim-text>
<claim-text>fixer de manière fixe mais amovible une extrémité (24a) du second élément de bras (24) à une partie intermédiaire (22c) de l'élément de levier coudé (22); et</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel l'étape consistant à retirer les éléments de bras (20, 24) du reste du pistolet et interchanger les éléments de bras comprend les étapes consistant à:
<claim-text>sans déranger le raccordement de l'élément de levier coudé (22) à l'actionneur (14):
<claim-text>retirer le premier élément de bras (20) du corps (10) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>retirer le second élément de bras (24) de l'élément de levier coudé (22);</claim-text>
<claim-text>monter le second élément de bras (24) sur le corps (10) à la place du premier élément de bras (20) mais à un angle différent par rapport au corps (10); et</claim-text>
<claim-text>monter un premier élément de bras (20) sur l'élément de levier coudé (22) à la place du second élément de bras (24), mais à un angle différent par rapport à l'élément de levier coudé (22), en relation généralement parallèle par rapport au second élément de bras (24).</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 5, dans lequel le procédé comprend l'étape supplémentaire consistant à former le second élément de bras (24) plus court que l'élément de bras (20) selon une étendue qui permet aux pointes de soudage (32, 28) d'être positionnées à proximité l'une de l'autre dans chaque axe du pistolet de soudage.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, comprenant en outre les étapes consistant à:
<claim-text>monter l'actionneur (14) sur le corps (10);</claim-text>
<claim-text>faciliter le mouvement des pointes de soudage (32, 28) dans les positions sur les faces opposées d'une pièce, en actionnant l'actionneur afin de transmettre le mouvement relatif aux éléments de bras (20, 24); et</claim-text>
<claim-text>porter un transformateur (12) avec le corps (10);</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel l'étape consistant à raccorder de manière amovible les éléments de bras (20, 24) au reste du pistolet comprend les étapes consistant à:
<claim-text>raccorder électriquement une première extrémité (36a) d'une première dérivation (36) au transformateur (12) et une seconde extrémité (36b) de la première dérivation (36) à une première face de bord (20c) du premier élément de bras (20); et</claim-text>
<claim-text>raccorder électriquement une première extrémité (34a) d'une seconde dérivation (34) au transformateur (12) et une seconde extrémité (34b) de la seconde dérivation (34) à une première face de bord (24c) du second élément de bras (24); et</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel l'étape consistant à retirer les éléments de bras (20, 24) du reste du pistolet et interchanger les éléments de bras comprend les étapes consistant à:
<claim-text>déconnecter les éléments de bras (20, 24) du corps (10);</claim-text>
<claim-text>déconnecter les secondes extrémités (36b, 34b) des dérivations (36, 34) des premières faces de bord (20c, 24c) des éléments de bras (20, 24);</claim-text>
<claim-text>connecter à nouveau les éléments de bras (20, 24) au corps (10) selon le second angle par rapport au corps (10);</claim-text>
<claim-text>raccorder les secondes extrémités des dérivations (36b, 34b) aux secondes faces de bord (20d, 24d) des éléments de bras (20, 24) qui sont à proximité des premières faces de bord (20c, 24c) mais inclinés par rapport aux premières faces de bord.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 7, dans lequel l'étape consistant à interchanger les éléments de bras (20, 24) comprend l'étape consistant à interchanger les premier et second éléments de bras avant de raccorder à nouveau les éléments de bras au corps.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Pistolet de soudage comprenant un corps de pistolet de soudage (10), un premier bras de soudage (20) portant une première pointe de soudage (32), un second bras de soudage (18) comprenant un segment de bras (24) portant une seconde pointe de soudage (28), un actionneur (14) monté sur le corps (10) et opérationnel pour transmettre le mouvement relatif aux bras de soudage (20, 18) afin de faciliter le mouvement des pointes de soudage (32, 28) dans des positions sur des faces opposées d'une pièce, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b>:
<claim-text>le pistolet comprend des structures de montage opérationnelles pour permettre de monter sélectivement le premier bras de soudage (20) et le segment de bras (24) sur le pistolet dans une première position, en relation généralement parallèle l'un par rapport à l'autre et s'étendant dans une première direction par rapport au corps (10) afin d'obtenir un premier axe de pistolet de soudage et une seconde position en relation généralement parallèle entre eux et s'étendant dans une seconde direction différente par rapport au corps (10) pour obtenir un second axe de pistolet de soudage différent,</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel lesdites première et seconde directions sont le long d'axes mutuellement orthogonaux ou le long de n'importe quelle direction entre eux.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Pistolet de soudage selon la revendication 9, dans lequel :
<claim-text>l'actionneur (14) est raccordé de manière opérationnelle au second bras de soudage (18) et est opérationnel pour déplacer le second bras de soudage (18) par rapport au premier bras de soudage (20); et</claim-text>
<claim-text>le raccordement de l'actionneur (14) au second bras de soudage (18) est identique, indépendamment du fait que le premier bras de soudage (20) et le second segment de bras (24) sont dans leur première position ou leur seconde position.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Pistolet de soudage selon la revendication 9, dans lequel:
<claim-text>le segment de bras (24) comprend un second segment de bras;<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>le second bras de soudage (18) comprend en outre un premier segment de bras (22) monté de manière pivotante au niveau de son extrémité (22b) sur le corps (10) et raccordé à son autre extrémité (22a) à l'actionneur (14); et</claim-text>
<claim-text>le second segment (24) est fixé de manière amovible à proximité de son extrémité (24a) au premier segment de bras (22) entre les extrémités (22a, 22b) du premier segment de bras (22).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Pistolet de soudage selon la revendication 11, dans lequel, avec le premier bras de soudage (20) et le second segment de bras (24) dans leurs premières positions, le second segment (24) s'étend à partir du premier segment de bras (22) selon un premier angle et dans les secondes positions du premier bras de soudage (20) et du second segment de bras (24), le second segment de bras (24) s'étend à partir du bras (10) selon un second angle différent.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Pistolet de soudage selon la revendication 12, dans lequel le premier bras de soudage (20) est monté de manière fixe mais amovible sur le corps (10) et dans sa première position, s'étend à partir du corps (10) selon un premier angle en relation parallèle par rapport au second segment de bras (24) et dans sa seconde position, s'étend à partir du premier segment de bras (22) selon un second angle différent en relation parallèle par rapport au second segment de bras (24).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Pistolet de soudage selon la revendication 9, dans lequel les structures de montage sont opérationnelles pour permettre au premier bras de soudage (20) et au segment de bras (24) d'être interchangés afin d'obtenir le second axe de pistolet de soudage avec le pistolet de soudage dans le premier axe de pistolet de soudage, le segment de bras (24) est positionné à la place du premier bras de soudage (20) mais à un angle différent par rapport au corps (10) et le premier bras de soudage (20) est positionné à la place du segment de bras (24) mais à un angle différent par rapport au corps (10).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Pistolet de soudage selon la revendication 11, dans lequel le second segment de bras (24) est plus court que le premier bras (20), moyennant quoi, pour obtenir un axe de soudage différent sans déranger le raccordement de l'actionneur (14) au premier segment de bras (22), le second segment de bras<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> (24) peut être retiré du premier segment de bras (22), le premier bras (20) retiré du corps (10) et monté sur le premier segment de bras (22) à la place du second segment de bras (24) mais à un angle différent par rapport au premier segment de bras (22), et le second segment de bras (24) monté sur le corps (10) à la place du premier bras (20) mais à un angle différent par rapport au corps (10) en relation généralement parallèle par rapport au premier segment de bras (22).</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16672347" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="135" he="213" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="157" he="166" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="159" he="140" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --><figure id="f0004" num="4"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="154" he="188" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --><figure id="f0005" num="5"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="153" he="191" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
