<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2055043-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2055043" kind="B1" date="20140101" family-id="38812751" file-reference-id="311118" date-produced="20180822" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146554223" ucid="EP-2055043-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2055043</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-07836363-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154828146" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>07836363</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20070731</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP204139973" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>07836363.7</doc-number><date>20070731</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140446436" ucid="US-2007017104-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>2007017104</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20070731</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140453706" ucid="US-50366106-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>50366106</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20060814</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130916</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988107363" load-source="docdb">H04L  12/18        20060101AFI20080415BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1949021743" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04L  12/189       20130101 LA20160416BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1949021744" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04L  12/1877      20130101 FI20160416BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132195153" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">ANZEIGE DER VERFÜGBARKEIT VON RUNDFUNKANKERN</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132195154" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">BROADCAST ANCHOR AVAILABILITY INDICATION</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132195155" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">INDICATION DE DISPONIBILITÉ D'ANCRE DE DIFFUSION</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918146985" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>ALCATEL LUCENT</last-name><address><country>FR</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918158586" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>ALCATEL LUCENT</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918142618" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>CASATI ALESSIO</last-name><address><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918172252" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>CASATI, ALESSIO</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918999136" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>CASATI, ALESSIO</last-name><address><street>15 Tower Road</street><city>Swindon Wiltshire SN5 5BG</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918154550" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>PALAT SUNDEEP KUMAR</last-name><address><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918154876" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>PALAT, SUNDEEP, KUMAR</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918999138" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>PALAT, SUNDEEP, KUMAR</last-name><address><street>17 Heytsbury gardens Grange park</street><city>Swindon Wiltshire SN5 6EE</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918167957" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>TATESH SAID</last-name><address><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918155886" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>TATESH, SAID</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918999137" load-source="patent-office" sequence="3" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>TATESH, SAID</last-name><address><street>6 Horcott Road</street><city>Swindon Wiltshire SN5 5BW</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918999140" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Alcatel Lucent</last-name><iid>101322554</iid><address><street>3 avenue Octave Gréard</street><city>75007 Paris</city><country>FR</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918999139" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Sarup, David Alexander</last-name><suffix>et al</suffix><iid>100824209</iid><address><street>Alcatel-Lucent Telecom Ltd Intellectual Property Business Group Christchurch Way Greenwich</street><city>London SE10 0AG</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="US-2007017104-W"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2007017104</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20070731</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2008020996-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2008020996</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20080221</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548985639" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS548876071" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS548887833" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS548832511" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS548876072" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS548985640" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS548992837" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548876073" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS548876074" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS548991427" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS548887834" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS548832512" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548992838" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548876075" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS548985641" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS548832513" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS548876076" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS548887835" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS548876077" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS548887836" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS548986711" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS548887837" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS548887838" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS548986712" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS548986713" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS548986714" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS548991428" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS548989047" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS548986715" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS548992839" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS548832514" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS548876078" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63957670" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001"><b><u>Field of the Invention</u></b></heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">This invention generally relates to communications.</p><heading id="h0002"><b><u>Description of the Related Art</u></b></heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">A variety of communication systems are known. Many wireless communication systems are considered cellular systems because a plurality of base stations are deployed to provide coverage over geographic regions or cells. Mobile stations, for example, communicate with the base stations, which provide access to an associated network to facilitate communications on behalf of the mobile stations. In many examples, a radio network controller serves as an interface between the base station and the network.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">There are times when one or more portions of a communication system may become unavailable. In 3GPP systems, for example, SGSN pools may be used. A SGSN will signal its non-availability to a radio network controller that has the ability to connect to it using RANAP protocol specified in 3GPP TS 25.413, for example. The SGSN may provide an overload indication, for example. Because the number of SGSNs and radio network controllers that can connect to them is relatively small, this approach works in conventional 3GPP systems.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">There are communication system arrangements, however, where such an approach is not sufficient. In some communication systems there is no radio network controller and base station controller capabilities are distributed among base nodes. It is possible for a base node to select from among a number of potential anchors. This approach is used, for example, in so-called flat IP cellular systems. In the event that an anchor becomes overloaded or is otherwise out of service, the only known way for a base node to determine that is to attempt a connection with that anchor and fail or to receive a notice from the anchor responsive to the attempted connection that the anchor is unavailable to accommodate a new session with that base node. This approach introduces undesirable bearer set up latency. Additionally, this approach does not scale and requires a long time before the affected base nodes are sequentially notified regarding the unavailability of that anchor.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p><p id="p0005" num="0005"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="EP1282321A2"><text>EP 1 282 321 A2</text></patcit> discloses a system and method for load sharing within a core network, wherein load data is stored at each of a plurality of pooled network resources, e.g. SGSNs, within the core network and wherein the load data is distributed from at least one network resource of the plurality of pooled network resources to other pooled network resources. In one example, the method includes downloading the load data from at least one of the pooled network resources to at least one radio network controller.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">There is a need for an arrangement to facilitate more efficient connections between base nodes and anchors in communication systems. This invention addresses that need.</p><heading id="h0003"><b><u>SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</u></b></heading><p id="p0007" num="0007">An exemplary method of communicating includes using a broadcast availability status indication from an anchor provided to a plurality of base nodes for configuring a set of candidate anchors that are currently available for establishing a connection, wherein the availability status indication includes information regarding a future time when the anchor will become unavailable.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">In one example, the broadcast status indication indicates that an anchor is one of available or unavailable.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">In one example, an anchor broadcasts the status indication independent of an inquiry from a base node attempting to establish a connection with the anchor.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">In one example, an anchor broadcasts the status indication on a periodic basis at regularly spaced intervals. In one example, when an anchor status changes, that anchor broadcasts a status indication as soon as possible responsive to the status change rather than waiting for the next regularly scheduled status indication.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">In one example, a base node receives a status indication and responsively makes any necessary corresponding changes to a set of candidate anchors maintained by the base station. In one example, each base station automatically updates a status of candidate anchors responsive to received broadcast status indications.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">The various features and advantages of this invention will become apparent to those skilled in the art from the following detailed description. The drawings that accompany the detailed description can be briefly described as follows.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p><heading id="h0004"><b><u>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</u></b></heading><p id="p0013" num="0013"><ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> schematically illustrates selected portions of an example communication system that is useful with an embodiment of this invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref> is a flowchart diagram summarizing one example approach.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 3</figref> is a flowchart diagram summarizing another example approach.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0005"><b><u>DETAILED DESCRIPTION</u></b></heading><p id="p0014" num="0014">Disclosed example embodiments of this invention demonstrate how using a broadcast anchor status indication that is broadcast by an anchor to a plurality of base nodes allows for configuring a candidate anchor set that includes status information of<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> at least one candidate anchor. Such an approach allows for a scalable, automated configuration of available candidate anchor sets in communication systems such as flat Internet Protocol cellular systems.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015"><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> schematically illustrates selected portions of an example communication system 20. A plurality of base nodes 22 facilitate communications on behalf of individual user devices, for example. A variety of devices may be used as a base node 22. One example includes a base station used for wireless communications. Such a base node may be used for macrocell or picocell coverage, for example. Another example base node is a router device that operates as a base station for a relatively limited or dedicated coverage area such as within a particular building. Another example base node is a server for a local area network. At least some of the base nodes 22 facilitate wireless communications between the base node and an end user device such as a mobile station or a computer.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">The example of <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> also includes a plurality of anchors 24. A variety of anchor devices can be used depending on the needs of a particular situation. In some examples at least one base node acts as an anchor some of the time. Each of the anchors 24 has the ability to communicate with a plurality of the base nodes 22. In one example, the communication between the anchors 24 and the base nodes 22 occurs over an Internet Protocol (IP) network 26. Each anchor 24 provides an availability status indication to a plurality of the base nodes 22 indicating whether that anchor is available for establishing new sessions or unavailable because the anchor is already overloaded, is out of service or is subject to a maintenance procedure, for example. One example includes broadcasting the availability status indication to a plurality of the base nodes for configuring a candidate anchor set at each base node that includes an indication of currently available anchors. The term "broadcasting" as used in this description is intended to cover broadcast and multicast techniques.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">The example availability status indication is different than a message from an anchor transmitted to a particular base node responsive to an inquiry or attempt by that base node to establish a connection with that anchor. The availability status indication is autonomously sent out by each anchor 24 independent of attempted access by base nodes or inquiries directly from a base node. Such an approach allows for scalability and automated or self-configuration of a candidate anchor set at each base node 22. Additionally, such an approach allows for more efficient overload status detection and reduces latency in bearer setup, at least in part, because a base<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> node can predetermine whether an anchor is available before attempting to establish a connection through that anchor.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018"><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref> includes a flowchart diagram 40 summarizing one example approach taken by an example anchor 24. At 42, the anchor 24 has an established multi-cast group. This is useful in an example where a multi-casting internet protocol is used by an anchor having internet routing capabilities for broadcasting the availability status indication. In one example, the multi-cast group includes IP addresses of each base node 22 with which an anchor is supposed to communicate the availability status indication. In one example, any base node 22 that has the possibility of connecting with an anchor 24 for purposes of establishing a session will be included in that anchor's multicast group. In most examples, the base nodes 22 will explicitly join a multicast group. One technique includes using an IMGPv3 join message. Given this description, those skilled in the art can determine how best to arrange a multicast group and to facilitate including base nodes in a multicast group to meet their particular needs.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">At 44, the anchor 24 determines whether there has been a change in its current status. For example, when an anchor 24 is currently available for new sessions, a determination is made whether the anchor has become unavailable because of an overload condition, for example. If there is no change from its current status, the anchor 24 in the example of <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref> sends a periodic availability status indication according to a preset schedule having regular intervals between the broadcast availability status indications. This occurs at 46 in the example of <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref>.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">In the event that there is a status change at an anchor 24, the step at 48 is taken to send an immediate indication of the new availability status to provide information to the various base nodes 22 as soon as possible regarding the change in status of that anchor 24. In one example, the immediate notification of the status change preempts the regularly scheduled interval for sending availability status indication.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">In one example, when the anchor is available, a first scheduled interval between availability status indications is used. When the anchor is unavailable, a second, smaller interval between indications is used to facilitate providing information regarding an unavailable anchor as soon as possible to any base nodes that have not already received an indication that the particular anchor is unavailable. This may occur, for example, when a new base node is added to a multicast group.<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></p><p id="p0022" num="0022">The example of <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref> includes a decision at 50 whether any new base nodes 22 have been added to the multicast group of an anchor 24. If so, the multicast group is updated and the anchor continues sending the availability status indications as described above.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">In one example, the availability status indication from an anchor includes current status information. In another example, at least one availability status indication provides information regarding a preselected or scheduled time during which the anchor will not be available. This may occur, for example, during a scheduled maintenance procedure. One example embodiment includes configuring a status indication to provide information regarding a particular anchor being unavailable at a future time. In such an example, the base nodes 22 maintain such information in association with the candidate anchor set for maintaining an indication that a particular anchor is unavailable at such a time. Such an approach allows for even more flexibility when selecting an anchor for establishing a new session even when an anchor is currently available but may very soon become unavailable.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024"><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 3</figref> includes a flowchart diagram 60 summarizing an example approach used by a base node 22. Each base node maintains a candidate anchor set as a look up table or database. At 62, the base node joins a multicast group. This occurs in one example by having an appropriate IP address configured into a base node 22 so that it will be included as part of a multicast group to which availability status indications are provided by at least one anchor with which that base node may establish a connection. Once a base node 22 is part of a multicast group, it begins receiving status indications from any anchor or anchors 24 that provide status indications to that multicast group. In some examples, a base node 22 will be a member of more than one multicast group, each of which may include one or more anchors 24.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">At 64, the base node 22 receives a status indication from a particular anchor 24. At 66, the base node determines whether that is a current candidate anchor. If so, at 68, the base node determines the current status of that anchor. At 70, the base node updates the current status to indicate whether that anchor is available or unavailable. The step at 70 may include changing the status or maintaining the status based upon a previously received availability status indication.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">The example of <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 3</figref> also includes a step at 72 where the base node determines that it is receiving an availability status indication for the first time from an anchor 24. In this example, the base node adds the anchor to the candidate set and<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> then proceeds to maintain an appropriate status of that anchor in the set. The base node uses the candidate anchor set information for purposes of selecting an anchor for establishing a new session, for example.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">Having multicast or broadcast status indication information from the anchors 24 available for the base nodes 22 facilitates more efficient connections between the base nodes 22 and the anchors 24 for establishing new sessions, for example. With the disclosed examples, there no longer is a need for a base node 22 to attempt to establish a connection with an anchor 24 that is not currently available. Instead, the base nodes 22 are able to select anchors 24 that are currently available.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">One example includes using a data origin authentication and integrity protection technique to protect the broadcast availability status indications and to ensure reliable information useful by the base nodes 22 for purposes of configuring their candidate anchor sets.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980499" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Verfahren zur Kommunikation, umfassend das<br/>
Verwenden einer von einem Anker (24) an eine Vielzahl von Basisknoten (22) ausgesendeten Verfügbarkeitsstatus-Angabe, um einen Satz von Kandidaten-Ankern, welcher gegenwärtig verfügbare Anker (24) einschließt, für den Aufbau einer Verbindung zu konfigurieren,<br/>
<b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b><br/>
die Verfügbarkeitsstatus-Angabe Informationen in Bezug auf den zukünftigen Zeitpunkt, zu welchem der Anker (24) verfügbar werden wird, umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Verfügbarkeitsstatus-Angabe eine Angabe darüber, dass der Anker (24) verfügbar ist, umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Verfügbarkeitsstatus-Angabe eine Angabe darüber, dass der Anker (24) nicht verfügbar ist, umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, umfassend<br/>
das Aussenden der Verfügbarkeitsstatus-Angabe simultan an die Vielzahl von Basisknoten (22).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, umfassend<br/>
das Aussenden der Verfügbarkeitsstatus-Angabe unabhängig von einer Anfrage von einem beliebigen der Vielzahl von Basisknoten (22).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, umfassend<br/>
das Aussenden der Verfügbarkeitsstatus-Angabe über ein Internetprotokoll-Netzwerk (26) unter Verwendung eines Multicast-Protokolls.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, umfassend<br/>
das Aussenden der Verfügbarkeitsstatus-Angabe periodisch zu einem jeden einer Vielzahl von Zeitpunkten mit regelmäßigen Abstand; und<br/>
das Aussenden der Verfügbarkeitsstatus-Angabe zu einem anderen Zeitpunkt in Reaktion auf eine Veränderung in der Verfügbarkeit des Ankers (24).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, umfassend<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> -->das Empfangen der ausgesendeten Verfügbarkeitsstatus-Angabe von dem Anker (24); und<br/>
in Reaktion darauf, das Konfigurieren des Satzes von Kandidaten-Ankern.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 8, umfassend<br/>
das Empfangen der ausgesendeten Verfügbarkeitsstatus-Angabe von einer Vielzahl von Ankern (24); und<br/>
das automatische Aktualisieren eines Status mindestens eines der Vielzahl von Ankern (24) innerhalb des Satzes von Kandidaten-Ankern in Reaktion auf eine entsprechende empfangene Angabe, dass sich der Status des mindestens einen Ankers (24) gegenüber einem vorherigen Status verändert hat.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980500" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A method of communicating, comprising<br/>
using a broadcast availability status indication from an anchor (24) to a plurality of base nodes (22) for configuring a candidate anchor set including currently available anchors (24) for establishing a connection,<br/>
<b>characterized in that</b><br/>
the availability status indication includes information regarding a future time when the anchor (24) will become unavailable.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The method of claim 1, wherein the availability status indication comprises an indication that the anchor (24) is available.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The method of claim 1, wherein the availability status indication comprises an indication that the anchor (24) is unavailable.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The method of claim 1, comprising<br/>
broadcasting the availability status indication simultaneously to the plurality of base nodes (22).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The method of claim 1, comprising<br/>
broadcasting the availability status indication independent of an inquiry from any of the plurality of base nodes (22).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The method of claim 1, comprising<br/>
broadcasting the availability status indication over an Internet Protocol network (26) using a multicasting protocol.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The method of claim 1, comprising<br/>
broadcasting the availability status indication periodically at each of a plurality of times spaced by a regular interval; and<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> -->broadcasting the availability status indication at another time responsive to a change in the availability of the anchor (24).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The method of claim 1, comprising<br/>
receiving the broadcast availability status indication from the anchor (24); and<br/>
responsively configuring the candidate anchor set.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The method of claim 8, comprising<br/>
receiving the broadcast availability status indication from a plurality of anchors (24); and<br/>
automatically updating a status of at least one of the plurality of anchors (24) within the candidate anchor set responsive to a corresponding received indication that the status of the at least one anchor (24) has changed from a previous status.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980501" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Procédé de communication, comprenant les étapes suivantes :
<claim-text>utiliser une indication d'état de disponibilité de diffusion à partir d'une ancre (24) vers une pluralité de noeuds de base (22) pour configurer un ensemble d'ancres candidates comprenant des ancres actuellement disponibles (24) pour établir une connexion,<br/>
<b>caractérisé en ce que</b><br/>
l'indication d'état de disponibilité comprend des informations concernant un moment futur où l'ancre (24) deviendra indisponible.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, dans lequel l'indication d'état de disponibilité comprend une indication selon laquelle l'ancre (24) est disponible.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, dans lequel l'indication d'état de disponibilité comprend une indication selon laquelle l'ancre (24) est indisponible.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, comprenant l'étape suivante<br/>
diffuser l'indication d'état de disponibilité simultanément vers la pluralité de noeuds de base (22).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, comprenant l'étape suivante<br/>
diffuser l'indication d'état de disponibilité indépendamment d'une demande à partir de l'un quelconque parmi la pluralité de noeuds de base (22).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, comprenant l'étape suivante<br/>
diffuser l'indication d'état de disponibilité sur un réseau de protocole Internet (26) en utilisant un protocole de multidiffusion.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, comprenant les étapes suivantes<br/>
diffuser l'indication d'état de disponibilité périodiquement à chacun parmi une pluralité de moments espacés à intervalles réguliers ; et<br/>
diffuser l'indication d'état de disponibilité à un autre moment en réponse à un changement de la disponibilité de l'ancre (24).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, comprenant l'étape suivante<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> -->recevoir l'indication d'état de disponibilité de diffusion à partir de l'ancre (24) ; et, en réponse, configurer l'ensemble d'ancres candidates.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 8, comprenant les étapes suivantes :
<claim-text>recevoir l'indication d'état de disponibilité de diffusion à partir d'une pluralité d'ancres (24) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>mettre à jour automatiquement un état d'au moins une parmi la pluralité d'ancres (24) dans l'ensemble d'ancres candidates en réponse à une indication reçue correspondante selon laquelle l'état de l'au moins une ancre (24) a changé par rapport à un état précédent.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16669177" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="165" he="150" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2,3"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="133" he="230" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
