<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2497256-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2497256" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="43970139" file-reference-id="315041" date-produced="20180825" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146587856" ucid="EP-2497256-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2497256</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-09851141-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154850048" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>09851141</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20091103</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140549438" ucid="SE-2009051240-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>SE</country><doc-number>2009051240</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20091103</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130809</date></intention-to-grant-date><search-report-dispatch-date><date>20121004</date></search-report-dispatch-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989324102" load-source="ipcr">G06F  17/30        20060101ALI20130429BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989324103" load-source="ipcr">G06K   9/62        20060101ALI20130429BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989324104" load-source="ipcr">G06Q  30/02        20120101ALI20130429BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989324105" load-source="ipcr">H04M   3/42        20060101AFI20130429BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989324106" load-source="ipcr">H04W   8/18        20090101ALI20130429BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989622788" load-source="ipcr">G06Q  30/00        20120101A I20111231RMEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989635425" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04W   8/18        20130101 LA20131130BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989636630" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G06Q  30/02        20130101 LI20131130BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989652930" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04M  15/58        20130101 FI20131130BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132368201" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">VERRINGERUND DER RECHENKOMPLEXITÄT WÄHREND EINER BENUTZERDATENANALYSE</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132368202" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">REDUCING COMPUTATIONAL COMPLEXITY DURING USER DATA ANALYSIS</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132368203" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">RÉDUCTION DE LA COMPLEXITÉ DE CALCUL PENDANT UNE ANALYSE DE DONNÉES UTILISATEUR</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919508887" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>ERICSSON TELEFON AB L M</last-name><address><country>SE</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919510078" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>TELEFONAKTIEBOLAGET LM ERICSSON (PUBL)</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919517826" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>ZAHOOR J MOHAMED</last-name><address><country>IN</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919523813" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>ZAHOOR, J MOHAMED</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919020373" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>ZAHOOR, J MOHAMED</last-name><address><street>1F Salma Classic APT. West madha church st Royapuram</street><city>Chennai 600013</city><country>IN</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919020372" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Telefonaktiebolaget LM Ericsson (publ)</last-name><iid>101190365</iid><address><city>164 83 Stockholm</city><country>SE</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919020374" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Egrelius, Fredrik</last-name><suffix>et al</suffix><iid>101307911</iid><address><street>Ericsson AB Patent Unit Kista Device, Service &amp; Media Torshamnsgatan 21-23</street><city>164 80 Stockholm</city><country>SE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="SE-2009051240-W"><document-id><country>SE</country><doc-number>2009051240</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20091103</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2011056099-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2011056099</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20110512</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549921567" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549886083" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549864614" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549866903" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549794444" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549794465" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549862765" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549886084" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549886085" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549779145" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549864615" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549864616" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549862774" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549886090" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549862775" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549794466" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549866904" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549886091" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549864617" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549886092" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549862776" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549921568" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549864622" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549862777" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549921569" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS549921570" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549921571" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549794467" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549921572" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549886093" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549778771" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549921573" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549862782" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549794468" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549794481" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS549779146" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63960290" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The invention relates generally to a method and apparatus for supporting analysis of users in a communication network by handling and organising data related to said users.</p><heading id="h0002">BACKGROUND</heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">In the field of telecommunication, solutions have been devised for enabling relevant and potentially attractive services that have been adapted to different service consumers according to their interests and needs in different situations. Some examples are directed advertising and personalised TV. There are also solutions for analysing users in a telecommunication network and identifying segments or "clusters" of users with common characteristics, such that services and marketing activities can be adapted to these user groups accordingly. This analysis work can be executed based on traffic data generated in communication networks.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">Traffic data is generally available from Charging Data Records (CDR) generated and stored for the networks mainly to support the charging of users for executed calls and sessions. Traffic data can also be obtained by means of various traffic analysing devices, such as Deep Packet Inspection (DPI) units and other traffic detecting devices, which can be installed at various communication nodes in the network. The traffic data may refer to voice calls, SMS (Short Message Service), MMS (Multimedia Message Service), e-mails and game sessions, and to circuit-switched as well as packet-switched communication, in this description<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> collectively referred to as "calls". The traffic data may also contain further information on the calls related to the time of day, call duration, location of users and type of service used. As a result, the user data that can be derived from such traffic data is often "multi-dimensional" in the sense of involving plural user-related parameters for each user.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">For operators and service providers, it has thus become important to understand the consumers in order to provide adapted or "tailor made" services and products. It is therefore useful to identify certain segments of similar users based on their behavioural characteristics. Information on the users can be derived from the available traffic data which thus can be further analysed by using various techniques for so-called "data mining". For example, Machine Learning Algorithms (MLA:s) and tools can be used for processing the traffic data, which may be utilised by operators and service providers when developing and adapting services.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">A Data Mining Engine (DME) may further be employed that collects traffic data and extracts user information therefrom using various data mining and machine learning algorithms. <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> illustrates an example of how data mining can be employed for a communication network, according to the prior art. A DME 100 typically uses various MLA:s 100a for processing traffic data TD provided from a data source 102, and further to identify clusters of users. The data source 102 collects CDR information and DPI information from the network which is then provided as traffic data TD to the DME 100. After processing the traffic data, the DME 100 provides the resulting cluster information as output data to<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> various service providers 104 to enable adapted services, products and marketing activities.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">Analysing large quantities of traffic data and other information is typically a very complex and time-consuming process sometimes involving millions of calls, in order to identify different groups of similar users based on their previously executed communications. In the field of data mining, quantization of various parameter values is widely used to facilitate the analysis work and to reduce the computing and processing capacity required. Quantization means that a measured parameter value is approximated to a representative value in discrete steps of intervals.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007"><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2</figref> is a schematic diagram illustrating how such quantization can be made in the case of two parameters X and Y of which values are obtained for a plurality of users in a communication network. For example, parameter X may be the costs in SEK (Swedish currency) for executed calls while parameter Y may be the duration in seconds of executed calls.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">In this example, the quantization is made such that obtained parameter values within predefined ranges are approximated according to a numeric scale 1-8 of finite intervals for each parameter X and Y, thereby forming cells of equal size each covering a pair of intervals of the scales. Each cell is assigned an identity which is representative for any pair of measured parameter values falling within the ranges defined by the cell. The cell identity may be any type of code and each cell covers values within a predefined interval "m" for each parameter. Although this particular example refers to cells in a two-dimensional quantization scheme or "parameter space", it can be readily understood that this kind of cell representation<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> is also applicable for any other multi-dimensional quantization schemes. Basically, this cell model implies that cells in a quantized parameter space are of equal length in all the dimensions although the actual parameters may well be measured in different entities, such as SEK and seconds, respectively.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">In this example, a cell is marked that has been given an identity of (8,5) which explicitly indicates the representative value ranges of 8 and 5 for parameters X and Y, respectively. Hence, the quantization is made such that any pair of measured X and Y values that falls within that cell is represented by the cell identity of (8,5). This will simplify the following computation made based on the representative cell identity, as compared to using the original values which are typically more detailed and precise, e.g. 1234 SEK and 56789 seconds, and therefore more complex to compute.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">When cells have been defined for a parameter space in the above manner, each pair of obtained parameter values is represented by a cell identity, which is done by reading or "scanning" input data related to multiple users in the communication network. <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 3</figref> illustrates an example of how different cells are populated with users falling within their respective cells, as marked in the cell diagram. In this case, three different clusters 300, 302 and 304 of populated cells can be discerned in the diagram, while some "stray" cells 306 have also been populated with users that cannot be considered to fall within any discerned cluster, which are therefore disregarded.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">Quantization is thus used in clustering, to achieve short processing time which is typically dependent merely on the number of cells in each dimension in the quantized<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> space. Some clustering algorithms known as "WaveCluster", "WaveCluster+" and "STING" use quantization in preparation to determine clusters in data. However, it is a problem with the quantization model described above, that a uniform size or granularity of cells must be selected in a trade-off between the accuracy, or "quality", of the clusters and the computational complexity, i.e. the finer cell granularity and higher accuracy/quality, the greater complexity, and vice versa.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">This has been addressed in the field of data mining by using adaptive quantization, i.e. varying the cell size depending on the distribution of input data and/or accuracy needed. Adaptive quantization techniques tend to use a small cell size in areas of the multi-dimensional parameter space with relatively dense data distribution, while a larger cell size is used in areas with more sparse data distribution, which is illustrated by an adaptive quantization scheme shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 4</figref>. Two areas 400 and 402 with dense data distribution are thus given a fine cell granularity, while other areas with more sparse data distribution are given a "coarser" cell granularity.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">Hence, adaptive quantization can provide good accuracy or quality in areas where it is really needed while lesser accuracy can be tolerated in other areas. However, in adaptive quantization, the input data must be read or scanned at least twice according to prior solutions: firstly to find out which areas in the multi-dimensional parameter space are densely populated for defining the adaptive cell sizes in different areas, and then secondly to quantize the input data according to the adaptive cell definitions. It can be readily understood that reading the typically large amounts of input data more than once can be very time-consuming,<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> also requiring great processing capacity. Moreover, reading the data twice requires that all data has been received, resulting in substantial delays.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US6882997B1"><text>US 6,882,997 B1</text></patcit> describes a wavelet based clustering method. The said patent discloses a spatial data mining method, where signal-processing techniques are applied to the spatial data which is considered as multi-dimensional signals. The method further involves converting the spatial data into the frequency domain using the wavelet transforms.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015"><patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="WO9948018A1"><text>WO 99/48018 A1</text></patcit> describes a system for clustering data of databases. The disclosed process employs criteria for deciding which data can be summarized and represented by a compressed set of sufficient statistics, and which data items must be carried in computer memory.</p><heading id="h0003">SUMMARY</heading><p id="p0016" num="0016">It is an object of the invention to generally address the issues outlined above. It is thus an object to support analysis of users in a communication network with relevant accuracy and quality where needed or desired, while the computational complexity for processing user data can be kept at a reasonable (i.e. relatively low) level. These objects and others may be achieved primarily by a solution according to the appended independent claims.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">According to different aspects, a method and an apparatus are defined for handling data related to users in a telecommunication network to support analysis of said users. In the method, plural sets of parameter values obtained from traffic data of the users are read, where each parameter value set is valid for a particular user and<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> comprises values of two or more measured user-related parameters. A first level quantization cell is also determined for each read set of parameter values according to a default first level quantization scheme. In this way, the first level quantization cells are effectively "populated" with users.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">Eventually, clusters of neighbouring first level quantization cells, which are populated by users, will emerge and can thus be identified, e.g. according to a predefined clustering condition. An adaptive second level quantization scheme is further formed by translating the identified clusters into new second level quantization cells. The users populating a new second level cell can thus be regarded as being similar by having basically the same characteristics with respect to the measured parameters. Representative parameter values are then also assigned to each second level quantization cell. The representative parameter values can be used for analysing the users, e.g. in the purpose of marketing activities and/or for adapting services and products.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">The apparatus involves a data handling unit configured to handle data basically according to the method above. The data handling unit comprises a parameter reading unit adapted to read sets of parameter values obtained from traffic data of said users, where each parameter value set is valid for a particular user and comprises values of two or more user-related parameters. The data handling unit further comprises a cell populating unit adapted to populate first level quantization cells with users according to a default first level quantization scheme by determining a first level quantization cell for each read set of parameter values. The data handling unit further comprises a cluster<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> identifying unit adapted to identify clusters of first level quantization cells populated by users, and a quantization unit adapted to form an adaptive second level quantization scheme by translating the identified clusters into second level quantization cells and assigning representative parameter values to each second level quantization cell.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">The invented method and apparatus may be implemented according to any of the following optional embodiments.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">In one embodiment, the first level quantization cells with populating users are stored in a first data storage, and the formation of second level quantization cells with assigned representative parameter values are stored in a second data storage. The work of reading parameter values, determining first level quantization cells, and identifying clusters, can also be distributed over plural processing entities operating in parallel, e.g. based on the users' MSISDN (Mobile Station International ISDN Number) number series or on the current load distribution in said processing entities.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">In further possible embodiments, clusters are identified according to a predefined clustering condition dictating when a user-populated first level quantization cell belongs to a cluster. The predefined clustering condition may dictate that a user-populated cell belongs to a cluster when bordering at least one user-populated neighbour cell. A counter of a first level quantization cell may also be incremented whenever that cell is populated by a user, and the predefined clustering condition could further dictate that a user-populated first level quantization cell belongs to a cluster when the number of users populating the cell reaches a preset population threshold.<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --></p><p id="p0023" num="0023">The action of identifying the clusters above may be triggered by any of: a preset timeout period has expired, a preset amount of parameter value sets have been read, and a preset amount of first level quantization cells have been populated with users. Furthermore, different types of parameter values may be assigned to each second level quantization cell, such as a set of parameter mean values and/or one or more sets of parameter boundary values defining the outer limits of parameter values covered by the corresponding identified cluster. The number of assigned parameter values can be freely selected depending on which level of accuracy is needed or desired for defining the second level cells.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">Further possible features and benefits of the invention will become apparent from the detailed description below.</p><heading id="h0004">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading><p id="p0025" num="0025">The invention will now be described in more detail by means of exemplary embodiments and with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which:
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is a schematic overview illustrating how data mining can be employed for a telecommunication network, according to the prior art.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2</figref> is a schematic diagram of a basic quantization scheme with uniform cells in a two-dimensional parameter space, according to the prior art.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 3</figref> is a schematic diagram of a two-dimensional quantization scheme in which three clusters are identified, according to the prior art.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 4</figref> is a schematic diagram of a two-dimensional adaptive quantization scheme, according to the prior art.<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 5</figref> is a schematic diagram illustrating an example of how a two-dimensional adaptive quantization scheme can be formed, according to one possible embodiment.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 6</figref> is a flow chart illustrating a procedure for handling and organising data related to users in a communication network to support analysis of said users, according to another possible embodiment.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 7</figref> is a schematic diagram illustrating another example of using parallel processor entities when forming a two-dimensional adaptive quantization scheme, according to yet another possible embodiment.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 8</figref> is a schematic block diagram illustrating an apparatus for data handling in more detail, according to further possible embodiments.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0005">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading><p id="p0026" num="0026">Briefly described, a solution is provided for obtaining relevant clustering accuracy and quality in areas of a multi-dimensional parameter space where needed or desired, while it is sufficient to read or scan the input data related to multiple users in a communication network just once. In this solution, quantization is made in two phases involving a predefined, or default, fixed first level quantization scheme which is a relatively fine mesh with small fixed cells, and an adaptive cluster-based second level quantization scheme which is basically a more coarse mesh with larger cells, respectively.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">In the first quantization phase, available user-related parameter values measured from traffic data are read and quantized according to the default first level quantization scheme, effectively populating the cells with users. As the first level quantization cells are populated<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> by users according to their parameter values, clusters of such populated cells can be identified, e.g. based on a predefined clustering condition dictating when a cell is considered to belong to a cluster. In this process, it may be of interest to register some suitable identification of the users populating the cells to know which cluster and/or first level cell each user belongs to, or just to register the number of users in each cell to know generally which clusters exist in the network.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">As the first level quantization scheme is relatively fine, i.e. having small cells, the identified clusters may have any size or shape. It may also happen that some neighbouring clusters overlap each other by one or more first level cells and such overlapping clusters are then considered to jointly form the same cluster.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">In the second quantization phase, the adaptive second level quantization scheme is formed based on the clusters identified from the first quantization phase, such that each identified cluster forms a second level quantization cell with the size and shape of that cluster. Each cell is also given an identity comprising a set of representative parameter values which are to be valid for all users populating that cell. The second level quantization is thus adaptive since the second level quantization cells will have different sizes and shapes according to the identified clusters, each cell being representative for a segment of users with similar or common characteristics. The representative parameter values may include mean values of the cluster and/or values defining the shape and size of the cell, such as its outer boundaries or the like.<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></p><p id="p0030" num="0030">The representative parameter values of the second level quantization cells are then used for analysing the users, e.g. with the purpose of adapting services, products and marketing activities, which can be useful for various service providers and network operators. As a result, the computational complexity is kept at a reasonably low level by this quantization while the second level cells clearly indicate segments of users. In this process, the users' parameter values may be input to various MLA:s or the like, e.g. in a DME, in order to compute different information therefrom.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">A representative parameter of a cluster or second level cell can thus be used to identify the characteristics of the users in that cluster/cell. One example is to give these parameters to a supervised learning algorithm which has already learned the characteristics of users having left the network, to identify whether an identified cluster of users exhibit a certain behaviour.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">A simplified example of how a two-dimensional adaptive quantization scheme can be formed when using the solution above, will now be described with reference to the schematic diagram of <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 5</figref>. Although this example refers to two-dimensional schemes involving only two user-related parameters X and Y for simplicity, it should be understood that this solution can be applied in the described manner for any number of user-related parameters and any corresponding multi-dimensional quantization schemes. The parameters X and Y may be any measurable user-related parameters that can be obtained from traffic data, as explained above.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">The process of quantization in two phases is illustrated from top to bottom in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 5</figref>. Thus, measured and<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> initially non-quantized parameter values relating to a plurality of users are first read and then quantized in the first quantization phase according to a default first level quantization scheme 500 having a fixed cell size forming a relatively fine mesh in an X-Y diagram, as shown in the upper half of the figure. When the parameter values are quantized in this way, they will appear or "land" in different cells such that the corresponding users then effectively "populate" the cells, according to the terminology used here. In one possible and relatively simple embodiment, a counter can be maintained for each first level quantization cell, which is incremented whenever that cell is populated by a user in this process. Another possibility is to maintain a list of populating users for each cell. The list will thus record a suitable identification of the user who has appeared in that cell.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">As the first level quantization cells are populated by users according to their parameter values, it is eventually possible to discern clusters of adjacent cells which are sufficiently populated with users. The clusters may be identified according to a predefined clustering condition dictating when a user-populated first level quantization cell is considered to belong to a cluster. For example, the predefined clustering condition may dictate that a user-populated cell belongs to a cluster when bordering at least one other user-populated neighbour cell. The predefined clustering condition may further dictate that a user-populated first level quantization cell belongs to a cluster when the number of users populating the cell reaches a preset population threshold, which can be detected by means of the above-mentioned counters.<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></p><p id="p0035" num="0035">In the figure, the user-populated cells are marked with crossed lines and in this example, four clusters 1-4 can be identified having various sizes and shapes, e.g. according to a predefined clustering condition as described above. Any stray cells populated with users but not falling within any discerned cluster, e.g. by not fulfilling the predefined clustering condition, have been disregarded and are not shown in this example, even though such cells may of course frequently occur.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">In the second phase of quantization, the above-identified clusters 1-4 are translated, or converted, into new second-level cells 1-4 encompassing sizes and shapes of the corresponding clusters, thereby forming an adaptive second level quantization scheme 502. Each formed second-level cell is thus populated by the users populating the original first level cells in the corresponding cluster. The new cells 1-4 of the adaptive second level quantization scheme 502 are shown in the lower half of the figure.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">Furthermore, representative parameter values are assigned to each second level cell. For example, at least a pair of representative parameter mean values (X,Y) can be assigned to each second level cell. Each cell may also be defined by its boundaries, i.e. the outer limits of X-values and Y-values, respectively, covered by the cluster. In that case, two further pairs of representative parameter boundary values X, Y are also assigned to each second level cell. The second level cell may also be assigned the latter boundary values only, thus omitting the above parameter mean values.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">In this example, cell 1 is assigned the parameter boundary values of (X<sub>A</sub>-X<sub>B</sub>) and (Y<sub>A</sub>-Y<sub>B</sub>), respectively, as well as the parameter mean values of (X<sub>1</sub>,Y<sub>1</sub>). Cells 2-4 can be assigned corresponding parameter boundary and mean values,<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> not shown. In this operation, the parameter mean values (X,Y) should preferably be selected for a second level cell to be as representative as possible for the users in the cluster/cell, thus basically "in the middle" of the second level cell, as shown in the figure.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">These representative parameter values may be considered as valid for all users populating the corresponding cell, the users therein effectively being identified as a segment of users with common or similar characteristics, at least with respect to the parameters X, Y, and can be used for analysing the users, as described above. It should be noted that the resulting second level cells may have any size and shape, while the first level cells of the default quantization scheme have regular and uniform shape and are non-overlapping. It should also be noted that the above simplified example of using a single pair of boundary values per parameter or dimension for defining the second level cells, the resulting shape of those cells will be relatively simple. However, when a more accurate second level cell should be formed from a cluster encompassing a complex shape, further parameter boundary values may be needed to properly define that cell.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">Hence, this solution can provide reduced computational complexity when using the representative parameter values for users according to the actual clusters formed, while maintaining relevant accuracy and quality. It is a further advantage that it is only necessary to scan or read the typically large amounts of input data once, i.e. initially for carrying out the first quantization phase. Thereby, the quantization process can start as soon as the first input data is received without having to wait for all the data to arrive for processing.<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></p><p id="p0041" num="0041">The above process of quantizing in two phases can thus be performed on a continuous basis, i.e. as soon as non-quantized parameter values become available. The clusters may then be modified dynamically such that the size and shape of the second level cells in the adaptive second level quantization scheme will change accordingly. For example, if a new cluster emerging in the first level quantization overlaps with an already existing cell in the second level quantization, the newly identified cluster is "merged" with the existing cell in the second level quantization to form a new expanded second level cell.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">A preset time-out period may also be employed for cell-populating users such that a user populating a particular first level cell is deleted from that cell when the time-out period expires, thereby decreasing the counter of that cell. In effect, the reason for that user populating the cell has become outdated and is no longer valid, particularly when the measured parameters are of dynamic nature. In that case, certain first level cells may eventually be excluded from the cluster, e.g. when not fulfilling a used clustering condition any more, thereby possibly reducing the size and shape of the corresponding second level cell.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">In a possible implementation, the first level quantization cells with populating users can be stored in a first data storage such as a cache, and the second level quantization cells with assigned representative parameter values and populating users can be stored in a second data storage such as a cache, thereby making the data readily available for processing. Furthermore, the work of processing input data and determining first level quantization cells may be distributed over plural processing<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> entities operating in parallel, which will be described further below. In that case, the work distribution may be based on the users' MSISDN (Mobile Station International ISDN Number) number series or similar terminal or user identity, or on the current distribution of processing and/or storing load in the processing entities.</p><p id="p0044" num="0044">The operation of identifying clusters of first level quantization cells may be triggered by any of: a preset timeout period has expired, a preset amount of parameter value sets have been read, and a preset amount of first level quantization cells have been populated with users. As said above, the collection of parameter values and population of first level cells may go on more or less continuously, while clusters may be identified or modified at any time, e.g. triggered as above.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045">A procedure for handling and organising data related to users in a communication network, will now be described with reference to the flow chart of <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 6</figref>. The steps in this procedure can be performed by a data handling unit, e.g. implemented in a DME or other entity for extracting user information, which may be controlled by an operator of the network or by a third party. It is assumed that multiple sets of parameter values can be obtained for the users from their traffic data available from the network, although this process as such lies somewhat outside the scope of this solution. Further, each set of parameter values is valid for a particular user and thus comprises values of two or more user-related parameters.</p><p id="p0046" num="0046">In a first shown <b>step 600,</b> the above sets of parameter values, obtained from traffic data of the users, are read or scanned, e.g. on a more or less continuous basis as data become available. In this step, the amount of data<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> to be read may be huge for a fairly extensive network. It is thus an advantage of this solution that this information is read just once.</p><p id="p0047" num="0047">A first level quantization cell is also determined for each received set of parameter values according to a default first level quantization scheme, in a <b>step 602,</b> such as the first level scheme 500 in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 5</figref>. Thereby, cells in a mesh of the first level quantization scheme are gradually populated with users. In practice, steps 600 and 602 can basically be executed in parallel such that whenever a set of parameter values of a user is read, a first level cell is determined into which the read values falls, thereby populating that cell. A counter for the cell may also be incremented, as described above, which is shown by an optional <b>step 604</b>. The first level quantization cells with populating users may also be stored in a first data storage.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048">At some point, clusters of the first level cells are identified, e.g. according to a predefined clustering condition, in a next <b>step 606</b>. The cluster identification may be triggered by different factors as described above, e.g. when a preset timeout period has expired, a preset amount of parameter value sets have been read, or when a preset amount of first level quantization cells have been populated with users. However, the invention is generally not limited to any particular identification triggering mechanism.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">In a following <b>step 608</b>, an adaptive second level quantization scheme is formed by translating the above-identified clusters into second level quantization cells, such as the quantization scheme 502 in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 5</figref>. Also, representative parameter values are assigned to each second level quantization cell, effectively as a cell identity, in<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> a further <b>step 610</b>. Thereby, the representative parameter values can be used for analysing the users, e.g. using various MLE:s or similar, which is a process lying outside the scope of this solution.</p><p id="p0050" num="0050">The above procedure will thus provide user information in the form of data that can be computed and processed without undue complexity and/or delays since, firstly, the input data is read just once and, secondly, the adaptive second level quantization is closely related to different segments of users with common or similar characteristics.</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">As indicated above, the work of reading parameter values, determining first level quantization cells, and identifying clusters, may be distributed over plural processing entities operating in parallel, which could make this process even less time-consuming. An example of using parallel processor entities when forming a two-dimensional adaptive quantization scheme, is illustrated by the diagram of <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 7</figref>. In this example, initially non-quantized user-related parameter values are read and quantized in the first quantization phase according to one or more default first level quantization schemes by means of four processing entities A-D operating in parallel. The figure shows that each processor A-D receives and processes a part of all available sets of parameter values, e.g. roughly 25% each if a uniform distribution is employed.</p><p id="p0052" num="0052">The distribution of input data and processing work over the processors may otherwise be selected based on various factors, e.g., different ranges of the users' MSISDN number series or the current load and/or available capacity of the processors. However, any other distribution mechanism<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> or condition may be employed and the invention is not limited in this respect.</p><p id="p0053" num="0053">At some point, processors A-D may eventually identify one or more clusters of first level cells, e.g. according to a clustering condition, and each identified cluster is then translated into a second level cell of a single common mesh structure of second level cells. The second level cells thus form an adaptive second level quantization scheme, as illustrated in the lower half of the figure. In the shown example, the processors A-D have identified one cluster each, in this case with rectangular shapes for simplicity, although two or more processors may well identify one or more clusters that basically coincide, either completely or partly.</p><p id="p0054" num="0054">An apparatus for data handling will now be described in more detail with reference to the block diagram of <figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 8</figref> illustrating a data handling unit 800 configured to handle data related to users in a telecommunication network 802 to support analysis of said users. The data handling unit 800 may be used to accomplish any of the above-described procedures and embodiments.</p><p id="p0055" num="0055">The data handling unit 800 comprises a parameter reading unit 800a adapted to read sets of parameter values P obtained from traffic data of the users, each parameter value set being valid for a particular user and comprising values of two or more user-related parameters. Unit 800 further comprises a cell populating unit 800b adapted to populate first level quantization cells with users according to a default first level quantization scheme by determining a first level quantization cell for each received set of parameter values.<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --></p><p id="p0056" num="0056">Unit 800 further comprises a cluster identifying unit 800c adapted to identify clusters of first level quantization cells populated by users, and a quantization unit 800d adapted to form an adaptive second level quantization scheme by translating the identified clusters into second level quantization cells. The cluster identifying unit 800c also assigns representative parameter values to each second level quantization cell. The representative parameter values can then be used for analysing the users, e.g. in a user analysing functionality 804 or similar, the details of which are somewhat outside the scope of this solution.</p><p id="p0057" num="0057">The data handling unit 800 may further comprise a first data storage or cache C1 adapted to store information on the first level quantization cells with populating users, which is provided from the cell populating unit 800b, e.g. on a more or less continuous manner as soon as the measured parameter values become available from the network 802. Unit 800 may also comprise a second data storage or cache C2 adapted to store the formation of second level quantization cells with assigned representative parameter values, as provided from the quantization unit 800d.</p><p id="p0058" num="0058">In practice, the operational functions in the parameter reading unit 800a, the cell populating unit 800b and the cluster identifying unit 800c for reading parameter values, determining first level quantization cells, and identifying clusters, respectively, may be distributed over plural processing entities operating in parallel, e.g. as shown in the example of <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 7</figref>.</p><p id="p0059" num="0059">The data handling unit 800 may be configured according to further embodiments. For example, the cluster identifying unit 800c may be further adapted to identify<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> said clusters according to a predefined clustering condition dictating when a user-populated first level quantization cell belongs to a cluster.</p><p id="p0060" num="0060">Further, the cell populating unit 800b may be further adapted to increment a counter of a first level quantization cell whenever that cell is populated by a user, in the manner described above. In another embodiment, the cluster identifying unit 800c is further adapted to identify clusters of first level quantization cells when triggered by any of: a preset timeout period has expired, a preset amount of parameter value sets have been read, and a preset amount of first level quantization cells have been populated with users.</p><p id="p0061" num="0061">The quantization unit 800d may be further adapted to assign one or more of the following parameter values to each second level quantization cell: a set of parameter mean values, and one or more sets of parameter boundary values defining the outer limits of parameter values covered by the corresponding identified cluster.</p><p id="p0062" num="0062">It should be noted that <figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 8</figref> merely illustrates various functional units in the data handling unit 800 in a logical sense, although the skilled person is free to implement these functions in practice using any suitable software and hardware means. Thus, the invention is generally not limited to the shown structure of the data handling unit 800 while its functional units 800a-d may be configured to operate according to the methods and procedures described above for Fig's 5-7, where appropriate. Further, the data handling unit 800 could alternatively be called a system, apparatus, arrangement or entity for data handling.<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --></p><p id="p0063" num="0063">By employing the invention according to any of the above-described aspects and embodiments, data relating to users in the network can be computed and processed with reduced complexity and/or delays by achieving a useful quantization. Thereby, less processing and storing capacity will be generally required. It is thus an advantage that it is sufficient to read the input data just once and that the adaptive second level quantization is closely related to different segments of users with common or similar characteristics.</p><p id="p0064" num="0064">This solution is also flexible in the sense that the quality or accuracy of the second level quantization can be freely selected by assigning a suitable number of representative parameter values, such as the above parameter boundary values, to define each second level cell with more or less accuracy. The described process can also be used in a continuous manner, allowing for clusters and second level cells to be formed, modified and merged more or less dynamically as new data becomes available from the network.</p><p id="p0065" num="0065">While the invention has been described with reference to specific exemplary embodiments, the description is generally only intended to illustrate the inventive concept and should not be taken as limiting the scope of the invention. The invention is defined by the appended claims.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56983607" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Verfahren zur Verarbeitung von Daten mit Bezug auf Benutzer in einem Telekommunikationsnetz, um Analysen der Benutzer zu unterstützen, umfassend den Schritt:
<claim-text>- Lesen (600) von Sätzen von Parameterwerten, die aus Verkehrsdaten der Benutzer gewonnen werden, wobei jeder Parameterwerte-Satz für einen bestimmten Benutzer gültig ist und Werte von zwei oder mehr benutzerbezogenen Parametern umfasst, und <b>gekennzeichnet durch</b> die Schritte:</claim-text>
<claim-text>- Bestimmen (602) einer Quantisierungszelle erster Ebene für jeden gelesenen Satz von Parameterwerten gemäß einem ersten Standardvorgabe-Quantisierungsschema erster Ebene, wodurch die Quantisierungszellen erster Ebene mit Benutzern belegt werden,</claim-text>
<claim-text>- Identifizieren (606) von Clustern von mit Benutzern belegten Quantisierungszellen erster Ebene,</claim-text>
<claim-text>- Bilden (608) eines adaptiven Quantisierungsschemas zweiter Ebene <b>durch</b> Umsetzung der identifizierten Cluster in Quantisierungszellen zweiter Ebene, und</claim-text>
<claim-text>- Zuweisen (610) von repräsentativen Parameterwerten zu jeder Quantisierungszelle zweiter Ebene, wobei die repräsentativen Parameterwerte zum Analysieren der Benutzer verwendet werden.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Quantisierungszellen erster Ebene mit zellenbelegenden Benutzern in einem ersten Datenspeicher (C1) gespeichert werden und die Bildung von Quantisierungszellen zweiter Ebene mit zugewiesenen repräsentativen Parameterwerten in einem zweiten Datenspeicher (C2) gespeichert wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1 oder 2, wobei die Arbeit des Lesens von Parameterwerten, des Bestimmens von Quantisierungszellen erster Ebene und des Identifizierens von Clustern über mehrere parallel arbeitende Verarbeitungsinstanzen verteilt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 3, wobei die Cluster gemäß einer vorher definierten Clusterbildungsbedingung identifiziert werden, die vorschreibt, wann eine mit Benutzern belegte Quantisierungszelle erster Ebene zu einem Cluster gehört.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 4, wobei der Schritt des Identifizierens von Clustern von Quantisierungszellen erster Ebene durch irgendeines von Folgendem ausgelöst wird: eine vorher festgelegte Zeitdauer ist abgelaufen, eine vorher festgelegte Menge von Parameterwerte-Sätzen ist gelesen worden, und eine vorher festgelegte Menge von Quantisierungszellen erster Ebene ist mit Benutzern belegt worden.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 5, wobei jeder Quantisierungszelle zweiter Ebene einer oder mehr der folgenden Parameterwerte zugewiesen werden: ein Satz von Parameter-Mittelwerten (X, Y) und ein oder mehr Sätze von Parameter-Grenzwerten<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --> (X<sub>A</sub>-X<sub>B</sub>, Y<sub>A</sub>-Y<sub>B</sub>,...), die die äußeren Grenzen der Parameterwerte definieren, die durch die entsprechenden identifizierten Cluster abgedeckt werden.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Datenverarbeitungseinheit (800), die dafür konfiguriert ist, Daten mit Bezug auf Benutzer in einem Telekommunikationsnetz (802) zu verarbeiten, um eine Analyse der Benutzer zu unterstützen, umfassend:
<claim-text>- eine Parameterleseeinheit (800a), die dafür eingerichtet ist, Sätze von Parameterwerten (P) zu lesen, die aus Verkehrsdaten der Benutzer gewonnen werden, wobei jeder Parameterwerte-Satz für einen bestimmten Benutzer gültig ist und Werte von zwei oder mehr benutzerbezogenen Parametern umfasst, und <b>gekennzeichnet ist durch</b>:</claim-text>
<claim-text>- eine Zellenbelegungseinheit (800b), die dafür eingerichtet ist, die Quantisierungszellen erster Ebene gemäß einem ersten Standardvorgabe-Quantisierungsschema erster Ebene mit Benutzern zu belegen <b>durch</b> Bestimmen einer Quantisierungszelle erster Ebene für jeden gelesenen Satz von Parameterwerten,</claim-text>
<claim-text>- eine Clusteridentifizierungseinheit (800c), die dafür eingerichtet ist, Cluster von mit Benutzern belegten Quantisierungszellen erster Ebene zu identifizieren,<br/>
und</claim-text>
<claim-text>- eine Quantisierungseinheit (800d), die dafür eingerichtet ist, ein adaptives Quantisierungsschema zweiter Ebene zu bilden <b>durch</b> Umsetzung der identifizierten Cluster in Quantisierungszellen zweiter Ebene und <b>durch</b> Zuweisen von repräsentativen Parameterwerten zu jeder Quantisierungszelle zweiter Ebene, wobei die repräsentativen Parameterwerte zum Analysieren (804) der Benutzer verwendet werden.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Datenverarbeitungseinheit nach Anspruch 7, ferner mit einer ersten Datenspeichereinrichtung (C1), die dafür eingerichtet ist, die Quantisierungszellen erster Ebene mit zellenbelegenden Benutzern zu speichern, und einer zweiten Datenspeichereinrichtung (C2), die dafür eingerichtet ist, die Bildung von Quantisierungszellen zweiter Ebene mit zugewiesenen repräsentativen Parameterwerten zu speichern.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Datenverarbeitungseinheit nach Anspruch 7 oder 8, wobei die Betriebsfunktionen in der Parameterleseeinheit (800a), der Zellenbelegungseinheit (800b) und der Clusteridentifizierungseinheit (800c) zum Lesen von Parameterwerten, zum Bestimmen von Quantisierungszellen erster Ebene beziehungsweise zum Identifizieren von Clustern jeweils über mehrere parallel arbeitende Verarbeitungsinstanzen verteilt werden.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Datenverarbeitungseinheit nach Anspruch 9, wobei die Arbeitsverteilung auf den MSISDN-Zahlenreihen der Benutzer beruht.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Datenverarbeitungseinheit nach Anspruch 9, wobei die Arbeitsverteilung auf der aktuellen Lastverteilung in den Verarbeitungsinstanzen beruht.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Datenverarbeitungseinheit nach einem der Ansprüche 7 bis 11, wobei die Clusteridentifizierungseinheit (800c) ferner dafür eingerichtet ist, die Cluster gemäß einer<!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --> vorher definierten Clusterbildungsbedingung zu identifizieren, die vorschreibt, wann eine mit Benutzern belegte Quantisierungszelle erster Ebene zu einem Cluster gehört.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Datenverarbeitungseinheit nach Anspruch 12, wobei die vorher definierte Clusterbildungsbedingung vorschreibt, dass eine mit Benutzern belegte Zelle zu einem Cluster gehört, wenn sie mindestens an eine mit Benutzern belegte Nachbarzelle angrenzt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Datenverarbeitungseinheit nach Anspruch 13, wobei die Zellenbelegungseinheit (800b) ferner dafür eingerichtet ist, einen Zähler einer Quantisierungszelle erster Ebene immer dann zu inkrementieren, wenn diese Zelle durch einen Benutzer belegt wird, und der vorher definierte Clusterbildungsbedingung ferner vorschreibt, dass eine mit Benutzern belegte Quantisierungszelle erster Ebene zu einem Cluster gehört, wenn die Anzahl der Benutzer, die die Zelle belegen, einen vorher festgelegten Belegungsschwellenwert erreicht.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Datenverarbeitungseinheit nach einem der Ansprüche 7 bis 14, wobei die Clusteridentifizierungseinheit (800c) ferner dafür eingerichtet ist, Cluster von Quantisierungszellen erster Ebene zu identifizieren, wenn dies durch irgendeines von Folgendem ausgelöst wird: eine vorher festgelegte Zeitdauer ist abgelaufen, eine vorher festgelegte Menge von Parameterwerte-Sätzen ist gelesen worden, und eine vorher festgelegte Menge von Quantisierungszellen erster Ebene ist mit Benutzern belegt worden.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0016" num="0016"><claim-text>Datenverarbeitungseinheit nach einem der Ansprüche 7 bis 15, wobei die Quantisierungseinheit (800d) ferner dafür eingerichtet ist, jeder Quantisierungszelle zweiter Ebene einen oder mehr der folgenden Parameterwerte zuzuweisen: einen Satz von Parameter-Mittelwerten, (X, Y) und einen oder mehr Sätze von Parameter-Grenzwerten (X<sub>A</sub>-X<sub>B</sub>, Y<sub>A</sub>-Y<sub>B</sub>,...), die die äußeren Grenzen von Parameterwerten definieren, die durch die entsprechenden identifizierten Cluster abgedeckt werden.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56983608" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A method of handling data related to users in a telecommunication network to support analysis of said users, comprising the step:
<claim-text>- reading (600) sets of parameter values obtained from traffic data of said users, each parameter value set being valid for a particular user and comprising values of two or more user-related parameters, and being <b>characterized by</b> the steps:</claim-text>
<claim-text>- determining (602) a first level quantization cell for each read set of parameter values according to a default first level quantization scheme, thereby populating first level quantization cells with users,</claim-text>
<claim-text>- identifying (606) clusters of first level quantization cells populated by users,</claim-text>
<claim-text>- forming (608) an adaptive second level quantization scheme by translating the identified clusters into second level quantization cells, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>- assigning (610) representative parameter values to each second level quantization cell, wherein the representative parameter values are used for analysing the users.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>A method according to claim 1, wherein said first level quantization cells with populating users are stored in a first data storage (C1), and said formation of second level quantization cells with assigned representative parameter values are stored in a second data storage (C2).<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>A method according to claim 1 or 2, wherein the work of reading parameter values, determining first level quantization cells, and identifying clusters, is distributed over plural processing entities operating in parallel.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>A method according to any of claims 1-3, wherein said clusters are identified according to a predefined clustering condition dictating when a user-populated first level quantization cell belongs to a cluster.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>A method according to any of claims 1-4, wherein the step of identifying clusters of first level quantization cells is triggered by any of: a preset timeout period has expired, a preset amount of parameter value sets have been read, and a preset amount of first level quantization cells have been populated with users.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>A method according to any of claims 1-5, wherein one or more of the following parameter values are assigned to each second level quantization cell: a set of parameter mean values (X,Y) and one or more sets of parameter boundary values (X<sub>A</sub>-X<sub>B</sub>, Y<sub>A</sub>-Y<sub>B</sub>, ...) defining the outer limits of parameter values covered by the corresponding identified cluster.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>A data handling unit (800) configured to handle data related to users in a telecommunication network (802) to support analysis of said users, comprising
<claim-text>- a parameter reading unit (800a) adapted to read sets of parameter values (P) obtained from traffic data of said users, each parameter value set being valid for a<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> particular user and comprising values of two or more user-related parameters, and being <b>characterized by</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>- a cell populating unit (800b) adapted to populate first level quantization cells with users according to a default first level quantization scheme by determining a first level quantization cell for each read set of parameter values,</claim-text>
<claim-text>- a cluster identifying unit (800c) adapted to identify clusters of first level quantization cells populated by users, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>- a quantization unit (800d) adapted to form an adaptive second level quantization scheme by translating the identified clusters into second level quantization cells and assigning representative parameter values to each second level quantization cell, wherein the representative parameter values are used for analysing (804) the users.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>A data handling unit according to claim 7, further comprising a first data storage (C1) adapted to store said first level quantization cells with populating users, and a second data storage (C2) adapted to store the formation of second level quantization cells with assigned representative parameter values.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>A data handling unit according to claim 7 or 8, wherein the operational functions in the parameter reading unit (800a), the cell populating unit (800b) and the cluster identifying unit (800c) for reading parameter values, determining first level quantization cells, and identifying clusters, respectively, is distributed over plural processing entities operating in parallel.<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>A data handling unit according to claim 9, wherein said<br/>
work distribution is based on the users' MSISDN number series.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>A data handling unit according to claim 9, wherein said work distribution is based on the current load distribution in said processing entities.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>A data handling unit according to any of claims 7-11,<br/>
wherein the cluster identifying unit (800c) is further adapted to identify said clusters according to a predefined clustering condition dictating when a user-populated first level quantization cell belongs to a cluster.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>A data handling unit according to claim 12, wherein the<br/>
predefined clustering condition dictates that a user-populated cell belongs to a cluster when bordering at least one user-populated neighbour cell.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>A data handling unit according to claim 13, wherein the<br/>
cell populating unit (800b) is further adapted to increment a counter of a first level quantization cell whenever that cell is populated by a user, and the predefined clustering condition further dictates that a user-populated first level quantization cell belongs to a cluster when the number of users populating the cell reaches a preset population threshold.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>A data handling unit according to any of claims 7-14,<br/>
wherein the cluster identifying unit (800c) is further<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --> adapted to identify clusters of first level quantization cells when triggered by any of: a preset timeout period has expired, a preset amount of parameter value sets have been read, and a preset amount of first level quantization cells have been populated with users.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0016" num="0016"><claim-text>A data handling unit according to any of claims 7-15,<br/>
wherein the quantization unit (800d) is further adapted to assign one or more of the following parameter values to each second level quantization cell: a set of parameter mean values (X,Y), and one or more sets of parameter boundary values (X<sub>A</sub>-X<sub>B</sub>, Y<sub>A</sub>-Y<sub>B</sub>, <b>...)</b> defining the outer limits of parameter values covered by the corresponding identified cluster.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56983609" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Procédé de gestion de données associées à des utilisateurs dans un réseau de télécommunication pour prendre en charge une analyse desdits utilisateurs, comprenant l'étape :
<claim-text>- de lecture (600) d'ensembles de valeurs de paramètre obtenues à partir de données de trafic desdits utilisateurs, chaque ensemble de valeurs de paramètre étant valide pour un utilisateur particulier et comprenant des valeurs de deux paramètres associés à un utilisateur ou plus, et étant <b>caractérisé par</b> les étapes :</claim-text>
<claim-text>- de détermination (602) d'une cellule de quantification de premier niveau pour chaque ensemble lu de valeurs de paramètre selon un schéma de quantification de premier niveau par défaut, peuplant de ce fait les cellules de quantification de premier niveau avec des utilisateurs,</claim-text>
<claim-text>- d'identification (606) de groupes de cellules de quantification de premier niveau peuplées par des utilisateurs,</claim-text>
<claim-text>- de formation (608) d'une méthode de quantification de deuxième niveau adaptative en transformant les groupes identifiés en des cellules de quantification de deuxième niveau, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>- d'attribution (610) de valeurs de paramètre représentatives à chaque cellule de quantification de deuxième niveau, dans lequel les valeurs de paramètre représentatives sont utilisées pour analyser les utilisateurs.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, dans lequel lesdites cellules de quantification de premier niveau peuplées avec des utilisateurs sont mémorisées dans une première mémoire de données (C1), et ladite formation de cellules de quantification de deuxième niveau avec des valeurs de paramètre représentatives attribuées est mémorisée dans une deuxième mémoire de données (C2).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1 ou 2, dans lequel la tâche de lecture de valeurs de paramètre, de détermination de cellules de quantification de premier niveau et d'identification de groupes est répartie sur plusieurs entités de traitement fonctionnant en parallèle.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 3, dans lequel lesdits groupes sont identifiés conformément à une condition de groupement prédéfinie prescrit quand une cellule de quantification de premier niveau peuplée avec des utilisateurs appartient à un groupe.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 4, dans lequel l'étape d'identification de groupes de cellules de quantification de premier niveau est déclenchée par l'un quelconque des cas suivants : une période de dépassement de délai prédéterminée a expiré, une quantité prédéterminée d'ensembles de valeurs de paramètre a été lue et une quantité prédéterminée de cellules de quantification de premier niveau a été peuplée avec des utilisateurs.<!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 5, dans lequel une ou plusieurs des valeurs de paramètre qui suivent sont attribuées à chaque cellule de quantification de deuxième niveau : un ensemble de valeurs moyennes de paramètre (X, Y) et un ou plusieurs ensembles de valeurs de frontière de paramètre (X<sub>A</sub>-X<sub>B</sub>, Y<sub>A</sub>-Y<sub>B</sub>, ...) définissant les limites extérieures des valeurs de paramètre couvertes par les groupes identifiés correspondants.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Unité de gestion de données (800) configurée pour gérer des données associées à des utilisateurs dans un réseau de télécommunication (802) pour prendre en charge une analyse desdits utilisateurs, comprenant :
<claim-text>- une unité de lecture de paramètre (800a) conçue pour lire des ensembles de valeurs de paramètre (P) obtenues à partir de données de trafic desdits utilisateurs, chaque ensemble de valeurs de paramètre étant valide pour un utilisateur particulier et comprenant des valeurs de deux paramètres associés à un utilisateur ou plus, et étant <b>caractérisée par</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>- une unité de peuplement de cellule (800b) conçue pour peupler des cellules de quantification de premier niveau avec des utilisateurs selon une méthode de quantification de premier niveau par défaut en déterminant une cellule de quantification de premier niveau pour chaque ensemble lu de valeurs de paramètre,</claim-text>
<claim-text>- une unité d'identification de groupe (800c) conçue pour identifier des groupes de cellules de quantification de premier niveau peuplées par des utilisateurs, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>- une unité de quantification (800d) conçue pour former une méthode de quantification de deuxième niveau adaptative en transformant les groupes identifiés en des cellules de quantification de deuxième niveau et en attribuant des valeurs de paramètre représentatives à chaque cellule de quantification de deuxième niveau, dans laquelle les valeurs de paramètre représentatives sont utilisées pour analyser (804) les utilisateurs.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Unité de gestion de données selon la revendication 7, comprenant en outre une première mémoire de données (C1) conçue pour mémoriser lesdites cellules de quantification de premier niveau peuplées avec des utilisateurs, et une deuxième mémoire de données (C2) conçue pour mémoriser la formation de cellules de quantification de deuxième niveau avec des valeurs de paramètre représentatives attribuées.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Unité de gestion de données selon la revendication 7 ou 8, dans laquelle les fonctions opérationnelles dans l'unité de lecture de paramètre (800a), l'unité de peuplement de cellule (800b) et l'unité d'identification de groupe (800c) pour lire des valeurs de paramètre, déterminer des cellules de quantification de premier niveau et identifier des groupes, respectivement, sont réparties sur plusieurs entités de traitement fonctionnant en parallèle.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Unité de gestion de données selon la revendication 9, dans laquelle ladite répartition des tâches est basée sur le numéro de série MSISDN des utilisateurs.<!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Unité de gestion de données selon la revendication 9, dans laquelle ladite répartition des tâches est basée sur la répartition des charges actuelles dans lesdites entités de traitement.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Unité de gestion de données selon l'une quelconque des revendications 7 à 11, dans laquelle l'unité d'identification de groupe (800c) est en outre conçue pour identifier lesdits groupes conformément à une condition de groupement prédéfinie prescrivant quand une cellule de quantification de premier niveau peuplée d'utilisateurs appartient à un groupe.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Unité de gestion de données selon la revendication 12, dans laquelle la condition de groupement prédéfinie prescrit qu'une cellule peuplée avec des utilisateurs appartient à un groupe lorsqu'elle a une frontière commune avec au moins une cellule voisine peuplée avec des utilisateurs.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Unité de gestion de données selon la revendication 13, dans laquelle l'unité de peuplement de cellule (800b) est en outre conçue pour incrémenter un compteur d'une cellule de quantification de premier niveau à chaque fois que la cellule est peuplée par un utilisateur, et la condition de groupement prédéfinie prescrit en outre qu'une cellule de quantification de premier niveau peuplée avec des utilisateurs appartient à un groupe lorsque le nombre d'utilisateurs peuplant la cellule atteint un seuil de population prédéterminé.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Unité de gestion de données selon l'une quelconque des revendications 7 à 14, dans laquelle l'unité d'identification de groupe (800c) est en outre conçue pour identifier des groupes de cellules de quantification de premier niveau lors d'un déclenchement par l'un quelconque des cas suivants : une période de dépassement de délai prédéterminée a expiré, une quantité prédéterminée d'ensembles de valeurs de paramètre ont été lus, et une quantité prédéterminée de cellules de quantification de premier niveau ont été peuplées avec des utilisateurs.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0016" num="0016"><claim-text>Unité de gestion de données selon l'une quelconque des revendications 7 à 15, dans laquelle l'unité de quantification (800d) est en outre conçue pour attribuer une ou plusieurs des valeurs de paramètre qui suivent à chaque cellule de quantification de deuxième niveau : un ensemble de valeurs moyennes de paramètre (X, Y), et un ou plusieurs ensembles de valeurs de frontière de paramètre (X<sub>A</sub>-X<sub>B</sub>, Y<sub>A</sub>-Y<sub>B</sub>, ...) définissant les limites extérieures des valeurs de paramètre couvertes par le groupe identifié correspondant.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16671599" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1,2"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="165" he="197" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="36"> --><figure id="f0002" num="3,4"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="158" he="177" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="37"> --><figure id="f0003" num="5"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="165" he="228" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="38"> --><figure id="f0004" num="6,7"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="160" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="39"> --><figure id="f0005" num="8"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="165" he="122" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
