<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2465000-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2465000" kind="B1" date="20140101" family-id="43824228" file-reference-id="315053" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146553026" ucid="EP-2465000-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2465000</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-10814679-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154826949" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>10814679</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20100728</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140445353" ucid="US-2010043473-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>2010043473</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20100728</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140452750" ucid="US-53831009-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>53831009</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20090810</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130725</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988112480" load-source="docdb">G02B   7/08        20060101AFI20120222BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988112785" load-source="docdb">G02B   7/09        20060101ALI20120222BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988122644" load-source="docdb">G02B   7/06        20060101ALI20120222BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988129985" load-source="docdb">G02B  23/12        20060101ALI20120222BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988136891" load-source="docdb">G02B   7/28        20060101ALI20120222BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2081233470" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G02B   7/08        20130101 LI20140606BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2081241926" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G02B  23/125       20130101 LI20140606BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2091556004" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G02B   7/287       20130101 LI20140627BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2091558828" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G02B   7/28        20130101 FI20140627BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2091564240" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G02B  23/00        20130101 LA20140624BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2091565344" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G02B   7/09        20130101 LI20140626BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132191562" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">SYSTEM UND VERFAHREN FÜR BINÄRE FOKUSSIERUNG IN NACHTSICHTGERÄTEN</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132191563" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">A SYSTEM AND METHOD FOR BINARY FOCUS IN NIGHT VISION DEVICES</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132191564" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">SYSTÈME ET PROCÉDÉ POUR UN FOYER BINAIRE DANS DES DISPOSITIFS DE VISION NOCTURNE</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918132428" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>EXELIS INC</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918164730" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>Exelis Inc.</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918137166" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>DOBBIE BLAIR REUBEN</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918164249" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>DOBBIE, BLAIR, REUBEN</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918996028" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>DOBBIE, BLAIR, REUBEN</last-name><address><street>2011 Springfield Drive</street><city>Roanoke, VA 24102</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918996030" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Exelis Inc.</last-name><iid>101305021</iid><address><street>1650 Tysons Boulevard, Suite 1700</street><city>McLean, VA 22102</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918996029" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Dreiss</last-name><iid>101251117</iid><address><street>Patentanwälte Gerokstrasse 1</street><city>70188 Stuttgart</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="US-2010043473-W"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2010043473</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20100728</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2011059536-A2"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2011059536</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20110519</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548852288" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS548964031" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS548852289" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS548880936" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS548972026" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS548965608" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS548964032" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS548852290" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548965609" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS548965610" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS548964580" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS548880937" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS548880938" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548852291" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548965611" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS548852292" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS548964033" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS548972027" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS548852293" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS548880939" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS548965612" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS548973966" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS548964034" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS548973967" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS548973968" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS548826280" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS548826281" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS548964035" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS548852294" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS548965613" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS548973969" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS548964036" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS548964037" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS548973970" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS548852295" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS548965618" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS548826294" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63957036" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001">FIELD OF INVENTION</heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to a binary focus mechanism for use with an optical device, particularly suited for night vision goggle applications.</p><heading id="h0002">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">Night vision systems are used in a wide variety of military, industrial and residential applications to enable sight in a dark environment. For example, night vision systems are utilized by military aviators during nighttime flights or military soldiers patrolling the ground. As another example, security cameras use night vision systems to monitor dark areas.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">conventional image intensified night vision equipment utilize an image intensifier (I<sup>2</sup>) to amplify a low light level (LL) scene. The image intensifier collects tiny amounts of light in a dark environment, including the lower portion of the infrared light spectrum, that are present in the environment but may be imperceptible to the human eye. The image intensifier amplifies the light so that the human eye can perceive the image. The light output from the image intensifier can either be supplied to a camera or directly to the eyes of the viewer. Image intensifier devices are commonly used in night vision goggles, i.e., a monocular or binocular, that are worn on a user's head for transmission of light output directly to the viewer.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">Night vision systems typically do not include an autofocus device. Conventional autofocus devices include an objective lens, an electronic imaging device (such as a charge coupled device (CCD) or complementary metal oxide semiconductor (CMOS) circuit), an electro-mechanical driver for positioning the objective lens relative to the imaging device and an electronic processor that performs real-time image analysis. In operation, the electronic processor determines a suitable focus adjustment based on the real-time image analysis. The electronic processor sends focus commands to the electro-mechanical driver to position the objective lens for optimal focusing of the image.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p><p id="p0005" num="0005">Because the processor is continually analyzing the image, and may adjust the objective lens over a wide range of focus positions, continuous electrical power is generally used by the autofocus components. In a conventional application, the power provided to the autofocus components may represent a significant percentage of the available power. For applications that are carried by an individual and are battery operated, the total operating time from a single battery charge may be strongly influenced by the power consumption by the autofocus device. In addition, the weight of existing autofocus devices, in particular, the weight of the electro-mechanical driver and battery components, tends to reduce the mobility of the observer.<br/>
<patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="JP07092395B"><text>JP 07 092 395</text></patcit> and <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="US6992275B"><text>US 6, 992, 275</text></patcit> disclose conventional night vision devices.</p><heading id="h0003">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading><p id="p0006" num="0006">The present invention relates to a focusing device for use with a night vision optical device. The focusing device includes an objective lens assembly positioned at a first or second focus position from an imaging device and a binary focus controller, coupled to the objective lens assembly, configured to translate the objective lens assembly relative to the imaging device to either the first or second focus position. The objective lens assembly is translated to either the first or second focus position in response to an orientation of the night vision optical device.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">The present invention also relates to a night vision optical device. The night vision optical device includes an objective lens assembly positioned at a first or second focus Position from an imaging device and a binary focus controller, coupled to the objective lens assembly. The binary focus controller includes a line of sight (LOS) sensor coupled to the night vision optical device, configured to detect an orientation of the night vision optical device relative to a horizontal LOS and a focus selector for selecting either the first or second focus position in response to the detected orientation of the night vision optical device. The binary focus controller is configured to translate the objective lens assembly relative to the imaging device to either the first or second focus position responsive to the focus selector.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">The present invention also relates to a method for controlling a focal position of an objective lens assembly positioned from an imaging device in a night vision optical device. The method includes detecting an orientation of the night vision optical device relative to a horizontal line of sight (LOS), selecting either a first or second focus position in response to the detected orientation of the night vision optical device and translating the objective lens assembly relative to the imaging device to the selected focus position.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p><heading id="h0004">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading><p id="p0009" num="0009">The invention may be understood from the following detailed description when read in connection with the accompanying drawing. Included in the drawing are the following figures:</p><p id="p0010" num="0010"><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a block diagram illustrating a position of a focal plane relative to an objective lens for objects at different distances from the objective lens;</p><p id="p0011" num="0011"><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> is a cross-section diagram of a focusing device according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention;</p><p id="p0012" num="0012"><figref idrefs="f0003">FIGS. 3A</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0004">3B</figref> are cross-section diagrams of the focusing device shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> as part of a night vision optical device, illustrating binary positioning of the objective lens assembly for distant and near objects, respectively, according to exemplary embodiments of the present invention;</p><p id="p0013" num="0013"><figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 4</figref> is a block diagram of a binary focus controller included in the focusing device shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>, according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention;</p><p id="p0014" num="0014"><figref idrefs="f0006">FIGS. 5A</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0007">5B</figref> are flow charts illustrating exemplary methods of binary positioning of an objective lens assembly, according to embodiments of the present invention;</p><p id="p0015" num="0015"><figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 6A</figref> is a block diagram of a night vision optical device, according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention;</p><p id="p0016" num="0016"><figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 6B</figref> is a block diagram of a night vision optical device, according to another exemplary embodiment of the present invention;</p><p id="p0017" num="0017"><figref idrefs="f0010">FIG. 7A</figref> is a cross-section diagram of a line of sight (LOS) sensor included in the binary focus controller shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 4</figref>, according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention;</p><p id="p0018" num="0018"><figref idrefs="f0011">FIGS. 7B and 7C</figref> are side view diagrams of the LOS sensor shown in <figref idrefs="f0010">FIG. 7A</figref>, illustrating examples of sensor orientation relative to an orientation of a night vision optical device for far and near focus positions, respectively, according to exemplary embodiments of the present invention;<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p><p id="p0019" num="0019"><figref idrefs="f0012">FIG. 8A</figref> is a circuit diagram of a tilt angle detector included in the LOS sensor shown in <figref idrefs="f0010">FIG. 7A</figref>, according to an exemplary embodiment of the present invention;</p><p id="p0020" num="0020"><figref idrefs="f0012">FIG. 8B</figref> is a perspective diagram of a tilt angle detector in the LOS sensor shown in <figref idrefs="f0010">FIG. 7A</figref>, according to another exemplary embodiment of the present invention;</p><p id="p0021" num="0021"><figref idrefs="f0013">FIG. 9A</figref> is a perspective diagram of a line of sight (LOS) sensor included in the binary focus controller shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 4</figref>, according to another exemplary embodiment of the present invention;</p><p id="p0022" num="0022"><figref idrefs="f0013">FIGS. 9B and 9C</figref> are side view diagrams of the LOS sensor shown in <figref idrefs="f0013">FIG. 9A</figref> coupled to a night vision optical device, illustrating examples of sensor orientation relative to an orientation of a night vision optical device for far and near focus positions, respectively, according to exemplary embodiments of the present invention;</p><p id="p0023" num="0023"><figref idrefs="f0014">FIGS. 10A and 10B</figref> are circuit diagrams of a lens positioner included in the binary focus controller shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 4</figref>, according to exemplary embodiments of the present invention; and</p><p id="p0024" num="0024"><figref idrefs="f0015">FIGS. 11A</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0016">11B</figref> are cross-sectional diagrams of the binary focus controller shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 4</figref>, according to another exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</p><heading id="h0005">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading><p id="p0025" num="0025">The invention will next be illustrated with reference to the figures. Such figures are intended to be illustrative rather than limiting and are included herewith to facilitate explanation of the present invention. The figures are not to scale, and are not intended to serve as engineering drawings.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, a block diagram illustrating a position of a focal plane (FP) FP<sub>1</sub> (or FP<sub>2</sub>) relative to objective lens 102 for object 104 (or object 104') at different distances from the objective lens. Objective lens 102 represents a general objective lens, and may include one or more optical lens elements. In general, objective lens 102 passes light rays 106 (or light rays 108) from object 104.(or object 104') and produces light rays 106' (or light rays 108') that converge onto FP<sub>1</sub> (or FP<sub>2</sub>). The focal plane represents the position of the focused image of an object. Typically, the focal plane represents the position of an imaging device (not shown), such as a CCD detector, a CMOS detector, or an image intensifier.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></p><p id="p0027" num="0027">In <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> two different conditions for focusing are illustrated. A first condition corresponds to object 104 located far from objective lens 102. Object 104 is illustrated as being located far enough away from objective lens 102 to be considered to be at optical infinity. Light rays 106 from object 104 are generally parallel light rays as they reach objective lens 102. Light rays 106 pass through objective lens 102 to form light rays 106' that converge at FP<sub>1</sub>. The FP<sub>1</sub> is located at a back focus distance (BFD) of BFD<sub>1</sub>.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">A second condition corresponds to object 104' located near objective lens 102. Object 104' is illustrated as being relatively close to objective lens 102 (i.e., not at infinity) to produce light rays 108 that diverge as they reach objective lens 102. Light rays 108 pass through objective lens 102 to form light rays 108' that converge at FP<sub>2</sub>. The FP<sub>2</sub> is located at BFD<sub>2</sub>. It may be appreciated that the first focal plane FP<sub>1</sub> is closer to objective lens 102 as compared with the second focal plane FP<sub>2</sub> and that objects 104, 104' are brought to focus at different back focus distances BFD<sub>1</sub>, BFD<sub>2</sub> in the image space of objective lens 102.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">Referring next to <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>, there is shown a focusing device for providing binary focusing, generally designated as 200. Focusing device 200 may be used in a night vision optical device, such as night vision optical device 300 (shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3A</figref>). Focusing device 200 includes objective lens assembly 202, imaging device 204, and binary focus controller 206. Imaging device 204 is coupled to housing 208. Objective lens assembly 202 is mounted to lens translation mechanism 210 that is also coupled to the housing. Thus, the objective lens assembly 202 translates along translation direction T relative to imaging device 204 via lens translation mechanism 210.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">In operation, binary focus controller 206 determines an orientation of a night vision optical device (such as night vision optical device 300 (<figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3A</figref>)) and translates objective lens assembly 202 relative to imaging device 204 to one of two discrete focus positions.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">In general, objective lens assembly 202 may include one or several optical power elements, such as lens elements and/or mirrors, that are at fixed positions relative to each other within the overall objective lens assembly. Thus, lens translation mechanism 210 is illustrated as translating the entire objective lens assembly 202 relative to imaging device 204. According to another exemplary embodiment, objective lens assembly 202 may include one or more optical power elements that move relative to other optical power elements, in order to adjust the back focal distance to imaging device 204. In this embodiment, lens translation mechanism 210 may translate one or several<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> optical power elements relative to other optical power elements within objective lens assembly 202, in order to provide the binary focusing described further below.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">Imaging device 204 may include any suitable device for obtaining an image of an object, such as a CCD detector, a CMOS detector or an image intensifier. Lens translation mechanism 210 may be any suitable mechanism, such as a carriage to translate objective lens assembly 202 relative to imaging device 204. Binary focus controller 206 is described further below with respect to <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 4</figref>.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">Referring next to <figref idrefs="f0003">FIGS. 3A</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0004">3B</figref>, cross-section diagrams of focusing device 200 are shown as being a section A of night vision optical device 300. In particular, <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3A</figref> shows the positioning of objective lens assembly 202 for distant object 302 (at back focal distance D<sub>1</sub>); and <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 3B</figref> illustrates positioning of objective lens assembly 202 for near object 304 (at back focal distance D<sub>2</sub>).</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">In <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3A</figref>, night vision optical device 306 is directed toward distant object 302 with a line of sight (LOS) that is substantially parallel to a horizontal direction 306 (i.e., night vision optical device 300 has a horizontal LOS). In this case, objective lens assembly 202 is positioned at distance D<sub>1</sub> relative to imaging device 204. The distance D<sub>1</sub> represents the first focus position (i.e. a far focus position) for objective lens assembly 202.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">In <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 3B</figref>, night vision optical device 300 is oriented at LOS 308' that is directed to near object 304. The LOS 308', thus, orients night vision optical device 300 at a tilt angle θ relative to horizontal plane 306. In this case, objective lens assembly 202 is positioned at distance D<sub>2</sub> relative to imaging device 204. The distance D<sub>2</sub> represents a second focus position (i.e. a near focus position) of objective lens assembly 202. In this case, it is assumed that the tilt angle θ is greater than a threshold angle (described further below), such that objective lens assembly is positioned at the near focus position.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">According to the present invention, the first and second focus positions are automatically determined by binary focus controller 206, based on the orientation of night vision optical device 300. Accordingly, the first focus position may be selected by binary focus controller 206 when the tilt angle θ is detected to be less than or equal to the predetermined threshold. The second focus position may be selected by binary focus controller 206 when the tilt angle θ is greater than the predetermined threshold. Thus, the present invention has a line of sight sensor that automatically drives objective lens assembly 202 to a near focus position when the LOS is above a predetermined threshold.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p><p id="p0037" num="0037">In a typical scenario, the user/viewer may want an infinity focus when looking along a horizontal LOS at far objects. The infinity focus position of conventional autofocus devices typically allows for clear viewing of far targets and scenes and supports a general mobility task. If the soldier needs to observe a near obstacle, (such as a log or a ditch during movement), however, it is not convenient or feasible to repeatedly manually adjust the focus of the conventional focusing device between a near and far position. In those cases, the soldier typically leaves the focus of conventional focus devices in the far focus position and gets a highly defocused image of the near obstacle when the night vision optical device is momentarily aimed down at the area in front of his feet. In general, a near focus of about five feet (about 1.524 m) (object distance) is typically used in order to support maneuvering around and through obstacles.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">The present invention provides two automatically determined, pre-set objective lens focus positions for a soldier. The present invention automatically selects the first or second focus position, without requiring the soldier to remove his hands from a weapon to adjust the focus. The binary focusing of the present invention may be useful for a dismounted soldier for both viewing of far targets and scenes and for maneuvering around near obstacles.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 4</figref>, an exemplary binary focus controller 206 is shown. Binary focus controller 206 includes LOS sensor 402, focus selector 404 and lens positioner 406. In general LOS sensor 402 uses the Earth's gravity vector to determine the orientation of night vision optical device 300 (<figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3A</figref>). Different example embodiments of LOS sensor 402 are described further below with respect to <figref idrefs="f0011 f0012 f0013">FIGS. 7-9</figref>. As described with respect to <figref idrefs="f0011 f0012 f0013">FIGS. 7-9</figref>, LOS sensor 402 may include electrical and/or mechanical components.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">Focus selector 404 receives tilt angle information from LOS sensor 402, determines the tilt angle θ from the tilt angle information. Focus selector 404 selects either the first or second focus positions based on the instantaneous tilt angle θ. It is understood that focus selector 404 may include an electronic processor and/or mechanical components. An example focus selector 404 that includes pneumatic components is described further below with respect to <figref idrefs="f0015">FIGS. 11A</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0016">11B</figref>. Focus selector 404 provides the selected focus position setting to lens positioner 406 (for example, as a focus command).</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">Lens positioner 406 receives the focus position setting (for example, a focus command) from focus selector 404 and provides a force to control translation of objective lens, via lens translation mechanism 210 (<figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>). An example of lens positioner 406 is<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> described further below with respect to <figref idrefs="f0014">FIGS. 10A and 10B</figref>. Another exemplary embodiment of binary focus controller 206 is described further below with respect to <figref idrefs="f0015">FIGS. 11A</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0016">11B</figref>. It is understood that lens positioner 406 may include electrical and/or mechanical components to translate objective lens assembly 202 (<figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>).</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">Referring next to <figref idrefs="f0006">FIGS. 5A</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0007">5B</figref>, exemplary methods for translating the objective lens assembly 202 (<figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>) relative to imaging device 204 to discrete binary focus positions are shown. In particular, <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 5A</figref> represents an exemplary embodiment for selecting a focus position based on a single threshold; and <figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 5B</figref> represents another exemplary embodiment for selecting a focus position based on two thresholds (threshold<sub>A</sub>, thresholds), thus implementing a hysteresis function.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 5A</figref>, at Step 500, a tilt angle θ is determined, for example, by focus selector 404 (<figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 4</figref>) based on tilt angle information received from LOS sensor 402. At Step 502, it is determined whether the tilt angle θ is less than or equal to a threshold. Although in an exemplary embodiment, the threshold is 40° below horizontal plane 306 (<figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 3B</figref>), it is understood that the threshold may be any suitable threshold for separating near and far focusing conditions for the user.</p><p id="p0044" num="0044">If the tilt angle θ is less than or equal to the threshold, Step 502 proceeds to Step 504. At Step 504, the focus is set to the first focus position (i.e., the far position shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3A</figref>), for example by focus selector 404 (<figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 4</figref>). For example, a focus command may be generated by focus selector 404 (<figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 4</figref>) indicating the first focus position. At Step 506, objective lens assembly 202 (<figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3A</figref>) is translated to the first focus position (at distance D<sub>1</sub>), for example, responsive to the focus command, by lens positioner 406 in conjunction with lens translation mechanism 210 (<figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>). Step 506 proceeds to Step 500.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045">If the tilt angle θ is greater than the threshold, Step 502 proceeds to Step 508. At Step 508, the focus is set to the second focus position (i.e., the near focus position shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 3B</figref>), for example, by focus selector 404 (<figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 4</figref>). For example, a focus command may be generated by focus selector 404 (<figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 4</figref>) indicating the second focus position. At Step 510, objective lens assembly 202 is translated to the second focus position (at distance D<sub>2</sub> shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 3B</figref>), for example, responsive to the focus command, by lens positioner 406 (<figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 4</figref>) in conjunction with lens translation mechanism 210 (<figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>). Step 510 proceeds to Step 500. The process of Steps 500-510 may be continued for updated tilt angle information.<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --></p><p id="p0046" num="0046">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 5B</figref>, at Step 512, the tilt angle θ is determined, for example, by focus selector 404 (<figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 4</figref>) using the tilt angle information received from LOS sensor 402. At Step 514, it is determined whether the tilt angle θ is less than or equal to a first threshold threshold<sub>A</sub>. Although in an exemplary embodiment, the threshold<sub>A</sub> is 40° below horizontal plane 306 (<figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 3B</figref>), it is understood that the first threshold may be any suitable threshold for separating near and far focusing conditions for the user.</p><p id="p0047" num="0047">If it is determined that the tilt angle θ is less or equal to threshold<sub>A</sub>, Step 514 proceeds to Step 516. At Step 516, the focus is set to the first focus position (i.e., the far position shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3A</figref>), for example, by focus selector 404 (<figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 4</figref>). At Step 518, objective lens assembly 202 (<figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3A</figref>) is translated to the first focus position (at distance D<sub>1</sub>), for example by lens positioner 406 (<figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 4</figref>) in conjunction with lens translation mechanism 210 (<figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>). Step 518 proceeds to Step 512.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048">If it is determined that the tilt angle θ is greater than threshold<sub>a</sub>, Step 514 proceeds to Step 520. At Step 520, it is determined whether the tilt angle θ is greater than or equal to a second threshold, threshold<sub>B</sub>. An exemplary embodiment, threshold<sub>b</sub> represents 45° below horizontal plane 306 (<figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 3B</figref>). Although in an exemplary embodiment, the threshold<sub>B</sub> is 45° below horizontal plane 306 (<figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 3B</figref>), it is understood that the second threshold may be any suitable threshold for providing a borderline region separating near and far focusing conditions for the user.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">If the tilt angle θ is greater than or equal to threshold<sub>B</sub>, Step 520 proceeds to Step 526. At Step 526, the focus is set to the second focus position (i.e., the near position shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 3B</figref>), for example, by focus selector 404 (<figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 4</figref>). At Step 528, objective lens assembly 202 (<figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 3B</figref>) is translated to second focus position (at distance D<sub>2</sub>), for example, by lens positioner 406 (<figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 4</figref>) in conjunction with lens translation mechanism 210 (<figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>). Step 528 proceeds to Step 512.</p><p id="p0050" num="0050">If it is determined, at Step 514, that the tilt angle θ is less than threshold<sub>B</sub> (and greater than threshold<sub>A</sub>, Step 514) Step 520 proceeds to Step 522. At Step 522, the focus setting is maintained at its current focus position, for example, by focus selector 404 (<figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 4</figref>). At Step 524, the objective lens assembly 202 is maintained at its current position (either at the first focus position or the second focus position). Step 524 proceeds to Step 512.</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">Steps 520-524 represents a hysteresis function that uses the previously determined focus position for conditions where the tilt angle θ is between threshold<sub>A</sub> and<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> threshold<sub>B</sub>: In this embodiment, the use of two thresholds, threshold<sub>A</sub>, threshold<sub>B</sub> may prevent repeated switching between the near and far lens positions when the LOS 308' (<figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 3B</figref>) is in a borderline orientation between threshold<sub>A</sub> and threshold<sub>B</sub>.</p><p id="p0052" num="0052">Steps 512-528 may be repeated for each detected tilt angle, for example, indefinitely.</p><p id="p0053" num="0053">Referring next to <figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 6A</figref>, a block diagram of an exemplary night vision optical device 300 is shown. Night vision optical device 300 includes objective lens assembly 202, binary focus controller 206, image intensifier 602 and eyepiece lens 604. Night vision optical device 300 may include other components, such as a high voltage power supply (HVPS).</p><p id="p0054" num="0054">Objective lens assembly 202 is positioned by binary focus controller 206 to receives light rays 608 from object 606 for a first or second focus position. Objective lens assembly 202 provides a focused image of a low light level scene to image intensifier 602, which may be powered by a HVPS. Image intensifier 602 amplifies the faint image at its input and reproduces a brighter version of this image on its output surface. This image is coherently transmitted to eyepiece lens 604 for display of the produced image. In <figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 6A</figref>, imaging device 204 is represented by image intensifier 602.</p><p id="p0055" num="0055">Referring next to <figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 6B</figref>, a block diagram of another exemplary night vision optical device 300' is shown. Night vision optical device 300' includes objective lens assembly 202, binary focus controller 206, imaging array 610, video electronics module 612 and video display 614. Night vision optical device 300' is similar to or functionally equivalent to night vision optical device 300, except that device 300' includes imaging array 610 for generating an image of object 606. In addition, device 300' includes video electronics module 612 and video display 614 for producing a real time video image of object 606.</p><p id="p0056" num="0056">Objective lens assembly 202 is positioned by binary focus controller 206 to receives light rays 608 from object 606 for a first or second focus position. Objective lens assembly 202 provides a focused image of a low light level scene to imaging array 610 for video applications. In <figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 6B</figref>, imaging device 204 is represented by imaging array 610. Imaging array 610, which may be, for example, of a CMOS or CCD type, senses the focused image and creates real time video data that contains a rendition of the image. The video data is provided to video electronics module 612 for converting the video data<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> from imaging array 610 into digital video data. Video display 614 receives that digital video data and displays the real time digital video image.</p><p id="p0057" num="0057">Referring next to <figref idrefs="f0010 f0011">FIGS. 7A-7C</figref>, an exemplary LOS sensor 402 is shown. In particular, <figref idrefs="f0010">FIG. 7A</figref> is a cross-section diagram of LOS sensor 402 coupled to a body 702 of night vision optical device 300 (<figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3A</figref>); <figref idrefs="f0011">FIG. 7B</figref> is a side view diagram of LOS sensor 402 for a far focus condition; and <figref idrefs="f0011">FIG. 7C</figref> is a side view diagram of LOS sensor 402 for a near focus condition.</p><p id="p0058" num="0058">In <figref idrefs="f0010 f0011">FIGS. 7A-7C</figref>, LOS sensor 402 includes a pendulum mass 704 rigidly coupled to pendulum arm 706. Pendulum arm 706 is also coupled to tilt angle detector 708. In addition, tilt angle detector 708 is coupled to body 702 of night vision optical device 300 (<figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3A</figref>). Pendulum mass 704 is coupled to body 702 such that pendulum mass 704 is maintained in a position corresponding to the gravity vector g.</p><p id="p0059" num="0059">As can be seen in <figref idrefs="f0011">FIGS. 7B and 7C</figref>, during movement of body 702 relative to the horizontal plane (i.e. the plane of X and Y), the position of pendulum mass 704 is maintained in a direction of gravity vector g. At the same time, the movement of body 702 causes rotation of pendulum arm 706 in rotation direction R relative to the Y axis. Tilt angle detector 708 detects the rotation of pendulum arm 706 and provides tilt angle information. The tilt angle information may be provided to focus selector 404 (<figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 4</figref>). Thus, the pendulum arm 706 rotation provides the tilt angle information.</p><p id="p0060" num="0060">Referring next to <figref idrefs="f0012">FIGS. 8A and 8B</figref>, exemplary tilt angle detectors 708, 708' for use with LOS sensor 402 (<figref idrefs="f0010">FIG. 7A</figref>) are shown. In particular, <figref idrefs="f0012">FIG. 8A</figref> is a circuit diagram of a tilt angle detector 708; and <figref idrefs="f0012">FIG. 8B</figref> is a perspective diagram of another tilt angle detector 708'.</p><p id="p0061" num="0061">In <figref idrefs="f0012">FIG. 8A</figref>, tilt angle detector 708 includes a potentiometer 804, voltage supply 802 and output terminal 808 coupled to potentiometer 804. Pendulum arm 706 is coupled to a wiper 806 of potentiometer 804. Thus, rotation of pendulum arm 706 varies the wiper position and the resulting voltage produced at output terminal 808. The voltage signal at output terminal 808 may be provided to focus selector 404 (<figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 4</figref>). Focus selector 404 may convert the voltage signal to a tilt angle, for example, by a digital look-up table. It is understood that focus selector 404 may be implemented using any suitable digital and/or analog electronics.<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></p><p id="p0062" num="0062">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0012">FIG. 8B</figref>, tilt angle detector 708' may include a magnetic rotational sensor including magnet 810 and magnetic rotary position encoding circuit 812. Pendulum arm 706 may be coupled to magnet 810. Rotation R of pendulum arm 706 may produce a pendulum position signal via encoding circuit 812. The pendulum position signal may be provided to focus selector 404, which may convert the position signal to a tilt angle, for example via a look-up table. Potentiometers and encoding circuits are known in the art and may be understood by the skilled person. It is understood that tilt angle detectors 708, 708' represent two exemplary embodiments for detecting an orientation of night vision optical device 300 (<figref idrefs="f0008 f0009">FIG. 6</figref>) relative to the horizontal plane 306 (<figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3A</figref>) and that other suitable tilt angle detectors may be used.</p><p id="p0063" num="0063">Referring now to <figref idrefs="f0013">FIGS. 9A-9C</figref>, another exemplary LOS sensor 402' is shown. In particular, <figref idrefs="f0013">FIG. 9A</figref> is a perspective diagram of a three-axis accelerometer 900 that is used as LOS sensor 402'. <figref idrefs="f0013">FIGS. 9B and 9C</figref> are examples illustrating the orientation of accelerometer 900 with respect to gravity vector g at far and near focus conditions, respectively.</p><p id="p0064" num="0064">Accelerometer 900 may be any suitable Micro-Electro-Mechanical system (MEMS) that may collect data along three axes X', Y' and Z' to detect gravity vector g. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0013">FIGS. 9B and 9C</figref>, accelerometer 900 is coupled to body 702 of night vision optical system 300 (<figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3A</figref>). Although not shown, accelerometer 900 may include other components, such as a preamplifier and/or filters having suitable filter coefficients to detect the gravity vector g. Accelerometer 900 provides a position signal (including X', Y' and Z' axis data) to focus selector 404 (<figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 4</figref>), which represents the tilt angle information.</p><p id="p0065" num="0065">For example, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0013">FIG. 9B</figref>, body 702 is oriented to the far focus position (i.e., having a horizontal LOS). When body 702 is moved to the far focus position, only the Z' axis data may contribute to the position signal. Accordingly, accelerometer 900 may produce: X' axis data of 0 m/s<sup>2</sup>, Y' axis data of 0 m/s<sup>2</sup> and a Z' axis data of 9.8 m/s<sup>2</sup>.</p><p id="p0066" num="0066">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0013">FIG. 9C</figref>, when body 702 is moved from the far focus condition (<figref idrefs="f0013">FIG. 9B</figref>) to the near focus condition, acceleration data from the Z' axis, as well the acceleration data from the X' axis and/or Y' axis may contribute to the position signal. For example, accelerometer 900 may produce: X' axis data of 6.93 m/s<sup>2</sup>. Z' axis data of 6.93 m/s<sup>2</sup> and Y' axis of 0 m/s<sup>2</sup>. The acceleration data produced by the X', Y' and Z' axes may be used to determine the tilt angle.<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --></p><p id="p0067" num="0067">Referring next to <figref idrefs="f0014">FIGS. 10A and 10B</figref>, circuit diagrams of exemplary lens positioner 406 for translating objective lens assembly 202 (<figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>) based on electrostatic charge is shown. In particular, <figref idrefs="f0014">FIG. 10A</figref> illustrates the circuit diagram to produce the far focus position translation; and <figref idrefs="f0014">FIG. 10B</figref> illustrates the circuit diagram to produce near focus position translation.</p><p id="p0068" num="0068">Lens positioner 406 includes electrically charged plates 1002-1 and 1002-2 that are respectively coupled to lens translation mechanism 210 (<figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>) and housing 208. Plates 1002 are provided with the same or opposite charges in order to produce a force F<sub>1</sub> or F<sub>2</sub> to translate objective lens assembly 202 (<figref idrefs="f0003">FIGS. 3A</figref>, <figref idrefs="f0004">3B</figref>) to respective back focus distances D<sub>1</sub>, D<sub>2</sub>. In order to apply the appropriate charge to plates 1002, lens positioner 406 includes HVPS 1006 and switch 1004. The position of switch 1004 may be set based on focus selector 404 (<figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 4</figref>). It is understood that an appropriate force F<sub>1</sub>, F<sub>2</sub> may be determined to translate objective lens assembly 202 (<figref idrefs="f0003">FIGS. 3A</figref>, <figref idrefs="f0004">3B</figref>) based on the desired back focal distances D<sub>1</sub>,D<sub>2</sub>.</p><p id="p0069" num="0069">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0014">FIG. 10A</figref>, switch 1004 is set to a first position, causing plates 1002-1 and 1002-2 to be oppositely charged. Because plates 1002 are oppositely charged, they are attracted to each other, causing an attraction force F<sub>1</sub>. The attraction force F<sub>1</sub> causes objective lens assembly 202 (<figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3A</figref>) to move to distance D<sub>1</sub>.</p><p id="p0070" num="0070">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0014">FIG. 10B</figref>, switch 1004 is set to a second position, causing plates 1002-1 and 1002-2 to have a same charge (e.g., a negative charge). Because plates 1002 have a same charge, they are repelled from each other, causing an repelling force F<sub>2</sub>. The repelling force F<sub>2</sub> causes objective lens assembly 202 (<figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 3B</figref>) to move to distance D<sub>2</sub>.</p><p id="p0071" num="0071">In an exemplary embodiment, HVPS 1006 may receive an input voltage of 3 V DC (with 10-15 mA) and produce an output voltage of 4-5 kV (with 10-15 nA). It is understood that any suitable power supply may be used to generate the appropriate force F to translate objective lens assembly 202 (<figref idrefs="f0003">FIGS. 3A</figref>, <figref idrefs="f0004">3B</figref>) to the appropriate first and second focus positions (i.e., to back focal distances D<sub>1</sub>, D<sub>2</sub>).</p><p id="p0072" num="0072">Referring next to <figref idrefs="f0015">FIGS. 11A</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0016">11B</figref>, a pneumatically based binary focus controller 206' is shown. In particular, <figref idrefs="f0015">FIG. 11A</figref> is a cross-section diagram of binary focus controller 206' for providing the near focus position (i.e., back focus distance D<sub>2</sub> shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 3B</figref>); and <figref idrefs="f0016">FIG. 11B</figref> is a cross-section diagram of binary focus controller 206' for providing the far focus position (i.e., back focus distance D<sub>1</sub> shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3A</figref>).<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></p><p id="p0073" num="0073">Binary focus controller 206' includes pendulum mass 704 that is coupled to a Pendulum arm at pivot point 1102. Because pendulum mass 704 is also coupled to linkage 1106 at pivot point 1104, pendulum mass 704 provides translation of linkage 1106 in the T<sub>1</sub> direction in response to movement of a night vision optical device 300 (<figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3A</figref>). Linkage 1106 is coupled to first piston 1108 positioned in first cylinder 1110 (i.e. a first pneumatic system). A second linkage 1118 is coupled to second piston 1116 that is positioned in a second cylinder 1112 (i.e. a second pneumatic system). First cylinder 1110 and second cylinder 1112 are pneumatically coupled to each other (i.e., second cylinder 1112 is slave to first cylinder 1110). Linkage 1118 is also coupled to lens translation mechanism 210.</p><p id="p0074" num="0074">Binary focus controller 206' also includes plenum chamber 1114 which receives and stores lightly pressurized air, for example, from a wearable pump (not shown) and which is coupled to first air cylinder 1110. Air cylinder 1110 includes ports open to ambient pressure (P).</p><p id="p0075" num="0075">Linkage 1106 represents a tilt angle detector (such as tilt angle detector 708 (<figref idrefs="f0010">FIG. 7A</figref>)). Linkage 1118, piston 1116 and second air cylinder 1112 represents a lens positioner (such as lens positioner 406 (<figref idrefs="f0008 f0009">FIG. 6</figref>)). First piston 1108 and first air cylinder 1110 represent a focus selector (such as focus selector 404 (<figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 4</figref>)).</p><p id="p0076" num="0076">In operation, the rotation of pendulum mass 704 drives first piston 1108 to one of two Positions in response to the tilt angle θ. When first piston 1108 changes position, pressurized air from plenum chamber 1114 flows to one side of second piston 1116, thus driving second piston 1116 to an opposite end of second cylinder 1112. First piston 1108 allows air from a decreasing volume side of second cylinder 1112 to reach equilibrium with the local ambient pressure, which provides a pressure differential to move second piston 1116. Thus, movement of pendulum mass 704 causes linear translation T<sub>1</sub> of linkage 1106 and also causes translation T<sub>2</sub> of linkage 1118. The translation T<sub>2</sub> of linkage 1118, in turn, translates objective lens assembly 202 to the near focus position (<figref idrefs="f0015">FIG. 11A</figref>) or to the far focus position (<figref idrefs="f0016">FIG. 11B</figref>).</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56978597" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Fokussiervorrichtung, enthaltend:
<claim-text>eine optische Nachtsichteinrichtung (300), die eine Objektivlinsenanordnung (202) und eine Abbildungseinrichtung (204) aufweist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei die Objektivlinsenanordnung (202) an einer ersten oder zweiten Fokusposition von der Abbildungseinrichtung (204) positioniert ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine binäre Fokussteuereinrichtung (206), die mit der Objektivlinsenanordnung (202) gekoppelt ist und dafür konfiguriert ist, die Objektivlinsenanordnung relativ zu der Abbildungseinrichtung entweder in die erste oder in die zweite Fokusposition zu verschieben,</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>gekennzeichnet durch</b>:
<claim-text>die Verschiebung der Objektivlinsenanordnung (202) in Reaktion auf eine Ausrichtung der optischen Nachtsichteinrichtung (300) in entweder die erste oder die zweite Fokusposition;</claim-text><claim-text>wobei die Fokussiervorrichtung ferner einen Pendelarm (706) und eine Pendelmasse (704) aufweist, die über den Pendelarm (706) mit der optischen Nachtsichteinrichtung gekoppelt ist, wobei sich der Pendelarm (706) mit der Pendelmasse (704) in Reaktion auf die Ausrichtung der optischen Nachtsichteinrichtung (300) dreht;<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></claim-text><claim-text>ein erstes Pneumatiksystem (1110), welches einen ersten Kolben (1108) aufweist;</claim-text><claim-text>ein erstes Verbindungsglied (1106), das mit der Pendelmasse (704) gekoppelt ist und ferner mit dem ersten Kolben (1108) des ersten Pneumatiksystems (1110) gekoppelt ist, wobei der erste Kolben (1108) dafür konfiguriert ist, auf der Grundlage einer Drehung der Pendelmasse (704) an einer ersten oder zweiten Position positioniert zu werden;</claim-text><claim-text>ein zweites Pneumatiksystem (1112), welches mit dem ersten Pneumatiksystem (1110) gekoppelt ist, wobei das zweite Pneumatiksystem (1112) einen zweiten Kolben (1116) aufweist, der dafür konfiguriert ist, in Reaktion auf die entsprechende erste oder zweite Position des ersten Kolbens (1108) an einer ersten oder zweiten weiteren Position positioniert zu werden; und</claim-text><claim-text>ein zweites Verbindungsglied (1118), welches mit der Objektivlinsenanordnung (202) und dem zweiten Kolben (1116) gekoppelt ist und dafür konfiguriert ist, die Objektivlinsenanordnung (202) in Reaktion auf die erste oder zweite weitere Position des zweiten Kolbens (1116) in entweder die erste oder die zweite Fokusposition zu verschieben.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Fokussiervorrichtung nach Anspruch 1, bei welcher die erste Fokusposition mit einem Objekt in Zusammenhang steht, das von der Objektivlinsenanordnung (202) entfernt ist, und die zweite Fokusposition mit einem Objekt in Zusammenhang steht, das wesentlich näher an der Objektivlinsenanordnung (202) positioniert ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Fokussiervorrichtung nach Anspruch 1, bei welcher die binäre Fokussteuereinrichtung eine Fokusauswahleinrichtung aufweist, die dafür konfiguriert ist, entweder die erste<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> oder die zweite Fokusposition in Reaktion auf die Ausrichtung der optischen Nachtsichteinrichtung auszuwählen,<br/>
wobei die Objektivlinsenanordnung in Reaktion auf die Fokusauswahleinrichtung entweder in die erste oder die zweite Fokusposition verschoben wird.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56978598" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A focusing device comprising:
<claim-text>a night vision optical device (300) including an objective lens assembly (202) and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an imaging device (204);</claim-text>
<claim-text>the objective lens assembly (202) positioned at a first or second focus position from the imaging device (204); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a binary focus controller (206), coupled to the objective lens assembly (202), configured to translate the objective lens assembly relative to the imaging device to either the first or second focus position,</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>characterized by</b>:
<claim-text>the objective lens assembly (202) being translated to either the first or second focus position in response to an orientation of the night vision optical device (300); the focusing device further comprising a pendulum arm (706) and a pendulum mass (704) coupled to the night vision optical device via the pendulum arm (706), the pendulum arm (706) rotating with the peridulum mass (704) responsive to the orientation of the night vision optical device (300);</claim-text><claim-text>a first pneumatic system (1110) comprising a first piston (1108);</claim-text><claim-text>a first linkage (1106) coupled to the pendulum mass (704) and further coupled to the first piston (1108) of the first pneumatic system (1110), the first piston (1108) configured to be positioned at a first or second position based on a rotation of the pendulum mass (704);</claim-text><claim-text>a second pneumatic system (1112) coupled to the first pneumatic system (1110), the second pneumatic system (1112) including a second piston (1116) configured to be positioned at a first or second further position responsive to the corresponding first or second position of the first piston (1108); and</claim-text><claim-text>a second linkage (1118) coupled to the objective lens assembly (202) and to the second piston (1116), configured to translate the objective lens assembly (202) to either the first or second focus position responsive to the first or second further position of the second piston (1116).</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The focusing device according to claim 1, wherein the first focus position is associated with an object positioned far from the objective lens assembly (202) and the second focus position is associated with the object positioned substantially closer to the objective lens assembly (202).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>A focusing device according to claim 1, wherein the binary focus controller includes a focus selector configured to select either the first or second focus position in response to the orientation of the night vision optical device,<br/>
wherein the objective lens assembly is translated to either the first or second focus position responsive to the focus selector.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56978599" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Dispositif de mise au point comportant:
<claim-text>un dispositif optique de vision nocturne (300) comprenant un ensemble de lentilles d'objectif (202) et un dispositif d'imagerie (204);</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'ensemble de lentilles d'objectif (202) étant positionné dans une première ou dans une seconde position de mise au point à partir du dispositif de d'imagerie (204); et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un contrôleur de mise au point binaire (206), couplé à l'ensemble de lentilles d'objectif (202), configuré pour translater l'ensemble de lentilles d'objectif par rapport au dispositif d'imagerie soit dans la première, soit dans la seconde position de mise au point,</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>caractérisé en ce que</b>:
<claim-text>l'ensemble de lentilles d'objectif (202) est translaté dans la première ou dans la seconde position de mise au point en réponse à une orientation du dispositif optique de vision nocturne (300);</claim-text><claim-text>le dispositif de mise au point comportant de plus un bras pendulaire (706) et une masse pendulaire (704) couplée au dispositif optique de vision nocturne par l'intermédiaire du bras pendulaire (706), le bras pendulaire (706) tournant avec la masse pendulaire (704) en réponse à l'orientation du dispositif optique de vision nocturne (300);<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --></claim-text><claim-text>un premier système pneumatique (1110) comportant un premier piston (1108);</claim-text><claim-text>une première tringlerie (1106) couplée à la masse pendulaire (704) et couplée de plus au premier piston (1108) du premier système pneumatique (1110), le premier piston (1108) étant configuré pour être positionné dans une première ou dans une seconde position en fonction d'une rotation de la masse pendulaire (704);</claim-text><claim-text>un second système pneumatique (1112) couplé au premier système pneumatique (1110), le second système pneumatique (1112) comprenant un second piston (1116) configuré pour être positionné dans une première ou seconde position en réponse à la première, ou à la seconde, position correspondante du premier piston (1108); et</claim-text><claim-text>une seconde tringlerie (1118) couplée à l'ensemble de lentilles d'objectif (202) et au second piston (1116), configurée pour translater l'ensemble de lentilles d'objectif (202) soit dans la première, soit dans la seconde position de mise au point en réponse à la première, ou à la seconde, position suivante du second piston (1116).</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Dispositif de mise au point selon la revendication 1, dans lequel la première position de mise au point est associée à un objet positionné loin de l'ensemble de lentilles d'objectif (202), et la seconde position de mise au point est associée à l'objet positionné sensiblement plus proche de l'ensemble de lentille d'objectif (202).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Dispositif de mise au point selon la revendication 1, dans lequel le dispositif de commande de mise au point binaire comprend un sélecteur de mise au point configuré<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> de manière à sélectionner soit la première, soit la deuxième, position de mise au point en réponse à l'orientation du dispositif optique de vision nocturne,<br/>
dans lequel l'ensemble de lentilles d'objectif est translaté soit dans la première, soit dans la seconde, position de mise au point en réponse au sélecteur de mise au point.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16668623" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="110" he="203" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="136" he="85" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3A"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="134" he="140" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --><figure id="f0004" num="3B"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="134" he="133" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --><figure id="f0005" num="4"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="143" he="209" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --><figure id="f0006" num="5A"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="154" he="146" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --><figure id="f0007" num="5B"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="149" he="211" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --><figure id="f0008" num="6A"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="118" he="176" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --><figure id="f0009" num="6B"><img id="if0009" file="imgf0009.tif" wi="119" he="196" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --><figure id="f0010" num="7A"><img id="if0010" file="imgf0010.tif" wi="144" he="169" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --><figure id="f0011" num="7B,7C"><img id="if0011" file="imgf0011.tif" wi="161" he="158" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --><figure id="f0012" num="8A,8B"><img id="if0012" file="imgf0012.tif" wi="160" he="156" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --><figure id="f0013" num="9A,9B,9C"><img id="if0013" file="imgf0013.tif" wi="165" he="145" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --><figure id="f0014" num="10A,10B"><img id="if0014" file="imgf0014.tif" wi="165" he="142" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="36"> --><figure id="f0015" num="11A"><img id="if0015" file="imgf0015.tif" wi="165" he="171" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="37"> --><figure id="f0016" num="11B"><img id="if0016" file="imgf0016.tif" wi="165" he="170" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
