<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2029991-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2029991" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="38790273" file-reference-id="270062" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146588702" ucid="EP-2029991-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2029991</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-07797566-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154850894" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>07797566</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20070518</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140557570" ucid="US-2007069206-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>2007069206</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20070518</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140553372" ucid="US-44576506-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>44576506</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20060602</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130717</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989326395" load-source="ipcr">G01L   1/24        20060101ALI20090127BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989326396" load-source="ipcr">G01L  11/02        20060101AFI20090127BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989620330" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G02B   6/02057     20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989636241" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G02B   6/02042     20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989649670" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G01L  11/025       20130101 FI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370739" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">MULTIKERN-GLASFASERSDRUCKENSOR</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370740" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">MULTI-CORE OPTICAL FIBER PRESSURE SENSOR</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370741" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">CAPTEUR DE PRESSION À FIBRE OPTIQUE À ÂMES MULTIPLES</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919523548" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>BAKER HUGHES INC</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919540824" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>BAKER HUGHES INCORPORATED</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919522014" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>CHILDERS BROOKS</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919545505" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>CHILDERS, BROOKS</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919024343" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>CHILDERS, BROOKS</last-name><address><street>1425 Red Hawk Run</street><city>Christiansburg, VA 24073</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919024344" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Baker Hughes Incorporated</last-name><iid>101074967</iid><address><street>2929 Allen Parkway Suite 2100</street><city>Houston, TX 77019</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919024345" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Mabey, Katherine Frances</last-name><suffix>et al</suffix><iid>100055447</iid><address><street>Dehns St Bride's House 10 Salisbury Square</street><city>London EC4Y 8JD</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="US-2007069206-W"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2007069206</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20070518</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2007143368-A2"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2007143368</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20071213</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549883034" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549805028" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549789433" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549872860" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549925129" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549883035" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549805029" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549925130" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549925131" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549879292" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549789434" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549789435" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549805030" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549925132" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549883036" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549872861" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549925133" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549789436" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549925134" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549787951" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549895646" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549787952" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549787957" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549895647" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549805031" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549787958" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549872866" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549805036" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549787959" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549879293" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549789437" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549925135" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63961121" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001"><b><u>BACKGROUND</u></b></heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">Optical fiber pressure sensors, particularly those utilized in harsh environments, such as in downhole environments, are predominantly plagued by temperature changes and drift sources. Thus, where measurement is attempted, additional sensors have been required to attempt to compensate for such temperature changes, and drift of the measurement. For example, two pressure sensors might be employed near each other having different sensor characteristics (i.e., different responses to the undesired parameter), and calculations may be made in an attempt to eliminate the effect of the parameter on the measurement (effectively in an attempt to isolate the parameter of interest, e.g., temperature effects at the point of interest).</p><p id="p0002" num="0002">While this may appear to be a good solution, conditions at the two sensors must be exact to aocurately eliminate the influences of the undesired parameter. Also, the need to set up and run multiple sensors at every measurement point of Interest can be tedious and costly.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US6218661B"><text>US 6218661</text></patcit> discloses a method and apparatus for mechanically enhancing the sensitivity of transversely loaded fiber optic sensors. <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="US20060013523A"><text>US 2006/0013523</text></patcit> discloses a fiber optic position and shape sensing device. <patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="EP0622622A"><text>EP 0622622</text></patcit> discloses a physical quantity detecting apparatus and internal combustion engine. <patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="US5841131A"><text>US 5841131</text></patcit> discloses a fiber optic pressure transducer. <patcit id="pcit0005" dnum="WO0037914A"><text>WO00/37914</text></patcit> discloses a bragg grating pressure sensor.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">What is needed in the art is a simple, low cost solution to elimination of temperature changes and drift sources in optical fiber pressure sensors.</p><heading id="h0002"><b><u>SUMMARY</u></b></heading><p id="p0005" num="0005">The present invention provides a pressure sensor in accordance with claim 1, and a method of sensing pressure in accordance with claim 9.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">The above-described and other problems and deficiencies of the prior art are overcome and alleviated by the presently described multi-core optical fiber pressure sensor, which includes an optical fiber having at least two cores, wherein the cores have<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> collocated measurement portions, for example, in-tiber interferometers or Bragg grating portions. In an exemplary embodiment, the fiber is arranged such that a pressure induced force will act on the multi-core fiber affecting the collocated measurement portions in a different manner. In another exemplary embodiment, such arrangement causes one grating to be in compression and another to be in tension. In another exemplary embodiment, the fiber is actuated by a pressure sensitive bellows or diaphragm. In another exemplary embodiment, the fiber is actuated by a force normal to the axis of the fiber. In another exemplary embodiment, the fiber is asymmetrically actuated along a longitudinal axis of the fiber.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">In other exemplary embodiments, different portions of the multi-core fiber are engineered to react differently to pressure, and light guiding cores in the collocated measurement portions are configured to sense pressure. In an exemplary embodiment, the fiber contains a lower modulus core near a first light guiding core and a higher modulus core near a second light guiding core. The provision of the multi-core fiber and the differential reaction of the pressure to the fiber portions containing the lower and higher modulus cores, respectively, at the measurement portions of the multiple cores, eliminate temperature changes or drift sources that might otherwise affect the measurements. In another exemplary embodiment, the multi-core fiber comprises at least two cores that have the same doping. In another embodiment, at least two cores are reflective to the same wavelength.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">In other exemplary embodiments, a reference pressure acts on a multi-core fiber in addition to a well bore (or other application) pressure. In such embodiment, the multi-core fiber contains at least two light guiding cores provided in different spatial<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> relationship relative to a hollow core. The hollow core acts as a port causing different pressure induced reactions with regard to the light guiding cores.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">The above-discussed and other features and advantages of the presently described multi-core optical fiber pressure sensor will be appreciated and understood by those skilled in the art from the following detailed description and drawings.</p><heading id="h0003"><b><u>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</u></b></heading><p id="p0010" num="0010"><ul><li>Referring now to the drawings, wherein like elements are numbered alike in the several FIGURES:</li><li><figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURE 1</figref> is a cross-sectional plan view of an exemplary multi-core fiber utilizing Bragg Gratings at a same distance along the fiber;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURE 2</figref> is a cross-sectional plan view of an exemplary multi-core fiber actuated by a push rod and bellows;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">FIGURE 3</figref> is a cross-sectional plan view of an exemplary multi-core fiber actuated by a push rod and diaphragm;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">FIGURE 4</figref> is a cross-sectional plan view of an exemplary multi-core fiber asymmetrically actuated by a push rod and diaphragm;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">FIGURE 5</figref> is a cross-sectional plan view of an exemplary multi-core fiber actuated by well pressure;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">FIGURE 6</figref> is a cross-sectional view of an exemplary multi-core fiber having different modulus cores and light guiding cores;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">FIGURE 7</figref> is a cross-sectional plan view of an exemplary multi-core fiber actuated by well and reference pressures; and<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">FIGURE 8</figref> is a cross-sectional view of an exemplary multi-core fiber having a hollow, port core and light guiding cores.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0004"><b><u>DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF EXEMPLARY EMBODIMENTS</u></b></heading><p id="p0011" num="0011">Reference will now be made in detail to exemplary embodiments, examples of which are illustrated in the accompanying drawings.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">Referring now to <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURE 1</figref>, a cross-sectional plan view of an exemplary multi-core fiber is illustrated generally at 10. A first core 12 and a second core 14 include Bragg grating portions 16, 18 at a same measurement portion, shown generally at 20, relative to a longitudinal axis, illustrated by line 22, of the fiber 10.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">The grating portions 16 and 18 may be written in the cores by any fashion and at any time. However, in an exemplary embodiment, the grating portions 16 and 18 are photo etched in cores 12 and 14 during fiberization. More specifically, the grating portions are written during the drawing process and prior to the application of a protective coating. In such exemplary embodiment, the collocated sensors are particularly insensitive to drift factors since all collocated grating portions will drift together.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">Also, while the above exemplary embodiment describes use of Bragg gratings, it should be recognized that other structures useful for reading out such fibers may be used, such as in-fiber interferometers, Rayleigh scatter and random photo etched structures, among others, as long as collocated measurement portions are provided in the fiber.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></p><p id="p0015" num="0015">Referring now to <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURE 2</figref>, a cross-sectional plan view of an exemplary multi-core fiber 10 is illustrated in a system designed to actuate the fiber by a push rod 24 and bellows 26. The push rod 24 extends from the bellows normally against the multi-core fiber, which is provided in a media isolated housing 28. The bellows 26 is responsive to a pressure change to cause the push rod 24 to bend the fiber 10.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">Referring back to <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURE 1</figref>, it is noted that the push rod 24 and bellows 26 is an exemplary mechanism to provide the pressure-induced force on the fiber illustrated by arrow 30. Such force 30 bends the fiber 10, placing exemplary grating 16 in tension and exemplary grating 18 in compression. Differential measurements in core 12 and 14 may then be taken to sense the pressure change. It is noted that not only are drift factors eliminated due to the collocated nature of the core measurement portions (e.g., gratings written during fiberization in multiple cores of a multi-core fiber), but temperature effects are also eliminated due to the nature of the multi-core system. In another exemplary embodiment, the multi-core fiber comprises at least two cores that have the same doping to minimize differential reactions to pressure. In another embodiment, at least two cores are reflective to the same wavelength.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">Referring now to <figref idrefs="f0002">FIGURE 3</figref>, a cross-sectional plan view of an exemplary multi-core fiber 10 is illustrated as being actuated by a push rod 24 and diaphragm 32. Other than use of the diaphragm 32 instead of the bellows 26, operation of the collocated sensor system is identical to that described above with regard to <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURE 2</figref>. It should be noted that any mechanism effective to transmit a force representative of pressure against the fiber is contemplated herein, the bellows and push rod and diaphragm and push rod embodiments being merely exemplary.<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></p><p id="p0018" num="0018">Referring now to <figref idrefs="f0002">FIGURE 4</figref>, a cross-sectional plan view of an exemplary multi-core fiber 10 is illustrated as being asymmetrically actuated by a push rod 24 and diaphragm. It should be recognized that any kind of actuation on the fiber may be performed, as long as the core measurement portions (20 in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURE 1</figref>) of cores 12 and 14 are differentially affected by a force representative of a pressure change.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">Referring now to <figref idrefs="f0003">FIGURE 5</figref>, a cross-sectional plan view of an exemplary multi-core fiber 34 is illustrated as being actuated by well pressure, illustrated generally at 36 as acting on the multi-core fiber 34 within the media isolated housing 28. Referring now to <figref idrefs="f0003">FIGURE 6</figref>, in this exemplary embodiment, the multi-core fiber 34 includes light guiding cores 12 and 14, as well as a low modulus core 38 and a high modulus core 40. As the well pressure 36 acts on the fiber 34, the low modulus core 38 and the high modulus core 40 react differently, causing the fiber 34 to bend. This bend accordingly affects the light guiding cores 12 and 14 differently (note that cores 12 and 14 should be arranged within the fiber such that they bend differently relative to the effects of the low and high modulus core reactions to pressure), and pressure may be calculated independent of temperature effects and drift factors. Also, while provision of low modulus and high modulus cores have been described with regard to this exemplary embodiment, any fiber construction that causes the fiber to deform under pressure is contemplated, including for example, a single core (provided at least partially along the core measurement portion) having a different modulus than the light guiding cores and having a different spacing with regard to cores 12 and 14. Also, the terms "low modulus" and "high modulus" are merely indicative of a difference in the modulus of the two cores,<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> and are not meant to necessarily imply a great difference in modulus properties between the two cores 38 and 40.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">Referring now to <figref idrefs="f0003">FIGURE 7</figref>, a cross-sectional plan view of an exemplary multi-core fiber 42 is illustrated as being actuated by well and reference pressures, illustrated generally at 36 and 44, respectively. A media isolated housing 46 is provided over the fiber 42 and includes a pressure seal 48, separating the well and reference pressure zones. Referring now to <figref idrefs="f0003">FIGURE 8</figref>, the fiber 34 includes light guiding cores 12 and 14, which are differentially spaced relative to a hollow core 50. Hollow core 50 extends from the well pressure zone 36 to the reference pressure zone 44 and causes deformation of the fiber 34 due to the difference in pressure between the reference pressure zone and the well pressure zone. Due to the differential spacing of the cores 12 and 14 relative to the hollow core 50, the bending will affect the light guiding cores 12 and 14 differently, and the change in pressure in the well pressure zone 36 can be measured.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">It will be apparent to those skilled in the art that, while exemplary embodiments have been shown and described, various modifications and variations can be made to the embodiments disclosed herein without departing from the scope of the invention as defined in the appended claims.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56986103" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Ein Drucksensor, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> der Drucksensor umfasst:
<claim-text>eine Glasfaser (10), die mehrere lichtleitende Kerne (12, 14) umfasst, wobei mindestens zwei lichtleitende Kerne nebeneinanderstehende optische Messabschnitte (16, 18) einschließen;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei die Glasfaser (10) konfiguriert ist, um sich als Reaktion auf eine Änderung des Umgebungsdrucks, die sich auf den Drucksensor auswirkt, zu biegen, wobei der Drucksensor einen Mechanismus umfasst, um eine Kraft (30) auf die Faser zu übertragen, die repräsentativ für die Änderung des Umgebungsdrucks, die sich auf den Drucksensor auswirkt, ist, die Faser (10) konfiguriert ist, um sich als Reaktion auf die Kraft (30) zu biegen,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei die mindestens zwei leitenden Kerne (12, 14) in der Glasfaser (10) angeordnet sind, so dass sie unterschiedlich durch das Biegen der Glasfaser beeinflusst werden, und</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei der Glasfaser (10) konfiguriert ist, so dass die Abfrage der nebeneinanderstehenden optischen Messabschnitte (16, 18) mit Licht eine Temperatur- und Nullpunktverschiebungs-korrigierte Druckmessung erzeugen kann.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Ein Drucksensor gemäß Anspruch 1, umfassend eine Betätigungsvorrichtung die konfiguriert ist, um die Glasfaser als Reaktion auf eine Änderung des Umgebungsdrucks zu biegen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Ein Drucksensor gemäß Anspruch 2, wobei die Glasfaser (10) in einem medienisolierten Gehäuse (28) angeordnet ist und/oder<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> wobei die Betätigungsvorrichtung eine Druckstange (24) ist, die auf einen Balg (26) oder eine Membran (26) reagiert.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Ein Drucksensor gemäß Anspruch 2, wobei die Betätigungsvorrichtung sich im Allgemeinen normalerweise relativ zu einer Längsachse der Faser auf die Faser auswirkt oder wobei die Betätigungsvorrichtung sich entlang oder nahe auf eine Längsachse der Faser auswirkt, um die Faser asymmetrisch zu belasten.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Ein Drucksensor gemäß Anspruch 1, wobei die Glasfaser (10) ferner einen Niedermodulkern (38) und einen Hochmodulkern (40) umfasst, vorzugsweise, wobei die Glasfaser in einem medienisolierten Gehäuse (28) angeordnet ist, welches einen Bereich aufweist, der für einen Umgebungsdruck (28) repräsentativ ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Ein Drucksensor gemäß Anspruch 1, wobei die Glasfaser ferner einen hohlen Kern (50) umfasst, der sich zwischen einem Umgebungsdruckbereich (36) und einem Referenzdruckbereich (44) ausdehnt, vorzugsweise wobei die Faser in einem medienisolierten Gehäuse (28) angeordnet ist, das eine Druckdichtung (48) zwischen den Umgebungsdruck- (36) und Referenzdruckzonen (44) aufweist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Ein Drucksensor gemäß einem der vorherigen Ansprüche, wobei mindestens zwei Kerne die gleiche Dotierung aufweisen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Ein Drucksensor gemäß einem der vorherigen Ansprüche, wobei mindestens zwei Kerne die gleiche Wellenlänge reflektieren.<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Ein Verfahren zum Druckmessen, umfassend:
<claim-text>Anbringen an einem Punkt von Interesse,</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Drucksensor, der <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet ist, dass</b> der Drucksensor eine Glasfaser (10) umfasst, die mehrere lichtleitende Kerne (12, 14) umfasst, wobei mindestens zwei lichtleitende Kerne (12, 14) nebeneinanderstehende optische Messabschnitte (16, 18) einschließen, und</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Mechanismus, um eine Kraft (30) auf die Faser zu übertragen, die repräsentativ für die Änderung des Umgebungsdrucks, die sich auf den Drucksensor auswirkt, ist,</claim-text>
<claim-text>Konfigurieren der Glasfaser, um sich als Reaktion auf die Kraft zu biegen, so dass die mindestens zwei lichtleitenden Kerne unterschiedlich durch das Biegen der Glasfaser beeinflusst werden, und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Abfragen der nebeneinanderstehenden optischen Messabschnitte (16, 18) mit Licht, um eine Temperatur- und Nullpunktverschiebungs-korrigierte Druckmessung zu erzeugen.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Ein Verfahren zum Druckmessen gemäß Anspruch 9, umfassend das Biegen der Glasfaser (10) mit einer Betätigungsvorrichtung, die konfiguiert ist, um sich als Reaktion auf eine Änderung des Umgebungsdrucks zu bewegen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Ein Verfahren zum Druckmessen gemäß Anspruch 10, umfassend das Biegen der Glasfaser (10) in einem medienisolierten Gehäuse (28).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Ein Verfahren zum Druckmessen gemäß Anspruch 10, umfassend Biegen der Glasfaser (10) mit einer Druckstange (24), die auf einen Balg oder eine Membran (26) reagiert.<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Ein Verfahren zum Druckmessen gemäß Anspruch 10, welches Biegen der Glasfaser (10) in eine Normalenrichtung relativ zu einer Längsachse der Faser umfasst oder welches asymmetrisches Belasten der Faser durch Drücken auf die Faser entlang oder nahe einer Längsachse der Faser umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Ein Verfahren zum Druckmessen gemäß Anspruch 10, welches Biegen der Faser (10) indem die Faser einem Umgebungsdruck ausgesetzt wird, umfasst, wobei die Faser konfiguriert ist, um sich als Reaktion auf eine Änderung des Umgebungsdrucks zu biegen oder welches vorzugsweise Biegen der Faser indem die Faser einem Referenzdrucks und einem Umgebungsdrucks ausgesetzt wird, umfasst.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56986104" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A pressure sensor, <b>characterised In that</b> the pressure sensor comprises:
<claim-text>an optical fiber (10) comprising a plurality of light guiding cores (12, 14), wherein at least two light guiding cores include callocated optical measurement portions (16, 18),</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the optical fiber (10) is configured to bend In response to a change in environmental pressure incident to said pressure sensor, the pressure sensor comprising a mechanism to transmit a force (30) against the fiber representative of a change in environmental pressure incident to said pressure senso, the fiber (10) being configured to bend in response to said force (30),</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the at least two guiding cores (12, 14) are positioned within said optical fiber (10) such that they are differentially affected by said bending of said optical fiber, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said optical fiber (10) is configured such that interrogation of said collocated optical measurement portions (16, 18) with light may generate a temperature and drift corrected pressure measurement.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>A pressure sensor in accordance with claim 1, comprising an actuating device configured to bend said optical fiber In response to an environmental pressure change.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>A pressure sensor in accordance with claim 2, wherein sold optical fiber (10) Is positioned within a media isolated housing (28), and/or wherein said actuating device is a push rod (24) acted upon by a bellows (26) or diaphragm (28).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>A pressure sensors in accordance with claim 2, wherein said actuating device generally acts normally on the fiber relative to a longitudinal axis of the fiber, or wherein said actuating device acts along or near a longitudinal axis of the fiber to asymmetrically lead the fiber.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>A pressure sensor in accordance with claim 1, wherein said optical fiber (10) further comprises a low modulus core (38) and a high modulus core (40), preferably wherein said optical fiber is positioned within a media isolated housing (28) having a zone representative of an environmental pressure.<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>A pressure sensor in accordance with claim 1, wherein said optical fiber further comprises a hollow core (50) extending between an environmental pressure zone (36) and a reference pressure zone (44), preferably wherein said fiber is positioned within a media isolated housing (28) having a pressure seal (48) between said environmental pressure (36) and reference pressure zones (44).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>A pressure sensor in accordance with any preceding claim, wherein at least two cores (12, 14) have the same doping.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>A pressure sensor in accordance with any preceding claim, wherein at least two cores (12, 14) are reflective to the same wavelength.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>A method of sensing pressure, comprising:
<claim-text>installing, at a point of interest,</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pressure sensor <b>characterised in that</b> the pressure sensor comprises an optical fiber (10) comprising a plurality of light guiding cores (12, 14), wherein at least two light guiding cores (12, 14) include collocated optical measurement portions (16, 18), and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a mechanism to transmit a force (30) against the fiber representative of a change in environmental pressure incident to said pressure sensor,</claim-text>
<claim-text>configuring said optical fiber to bend in response to said force such that the at least two light guiding cores are differentially affected by said bending of said optical fiber, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>interrogating said collocated optical measurement portions (16, 18) with light to generate a temperature and drift corrected pressure measurement.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>A method of sensing pressure In accordance with claim 9, comprising bending said optical fiber (10) with an actuating device configured to move in response to an environmental pressure change.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>A method of sensing pressure in accordance with claim 10, comprising bending said optical fiber within a media isolated housing (28).<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>A method of sensing pressure in accordance with claim 10, comprising bending said optical fiber (10) with a push rod (24) acted upon by a bellows or diaphragm (26).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>A method of sensing pressure in accordance with claim 10, comprising bending said optical fiber (10) in a normal direction relative to a longitudinal axis of the fiber, or comprising asymmetrically loading the fiber by pushing on the fiber along or near a longitudinal axis of the fiber.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>A method of sensing pressure in accordance with claim 10, comprising bending said fiber (10) by exposing said fiber to an environmental pressure, wherein the fiber is configured to bend in response to a change in environmental pressure, preferably comprising bending said fiber by exposing said fiber to a reference pressure and an environmental pressure.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56986105" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Capteur de pression, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> le capteur de pression comprend :
<claim-text>une fibre optique (10) comprenant une pluralité d'âmes de guidage de lumière (12, 14), dans lequel au moins deux âmes de guidage de lumière comprennent des portions de mesure optique (16, 18) disposées côte à côte ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel la fibre optique (10) est configurée pour fléchir en réponse à un changement de la pression environnementale incidente sur ledit capteur de pression, le capteur de pression comprenant un mécanisme pour transmettre une force (30) contre la fibre représentative d'un changement de la pression environnementale incidente sur ledit capteur de pression, la fibre (10) étant configurée pour fléchir en réponse à ladite force (30),</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel les au moins deux âmes de guidage (12, 14) sont positionnées dans ladite fibre optique (10) de sorte qu'elles soient affectées de manière différenciée par ladite flexion de ladite fibre optique, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel ladite fibre optique (10) est configurée de sorte que l'interrogation desdites portions de mesure optique (16, 18) disposées côte à côte par de la lumière puisse générer une mesure de la pression corrigée par la température et la dérive.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Capteur de pression selon la revendication 1, comprenant un dispositif d'actionnement configuré pour faire fléchir ladite fibre optique en réponse à un changement de la pression environnementale.<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Capteur de pression selon la revendication 2, dans lequel ladite fibre optique (10) est positionnée dans un logement isolé (28) et/ou dans lequel ledit dispositif d'actionnement est une tige poussoir (24) sur laquelle agit un soufflet (26) ou un diaphragme (26).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Capteur de pression selon la revendication 2, dans lequel ledit dispositif d'actionnement agit de manière générale normalement sur la fibre par rapport à un axe longitudinal de la fibre ou dans lequel ledit dispositif d'actionnement agit le long d'un axe longitudinal ou près d'un axe longitudinal de la fibre pour charger celle-ci de manière asymétrique.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Capteur de pression selon la revendication 1, dans lequel ladite fibre optique (10) comprend en outre une âme de faible module (38) et une âme de module élevé (40, de préférence dans lequel ladite fibre optique est positionnée dans un logement isolé (28) ayant une zone représentative d'une pression environnementale.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Capteur de pression selon la revendication 1, dans lequel ladite fibre optique comprend par ailleurs une âme creuse (50) s'étendant entre une zone de pression environnementale (36) et une zone de pression de référence (44), de préférence dans lequel ladite fibre est positionnée dans un logement isolé (28) ayant un joint étanche à la pression (48) entre lesdites zones de pression environnementale (36) et de pression de référence (44).<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Capteur de pression selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans lequel au moins deux âmes (12, 14) ont le même dopage.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Capteur de pression selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans lequel au moins deux âmes (12, 14) sont réfléchissantes pour la même longueur d'onde.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Procédé de détection de pression, comprenant les étapes consistant à :
<claim-text>installer, en un point d'intérêt,</claim-text>
<claim-text>un capteur de pression, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> le capteur de pression comprend une fibre optique (10) comprenant une pluralité d'âmes de guidage de lumière (12, 14), dans lequel au moins deux âmes de guidage de lumière (12, 14) comprennent des portions de mesure optique (16, 18) disposées côte à côte, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un mécanisme pour transmettre une force (30) contre la fibre représentative d'un changement de la pression environnementale incidente sur ledit capteur de pression,</claim-text>
<claim-text>configurer ladite fibre optique pour qu'elle fléchisse en réponse à ladite force de sorte que les au moins deux âmes de guidage de lumière soient affectées de manière différenciée par ladite flexion de la dite fibre optique, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>interroger lesdites portions de mesure optique (16, 18) disposées côte à côte par de la lumière pour générer une mesure de la pression corrigée par la température et la dérive.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Procédé de détection de pression selon la revendication 9, comprenant la flexion de ladite fibre optique (10) avec un dispositif<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> d'actionnement configuré pour se déplacer en réponse à un changement de pression environnementale.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Procédé de détection de pression selon la revendication 10, comprenant la flexion de ladite fibre optique dans un logement isolé (28).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Procédé de détection de pression selon la revendication 10, comprenant la flexion de ladite fibre optique (10) par une tige poussoir (24) sur laquelle agit un soufflet ou un diaphragme (26).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Procédé de détection de pression selon la revendication 10, comprenant la flexion de ladite fibre optique (10) dans une direction normale par rapport à un axe longitudinal de la fibre ou comprenant la charge asymétrique de la fibre par poussée sur la fibre le long d'un axe longitudinal ou près d'un axe longitudinal de celle-ci.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Procédé de détection de pression selon la revendication 10, comprenant la flexion de ladite fibre (10) en exposant ladite fibre à une pression environnementale, dans lequel la fibre est configurée pour fléchir en réponse à un changement de la pression environnementale, de préférence comprenant la flexion de ladite fibre en exposant celle-ci à une pression de référence et à une pression environnementale.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16672353" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1,2"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="103" he="214" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --><figure id="f0002" num="3,4"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="75" he="222" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --><figure id="f0003" num="5,6,7,8"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="146" he="223" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
