<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2625540-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2625540" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="44187441" file-reference-id="315057" date-produced="20180825" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146588042" ucid="EP-2625540-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2625540</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-10761025-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154850234" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>10761025</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20101007</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140554501" ucid="EP-2010064975-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>2010064975</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20101007</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20131007</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989324590" load-source="docdb">G01R  31/34        20060101AFI20120426BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989638701" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G01R  31/34        20130101 FI20130815BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2122925827" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G01R  31/343       20130101 LI20141001BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132368759" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Erkennung eines fehlenden Statornutenkeils einer elektrischen Maschine</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132368760" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Detection of a missing stator slot wedge in an electrical machine</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132368761" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Détection d'une encoche de stator manquante dans une machine électrique</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919544145" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>ABB RESEARCH LTD</last-name><address><country>CH</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919537334" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>ABB RESEARCH LTD.</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919508711" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>PINTO CAJETAN</last-name><address><country>IN</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919525890" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>Pinto, Cajetan</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919021277" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Pinto, Cajetan</last-name><address><street>25/33 Suman K.C. Road Bandra Reclamation</street><city>Mumbai 400 500</city><country>IN</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919520180" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>RODRIGUEZ PEDRO</last-name><address><country>SE</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919542865" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>RODRIGUEZ, PEDRO</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919021274" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>RODRIGUEZ, PEDRO</last-name><address><street>Gunnilbogatan 26A</street><city>S-723 40 Västerås</city><country>SE</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919021275" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>ABB Research Ltd.</last-name><iid>101072810</iid><address><street>Affolternstrasse 44</street><city>8050 Zürich</city><country>CH</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919021276" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Savela, Reino Aleksi</last-name><iid>101272164</iid><address><street>ABB Intellectual Property Ingenjör Bååths Gata 11</street><city>SE-721 83 Västerås</city><country>SE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="EP-2010064975-W"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2010064975</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20101007</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2012045353-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2012045353</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20120412</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549780664" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS549797109" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549780677" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549868947" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549888340" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549781699" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549797110" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549780678" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549781700" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549781705" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549872379" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549868948" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549868949" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549780679" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549781706" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549780680" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549797111" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549888341" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549781707" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549868954" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549781708" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549866469" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549922384" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549866474" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549866475" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549922385" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS549922386" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549872380" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549797112" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549922387" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549781717" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549872381" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549781718" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS549922388" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549780693" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549797125" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549922389" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS549888342" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63960470" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to condition monitoring of an electrical machine. A current spectrum of the machine is analysed in order to determine whether a stator slot wedge is missing or not.</p><heading id="h0002">BACKGROUND ART</heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0001">figure 1</figref>, a stator slot wedge 10 is an element which holds a stator coil 20 in place in a stator slot 30 of an electrical machine. One side of the stator slot wedge 10 faces the stator coil 20 while the opposite side faces an air gap between the stator 40 and a rotor. Magnetic stator slot wedges are commonly used as they offer several benefits compared with non-magnetic ones. Such benefits are: reduced core losses and hence reduced temperature rise, lower magnetizing current and hence improved power factor, reduced inrush current, more efficient motor. A typical magnetic stator slot wedge material may comprise 75 % iron powder, 7 % glass fabric and 18% epoxy resin.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">However, magnetic stator slot wedges are more brittle than non-magnetic ones due to the high percentage of iron powder. It is known that magnetic stator slot wedges have a tendency to get loose and fall off the stator slots. This is caused by magnetic forces acting in the air gap and producing vibrations. The stator slot wedges are under consistent variable force, and if they are not sitting tight in the stator slots they start to move and wear at their edges to ultimately get loose enough to be pulled off the slots or to be broken apart.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p><p id="p0004" num="0004">A missing stator slot wedge can cause a rotor or stator winding failure (a catastrophic failure for the machine), and therefore it is important to detect a missing stator slot wedge at an early stage. A conventional procedure for detecting a missing stator slot wedge is to open the machine and by visual inspection search for debris in the stator. This methodology is costly since the machine must be dismantled. Therefore, there is a need to improve the existing condition monitoring methods for electrical machines.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005"><nplcit id="ncit0001" npl-type="s"><text>Davis, M., "Problems and Solutions with Magnetic Stator Wedges", Iris Rotating Machine Conf., San Antonio, TX, June 2007, pages 1-5</text></nplcit> discloses missing stator slot wedge detection based on current spectrum analysis.</p><heading id="h0003">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading><p id="p0006" num="0006">One object of the invention is to provide a method for detecting a missing stator slot wedge in an electrical machine without a need to open the machine.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">This object is achieved by the method according to appended claim 1.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">The invention is based on the realization that missing stator slot wedges cause alteration in the machine's current spectrum in a high frequency area, and that this "signature" can be used as an indicator of the stator slot wedges' condition.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">According to a first aspect of the invention, there is provided a method for detecting a missing stator slot wedge in an electrical machine, the method comprising the steps of: measuring a first current from a first machine; providing a first current spectrum from the first current measurement, the first current spectrum reaching a high frequency area above two times the main frequency; and using values of the first current spectrum in the high frequency area to determine whether a stator slot wedge is missing or not. By this measure a missing stator slot wedge in an electrical machine can be detected without a need to open the machine.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p><p id="p0010" num="0010">According to one embodiment of the invention the first current spectrum reaches a high frequency area above ten times such as twenty, thirty, forty or fifty times the main frequency. A deviation between current spectrums of a healthy machine and a machine with missing stator slot wedges is particularly apparent at certain higher frequencies. It is therefore advantageous to observe the current spectrum at this higher frequency range to determine whether a stator slot wedge is missing or not.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">According to one embodiment of the invention the first machine is an induction machine and the first current spectrum reaches a high frequency area defined by equation <maths id="math0001" num=""><math display="block"><mi>F</mi><mo>=</mo><msub><mi>R</mi><mi>r</mi></msub><mo>⁢</mo><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>-</mo><mi>s</mi></mrow><mi>p</mi></mfrac></mfenced><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi>f</mi><mi>s</mi></msub><mo>,</mo></math><img id="ib0001" file="imgb0001.tif" wi="34" he="13" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths><br/>
wherein <i>R<sub>r</sub></i> is a number of rotor slots, <i>s</i> is a slip of the motor, <i>p</i> is a number of pole pairs per phase, and <i>f<sub>s</sub></i> is a supply frequency. Simulations show that in the case of induction machines the deviation between current spectrums of a healthy machine and a machine with missing stator slot wedges is particularly apparent around the frequency area defined by the given equation.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">According to one embodiment of the invention the method further comprises the step of detecting whether an amplitude of the first current spectrum exceeds or goes below a threshold value in the high frequency area to determine whether a stator slot wedge is missing or not. By defining threshold values within which the machine is concluded to be healthy, a single current measurement suffices to determine whether a stator slot wedge is missing or not.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">According to one embodiment of the invention the method further comprises the step of detecting whether an amplitude of a harmonic in the high frequency area of the first current spectrum exceeds or goes below a threshold value to determine whether a stator slot wedge is missing or not.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> Simulations show that deviation between the current spectrums of a healthy machine and a machine with missing stator slot wedges is particularly apparent at certain harmonics. It is therefore advantageous to observe the amplitude of these certain harmonics to determine whether a stator slot wedge is missing or not.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">According to one embodiment of the invention the harmonic to be observed is one of the harmonics defined by equation <maths id="math0002" num=""><math display="block"><mi>F</mi><mo>=</mo><msub><mi>R</mi><mi>r</mi></msub><mo>⁢</mo><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>-</mo><mi>s</mi></mrow><mi>p</mi></mfrac></mfenced><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi>f</mi><mi>s</mi></msub><mo>±</mo><mn>2</mn><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="italic">mf</mi><mi>s</mi></msub><mo>,</mo></math><img id="ib0002" file="imgb0002.tif" wi="47" he="14" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths><br/>
wherein <i>R<sub>r</sub></i> is a number of rotor slots, <i>s</i> is a slip of the motor, <i>p</i> is a number of pole pairs per phase, <i>f<sub>s</sub></i> is a supply frequency, and <i>m</i> is an integer 0, 1, 2 or 3. Simulations show that in the case of induction machines the deviation between current spectrums of a healthy machine and a machine with missing stator slot wedges is particularly apparent at the harmonics defined by the given equation.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">According to one embodiment of the invention the method further comprises the step of detecting whether a certain harmonic is present to determine whether a stator slot wedge is missing or not. Simulations show that in certain cases a missing stator slot wedge causes a new harmonic to appear. In those cases it suffices to detect a presence of such harmonic to determine whether a stator slot wedge is missing or not.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">According to one embodiment of the invention the method further comprises the steps of: measuring a reference current from a reference machine; providing a reference current spectrum from the reference current measurement; comparing the first current spectrum with the reference current spectrum to determine whether a stator slot wedge is missing or not. Reliable information about the presence of the stator slot wedges is gained when the current spectrum<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> of the machine under interest is compared with a current spectrum of a reference machine.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">According to one embodiment of the invention the method further comprises the step of detecting whether the first current spectrum deviates from the reference current spectrum by a certain threshold value to determine whether a stator slot wedge is missing or not. A threshold value is a simple criterion for concluding that a stator slot wedge is missing.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">According to one embodiment of the invention the reference machine corresponds to the first machine, and the condition of the stator slot wedges in the reference machine is well known. Readily comparable current spectrums are achieved when the reference machine is identical with the machine under interest, and when the condition of the reference machine is known.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">According to one embodiment of the invention the stator slot wedges in the reference machine are complete. When a current spectrum of the reference machine corresponds to an ideal situation with complete stator slot wedges, it is easier to detect a deviation between it and a current spectrum of a machine with missing stator slot wedges.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">According to one embodiment of the invention the method further comprises the steps of: measuring a second current from the first machine, the second current representing a different electrical phase than the first current; providing a second current spectrum from the second current measurement; comparing the first current spectrum with the second current spectrum to determine whether a stator slot wedge is missing or not. Simulations show that a missing stator slot wedge causes current spectrums from different electrical phases to deviate from each other. This deviation can be utilized to determine whether a stator slot wedge is missing or not.<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></p><p id="p0021" num="0021">According to one embodiment of the invention the method further comprises the step of detecting whether the first current spectrum deviates from the second current spectrum by a certain threshold value to determine whether a stator slot wedge is missing or not. A threshold value is a simple criterion for concluding that a stator slot wedge is missing.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">According to one embodiment of the invention the first current is a branch current. The branch current is a more sensitive indicator than the total current for the detection of missing stator slot wedges, and therefore it is the preferred indicator when accessible.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">According to one embodiment of the invention the method further comprises the step of detecting whether a harmonic according to the following equation is present to determine whether a stator slot wedge is missing or not: <maths id="math0003" num=""><math display="block"><mi>F</mi><mo>=</mo><msub><mi>R</mi><mi>r</mi></msub><mo>⁢</mo><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>-</mo><mi>s</mi></mrow><mi>p</mi></mfrac></mfenced><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi>f</mi><mi>s</mi></msub><mo>-</mo><mn>2</mn><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="italic">f</mi><mi>s</mi></msub><mo>,</mo></math><img id="ib0003" file="imgb0003.tif" wi="45" he="14" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths><br/>
wherein <i>R<sub>r</sub></i> is a number of rotor slots, <i>s</i> is a slip of the motor, <i>p</i> is a number of pole pairs per phase, and <i>f<sub>s</sub></i> is a supply frequency. Simulations show that in an induction machine a missing stator slot wedge causes a new harmonic according to the given equation to appear. It therefore suffices to detect a presence of that harmonic to determine whether a stator slot wedge is missing or not.</p><heading id="h0004">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading><p id="p0024" num="0024">The invention will be explained in greater detail with reference to the accompanying drawings, wherein
<dl id="dl0001"><dt>figure 1</dt><dd>shows a typical stator slot arrangement with a stator slot wedge,</dd><dt>figure 2a</dt><dd>shows a current spectrum of a healthy machine,<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></dd><dt>figure 2b</dt><dd>shows a current spectrum of a machine with one stator slot wedge missing,</dd><dt>figure 3</dt><dd>shows current spectrums for two phases of a same machine with three stator slot wedges missing,</dd><dt>figure 4a</dt><dd>shows a current spectrum of a branch current for a healthy machine, and</dd><dt>figure 4b</dt><dd>shows a current spectrum of a branch current for a machine with one missing stator slot wedge.</dd></dl></p><heading id="h0005">DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading><p id="p0025" num="0025">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0002">figure 2a</figref>, an example of a current spectrum for an electrical machine is shown. The electrical machine has a main frequency component at 50 Hz corresponding to the grid frequency. The values in the current spectrum are relative logarithmic values expressed in decibels (dB) according to equation <maths id="math0004" num=""><math display="block"><msub><mi>I</mi><mi mathvariant="italic">dB</mi></msub><mo>=</mo><mn>20</mn><mo>⁢</mo><mi>log</mi><mfenced><mfrac><mi>I</mi><msub><mi>I</mi><mi>m</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced><mo>,</mo></math><img id="ib0004" file="imgb0004.tif" wi="35" he="13" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths><br/>
wherein <i>I<sub>dB</sub></i> is a relative current amplitude, <i>I</i> is a current amplitude of each respective frequency component, and <i>I<sub>m</sub></i> is a current amplitude of the main frequency component. Consequently, <i>I<sub>dB</sub></i> gets a value zero at the main frequency, and a value below zero at the remaining frequencies. Harmonics showing peak <i>I<sub>dB</sub></i> values can be recognized at frequency values that are multiples of the main frequency. Otherwise the <i>I<sub>dB</sub></i> curve is relatively flat with values mainly between -100 dB and -120 dB. The current spectrum in <figref idrefs="f0002">figure 2a</figref> is representative for a healthy machine with complete stator slot wedges. The values in <figref idrefs="f0002">figure 2a</figref> are received from a simulation, but it is expected that measurements give corresponding results. This is also the case in the remaining <figref idrefs="f0002">figures 2b</figref>, <figref idrefs="f0001">3</figref>, <figref idrefs="f0003">4a and 4b</figref>. In the case of real<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> condition monitoring the current obviously needs to be measured.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">It should also be mentioned that all examples in this disclosure apply for an induction machine. The invention, however, is not limited to induction machines but may as well be used for detecting a missing stator slot wedge in a synchronous machine.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027"><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2b</figref> shows a current spectrum for a machine with one stator slot wedge missing. It can be noticed that the two spectrums in <figref idrefs="f0002">figures 2a and 2b</figref> deviate remarkably from each other especially at high frequencies. This deviation in the current spectrums implies that by appropriately interpreting a current spectrum of an electrical machine, the current spectrum values can be turned into information about whether a stator slot wedge is missing or not. For example, an upper and lower threshold values may be defined for an average <i>I<sub>dB</sub></i> within a certain frequency area in a healthy machine. If the actual <i>I<sub>dB</sub></i> exceeds the upper threshold value or goes below the lower threshold value, then the conclusion is that a stator slot wedge is missing. Alternatively, the amplitude of a certain individual harmonic can be observed. It depends on the machine type which indicator is the most appropriate one for detecting a missing stator slot wedge.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">In the example corresponding to <figref idrefs="f0002">figure 2b</figref> the prominent harmonics in the frequency area around 1700-2000 Hz are given by equation <maths id="math0005" num=""><math display="block"><mi>F</mi><mo>=</mo><msub><mi>R</mi><mi>r</mi></msub><mo>⁢</mo><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>-</mo><mi>s</mi></mrow><mi>p</mi></mfrac></mfenced><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi>f</mi><mi>s</mi></msub><mo>±</mo><mn>2</mn><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="italic">mf</mi><mi>s</mi></msub><mo>,</mo></math><img id="ib0005" file="imgb0005.tif" wi="47" he="14" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths><br/>
wherein <i>R<sub>r</sub></i> is a number of rotor slots, <i>s</i> is a slip of the motor, <i>p</i> is a number of pole pairs per phase, <i>f<sub>s</sub></i> is a supply frequency, and <i>m</i> is an integer 0, 1, 2 or 3. The slip <i>s</i> is defined by equation <maths id="math0006" num=""><math display="block"><mi>s</mi><mo>=</mo><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>η</mi><mi>s</mi></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>η</mi><mi>r</mi></msub></mrow><msub><mi>η</mi><mi>s</mi></msub></mfrac></mfenced><mo>,</mo></math><img id="ib0006" file="imgb0006.tif" wi="29" he="16" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths><!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> wherein η<sub>s</sub> is a rotational speed of a stator field and n<sub>r</sub> is a rotational speed of a rotor. In this particular case it is advisable to observe the relative current amplitude <i>I<sub>dB</sub></i> around the prominent harmonics to determine whether a stator slot wedge is missing or not.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029"><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 3</figref> shows current spectrums for two phases of a same machine in a case where three stator slot wedges are missing. In a healthy machine the two curves would be identical, but with missing stator slot wedges the curves clearly deviate from each other. Again, in a similar manner as explained hereinbefore, this deviation can be used to interpret whether a stator slot wedge is missing or not.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030"><figref idrefs="f0003">Figures 4a and 4b</figref> show current spectrums of a branch current between different stator coils in a same electrical phase. The curve of <figref idrefs="f0003">figure 4a</figref> is for a healthy machine, and that of <figref idrefs="f0003">figure 4b</figref> for a machine with one missing stator slot wedge. In <figref idrefs="f0003">figure 4b</figref> it can be seen that there is a clear new harmonic in-between the two principal rotor slot harmonics. This harmonic is given by equation <maths id="math0007" num=""><math display="block"><mi>F</mi><mo>=</mo><msub><mi>R</mi><mi>r</mi></msub><mo>⁢</mo><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>-</mo><mi>s</mi></mrow><mi>p</mi></mfrac></mfenced><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi>f</mi><mi>s</mi></msub><mo>-</mo><mn>2</mn><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="italic">f</mi><mi>s</mi></msub><mo>,</mo></math><img id="ib0007" file="imgb0007.tif" wi="47" he="14" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths><br/>
wherein <i>R<sub>r</sub></i> is a number of rotor slots, <i>s</i> is a slip of the motor, <i>p</i> is a number of pole pairs per phase, and <i>f<sub>s</sub></i> is a supply frequency. Therefore, detecting the presence of this particular harmonic can be used to determine whether a stator slot wedge is missing or not.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">In the examples given above the conclusion about whether a stator slot wedge is missing or not is either based on values of a relative current amplitude <i>I<sub>dB</sub></i> or on presence of certain harmonics. The invention is not, however, limited to the examples given above, but a person skilled in the art may use additional ways to interpret the current spectrums in the high frequency area to determine whether a stator slot wedge is missing or not.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56984147" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Verfahren zum Detektieren eines fehlenden Stator-Nutkeils (10) in einer elektrischen Maschine, wobei das Verfahren die folgenden Schritte umfasst:
<claim-text>- Messen eines ersten Stroms von einer ersten Maschine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- Liefern eines ersten Stromspektrums von der ersten Strommessung, wobei das erste Stromspektrum einen Hochfrequenzbereich oberhalb der zweifachen Hauptfrequenz erreicht; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>- Verwenden von Werten des ersten Stromspektrums in dem Hochfrequenzbereich, um zu bestimmen, ob ein Stator-Nutkeil (10) fehlt oder nicht.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, wobei das erste Stromspektrum einen Hochfrequenzbereich oberhalb der zehnfachen sowie zwanzig-, dreißig-, vierzig- oder fünfzigfachen Hauptfrequenz erreicht.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, wobei die erste Maschine eine Induktionsmaschine ist und das erste Stromspektrum einen Hochfrequenzbereich erreicht, der durch die Gleichung <maths id="math0011" num=""><math display="block"><mi>F</mi><mo>=</mo><msub><mi>R</mi><mi>r</mi></msub><mo>⁢</mo><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>-</mo><mi>s</mi></mrow><mi>p</mi></mfrac></mfenced><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi>f</mi><mi>s</mi></msub><mo>,</mo></math><img id="ib0011" file="imgb0011.tif" wi="41" he="13" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths><br/>
definiert ist, wobei <i>R<sub>r</sub></i> eine Anzahl von Rotorschlitzen ist, <i>s</i> ein Schlupf des Motors ist, <i>p</i> eine<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> Anzahl der Polpaare pro Phase ist und <i>f<sub>s</sub></i> eine Versorgungsfrequenz ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei das Verfahren ferner den folgenden Schritt umfasst
<claim-text>- Detektieren, ob eine Amplitude des ersten Stromspektrums einen Schwellenwert in dem Hochfrequenzbereich übersteigt oder unterschreitet, um zu bestimmen, ob ein Stator-Nutkeil (10) fehlt oder nicht.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei das Verfahren ferner den folgenden Schritt umfasst
<claim-text>- Detektieren, ob eine Amplitude einer Harmonischen in dem Hochfrequenzbereich des ersten Stromspektrums einen Schwellenwert übersteigt oder unterschreitet, um zu bestimmen, ob ein Stator-Nutkeil (10) fehlt oder nicht.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 5, wobei die Harmonische eine der Harmonischen ist, die durch die Gleichung <maths id="math0012" num=""><math display="block"><mi>F</mi><mo>=</mo><msub><mi>R</mi><mi>r</mi></msub><mo>⁢</mo><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>-</mo><mi>s</mi></mrow><mi>p</mi></mfrac></mfenced><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi>f</mi><mi>s</mi></msub><mo>±</mo><mn>2</mn><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="italic">mf</mi><mi>s</mi></msub><mo>,</mo></math><img id="ib0012" file="imgb0012.tif" wi="53" he="12" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths><br/>
definiert sind, wobei <i>R<sub>r</sub></i> eine Anzahl von Rotorschlitzen ist, <i>s</i> ein Schlupf des Motors ist, <i>p</i> eine Anzahl der Polpaare pro Phase ist, <i>f<sub>s</sub></i> eine Versorgungsfrequenz ist und <i>m</i> eine ganze Zahl 0, 1, 2 oder 3 ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei das Verfahren ferner den folgenden Schritt umfasst
<claim-text>- Detektieren, ob eine bestimmte Harmonische vorhanden ist, um zu bestimmen, ob ein Stator-Nutkeil (10) fehlt oder nicht.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei das Verfahren ferner den folgenden Schritt umfasst
<claim-text>- Messen eines Referenzstroms von einer Referenzmaschine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- Liefern eines Referenzstromspektrums von der Referenzstrommaschine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- Vergleichen des ersten Stromspektrums mit dem Referenzstromspektrum, um zu bestimmen, ob ein Stator-Nutkeil (10) fehlt oder nicht.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 8, wobei das Verfahren ferner den folgenden Schritt umfasst
<claim-text>- Detektieren, ob das erste Stromspektrum von dem Referenzstromspektrum um einen bestimmten Schwellenwert abweicht, um zu bestimmen, ob ein Stator-Nutkeil (10) fehlt oder nicht.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 9, wobei die Referenzmaschine der ersten Maschine entspricht, und der Zustand des Stator-Nutkeils (10) in der Referenzmaschine gut bekannt ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 10, wobei die Stator-Nutkeile (10) in der Referenzmaschine vollständig sind.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei das Verfahren ferner die folgenden Schritte umfasst:
<claim-text>- Messen eines zweiten Stroms von der ersten Maschine, wobei der zweite Strom eine andere elektrische Phase als der erste Strom repräsentiert;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- Liefern eines zweiten Stromspektrums von der zweiten Strommessung;<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>- Vergleichen des ersten Stromspektrums mit dem zweiten Stromspektrum, um zu bestimmen, ob ein Stator-Nutkeil (10) fehlt oder nicht.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 12, wobei das Verfahren den folgenden Schritt umfasst
<claim-text>- Detektieren, ob das erste Stromspektrum von dem zweiten Stromspektrum um einen bestimmten Schwellenwert abweicht, um zu bestimmen, ob ein Stator-Nutkeil (10) fehlt oder nicht.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei der erste Strom ein Zweigstrom ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 14, wobei das Verfahren ferner den folgenden Schritt umfasst
<claim-text>- Detektieren, ob eine Harmonische gemäß der folgenden Gleichung vorhanden ist, um zu bestimmen, ob ein Stator-Nutkeil (10) fehlt oder nicht: <maths id="math0013" num=""><math display="block"><mi>F</mi><mo>=</mo><msub><mi>R</mi><mi>r</mi></msub><mo>⁢</mo><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>-</mo><mi>s</mi></mrow><mi>p</mi></mfrac></mfenced><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi>f</mi><mi>s</mi></msub><mo>-</mo><mn>2</mn><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="italic">f</mi><mi>s</mi></msub><mo>,</mo></math><img id="ib0013" file="imgb0013.tif" wi="51" he="13" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths><br/>
wobei <i>R<sub>r</sub></i> eine Anzahl von Rotorschlitzen ist, <i>s</i> ein Schlupf des Motors ist, <i>p</i> eine Anzahl der Polpaare pro Phase ist und <i>f<sub>s</sub></i> eine Versorgungsfrequenz ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56984148" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A method for detecting a missing stator slot wedge (10) in an electrical machine, the method comprising the steps of:
<claim-text>- measuring a first current from a first machine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- providing a first current spectrum from the first current measurement, the first current spectrum reaching a high frequency area above two times the main frequency; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>- using values of the first current spectrum in the high frequency area to determine whether a stator slot wedge (10) is missing or not.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>A method according to claim 1, wherein the first current spectrum reaches a high frequency area above ten times such as twenty, thirty, forty or fifty times the main frequency.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>A method according to claim 1, wherein the first machine is an induction machine and the first current spectrum reaches a high frequency area defined by equation <maths id="math0008" num=""><math display="block"><mi>F</mi><mo>=</mo><msub><mi>R</mi><mi>r</mi></msub><mo>⁢</mo><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>-</mo><mi>s</mi></mrow><mi>p</mi></mfrac></mfenced><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi>f</mi><mi>s</mi></msub><mo>,</mo></math><img id="ib0008" file="imgb0008.tif" wi="41" he="14" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths><br/>
wherein <i>R<sub>r</sub></i> is a number of rotor slots, <i>s</i> is a slip of the motor, <i>p</i> is a number of pole pairs per phase, and <i>f<sub>s</sub></i> is a supply frequency.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>A method according to any of the preceding claims, wherein the method further comprises the step of
<claim-text>- detecting whether an amplitude of the first current spectrum exceeds or goes below a threshold value in the high frequency area to determine whether a stator slot wedge (10) is missing or not.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>A method according to any of the preceding claims, wherein the method further comprises the step of<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> -->
<claim-text>- detecting whether an amplitude of a harmonic in the high frequency area of the first current spectrum exceeds or goes below a threshold value to determine whether a stator slot wedge (10) is missing or not.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>A method according to claim 5, wherein the harmonic is one of the harmonics defined by equation <maths id="math0009" num=""><math display="block"><mi>F</mi><mo>=</mo><msub><mi>R</mi><mi>r</mi></msub><mo>⁢</mo><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>-</mo><mi>s</mi></mrow><mi>p</mi></mfrac></mfenced><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi>f</mi><mi>s</mi></msub><mo>±</mo><mn>2</mn><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="italic">mf</mi><mi>s</mi></msub><mo>,</mo></math><img id="ib0009" file="imgb0009.tif" wi="48" he="13" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths><br/>
wherein <i>R<sub>r</sub></i> is a number of rotor slots, <i>s</i> is a slip of the motor, <i>p</i> is a number of pole pairs per phase, <i>f<sub>s</sub></i> is a supply frequency, and <i>m</i> is an integer 0, 1, 2 or 3.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>A method according to any of the preceding claims, wherein the method further comprises the step of
<claim-text>- detecting whether a certain harmonic is present to determine whether a stator slot wedge (10) is missing or not.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>A method according to any of the preceding claims, wherein the method further comprises the steps of:
<claim-text>- measuring a reference current from a reference machine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- providing a reference current spectrum from the reference current measurement;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- comparing the first current spectrum with the reference current spectrum to determine whether a stator slot wedge (10) is missing or not.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>A method according to claim 8, wherein the method further comprises the step of
<claim-text>- detecting whether the first current spectrum deviates from the reference current spectrum by a certain threshold value to determine whether a stator slot wedge (10) is missing or not.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>A method according to claim 9, wherein the reference machine corresponds to the first machine, and the<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> condition of the stator slot wedges (10) in the reference machine is well known.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>A method according to claim 10, wherein the stator slot wedges (10) in the reference machine are complete.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>A method according to any of the preceding claims, wherein the method further comprises the steps of:
<claim-text>- measuring a second current from the first machine, the second current representing a different electrical phase than the first current;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- providing a second current spectrum from the second current measurement;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- comparing the first current spectrum with the second current spectrum to determine whether a stator slot wedge (10) is missing or not.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>A method according to claim 12, wherein the method further comprises the step of
<claim-text>- detecting whether the first current spectrum deviates from the second current spectrum by a certain threshold value to determine whether a stator slot wedge (10) is missing or not.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>A method according to any of the preceding claims, wherein the first current is a branch current.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>A method according to claim 14, wherein the method further comprises the step of
<claim-text>- detecting whether a harmonic according to the following equation is present to determine whether a stator slot wedge (10) is missing or not: <maths id="math0010" num=""><math display="block"><mi>F</mi><mo>=</mo><msub><mi>R</mi><mi>r</mi></msub><mo>⁢</mo><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>-</mo><mi>s</mi></mrow><mi>p</mi></mfrac></mfenced><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi>f</mi><mi>s</mi></msub><mo>-</mo><mn>2</mn><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="italic">f</mi><mi>s</mi></msub><mo>,</mo></math><img id="ib0010" file="imgb0010.tif" wi="48" he="13" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths><br/>
wherein <i>R<sub>r</sub></i> is a number of rotor slots, <i>s</i> is a slip of the motor, p is a number of pole pairs per phase, and <i>f<sub>s</sub></i> is a supply frequency.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56984149" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Procédé pour détecter une cale d'encoche de stator manquante (10) dans une machine électrique, le procédé comprenant les étapes consistant à :
<claim-text>- mesurer un premier courant fourni par une première machine ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- établir un spectre du premier courant à partir de la mesure du premier courant, le spectre du premier courant atteignant une région de hautes fréquences supérieure à deux fois la fréquence principale ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>- utiliser des valeurs du spectre du premier courant dans la région de hautes fréquences dans le but de déterminer si une cale d'encoche de stator (10) est manquante ou pas.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, dans lequel le spectre du premier courant atteint une région de hautes fréquences supérieure à dix fois la fréquence principale, notamment vingt, trente, quarante ou cinquante fois la fréquence principale.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, dans lequel la première machine est une machine à induction et le spectre du premier courant atteint une région de hautes fréquences définie par l'équation : <maths id="math0014" num=""><math display="block"><mi>F</mi><mo>=</mo><msub><mi>R</mi><mi>r</mi></msub><mo>⁢</mo><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>-</mo><mi>s</mi></mrow><mi>p</mi></mfrac></mfenced><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi>f</mi><mi>s</mi></msub><mo>,</mo></math><img id="ib0014" file="imgb0014.tif" wi="37" he="13" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths><br/>
où <i>R<sub>r</sub></i> est un nombre d'encoches de rotor, <i>s</i> est un<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> glissement du moteur, <i>p</i> est un nombre de paires de pôles par phase et <i>f<sub>s</sub></i> est une fréquence d'alimentation.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, comprenant en outre l'étape consistant à :
<claim-text>- détecter si une amplitude du spectre du premier courant passe au-dessus ou en dessous d'une valeur de seuil dans le but de déterminer si une cale d'encoche de stator (10) est manquante ou pas.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, comprenant en outre l'étape consistant à :
<claim-text>- détecter si une amplitude d'un harmonique dans la région de hautes fréquences du spectre du premier courant passe au-dessus ou en dessous d'une valeur de seuil dans la région de hautes fréquences dans le but de déterminer si une cale d'encoche de stator (10) est manquante ou pas.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 5, dans lequel l'harmonique est l'un des harmoniques définis par l'équation : <maths id="math0015" num=""><math display="block"><mi>F</mi><mo>=</mo><msub><mi>R</mi><mi>r</mi></msub><mo>⁢</mo><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>-</mo><mi>s</mi></mrow><mi>p</mi></mfrac></mfenced><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi>f</mi><mi>s</mi></msub><mo>±</mo><mn>2</mn><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="italic">mf</mi><mi>s</mi></msub><mo>,</mo></math><img id="ib0015" file="imgb0015.tif" wi="49" he="14" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths><br/>
où <i>R<sub>r</sub></i> est un nombre d'encoches de rotor, <i>s</i> est un glissement du moteur, <i>p</i> est un nombre de paires de pôles par phase, <i>f<sub>s</sub></i> est une fréquence d'alimentation et m est un entier valant 0, 1, 2 ou 3.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, comprenant en outre l'étape consistant à :
<claim-text>- détecter si un certain harmonique est présent dans le but de déterminer si une cale d'encoche de stator (10) est manquante ou pas.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> revendications précédentes, comprenant en outre les étapes consistant à :
<claim-text>- mesurer un courant de référence fourni par une machine de référence ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- établir un spectre du courant de référence à partir de la mesure du courant de référence ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- comparer le spectre du premier courant au spectre du courant de référence dans le but de déterminer si une cale d'encoche de stator (10) est manquante ou pas.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 8, comprenant en outre l'étape consistant à :
<claim-text>- détecter si le spectre du premier courant s'écarte du spectre du courant de référence d'une certaine valeur de seuil dans le but de déterminer si une cale d'encoche de stator (10) est manquante ou pas.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 9, dans lequel la machine de référence correspond à la première machine et l'état des cales d'encoches de stator (10) dans la machine de référence est bien connu.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 10, dans lequel les cales d'encoches de stator (10) dans la machine de référence sont complètes.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, comprenant en outre les étapes consistant à :
<claim-text>- mesurer un deuxième courant fourni par la première machine, le deuxième courant représentant une phase électrique différente de celle du premier courant ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- établir un spectre du deuxième courant à partir de la mesure du deuxième courant ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- comparer le spectre du premier courant au spectre du deuxième courant dans le but de déterminer si une cale d'encoche de stator (10) est manquante ou<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> pas.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 12, comprenant en outre l'étape consistant à :
<claim-text>- détecter si le spectre du premier courant s'écarte du spectre du deuxième courant d'une certaine valeur de seuil dans le but de déterminer si une cale d'encoche de stator (10) est manquante ou pas.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans lequel le premier courant est un courant de branche.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 14, comprenant en outre l'étape consistant à :
<claim-text>- détecter si un harmonique selon l'équation qui suit est présent dans le but de déterminer si une cale d'encoche de stator (10) est manquante ou pas : <maths id="math0016" num=""><math display="block"><mi>F</mi><mo>=</mo><msub><mi>R</mi><mi>r</mi></msub><mo>⁢</mo><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>-</mo><mi>s</mi></mrow><mi>p</mi></mfrac></mfenced><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi>f</mi><mi>s</mi></msub><mo>-</mo><mn>2</mn><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="italic">f</mi><mi>s</mi></msub><mo>,</mo></math><img id="ib0016" file="imgb0016.tif" wi="48" he="14" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths><br/>
où <i>R<sub>r</sub></i> est un nombre d'encoches de rotor, <i>s</i> est un glissement du moteur, <i>p</i> est un nombre de paires de pôles par phase et <i>f<sub>s</sub></i> est une fréquence d'alimentation.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16671764" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1,3"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="153" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2a,2b"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="131" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --><figure id="f0003" num="4a,4b"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="121" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
