<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2426668-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2426668" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="39183317" file-reference-id="315728" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146588449" ucid="EP-2426668-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2426668</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-11009492-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154850641" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>11009492</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20070912</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP182925771" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>11009492.7</doc-number><date>20070912</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140552896" ucid="EP-07815815-A" linkage-type="3" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>07815815</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20070912</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140554193" ucid="US-84415406-P" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>84415406</doc-number><kind>P</kind><date>20060913</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130620</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989325653" load-source="docdb">G11C   7/10        20060101ALI20120118BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989325654" load-source="docdb">G11C   8/08        20060101ALI20120118BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989325655" load-source="docdb">G11C  11/56        20060101AFI20120118BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989325656" load-source="docdb">G11C  16/02        20060101ALI20120118BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989325657" load-source="docdb">G11C  16/04        20060101ALI20120118BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989325658" load-source="docdb">G11C  16/12        20060101ALI20120118BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989325659" load-source="docdb">G11C  16/34        20060101ALI20120118BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2023461240" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G11C  11/5642      20130101 LI20150910BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2023461493" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G11C  11/5628      20130101 LI20150910BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2023462284" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G11C  16/0483      20130101 LI20150910BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2023464639" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G11C2211/5621      20130101 LA20150910BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2023470141" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G11C  16/344       20130101 LI20150910BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2023470806" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G11C  16/3454      20130101 LI20150910BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2023470958" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G11C  16/10        20130101 LI20150909BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2023471042" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G11C  16/12        20130101 LI20150910BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989622060" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G11C  16/34        20130101 FI20130912BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132369980" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Flash-Mehrebenen-Schwellenspannungsverteilungsschema</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132369981" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Flash multi-level threshold distribution scheme</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132369982" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Schéma de distribution de seuil à plusieurs niveaux flash</invention-title></technical-data><related-documents><relation type="division"><child-doc ucid="EP-11009492-A"><document-id load-source="patent-office" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>11009492</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20070912</date></document-id></child-doc><parent-doc ucid="EP-07815815.1"><document-id load-source="patent-office" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>07815815.1</doc-number><date>20070912</date></document-id></parent-doc></relation></related-documents><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919520678" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>MOSAID TECHNOLOGIES INC</last-name><address><country>CA</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919508341" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>MOSAID TECHNOLOGIES INCORPORATED</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919523954" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>KIM JIN-KI</last-name><address><country>CA</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919536244" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>KIM, JIN-KI</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919023160" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>KIM, JIN-KI</last-name><address><street>46 Ironside Court</street><city>Kanata Ontario K2K 3H6</city><country>CA</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919023161" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>MOSAID Technologies Incorporated</last-name><iid>101127392</iid><address><street>11 Hines Road, Suite 203</street><city>Ottawa, ON K2K 2X1</city><country>CA</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919023162" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>UEXKÜLL &amp; STOLBERG</last-name><iid>100059946</iid><address><street>Patentanwälte Beselerstrasse 4</street><city>22607 Hamburg</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549924068" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549893031" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549870219" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549785634" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549879873" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549924069" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549875345" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549893032" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549879874" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549785681" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549870220" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549870221" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549875374" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549893037" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549879875" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549785635" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549893038" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549870222" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549879876" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549875375" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549924070" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549875376" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549875377" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549924071" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549924072" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549924073" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549785682" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549924074" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549924075" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549875382" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549785636" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549893039" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63960871" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001"><b>CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS</b></heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">This application claims the benefit of priority of <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US84415406P"><text>U.S. Provisional Patent Application No. 60/844,154 filed on September 13, 2006</text></patcit>.</p><heading id="h0002"><b>FIELD OF THE INVENTION</b></heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">The present invention relates generally to Flash memory. More particularly, the present invention relates to a Flash memory device, a method for programming of Flash memory cell and a method for and a method for verifying a threshold voltage.</p><heading id="h0003"><b>BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</b></heading><p id="p0003" num="0003">Numerous types of consumer electronics products rely on some form of mass storage for retaining data or software for the execution of code by a microcontroller. Such consumer electronics are prolific, and include devices such as personal digital assistants (PDA's), portable music players, portable multimedia players (PMP's) and digital cameras. In PDA's, mass storage is required for storing applications and data, while portable music players and digital cameras require large amounts of mass storage for retaining music file data and/or image data. The mass storage solution for such portable electronics is preferably small in size, consumes minimal power, and has high storage density. This limits the selection to non-volatile forms of memory since volatile memories, such as static random access memory (SRAM) and dynamic random access memory (DRAM), require a constant application of power in order to retain data. As is known in the art, portable electronics rely on batteries that have a finite power supply. Therefore, non-volatile memories that retain data after power is removed are preferred.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">While many consumer products use commodity Flash memory, Flash memory is indirectly used by consumers in products such as cell phones and devices with microprocessing functions. More specifically, the application specific integrated circuits (ASIC) commonly found in consumer electronics can have integrated Flash memory to enable<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> firmware upgrades. Needless to say, Flash memory is versatile due to its optimal balance in size, storage density, and speed, making it a preferred non-volatile mass storage solution for consumer electronics.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005"><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> is a block diagram of a typical Flash memory device. Flash memory <b>10</b> includes logic circuitry for controlling various functions of the Flash circuits, registers for storing address and data, high voltage circuits for generating the required program and erase voltages, and core memory circuits for accessing the Flash memory array. The functions of the shown circuit blocks of Flash memory <b>10</b> should are well known in the art. Persons skilled in the art will understand that Flash memory <b>10</b> shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> represents one possible Flash memory configuration among many possible configurations.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">A read operation is a relatively straightforward access of data stored at a particular memory location of the memory array, called an address. Prior to a write operation to a specific block of the memory array, the specific block must first be erased with the application of high voltages. A write operation, more accurately called a program operation, requires the careful application of high voltages to a selected memory location, followed by a program verify operation to ensure that the data has been properly programmed. Furthermore, since high voltages are used, the Flash chip must be designed to be relatively tolerant to inadvertent programming of non-selected memory cells.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007"><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref> is a circuit schematic showing a NAND cell string used in memory cell array shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>. <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref> is a circuit schematic of two NAND memory cell strings. Each NAND memory cell string includes 32 serially connected floating gate memory cells <b>50</b> each connected to respective wordlines WL0 to WL31, a string select transistor <b>52</b> connected between the bitline <b>54</b> and the first floating gate memory cell <b>50,</b> and a ground select transistor <b>56</b> connected between a common source line (CSL) <b>58</b> and the last floating gate memory cell <b>50.</b> The gate of string select transistor <b>52</b> receives a string select signal SSL, while the gate of ground select transistor <b>56</b> receives a ground select signal GSL. The NAND memory cell strings of a block share common wordlines, string select SSL, and ground select GSL signal lines. The construction and arrangement of the shown NAND memory string is well known in the art.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p><p id="p0008" num="0008">As previously mentioned, the NAND memory cell strings of the memory array are first erased, according to well-known techniques in the art. Each block of NAND memory cell strings can be selectively erased; therefore one or more blocks can be simultaneously erased. When successfully erased, all erased floating gate memory cells <b>50</b> will have a negative threshold voltage. In effect, all erased memory cells <b>50</b> are set to a default logic state, such as a logic "1", for example. Programmed memory cells <b>50</b> will have their threshold voltages changed to a positive threshold voltage, thus representing the opposite "0" logic state.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009"><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 3</figref> is a cross-sectional schematic of a typical Flash memory cell. A structure of such cells in well known in the art. Generally, control gate <b>60</b> is connected to a word line, while the floating gate <b>62</b> is isolated from all other nodes by an oxide insulator <b>61.</b> Electrons (charge carriers) are injected into or ejected from floating gate <b>62</b> and substrate <b>68</b> having a source <b>64</b> and a drain <b>66</b>, through thin tunneling oxide <b>63</b> between floating gate <b>62</b> and substrate <b>68</b>.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010"><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 4</figref> is a cross-sectional schematic of a nitride ROM cell having charge traps. Such a cell is also known in the art. In a nitride ROM cell, the floating gate is eliminated and the data is placed in a "holding chamber" or "charge traps" of the non-conductive layer <b>72</b>, for example, of silicon nitride, between the control gate <b>70</b> and substrate <b>78</b> having a source <b>74</b> and a drain <b>76</b>. Recently, silicon nanocrystals have also been used as charge traps.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">Generally, a cell is programmed by applying a high voltage to its gate while keeping its source and drain terminals grounded. The high electrical field causes electrons in the memory cell channel to cross the gate oxide and embed in the floating gate (known as Fowler-Nordheim (F-N) Tunneling), thereby increasing the effective threshold voltage of the memory cell.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">Due to the ever-increasing need for size reduction as well as the desire to increase the density of data storage, multi-level FLASH cells are now being widely used. As the name suggests, multi-level cells have more than two logic states per cell. A single cell storing two bits of information has 4 logic states corresponding to different levels of charge levels stored in the floating gates (or charge traps). Generally, a multi-level cell capable of storing N binary bits of data will have 2<sup>N</sup> states or logic levels.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p><p id="p0013" num="0013">However, each floating gate transistor has a certain total range of threshold voltages in which it may practically be operated. The total range is divided into the number of states defined for the memory cell including allowances for clear distinction of one state from another. Variations in fabrication processes and ageing of the device may cause shifts in the threshold voltages. These shifts can weaken the strength of cell states by moving one state closer to the next state. Also, as more levels are squeezed into a fixed total range (for example, fixed supply-voltage range), the tolerance for these shifts decreases.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014"><figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 5</figref> is a threshold voltage (Vt) distribution graph for a multi-level Flash memory cell. The intermediate reference voltages are also shown. This particular graph illustrates the thresholds of a Flash memory cell capable of storing 2 bits of data. Therefore, each multi-level Flash memory cell must store one of four threshold voltages. In this prior art scheme, an erased state represented by a negative threshold voltage lies in an erase voltage domain. All erased memory cells will by default have this negative threshold voltage. The remaining three states must be programmed, and their corresponding threshold voltages will be positive in value and lie in the program voltage domain. In this example, the erase voltage domain is below zero while the program voltage domain is above zero volts. A problem with this scheme is the required tightness of the distribution for each state and the distance between the states.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">Programming is typically done by the page, meaning that all the memory cells <b>50</b> in the block connected to the same wordline are selected to be programmed with write data (logic "0") at the same time. The remaining memory cells are thus unselected during programming. Since the memory cells start in the erased state (logic "1") prior to programming, only the memory cells to be programmed with the logic "0" should be subjected to the high electric fields necessary to promote F-N tunneling. However, due to the physical connections of the memory array, all the memory cells along the same wordline receive the same high voltage programming level. As a result, there is a potential that erased memory cells will have their threshold voltages unintentionally shifted. This is called program disturb, which is well known in the Flash memory field. This problem is more pronounced in multi-level cells as more levels are squeezed into a fixed voltage range.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></p><p id="p0016" num="0016">Several parameters such as, Vt window, Vt distance, and Vread distance, are key parameters to determine read/write speed, reliability and lifetime of multi-level flash memory shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 5</figref>. These three parameters influence one another: the cell Vt window and the cell Vt distance in a multi-level flash memory are much tighter than those in single-level flash memory since, in the case of a 2 bit cell, three cell states are in the program voltage domain with a positive Vt. If the cell Vt window is wider, the cell Vt distance is narrower. This reduces read sensing margin and eventually leads to a failure to sense neighboring cell states. In other words, Vt overlap or even minimum Vt distance between neighboring cell states leads to device failure.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">The strength or safety margin of a Vt-state is greatest when the Vt is half-way between adjacent reference voltages. Upper and lower limits for each Vt-state defining a cell Vt window may be specified. For example, in <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 5</figref>, cell state 0 is between lower limit VL0 (-3 volts) and upper limit VU0 (-2 volts). Cell state 1 is between lower limit VL1 (0.3 volts) and upper limit VU1 (0.8 volts). Typically, the cell Vt window in multi-level flash memory is in between 0.5 to 1.0 volts. Ideally, a narrow cell Vt window is preferred for better definition and distinction of a state.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">The cell Vt distance, which is defined as the difference in Vt between the lower limit of Vt of the threshold voltage range of one cell state and the upper limit of Vt of the threshold voltage range of the previous cell state. For example, the Vt distance between cell state 2 and cell state 1 is 1.5 - 0.8 = 0.7 volts. Typically the cell Vt distance in a multi-level flash memory cell is in between 0.7 to 1.0V. As is evident, larger cell Vt distances are preferred.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">It is also desirable to have the Vread distance, the distance between the read pass voltage and the upper limit of the fully programmed state as high as possible. For example, in <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 5</figref>, Vread distance is 5.5 - 3.3 = 1.2 volts. However, for optimum performance of the memory cell, a lower Vread is preferred as high Vread can cause disturbance. Therefore, there is a trade-off between Vread distance and the value of Vread. Moreover, the fixed supply-voltage range available may determine the maximum Vread value.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">Furthermore, as the number of rewrite (erase &amp; program) cycle increases, the cell Vt window becomes wider by tunnel oxide degradation due to trapped charges. Also, the read pass voltage Vread should be lower to minimize read disturbance to unselected cells in the<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> selected string. However, in order to accommodate the three cell states (in 2 bit cell) in the program voltage domain, the Vread distance has to be maintained at least well above VU3. This increases the level of Vread.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">In order to tightly control the Vt of the programmed cell, incremental step pulse programming (ISPP) has been proposed and widely used in flash memories. <figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 6</figref> is a graph illustrating the relationship between the number of program pulses applied to a wordline for programming a threshold voltage versus the size of each pulse. Generally, tight threshold voltage distributions can be obtained when the step size of each program pulse is small. However, the trade-off is programming time since more program pulses would be required.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">Accumulated program/erase cycles in multi-level flash memories with the above prior art scheme for cell Vt distribution typically results in well-known problems as described below.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">Repeated charge transfer causes electrons to be trapped in the floating gate and the dielectric, which degrades program and erase characteristics of the cells. Consequently, cells require gradually higher program and erase voltages as the number of erase-program cycle increases; resulting in limiting the number of erase-program cycles on a cell.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">The data retention characteristic in multi-level cells will be drastically degraded due to a small cell Vt distance. Moreover, as the Vt distribution for a given state is larger, the maximum Vt of programmed cells is higher. The higher Vt requires a higher programming voltage Vpgm, and adversely affects the data retention characteristics due to the larger electric field across the tunnel oxide. Moreover, the higher Vt required in multi-level cells require higher Vread. This causes read disturbance to unselected memory cells in the selected NAND cell string during read operations (i.e. soft-program by higher Vread to unselected memory cells).</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">In addition, the higher voltage requirements for read and write operations in multi-level flash memory does not scale with device dimension scaling as the electric field across all transistors including memory cells cannot be reduced.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p><p id="p0026" num="0026">Therefore, the life of a multi-level Flash memory cell is relatively short, typically only 10,000 cycles. This is significantly shorter than the 100,000 cycle limit for single bit per cell Flash memory devices.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027"><patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="US5953255A"><text>US 5,953,255</text></patcit> discloses an array of MOS memory cells having functionally symmetrical drain and source regions that may be programmed and/or erased using low voltage. e.g., less than about 7V. In a NAND-type array, UV-erasure increases threshold voltage Vt to erase memory cell contents, and low voltage-low current hot-hole injection ("HHI") decreases Vt to program the memory cells. <figref idrefs="f0010">Figure 12</figref> of <patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="US5953255A"><text>US 5,953,255</text></patcit> shows an erased state having a positive threshold voltage and programmed threshold voltages that are positive and negative. For NOR-type arrays, HHI decreases Vt to erase memory cell contents and channel-hot-electron ("CHE") injection increases Vt to program cell contents. Erase.and program potentials are low (&lt;7V), enabling arrays to be readily fabricated on a common IC with low voltage circuits. Because HHI strongly converges Vt, the memory cells may store more than two data values, which increases cell storage density. Cell symmetry permits swapping drain for source before cell endurance becomes too troublesome, which swapping can substantially increase the endurance lifetime for an array. Arrays may be used as flash memory, as EPROM replacement, or as one-time-programmable memory.</p><heading id="h0004"><b>SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</b></heading><p id="p0028" num="0028">It is an object of the present invention to obviate or mitigate at least one disadvantage of previous multi-level Flash memory cells devices. For example, present invention improves endurance of Flash memory cells by distributing programming threshold voltages in erase and program voltage domains.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">The present invention is defined by the independent claims.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --><!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --></p><p id="p0030" num="0030">The aspects and features of the present invention will become apparent to those ordinarily skilled in the art upon review of the following description of specific embodiments of the invention in conjunction with the accompanying figures.</p><heading id="h0005"><b>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</b></heading><p id="p0031" num="0031">Embodiments of the present invention will now be described, by way of example only, with reference to the attached Figures, wherein:
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> is a block diagram of a typical Flash memory device;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref> is a circuit schematic of a NAND cell string;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 3</figref> is a cross-sectional schematic of a typical Flash memory cell;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 4</figref> is a cross-sectional schematic of a nitride ROM cell having charge traps;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 5</figref> is a threshold voltage (Vt) distribution graph for a multi-level Flash memory cell of the prior art;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 6</figref> is a graph illustrating the relationship between the number of program pulses applied to a wordline for programming a threshold voltage versus the size of each pulse;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005">Figure 7</figref> is an exemplary embodiment of the invention showing a threshold voltage distribution for a Flash memory cell capable of storing 2 bits of data;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0006">Figure 8</figref> is an alternate embodiment of the invention showing a threshold voltage distribution graph for a Flash memory cell capable of storing 3 bits of data;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0007">Figure 9</figref> is a block diagram of the row circuits for a multi-level Flash memory device, according to an embodiment of the present invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0008">Figure 10</figref> is a circuit schematic of the block decoder and the wordline driver circuit shown in <figref idrefs="f0007">Figure 9</figref>;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0009">Figure 11</figref> is a circuit schematic of the row decoder circuit shown in <figref idrefs="f0007">Figure 9</figref>;<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></li><li><figref idrefs="f0010">Figure 12</figref> is a flow chart showing a method for performing an erase-verify operation;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0011">Figure 13</figref> is a flow chart showing a method for programming multiple threshold voltages, according to an embodiment of the present invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0012">Figure 14</figref> is a flow chart showing a program verify method, according to an embodiment of the present invention; and,</li><li><figref idrefs="f0013">Figure 15</figref> is a flow chart showing a method for reading data, according to an embodiment of the present invention.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0006"><b>DETAILED DESCRIPTION</b></heading><p id="p0032" num="0032">Generally, aspects of the present invention provide a threshold voltage distribution scheme for multi-level Flash cells with optimal Vt window and maximum Vt distance, while at the same time maintaining Vread at lower levels. In one embodiment, this is accomplished by programming at least one cell state in the erase voltage domain (for example, with a negative Vt value).</p><p id="p0033" num="0033"><figref idrefs="f0005">Figure 7</figref> is an exemplary embodiment of the invention. <figref idrefs="f0005">Figure 7</figref> shows a threshold voltage distribution for a multi-level Flash memory cell capable of storing 2 bits of data. In the present embodiment, there is one program state (cell state 1, corresponding to data "10") lying in the erased voltage domain with erased state (cell state 0, corresponding to data "11"). Therefore, there are two cell states lying in the erased voltage domain and two cell states (cell state 2, corresponding to data "01" and cell state 3, corresponding to data "00") in the program voltage domain. By programming this state in the erased voltage domain, different advantages are obtained. First, endurance is immediately increased relative to the prior art devices having the same Vt window, since the Vt distance between states is increased. Second, endurance is further increased by minimizing the Vt window, at the expense of programming speed. Third, the Vt distance and Vt window requirements are relaxed to provide improved programming performance over prior art devices, but having the same endurance. In addition, the Vread voltage for unselected cells can be lowered, for example, from a typical value of 5.5 volts to 4.8 volts. <figref idrefs="f0005">Figure 7</figref> shows example values VL and VU values, but any VL and VU can be set for each state.<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --></p><p id="p0034" num="0034">In conventional approaches, such as the threshold voltage scheme described with reference to <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 5</figref>, the cell state 0 has a negative Vt (erase voltage domain) while the remaining three cell states (states 1, 2, and 3) have positive Vt's (program voltage domain). In the threshold voltage scheme of the present embodiment as illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0005">Figure 7</figref>, cell states 0 and 1 have negative Vt's, while cell states 2 and 3 have positive Vt's. The number of cell states in the erase voltage domain and the program voltage domain are equal and hence this scheme is referred to as a "balanced" Vt distribution scheme.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">This balanced cell Vt distribution scheme provides at least the following advantages: Due to the separation of the cell states, the Vt window of each state can be widened, thus improving the program speed. The cell Vt distance is maximized, which will greatly improve data retention and endurance. This scheme further lowers the program voltage Vpgm and program-pass voltage Vpass, allowing for scaling with device geometry scaling. It also enables lowering of the Vread voltage, which, as a result, provides higher immunity to read disturbance typically encountered by conventional high Vread values. While <figref idrefs="f0005">Figure 7</figref> is an example Vt distribution for a two bit per cell device, cells storing any number of bits will benefit from the embodiments of the present invention.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036"><figref idrefs="f0006">Figure 8</figref> is an alternate embodiment of the invention. <figref idrefs="f0006">Figure 8</figref> shows a threshold voltage distribution graph for a multi-level Flash memory cell capable of storing 3 bits of information (i.e. eight different states). It should be noted that in the embodiment of <figref idrefs="f0006">Figure 8</figref>, exactly half of the eight possible states lie in the erase voltage domain while the other half lies in the program voltage domain. In further alternate embodiments, there can be five states in the erase voltage domain or three states in the erase voltage domain, or other combinations having at least two states in the erase voltage domain.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">As previously discussed for <figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 6</figref>, ISPP is used for programming desired threshold voltages corresponding to the different states of the multi-level Flash memory cells. As all memory cells are programmed to a desired threshold voltage from the erased state, ISPP gradually shifts the negative threshold voltage of an erased Flash memory cell using increasingly larger voltage pulses applied to its control gate. The incremental step size and number of pulses determines the final threshold voltage of the programmed Flash memory cell. According to an embodiment of the present invention, a programmed state in the erase<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> voltage domain is achieved by setting the number of pulses and step size of the pulses such that the desired negative threshold voltage is obtained. In the example of <figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 6</figref>, a -2V threshold voltage is obtained by using between 2 and 3 pulses, depending on the selected pulse step size. Once the erase domain program states have been programmed, the remaining program domain states are programmed according to known techniques. It is noted that the step size for programming the erase domain states can be small without impacting programming speed since the threshold voltage shift from the erase state is relatively small.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">A part of any programming operation is the program verify operation, which is used to check that the data has been properly programmed. For example, the desired threshold voltage may not have been set during a program operation. Therefore, the memory cell(s) is subjected to reprogramming until the program verify clears the memory cell, or until it is determined that the cell is defective. Once the program verify operation clears the memory cells, the data can be read. According to an embodiment of the present invention, program verify and read operations are executed with both positive and negative voltages.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">Table 1 shows bias conditions of the selected wordline and unselected wordlines to distinguish each cell state during read, verify &amp; control programmed cell Vt during program in a conventional multi-level flash memory using the cell Vt distribution scheme of <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 5</figref>. Table 2 shows bias conditions of the selected wordline and unselected wordlines during program verify and read in a multi-level flash memory programmable to have at least two states in the erase voltage domain, according to an aspect of the present invention.
<tables id="tabl0001" num="0001"><table frame="all"><title><b>Table 1</b></title><tgroup cols="5"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="27mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="30mm"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="36mm"/><colspec colnum="4" colname="col4" colwidth="31mm"/><colspec colnum="5" colname="col5" colwidth="36mm"/><thead><row><entry morerows="1" valign="top"/><entry namest="col2" nameend="col3" align="left" valign="top">Program Verify</entry><entry namest="col4" nameend="col5" align="left" valign="top">Read</entry></row><row><entry valign="top">Selected Wordline</entry><entry valign="top">Unselected Wordlines</entry><entry valign="top">Selected Wordline</entry><entry valign="top">Unselected Wordlines</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry>Cell State 0 ⇔ 1</entry><entry>0.3V</entry><entry>5.5V (Vread)</entry><entry>0V (Vref_rd1)</entry><entry>5.5V (Vread)</entry></row><row><entry/><entry>(Vref_pv1)</entry><entry/><entry/><entry/></row><row><entry>Cell State 1 ⇔ 2</entry><entry>1.5V</entry><entry>5.5V (Vread)</entry><entry>1.1V (Vref_rd2)</entry><entry>5.5V (Vread)</entry></row><row><entry/><entry>(Vref_pv2)</entry><entry/><entry/><entry/></row><row><entry>Cell State 2 ⇔ 3</entry><entry>2.8V</entry><entry>5.5V (Vread)</entry><entry>2.3V (Vref_rd3)</entry><entry>5.5V (Vread)</entry></row><row><entry/><entry>(Vref_pv3)</entry><entry/><entry/><entry/></row></tbody></tgroup></table></tables><!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --></p><p id="p0040" num="0040">Table 2 shows exemplary bias conditions for the program verify and read operations used for a multi-level Flash cell programmable to have at least two states in the erase voltage domain. As illustrated in Table 2, the negative voltages are applied to the selected wordline during the read and program verify operations for cells having negative cell Vt (i.e. cell state 0 and cell state 1). It should be noted that the voltage values in Table 2 are for illustration purpose only. In other words, voltage values in Table 2 can be varied according to process technology and cell characteristics.
<tables id="tabl0002" num="0002"><table frame="all"><title><b>Table 2</b></title><tgroup cols="5"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="27mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="30mm"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="36mm"/><colspec colnum="4" colname="col4" colwidth="31mm"/><colspec colnum="5" colname="col5" colwidth="36mm"/><thead><row><entry morerows="1" valign="top"/><entry namest="col2" nameend="col3" align="left" valign="top">Program Verify</entry><entry namest="col4" nameend="col5" align="left" valign="top">Read</entry></row><row><entry valign="top">Selected Wordline</entry><entry valign="top">Unselected Wordlines</entry><entry valign="top">Selected Wordline</entry><entry valign="top">Unselected Wordlines</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry>Cell State 0 ⇔ 1</entry><entry>-1.1V</entry><entry>4.8V (Vread)</entry><entry>-1.5V</entry><entry>4.8V (Vread)</entry></row><row><entry/><entry>(Vref_pv1)</entry><entry/><entry>(Vref_rd1)</entry><entry/></row><row><entry>Cell State 1 ⇔ 2</entry><entry>0.5V (Vref_pv2)</entry><entry>4.8V (Vread)</entry><entry>0V (Vref_rd2)</entry><entry>4.8V (Vread)</entry></row><row><entry>Cell State 2 ⇔ 3</entry><entry>2.1V (Vref_pv3)</entry><entry>4.8V (Vread)</entry><entry>1.5V (Vref_rd3)</entry><entry>4.8V (Vread)</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></tables></p><p id="p0041" num="0041">Due to shift in the Vt of at least one programmed cell state to the erase voltage domain, the program verify voltage and read voltage applied to the selected wordlines are different from conventional program verify and read operations, as shown in Table 2. Typically, all program verify voltage and read voltage are implemented with positive voltage values. However, the threshold voltage distribution scheme for multi-level Flash cells described herein utilizes both positive and negative voltages for program verify and read operations. This results in changes to the implementation for the wordline circuits as described below.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042"><figref idrefs="f0007">Figure 9</figref> is a block diagram of an exemplary row control logic for a multi-level Flash memory device according to an embodiment of the present invention. The row control logic <b>100</b> includes a block decoder <b>102</b>, a row decoder circuit <b>108</b> and a wordline driver circuit <b>110</b>. The device having row control logic <b>100</b> has a high voltage generator <b>104</b> and a negative voltage generator <b>106</b>, which may be used by other circuits that are not shown in <figref idrefs="f0007">Figure 9</figref>. There is one block decoder <b>102</b> per memory block, which receives a block address BA, for<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> enabling the wordline drivers. The row decoder <b>108</b> is commonly shared among all memory blocks, which receives a row address RA_b, as well as other signals which are not shown, for generating the source select signal SS, wordline signals S[0:n], and the ground select signal GS, generically referred to as row signals. Since at least one of the programmed states will be in the erase voltage domain (with a negative threshold voltage for example), the block decoder <b>102</b> and the row decoder circuit <b>108</b> will receive one or more negative voltages for application to a selected wordline signal. In response to a valid block address BA and row decoder signals, signals SSL, GSL and WL0-WLn are set to their required voltage levels during program, program verify and read operations. Example voltages are shown in Table 2 for program verify and read operations.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043"><figref idrefs="f0008">Figure 10</figref> is a circuit schematic showing circuit details of the block decoder <b>102</b> and wordline driver circuit <b>110</b> of <figref idrefs="f0007">Figure 9</figref>. Block decoder <b>102</b> is associated with one memory block, and includes a cross coupled inverter latch circuit and level shifter circuit. The latch circuit includes cross-coupled inverters <b>200</b> and <b>202</b>, an n-channel reset transistor <b>204</b>, and n-channel enable transistors <b>206</b> and <b>208</b>. The latch circuit is enabled, or set, when latch enable signal LTCH_EN and a block address BA are at the high logic level. The latch circuit of inverters <b>200</b> and <b>202</b> is reset when signal RST_BD is at the high logic level. The level shifter circuit includes a pair of cross-coupled p-channel transistors <b>210</b> and <b>212</b>, each being connected to respective n-channel steering transistors <b>214</b> and <b>216</b>. The shared terminals of transistors <b>210</b> and <b>212</b> receives a high voltage Vh while the shared terminals of transistors <b>214</b> and <b>216</b> receives a negative voltage Vn. Node Vh is connected to the positive voltage generator <b>104</b> while node Vn is connected to the negative voltage generator <b>106</b>. Steering transistors <b>214</b> and <b>216</b> have gate terminals connected to the output of inverter <b>200</b> and inverter <b>218</b>, the input of which is connected to the gate of transistor <b>214</b>. It is noted that the high voltage supply provided to inverter <b>200</b> is lower than Vh while the low voltage supply provided to inverter <b>202</b> is higher than Vn. The output of the level shifter circuit (an enabling signal) BD_out drives the gate terminals of all the n-channel pass transistors <b>220</b> of wordline drivers <b>110</b>. The substrate terminal of all the pass transistors <b>220</b> are connected to Vn. Each pass transistor can selectively pass the source select (SS), wordline (S0-Sn) and ground select (GS) signals to the memory array. Placeholder "n" can be any non-zero integer number,<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> typically corresponding to the maximum number of cells in the Flash cell string. The general operation of the block decoder circuit is now described.</p><p id="p0044" num="0044">In a read operation for example, one memory block is selected while other blocks remain unselected. In otherwords, one memory block is enabled while remaining memory blocks are disabled. To enable a memory block, LTCH_EN and BA will be at the high logic level, thereby setting the level shifter circuit to output high voltage Vh. Therefore, all the pass transistors 220 of wordline driver circuit 110 are turned on. Unselected wordlines (unselected Si) will be set to a Vread voltage while the selected wordline (selected Si) will be set to the desired voltage. The desired voltage can be -1.5V if the present read operation is intended to distinguish between cell state 0 and cell state 1, for example. Disabled memory blocks will have their corresponding block decoder circuit output set to output low voltage Vn (-1.5V for example). Therefore, all the pass transistors <b>220</b> in the unselected memory blocks will be turned off even though one of the Si signals may be at Vn of -1.5V for example. Table 3 illustrates example Vh and Vn voltages for read, program, program verify, erase and erase verify operations.
<tables id="tabl0003" num="0003"><table frame="all"><title><b>Table 3</b></title><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="26mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="14mm"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="34mm"/><thead><row><entry align="center" valign="top"/><entry align="center" valign="top">Vh</entry><entry align="center" valign="top">Vn</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry>Read</entry><entry>∼ 6.5V</entry><entry>0V/-1.5V (Vref_rd1)</entry></row><row><entry>Program</entry><entry>∼ 18V</entry><entry>0v</entry></row><row><entry>Program Verify</entry><entry>∼ 6.5V</entry><entry>0V/-1.1V (Vref_pv1)</entry></row><row><entry>Erase</entry><entry>Vdd</entry><entry>0v</entry></row><row><entry>Erase Verify</entry><entry>∼ 6.5V</entry><entry>0v</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></tables></p><p id="p0045" num="0045"><figref idrefs="f0009">Figure 11</figref> is a circuit schematic showing one row decoder circuit of row decoder <b>108</b> of <figref idrefs="f0007">Figure 9</figref>. The presently shown schematic of <figref idrefs="f0009">Figure 11</figref> is a functional representation only, as there can be different specific circuit implementations that are possible. In prior art row decoder circuits, only voltages in the program voltage domain are provided. According to an embodiment of the present invention, both program voltage domain (ie. positive voltages) and<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> erase voltage domain (ie. negative voltages) are provided by the presently shown row decoder circuit. <figref idrefs="f0009">Figure 11</figref> shows one circuit for generating one row signal Si where i can be an integer value between 0 and n, but the circuits for generating signals SS and GS are similarly configured. The row decoder circuit includes a multiplexor <b>300</b> for receiving all the voltages that are used during program, program verify, read, erase and erase verify operations. This includes for example, a program verify voltage Vver, a read voltage Vread, a pass voltage Vpass, and a programming voltage Vpgm.</p><p id="p0046" num="0046">Multiplexor <b>300</b> further receives the different reference voltages used for read and program verify operations, such as Vref_rd1, Vref_rd2 and Vref_rd3 for the 2 bit/cell configuration. In the present embodiment, Vref_rd1 is a negative erase domain voltage while Vref_rd2 and Vref_rd3 are positive program domain voltages. Any number of voltages can be provided to multiplexor <b>300</b>, and then selectively passed to node Sn. Voltage selection signal Vselect is used to pass any one of the voltages. Those skilled in the art will understand that Vselect will be a multi-bit signal, the number depending on the number of input ports that multiplexor <b>300</b> is configured to have. The row decoder circuit includes an n-channel disabling transistor <b>302</b> connected between node Sn and ground for disabling the circuit when not in use, or during a power down mode of operation, for example.</p><p id="p0047" num="0047">In general operation, signal Sn is enabled in response to a selected address for enabling a particular wordline when address RA_b is at the low logic level. RA_b can be a decoded row address or a predecoded row address. Depending on the operation being performed, Vselect will be set to pass one of the voltages received by multiplexor <b>300</b> to the Sn node. While not shown, the voltage generators <b>104</b> and <b>106</b> of <figref idrefs="f0007">Figure 9</figref> are controlled to provide the appropriate voltage levels depending on the operation being performed. Table 4 illustrates example voltages applied to the wordlines and by the row decoder circuit during a read operation for selected and unselected wordlines Si, where i is an integer value between 0 and n. Table 5 illustrates example voltages applied to the wordlines and by the row decoder circuit during a program verify operation for selected and unselected wordlines Si, where i is an integer value between 0 and n.<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> -->
<tables id="tabl0004" num="0004"><table frame="all"><title><b>Table 4</b></title><tgroup cols="4"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="52mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="28mm"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="28mm"/><colspec colnum="4" colname="col4" colwidth="28mm"/><thead><row><entry align="center" valign="top"><b>Signal</b></entry><entry align="center" valign="top"><b>Cell State 1⇔2</b></entry><entry align="center" valign="top"><b>Cell State 2 ⇔ 3</b></entry><entry align="center" valign="top"><b>Cell State 3 ⇔ 4</b></entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry>Unselected BD_out</entry><entry align="center">-1.5V</entry><entry align="center">-1.5V or 0V</entry><entry align="center">-1.5V or 0V</entry></row><row><entry>(Unselected Block)</entry><entry align="center"/><entry align="center"/><entry align="center"/></row><row><entry>Selected BD_out (Selected Block)</entry><entry align="center">6.5V</entry><entry align="center">6.5V</entry><entry align="center">6.5V</entry></row><row><entry>Vh</entry><entry align="center">6.5V</entry><entry align="center">6.5V</entry><entry align="center">6.5V</entry></row><row><entry>Vn</entry><entry align="center">-1.5V</entry><entry align="center">-1.5V or 0V</entry><entry align="center">-1.5V or 0V</entry></row><row><entry>SS</entry><entry align="center">4.8V (Vread)</entry><entry align="center">4.8V (Vread)</entry><entry align="center">4.8V (Vread)</entry></row><row><entry>Selected Si</entry><entry align="center">-1.5V (Vref_rd1)</entry><entry align="center">0V (Vref_rd2)</entry><entry align="center">1.5V (Vref_rd3)</entry></row><row><entry>Unselected Si</entry><entry align="center">4.8V (Vread)</entry><entry align="center">4.8V (Vread)</entry><entry align="center">4.8V (Vread)</entry></row><row><entry>GS</entry><entry align="center">4.8V (Vread)</entry><entry align="center">4.8V (Vread)</entry><entry align="center">4.8V (Vread)</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></tables>
<tables id="tabl0005" num="0005"><table frame="all"><title><b>Table 5</b></title><tgroup cols="4"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="52mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="27mm"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="28mm"/><colspec colnum="4" colname="col4" colwidth="28mm"/><thead><row><entry align="center" valign="top"><b>Signal</b></entry><entry align="center" valign="top"><b>Cell State 1 ⇔ 2</b></entry><entry align="center" valign="top"><b>Cell State 2 ⇔ 3</b></entry><entry align="center" valign="top"><b>Cell State 3 ⇔ 4</b></entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry rowsep="0">Unselected BD_out</entry><entry rowsep="0" align="center">-1.1V</entry><entry rowsep="0" align="center">-1.1 V or 0V</entry><entry rowsep="0" align="center">-1.1V or 0V</entry></row><row><entry>(Unselected Block)</entry><entry align="center"/><entry align="center"/><entry align="center"/></row><row><entry>Selected BD_out (Selected Block)</entry><entry align="center">6.5V</entry><entry align="center">6.5V</entry><entry align="center">6.5V</entry></row><row><entry>Vh</entry><entry align="center">6.5V</entry><entry align="center">6.5V</entry><entry align="center">6.5V</entry></row><row><entry>Vn</entry><entry align="center">-1.1V</entry><entry align="center">0.5V or 0V</entry><entry align="center">2.1V or 0V</entry></row><row><entry>SS</entry><entry align="center">4.8V (Vread)</entry><entry align="center">4.8V (Vread)</entry><entry align="center">4.8V (Vread)</entry></row><row><entry>Selected Si</entry><entry align="center">-1.1V (Vref_pvl)</entry><entry align="center">0.5V (Vref_pv2)</entry><entry align="center">2.1V (Vref_pv3)</entry></row><row><entry>Unselected Si</entry><entry align="center">4.8V (Vread)</entry><entry align="center">4.8V (Vread)</entry><entry align="center">4.8V (Vread)</entry></row><row><entry>GS</entry><entry align="center">4.8V (Vread)</entry><entry align="center">4.8V (Vread)</entry><entry align="center">4.8V (Vread)</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></tables></p><p id="p0048" num="0048">In the prior art programming schemes, programmed cell states are confined to the program voltage domain, ie. having positive threshold voltages. In the presently disclosed balanced threshold programming scheme, at least one programmed cell state resides in the erase voltage domain. Therefore, an erase verify algorithm is used for ensuring that all the erased memory cells have the proper erase threshold voltage level. <figref idrefs="f0010">Figure 12</figref> is a flow chart showing a method for performing an erase verify operation according to an embodiment of<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> the present invention. Since a programmed state will be in the erase voltage domain, the method of <figref idrefs="f0010">Figure 12</figref> ensures that all the memory cells are sufficiently erased such that their threshold voltages do not lie within the designated negative threshold voltage range for a programmed state.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">The method of <figref idrefs="f0010">Figure 12</figref> commences at step <b>400</b> by erasing a selected block of the memory array. After all the memory cells have been erased, all the bitlines of the selected memory block are precharged to a first voltage level such as VDD at step <b>402</b>. A reference voltage is then applied to all the wordlines of the memory cells at step <b>404</b>. It is presumed that the memory cells are configured as NAND cell strings, such as the ones previously shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref>. The reference voltage is selected to be greater than the highest possible erase threshold voltage for the erase state, and lower than the lowest possible program threshold voltage for the adjacent program state. Generally, the reference voltage in the erase domain voltage, and in the example where the erase domain is below 0V, the reference voltage is a negative voltage level. With reference to the example threshold voltage distribution of <figref idrefs="f0005">Figure 7</figref> for example, if all the memory cells have been properly erased, then their threshold voltage should be between -2.9 and -2.1 volts. The reference voltage applied to the wordlines will be about -1.5 volts. If all the memory cells have been properly erased, then the -1.5 volt level on wordlines 0 to 31 is sufficient to turn on the transistors and discharge the bitline to CSL or ground. However, if any one of the cells in the NAND cell string has a threshold voltage higher than -1.5 volts, then the bitline will not discharge to ground. Therefore, the bitline voltage is sensed at step <b>406</b>. At step <b>408</b>, a determination is made to see if the bitline voltage is equal or not to the original pre-charge voltage. If the bitline voltage is the same, then the method loops back to step <b>400</b> to re-erase the cells and repeat the verification process. Otherwise, all the memory cells have been properly erased and the erase verify method ends at step <b>410</b>.</p><p id="p0050" num="0050">After all the memory cells have been verified as being successfully erased, programming of data to the memory cells can proceed. <figref idrefs="f0011">Figure 13</figref> is a flow chart illustrating a method of programming one programmed state in the erase voltage domain, according to an embodiment of the present invention. The method starts at step <b>500</b> by setting the ISPP parameters such as number of program pulses and step size for each pulse, for the state to be<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> programmed in the erase voltage domain. At step <b>502</b> the erase voltage domain threshold voltage is programmed to the selected Flash memory cells. As previously mentioned, the erase threshold voltage of a memory cell is effectively shifted to the desired erase domain threshold voltage level by using a predetermined number of program pulses and step sizes in accordance with the ISPP scheme. At step <b>504</b> a program verify operation is executed to ensure that the programmed state has been properly programmed. More specifically, the program verify will use the appropriate erase voltage domain reference voltage to verify the programmed state. In the present example, the program verify reference voltage will be a negative voltage level. Further details of the program verify operation are shown later in <figref idrefs="f0012">Figure 14</figref>.</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">A determination is made at step <b>506</b> to see if at least one memory cell fails program verification. If at least one failure is determined, then the method loops back to step <b>502</b> for reprogramming of the at least one memory cell. Otherwise, all the memory cells have been deemed to have been successfully programmed, and the method proceeds to step <b>508</b> where subsequent programming sequences are executed for the remaining states. The remaining states can include further erase voltage domain states and/or program voltage domain states. Further erase voltage domain states are programmed according to the same sequence shown in steps <b>500</b> to <b>506</b>, but with different ISPP parameters and program verify reference voltages.</p><p id="p0052" num="0052"><figref idrefs="f0012">Figure 14</figref> is a flow chart of a method for performing a program verify operation after a state has been programmed in the erase voltage domain. The method starts at step <b>600</b> by precharging the bitlines to a first voltage level, such as positive voltage level for example. At step <b>602</b> the selected wordline corresponding to the page that was programmed is driven to an erase voltage domain reference voltage, and unselected wordlines are driven to a read voltage at step <b>604</b>. The erase voltage domain reference voltage is selected to be lower than the desired threshold voltage range of the currently programmed state, but higher than the adjacent state having a lower threshold voltage range. In the example of <figref idrefs="f0005">Figure 7</figref>, if the programmed state being verified is cell state 1, then the erase voltage domain reference voltage is selected to be higher than Vref1-rd. The read voltage is typically a program voltage domain voltage sufficient to turn on a memory cell having the highest programmed threshold voltage, such as Vread in the example of <figref idrefs="f0005">Figure 7</figref>. The bitline is sensed at step <b>606</b>, and a<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> determination is made at step <b>608</b> to see if the bitline voltage has changed, ie. been discharged through the NAND cell string. If there is a change to the bitline voltage, then the threshold voltage of the currently programmed state is too low and conducts current. Thus the memory cell(s) are deemed to have failed, and the method proceeds to step <b>610</b> to repeat programming for the failed cell(s). Otherwise, the program verify method ends at step <b>612</b> as all the cells have passed verification for the currently programmed state.</p><p id="p0053" num="0053">Once data has been programmed and verified, it can be read from the memory array. In one multi-level sensing scheme, latches for the two bits representing one of four possible logic states are set to default states, such as 1,1 for example. Reading is accomplished by iteratively reading out the cell by applying Vref1-rd, Vref2-rd and Vref3-rd in each iteration. If the threshold voltage of the selected memory cell is determined to be less than the applied reference voltage for that iteration, then neither bit state is changed, or toggled. If the threshold voltage of the selected memory cell is determined to be greater than the applied reference voltage for that iteration, then one bit state is changed, or toggled. The particular bit to toggle depends on the specific read iteration being executed. This ensures that the bit states for the lowest threshold voltage (ie. erased state) will remain unchanged for each subsequent iteration. Hence, for a two bit multi-level memory cell, three read iterations are required for determining the two bit state of the memory cell.</p><p id="p0054" num="0054"><figref idrefs="f0013">Figure 15</figref> is a flow chart of a method for reading one cell state in the erase voltage domain. The method starts at step <b>7</b>00 by precharging the bitlines to a first voltage level, such as a positive voltage level for example. The selected wordline is driven to an erase voltage domain reference voltage at step <b>702</b>, while the remaining unselected wordlines are driven to a read voltage at step <b>704</b>. In the presently described example, the erase voltage domain reference voltage is selected to be lower than the desired threshold voltage range of the currently programmed state, but higher than the adjacent state having a lower threshold voltage range. In the example of <figref idrefs="f0006">Figure 8</figref>, if the programmed state being read is cell state 1, then the erase voltage domain reference voltage is selected to be Vref1-rd. The read voltage is typically a program voltage domain voltage sufficient to turn on a memory cell having the highest programmed threshold voltage, such as Vread in the example of <figref idrefs="f0006">Figure 8</figref>. The bitline is sensed at step <b>706</b> to determine if the cell threshold voltage is either greater than or less<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> than Vref1-rd, and the states of the bits are updated. At step <b>708</b>, the remaining states are sensed to complete the read operation for the memory cell. The remaining states can be further erase voltage domain states and program voltage domain states. In otherwords, the read process will repeat with the updated parameters corresponding to the state being sensed, ie, setting the reference voltage to Vref2-rd at step <b>700</b>. Once all the possible states stored in the Flash memory cell are sensed, the multi- bit logic states corresponding to the threshold level stored in the memory cell are output through read path circuits at step <b>710</b>.</p><p id="p0055" num="0055">Therefore, by programming at least one state in the erase voltage domain as previously described by the embodiments of the present invention, reliability or endurance of a multi-level Flash memory device is maximized relative to prior art multi-level Flash memory devices because the Vt window for each cell state is minimized while the Vt distance between cell states is maximized. Alternately, the Vt window for each cell state can be relaxed, thereby increasing ISPP programming speed relative to prior art multi-level Flash memory devices as the step sizes are increased and number of steps are decreased. Those skilled in the art will understand that optimization of the Vt window and Vt distance will be tailored for the specific application of the multi-level Flash memory device.</p><p id="p0056" num="0056">The above-described embodiments of the present invention are intended to be examples only. Alterations, modifications and variations may be effected to the particular embodiments by those of skill in the art without departing from the scope of the invention, which is defined solely by the claims appended hereto.</p><p id="p0057" num="0057">For example, the erase voltage domain is described in the example embodiments as being voltages less than 0V while the program voltage domain include voltages greater than 0V. In an alternate embodiment, the threshold voltage distribution scheme can be inverted, such that the erase voltage domain includes voltages greater than 0V while the program voltage domain includes voltages less than 0V.</p><p id="p0058" num="0058">In the preceding description, for purposes of explanation, numerous details are set forth in order to provide a thorough understanding of the embodiments of the invention. However, it will be apparent to one skilled in the art that these specific details are not required in order to practice the invention. In other instances, well-known electrical structures and<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> circuits are shown in block diagram form in order not to obscure the invention. For example, specific details are not provided as to whether the embodiments of the invention described herein are implemented as a software routine, hardware circuit, firmware, or a combination thereof.</p><p id="p0059" num="0059">Embodiments of the invention can be represented as a software product stored in a machine-readable medium (also referred to as a computer-readable medium, a processor-readable medium, or a computer usable medium having a computer-readable program code embodied therein). The machine-readable medium can be any suitable tangible medium, including magnetic, optical, or electrical storage medium including a diskette, compact disk read only memory (CD-ROM), memory device (volatile or non-volatile), or similar storage mechanism. The machine-readable medium can contain various sets of instructions, code sequences, configuration information, or other data, which, when executed, cause a processor to perform steps in a method according to an embodiment of the invention. Those of ordinary skill in the art will appreciate that other instructions and operations necessary to implement the described invention can also be stored on the machine-readable medium. Software running from the machine-readable medium can interface with circuitry to perform the described tasks.</p><p id="p0060" num="0060">The above-described embodiments of the invention are intended to be examples only. Alterations, modifications and variations can be effected to the particular embodiments by those of skill in the art without departing from the scope of the invention, which is defined solely by the claims appended hereto.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56985353" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Speichervorrichtung mit:
<claim-text>einem Speicher-Array mit Speicherzellen (50), die in Zeilen und Spalten angeordnet sind, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b>:
<claim-text>jede Speicherzelle (50) löschbar ist, um eine negative Lösch-Schwellenspannung zu haben, und in einem Programmierbetrieb programmierbar ist, um mindestens eine negative Programmier-Schwellenspannung zu haben;</claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Wortleitungs-Treiber (110) zum selektiven Treiben einer Wortleitung (WLn) an einem Gate-Anschluss (60) einer Speicherzelle mit einer Programmierspannung angeschlossen ist, um die negative Lösch-Schwellenspannung während des Programmierbetriebs in die mindestens eine negative Programmier-Schwellenspannung zu ändern.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Speichervorrichtung nach Anspruch 1, wobei<br/>
jede Speicherzelle programmierbar ist, um eine positive Programmier-Schwellenspannung zu haben.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Speichervorrichtung nach Anspruch 1, wobei jede Speicherzelle N Datenbits speichert, die 2N Schwellenspannungen entsprechen, wobei N ein Ganzzahlwert von mindestens 2 ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Speichervorrichtung nach Anspruch 3, wobei ein erster Bereich der 2N Schwellenspannungen negative Schwellenspannungen hat und ein zweiter Bereich der 2N Schwellenspannungen positive Schwellenspannungen hat, wobei optional<br/>
eine von dem ersten Bereich der 2N Schwellenspannungen negative Schwellenspannungen hat,<br/>
der erste Bereich die Hälfte der 2N Schwellenspannungen enthält,<br/>
der erste Bereich mehr als die Hälfte der 2N Schwellenspannungen enthält, oder<br/>
der erste Bereich weniger als die Hälfte der 2N Schwellenspannungen enthält.<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Verfahren zum Speichern von Daten in einer Flash-Speicherzelle, <b>gekennzeichnet durch</b>:
<claim-text>Löschen der Flash-Speicherzelle (50), um einen gelöschten Zustand mit einer negativen Schwellenspannung zu haben,</claim-text>
<claim-text>Programmieren der Flash-Speicherzelle (50), um irgendeinen von einem ersten Bereich von programmierten Zuständen, die von dem gelöschten Zustand mit einer negativen Schwellenspannung verschieden sind, und einen zweiten Bereich von programmierten Zuständen mit einer positiven Schwellenspannung zu haben.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 5, wobei die Flash-Speicherzelle irgendeinen von 2N Zuständen speichert, wobei N ein Ganzzahlwert von mindestens 2 ist, wobei optional<br/>
eine Hälfte der 2N Zustände mit einer negativen Schwellenspannung den ersten Bereich von programmierten Zuständen und den gelöschten Zustand enthält,<br/>
mehr als die Hälfte der 2N Zustände mit einer negativen Schwellenspannung den ersten Bereich von programmierten Zuständen und den gelöschten Zustand enthält, wobei weniger als die Hälfte der 2N Zustände mit einer negativen Schwellenspannung den ersten Bereich von programmierten Zuständen und den gelöschten Zustand enthält, oder<br/>
das Programmieren das Treiben einer mit der Flash-Speicherzelle (50) verbundenen Wortleitung (WLn) mit einer Programmierspannung umfasst, um eine negative Schwellenspannung, die dem gelöschten Zustand entspricht, in eine positive Schwellenspannung zu ändern, die irgendeinem von dem ersten Bereich von programmierten Zuständen und dem zweiten Bereich von programmierten Zuständen entspricht.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Speichervorrichtung nach Anspruch 1, wobei<br/>
mindestens eine Speicherzelle (50) des Speicher-Arrays programmierbar ist, um einen von einem ersten Zellenzustand und einem zweiten Zellenzustand zu haben, wobei der erste Zellenzustand eine Schwellenspannung in einem Schwellenspannungsbereich zwischen einer negativen Spannung und einer positiven Spannung hat.<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Speichervorrichtung nach Anspruch 7, wobei der zweite Zellenzustand eine zweite Schwellenspannung hat, die kleiner ist als die Schwellenspannung des ersten Zellenzustands.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Speichervorrichtung nach Anspruch 8, wobei der erste Zellenzustand einem gelöschten Zustand oder einem programmierten Zustand entspricht, und der zweite Zellenzustand einem anderen programmierten Zustand entspricht,<br/>
der erste Zellenzustand einem ersten programmierten Zustand entspricht und der Schwellenspannungsbereich ein erster Schwellenspannungsbereich ist, und der zweite Zellenzustand einem zweiten programmierten Zustand mit der zweiten Schwellenspannung innerhalb eines zweiten Schwellenspannungsbereichs entspricht, der niedriger ist als der erste Schwellenspannungsbereich, oder<br/>
der zweite Zellenzustand einem gelöschten Zustand entspricht.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Speichervorrichtung nach Anspruch 9, außerdem mit einem Löschzustand, der einen Lösch-Schwellenspannungsbereich hat, der niedriger ist als der zweite Schwellenspannungsbereich, wobei optional die mindestens eine Speicherzelle auf einen dritten programmierten Zustand programmierbar ist, der einen dritten Schwellenspannungsbereich hat, der höher ist als der erste Schwellenspannungsbereich.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Verfahren zum Verifizieren eines erfolgreichen Programmierens einer Flash-Speicherzelle (50), die mit einer Bitleitung gekoppelt ist, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die Flash-Speicherzelle (50) von einem gelöschten Zustand mit einer ersten negativen Schwellenspannung auf einen programmierten Zustand mit einer zweiten negativen Schwellenspannung programmiert ist;<br/>
Treiben einer mit der Flash-Speicherzelle (50) verbundenen Wortleitung (WLn) mit einer negativen Referenzspannung; und<br/>
Bestimmen einer fehlerhaften Programmierung der Flash-Speicherzelle (50), wenn sich ein Spannungspegel der Bitleitung in Reaktion auf die Wortleitung bei der negativen Referenzspannung verändert.<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 11,<br/>
außerdem mit dem Vorladen der Bitleitung auf den Spannungspegel, bevor die Wortleitung getrieben wird,<br/>
wobei das Bestimmen das Erfassen einer Veränderung des Spannungspegels der Bitleitung umfasst, wenn die Flash-Speicherzelle in Reaktion auf die Wortleitung bei einer negativen Referenzspannung eingeschaltet wird,<br/>
wobei der programmierte Zustand einem ersten Zellenzustand entspricht, und die negative Referenzspannung größer ist als eine negative Schwellenspannung, die einem zweiten Zellenzustand der Flash-Speicherzelle entspricht.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 12, wobei<br/>
der zweite Zellenzustand einem anderen programmierten Zustand entspricht.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 11, wobei der programmierte Zustand einen Schwellenspannungsbereich hat, der durch eine untere Spannungsgrenze und eine obere Spannungsgrenze definiert ist, die größer ist als die untere Spannungsgrenze, wobei die untere Spannungsgrenze eine negative Spannung ist, wobei optional<br/>
die obere Spannungsgrenze einen andere negative Spannung ist, oder<br/>
die obere Spannungsgrenze eine positive Spannung ist.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56985354" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A memory device comprising:
<claim-text>a memory array having memory cells (50) arranged in rows and columns, <b>characterized in that</b>:
<claim-text>each memory cell (50) is erasable to have a negative erase threshold voltage and programmable in a program operation to have at least one negative program threshold voltage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a wordline driver (110) for selectively driving a wordline (WLn) connected to a gate terminal (60) of a memory cell with a programming voltage for changing the negative erase threshold voltage to the at least one negative program threshold voltage during the program operation.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The memory device of claim 1, wherein<br/>
each memory cell is programmable to have a positive program threshold voltage.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The memory device of claim 1, wherein each memory cell stores N bits of data corresponding to 2N threshold voltages, where N is an integer value of at least 2.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The memory device of claim 3, wherein a first portion of the 2N threshold voltages have negative threshold voltages, and a second portion of the 2N threshold voltages have positive threshold voltages, optionally, wherein<br/>
one of the first portion of the 2N threshold voltages have negative threshold voltages,<br/>
the first portion includes half of the of the 2N threshold voltages,<br/>
the first portion includes more than half of the 2N threshold voltages, or<br/>
the first portion includes less than half of the 2N threshold voltages.<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>A method for storing data in a flash memory cell <b>characterized in that</b>:
<claim-text>erasing the flash memory cell (50) to have an erased state with a negative threshold voltage,</claim-text>
<claim-text>programming the flash memory cell (50) to have any one of a first portion of programmed states distinct from the erased state having a negative threshold voltage and a second portion of programmed states having a positive threshold voltage.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The method of claim 5, wherein the flash memory cell stores any one of 2N states, where N is an integer value of at least 2, optionally, wherein<br/>
half of the 2N states having a negative threshold voltage include the first portion of programmed states and the erased state,<br/>
more than half of the 2N states having a negative threshold voltage include the first portion of programmed states and the erased state, less than half of the 2N states having a negative threshold voltage include the first portion of programmed states and the erased state, or<br/>
programming includes driving a wordline (WLn) connected to the flash memory cell (50) with a programming voltage for changing a negative threshold voltage corresponding to the erase state to a positive threshold voltage corresponding to any one of the first portion of programmed states and the second portion of programmed states.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The memory device of claim 1, wherein<br/>
at least one memory cell (50) of the memory array is programmable to have one of a first cell state and a second cell state, the first cell state having a threshold voltage in a threshold voltage range between a negative voltage and a positive voltage.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The memory device of claim 7; wherein the second cell state has a second threshold voltage less than the threshold voltage of the first cell state.<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The memory device of claim 8, wherein the first cell state corresponds to an erase state or a programmed state, and the second cell state corresponds to another programmed state,<br/>
the first cell state corresponds to a first programmed state and the threshold voltage range is a first threshold voltage range, and the second cell state corresponds to a second programmed state having the second threshold voltage within a second threshold voltage range lower than the first threshold voltage range, or<br/>
the second cell state corresponds to an erase state.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The memory device of claim 9, further comprising an erase state having an erase threshold voltage range lower than the second threshold voltage range, optionally wherein the at least one memory cell is programmable to a third programmed state having a third threshold voltage range greater than the first threshold voltage range.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>A method for verifying successful programming of a flash memory cell (50) coupled to a bitline, <b>characterized in that</b> the flash memory cell (50) is programmed from an erased state having a first negative threshold voltage to a programmed state having a second negative threshold voltage;<br/>
driving a wordline (WLn) connected to the flash memory cell (50) with a negative reference voltage; and<br/>
determining failed programming of the flash memory cell (50) if a voltage level of the bitline changes in response to the wordline at the negative reference voltage.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>The method of claim 11,<br/>
further including precharging the bitline to the voltage level before driving the wordline,<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> -->wherein determining includes sensing a change in the voltage level of the bitline when the flash memory cell turns on in response to the wordline at the negative reference voltage,<br/>
wherein the programmed state corresponds to a first cell state, and the negative reference voltage is greater than a negative threshold voltage corresponding to a second cell state of the flash memory cell.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>The method of claim 12, wherein<br/>
the second cell state corresponds to another programmed state.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>The method of claim 11, wherein the programmed state has a threshold voltage range defined by a lower voltage limit and an upper voltage limit greater than the lower voltage limit, the lower voltage limit being a negative voltage, optionally, wherein<br/>
the upper voltage limit is another negative voltage, or<br/>
the upper voltage limit is a positive voltage.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56985355" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Dispositif mémoire comprenant :
<claim-text>une matrice de mémoire comportant des cellules de mémoire (50) agencées en rangées et en colonnes, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> :
<claim-text>chaque cellule de mémoire (50) peut être effacée avec une tension de seuil d'effacement négative et programmable dans une opération de programmation ayant au moins une tension de seuil de programmation négative ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un pilote de ligne de mots (110) pour commander de manière sélective une ligne de mots (WLn) connectée à une borne de grille d'une cellule de mémoire avec une tension de programmation pour charger la tension de seuil d'effacement négative à l'au moins une tension de seuil de programmation négative pendant l'opération de programmation.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Dispositif mémoire selon la revendication 1, dans lequel<br/>
chaque cellule de mémoire est programmable avec une tension de seuil de programmation positive.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Dispositif mémoire selon la revendication 1, dans lequel chaque cellule de mémoire contient N bits de données correspondant à 2N tensions de seuil, où N est une valeur entière au moins égale à 2.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Dispositif mémoire selon la revendication 3, dans lequel une première portion des 2N tensions de seuil comportent des tensions de seuil négatives et une seconde portion des 2N tensions de seuil comportent des tensions de seuil positives, de manière facultative, dans lequel<br/>
une tension de la première portion des 2N tensions de seuil est une tension de seuil négative,<br/>
la première portion comporte la moitié des 2N tensions de seuil,<br/>
la première portion comporte plus de la moitié des 2N tensions de seuil, ou<br/>
la première portion comporte moins de la moitié des 2N tensions de seuil.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Procédé d'enregistrement de données dans une cellule de mémoire flash, <b>caractérisé par</b> :
<claim-text>l'effacement de la cellule de mémoire flash (50) ayant un état effacé avec une tension de seuil négative,<!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>la programmation de la cellule de mémoire flash (50) à une tension quelconque d'une première portion d'états programmés distincts de l'état effacé ayant une tension de seuil négative et une seconde portion d'états programmés ayant une tension de seuil positive.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 5, dans lequel la cellule de mémoire flash contient l'un quelconque des 2N états, où N est une valeur entière au moins égale à 2, de manière facultative, dans lequel<br/>
la moitié des 2N états ayant une tension de seuil négative comporte la première portion des états programmés et l'état effacé,<br/>
plus de la moitié des 2N états ayant une tension de seuil négative comporte la première portion des états programmés et l'état effacé, moins de la moitié des 2N états ayant une tension de seuil négative comporte la première portion des états programmés et l'état effacé, ou<br/>
la programmation comporte la commande d'une ligne de mots (WLn) connectée à la cellule de mémoire flash (50) avec une tension de programmation pour changer la tension de seuil négative correspondant à l'état effacé en une tension de seuil positive correspondant à une portion quelconque de la première portion des états programmés et de la seconde portion des états programmés.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Dispositif mémoire selon la revendication 1, dans lequel<br/>
au moins une cellule de mémoire (50) de la matrice de mémoire est programmable ayant au moins un premier état de cellule et un deuxième état de cellule, le premier état de cellule ayant une tension de seuil dans une plage de tensions de seuil comprise entre une tension négative et une tension positive.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Dispositif mémoire selon la revendication 7, dans lequel le deuxième état de cellule comporte une seconde tension de seuil inférieure à la première tension de seuil du premier état de cellule.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Dispositif mémoire selon la revendication 8, dans lequel le premier état de cellule correspond à un état effacé ou à un état programmé, et le deuxième état de cellule correspond à un autre état programmé,<br/>
le premier état de cellule correspond à un premier état programmé et la plage de tensions de seuil est une première plage de tensions de seuil et le deuxième état de cellule correspond à un deuxième état programmé ayant la<!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --> seconde tension de seuil dans une deuxième plage de tensions de seuil inférieure à la première plage de tensions de seuil, ou<br/>
le deuxième état de cellule correspond à un état effacé.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Dispositif mémoire selon la revendication 9, comprenant en outre un état effacé ayant une plage de tensions de seuil d'effacement inférieure à la seconde plage de tensions de seuil, de manière facultative, dans lequel l'au moins une cellule de mémoire est programmable à un troisième état programmé ayant une troisième plage de tensions de seuil supérieure à la première plage de tensions de seuil.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Procédé de vérification de la réussite de la programmation d'une cellule de mémoire flash (50) couplée à une ligne de bits, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> la cellule de mémoire flash (50) est programmée depuis un état effacé ayant une première tension de seuil négative à un état programmé ayant une seconde tension de seuil négative ;<br/>
la commande d'une ligne de mots (WLn) connectée à la cellule de mémoire flash (50) avec une tension de référence négative ; et<br/>
la détermination de l'échec de la programmation de la cellule de mémoire flash (50) si le niveau de tension de la ligne de bits varie en réponse à la ligne de mots à la tension de référence négative.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 11,<br/>
comportant en outre la précharge de la ligne de bits au niveau de tension avant de commander la ligne de mots,<br/>
dans lequel la détermination comporte la détection d'une variation du niveau de tension de la ligne de bits lorsque la cellule de mémoire flash est activée en réponse à la ligne de mots à la tension de référence négative,<br/>
dans lequel l'état programmé correspond à un premier état de cellule, et la tension de référence négative est supérieure à une tension de seuil négative correspondant à un deuxième état de cellule de la cellule de mémoire flash.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 12, dans lequel<br/>
le deuxième état de cellule correspond à un autre état programmé.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 11, dans lequel l'état programmé comporte une plage de tensions de seuil définie par une limite de tension inférieure et une limite de tension supérieure, plus grande que la limite de<!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --> tension inférieure, la limite de tension inférieure étant une tension négative, de façon facultative, dans lequel<br/>
la limite de tension supérieure est une autre tension négative, ou la limite de tension supérieure est une tension positive.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16672138" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="131" he="196" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="36"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2,3,4"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="135" he="143" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="37"> --><figure id="f0003" num="5"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="113" he="162" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="38"> --><figure id="f0004" num="6"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="144" he="113" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="39"> --><figure id="f0005" num="7"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="111" he="167" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="40"> --><figure id="f0006" num="8"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="105" he="175" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="41"> --><figure id="f0007" num="9"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="137" he="135" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="42"> --><figure id="f0008" num="10"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="146" he="164" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="43"> --><figure id="f0009" num="11"><img id="if0009" file="imgf0009.tif" wi="106" he="97" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="44"> --><figure id="f0010" num="12"><img id="if0010" file="imgf0010.tif" wi="86" he="150" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="45"> --><figure id="f0011" num="13"><img id="if0011" file="imgf0011.tif" wi="65" he="130" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="46"> --><figure id="f0012" num="14"><img id="if0012" file="imgf0012.tif" wi="115" he="154" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="47"> --><figure id="f0013" num="15"><img id="if0013" file="imgf0013.tif" wi="68" he="133" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
