<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2171394-B9" country="EP" doc-number="2171394" kind="B9" date="20140101" family-id="39473631" file-reference-id="318251" date-produced="20180822" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146553991" ucid="EP-2171394-B9"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2171394</doc-number><kind>B9</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-07805733-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154827914" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>07805733</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20070724</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP175860735" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>07805733.8</doc-number><date>20070724</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140452772" ucid="IT-2007000521-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>IT</country><doc-number>2007000521</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20070724</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130108</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><term-of-grant><lapse-of-patent mxw-id="PLA1080582"><document-id><country>BG</country><date>20130926</date></document-id></lapse-of-patent><lapse-of-patent mxw-id="PLA1080583"><document-id><country>FI</country><date>20130626</date></document-id></lapse-of-patent><lapse-of-patent mxw-id="PLA1080584"><document-id><country>GR</country><date>20130927</date></document-id></lapse-of-patent><lapse-of-patent mxw-id="PLA1080585"><document-id><country>LT</country><date>20130626</date></document-id></lapse-of-patent><lapse-of-patent mxw-id="PLA1080586"><document-id><country>SE</country><date>20130626</date></document-id></lapse-of-patent><lapse-of-patent mxw-id="PLA1080587"><document-id><country>SI</country><date>20130626</date></document-id></lapse-of-patent></term-of-grant><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988121241" load-source="docdb">G01B   5/008       20060101AFI20090217BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988130463" load-source="docdb">G01B  21/04        20060101ALI20090217BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988134629" load-source="docdb">G01B   7/008       20060101ALI20090217BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2048033021" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G01B  21/04        20130101 LA20150609BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2048035818" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G01B   5/008       20130101 FI20150610BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2048036774" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G01B  21/045       20130101 LI20150610BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2048039716" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G01B   5/0016      20130101 LI20150610BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2048042682" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G01B  21/042       20130101 LA20150609BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132194457" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">VERFAHREN ZUM KOMPENSIEREN VON DURCH DEFORMATIONEN EINES MESSMASCHINENBEDS UNTER DER LAST EINES ARBEITSTÜCKS VERURSACHTEN MESSFEHLERN UND GEMÄSS DEM VERFAHREN ARBEITENDE MESSMASCHINE</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132194458" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">METHOD FOR COMPENSATING MEASUREMENT ERRORS CAUSED BY DEFORMATIONS OF A MEASURING MACHINE BED UNDER THE LOAD OF A WORKPIECE AND MEASURING MACHINE OPERATING ACCORDING TO SAID METHOD</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132194459" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">PROCÉDÉ PERMETTANT DE COMPENSER LES ERREURS DE MESURE PROVOQUÉES PAR DES DÉFORMATIONS D'UN BANC DE MACHINE SOUS LE POIDS D'UNE PIÈCE USINÉE ET MACHINE DE MESURE FONCTIONNANT SELON LEDIT PROCÉDÉ</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918148094" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>HEXAGON METROLOGY SPA</last-name><address><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918147151" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>HEXAGON METROLOGY S.P.A.</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918149110" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>MERLO LORENZO</last-name><address><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918160196" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>MERLO, LORENZO</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918998613" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>MERLO, LORENZO</last-name><address><street>C.so Mediterraneo, 124</street><city>I-10129 Torino</city><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918998615" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Hexagon Metrology S.p.A.</last-name><iid>100996738</iid><address><street>Via Vittime di Piazza della Loggia, 6</street><city>10024 Moncalieri</city><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918998614" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Franzolin, Luigi</last-name><suffix>et al</suffix><iid>101079191</iid><address><street>Studio Torta S.p.A. Via Viotti, 9</street><city>10121 Torino</city><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="IT-2007000521-W"><document-id><country>IT</country><doc-number>2007000521</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20070724</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2009013769-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2009013769</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20090129</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548982219" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS548991624" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS548831154" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS548989732" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS548871265" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS548982220" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS548991625" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548871266" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS548871267" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS548985347" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS548831155" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS548831156" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548991626" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548871268" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS548982221" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS548989733" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS548991627" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS548831157" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS548871269" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS548886400" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS548982222" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS548886401" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS548886402" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS548982879" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS548985348" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS548982880" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS548989734" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS548985349" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS548982881" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS548989735" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS548831158" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS548871270" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63957560" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --><heading id="h0001"><u>TECHNICAL FIELD</u></heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to a method of compensating the measurement errors of a measuring machine deriving from the deformations of the machine bed caused by the load exerted by the workpiece to be measured on the machine bed, as well as to a measuring machine operating according to said method.</p><heading id="h0002"><u>BACKGROUND ART</u></heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">As is known, measuring machines are generally provided with a fixed base or machine bed and a mobile unit designed to move a measuring head according to co-ordinate axes with respect to the machine bed in a measurement space located above the machine bed. The mobile unit generally comprises a main carriage, which is mobile along an axis that is longitudinal with respect to the machine bed, and one or more carriages carried by the main carriage, which are mobile along respective co-ordinate axes.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">The machine bed can be monolithic, for example made of granite or cast iron, or else can comprise a set of components rigidly fixed to one another to form a substantially rigid structure. The machine bed generally has two functions: supporting and constraining the workpiece being measured, and defining a guide for the mobile unit, and in particular for the main carriage of the machine, along one of the co-ordinate axes of the machine.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">Measuring machines of the aforesaid type are generally provided with a system for compensation of geometrical errors, i.e., of the measurement errors depending upon the<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> constructional defects of the machine (for example, rectilinearity errors of the axes, defects of orthogonality between the axes, etc.).</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">Current compensation techniques, of a strictly geometrical nature, do not generally take into account the measurement errors deriving from the elastic deformations of the machine bed under the weight of the workpiece to be measured. When the workpiece to be measured has a considerable weight (for example, in the case of dies, engine parts, castings of large dimensions) said errors may be non-negligible and jeopardize the accuracy of the machine.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="DE10214489A"><text>DE-A-102 14 489</text></patcit> discloses a method of compensating the measurement errors caused by deformations of a measuring machine bed under the load of a workpiece, having the features of the preamble of claim 1.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">A scope of the present invention is to device an improved compensation method that allows the weight of the workpiece, as well as its position and constraint on the machine bed, to be taken into consideration in order to calculate correction values.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">The aforesaid purpose is achieved by a compensation method according to Claim 1.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">The present invention likewise regards a measuring machine operating according to said method as defined in claim 12.</p><heading id="h0003"><u>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</u></heading><p id="p0010" num="0010">For a better understanding of the present invention, described in what follows is a preferred embodiment, provided by way of non-limiting example with reference to the annexed drawings, wherein:
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> is a schematic perspective view of a measuring machine operating according to the method of the present invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref> is a schematic side view of the machine of <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>, in the absence of load;<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --><!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 3</figref> is a schematic side view of the machine of <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref>, with a schematic representation of the geometrical variations induced by placing the workpiece on the machine bed;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 4</figref> is a graph illustrating the evolution of the rotations of pitch and roll of a main carriage of the machine according to the path of travel, in the presence of a load on the machine bed;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 5</figref> is a schematic perspective view of the machine bed illustrating the deformations induced by the weight of the workpiece;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 6</figref> is a block diagram of a compensation method ; and</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 7</figref> is a block diagram of a measurement method, which uses a corrected compensation map obtained using the method of the invention.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0004"><u>BEST MODE FOR CARRYING OUT THE INVENTION</u></heading><p id="p0011" num="0011">With reference to <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>, designated as a whole by 1 is a portal measuring machine. It is at once pointed out that the method forming the subject of the present invention can be used for the compensation of the errors of machines of different architecture, for example with horizontal arm or pillars.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">The machine 1 comprises a plane machine bed 2 provided with a horizontal working surface 3 designed to support an object to be measured (not illustrated), and a unit 4, which is mobile with respect to the machine bed 2 along co-ordinate axes.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">The unit 4 comprises a main portal carriage 5 (in what follows, for reasons of brevity, "portal 5"), which is mobile with respect to the machine bed 2 along a horizontal axis Y. The portal 5 is provided with a pair of uprights 6 and 7 and a cross-member 8 extending between the uprights 6 and 7 in a<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> direction parallel to a horizontal axis X and perpendicular to the axis Y.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">The unit 4 moreover comprises a secondary carriage 9, carried by the cross-member 8 and mobile on the cross-member along the axis X, and a measurement column 10, carried by the carriage 9 and mobile with respect thereto along a vertical axis Z orthogonal to the axes X and Y.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">Mounted on a bottom end of the column 10, possibly via a two-axes articulation device (not illustrated) is a touch probe 11.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">The portal 5, the carriage 9, and the column 10 are mobile under the control of respective electric motors (not illustrated), which are in turn controlled by a measurement and control unit 12. The latter is connected to position transducers (not illustrated) associated to the machine axes and to the probe 11 so as to receive from the latter signals for enabling acquisition of the instantaneous co-ordinates of the machine axes.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">The machine 1 is equipped with a system for compensation of geometrical errors that is in itself known. Compensation is carried out on the basis of a stored map 13 determined in loadless conditions via a kinematic model of the machine of a conventional type.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">With reference to <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>, identified on the working surface 3 is a fixed reference setting position REF used for geometrical.compensation of the machine. Defined moreover is a cartesian reference system xyz with axes parallel to the axes X, Y, Z of the machine and origin in the point REF.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">The compensation map is obtained in a known way, and hence not described in detail, by means detecting the error parameters<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> in points appropriately set at a distance from one another along the axes x, y, z. For each of the aforesaid points, differential measurements of position are carried out with respect to the point REF, for example via an interferometer, and differential measurements of inclination, for example using a fixed inclinometer located in the point REF and an inclinometer mounted on the mobile unit 4.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">According to the present invention, an additional compensation method is proposed that will moreover enable determination of the effects of the deformation of the machine bed 2 due to placing of the workpiece to be measured on the machine bed. For metrological purposes, said effects basically result in an alteration of the geometry of the axis Y, i.e., in variations of configuration of the portal 5 as a function of its position along the path of travel. Said variations are highlighted schematically from a comparison of <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 3</figref>, where the machine bed 2 is loaded by a weight W, with <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref>, where the machine bed is not loaded.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">The alterations of the geometry of the axis Y are similar to the ones due to the geometrical errors of the machine, which are included in the map 13 of geometrical compensation of the machine 1, determined in the absence of load. The variations of attitude due to the weight, calculated for example using a finite-element numeric simulation model, can thus be entered as additional corrections in the existing compensation map.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">In this way, compensation of the phenomenon of deformation under examination can be obtained.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">The numeric simulation can be implemented in the machine, for example, in one of the following ways:
<ul><li>integration of a finite-element model and of the corresponding calculation program in the measurement and control unit 12 of the machine 1; at each placing of the<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> workpiece, the calculating routine is set up and run; and</li><li>storage in the measurement and control unit 12 of the machine 1 of a map containing data of deformation of the machine bed calculated previously once and for all for a pre-defined set of load cases.</li></ul></p><p id="p0024" num="0024">Described in what follows is an example of embodiment of the second mode of implementation described above.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">On this hypothesis, it is assumed that the main attitude variations of the portal 5, caused by the deformation of the machine bed 2, are the rotations about the horizontal axes (x and y), whilst the other components are neglected. The compensation method is, however, to be considered altogether general and applicable to any component of the deformation.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">The rotations about the axes x and y, referred to as pitch and roll, correspond to the ones considered by the geometrical compensation commonly used, as described above, and are understood with respect to the reference system x, y, z, fixed with respect to the point REF.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">For a series of conditions of basic load on the machine bed 2, using finite-element calculation, it is possible to create a map containing the values of the rotations of pitch and roll of the portal 5 as a function of its position along the path of travel.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">For example, as basic load condition there may be assumed the application of a unit vertical force F (e.g., 1 kN) on a point of a grid aligned to the axes X, Y, of pre-set pitch (e.g. 100 mm), lying on the working surface 3 (<figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>). For each basic load condition, i.e., for each point of application of the unit force belonging to the grid, there are previously calculated, using the finite-element method, the values of rotation of pitch and roll of the portal 5 as the position of<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> the portal varies along its own path of travel (i.e., as Y varies).</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">The graph of <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 4</figref> illustrates the evolution of the rotations of pitch and roll of the portal 5 as Y varies, for a given basic load condition.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">Calculating the rotations of pitch and roll as the position of the carriage varies for all the pre-defined basic load conditions, it is possible to create a pre-defined deformation map 14 that is stored in the measurement and control unit 12 of the machine 1 as being characteristic of that given model of machine.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">A real condition of load, corresponding to the placing on the machine bed of a given workpiece to be measured; will be defined by the set of the characteristics that concur to determine the load transmitted to the machine bed in the case in point, namely:
<ul><li>total weight of the workpiece and of the possible supporting and fixing equipment;</li><li>position of the centroid of the total load; and</li><li>mode of resting on the working surface (number and position of the points or of the areas of resting).</li></ul></p><p id="p0032" num="0032">The different positions of the resting points, of the centroid, etc. are understood as co-ordinates with respect to the reference system XY.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">According to a preferred embodiment of the invention, the method envisages a series of rules and assumptions that will enable any condition of actual load to be brought back to an equivalent condition that can be represented using the basic loads.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">The standard load conditions taken into account can be, for<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> example, the following:
<ol><li>a) resting on any three points with any position of the centroid;</li><li>b) resting on four points at the vertices of a rectangle oriented parallel to XY with any position of the centroid;</li><li>c) resting on n points with a known load on each of them;</li><li>d) resting distributed over a rectangular area oriented parallel to XY and approximated by an integer number of meshes of the grid, with any position of the centroid; and</li><li>e) resting distributed uniformly over an area approximated by an integer number of meshes of the grid.</li></ol></p><p id="p0035" num="0035">Once the standard load conditions have been defined, it is necessary to define the rules of interpolation for transforming the configurations of standard load into linear combinations of cases of basic load.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">Said rules may, for example, be the following:
<ul><li>in the case of a load concentrated on one resting point, the load is decomposed into four forces applied on the vertices of the mesh of the grid containing the resting point, and calculated, for example, by imposing for each mesh equilibrium to rotation and absence of torsion with respect to two axes passing through the point of application of the load and parallel to the sides of the mesh;</li><li>in the case of distributed resting (<figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 5</figref>), the total load weighing on each mesh of the grid is calculated, and said load is decomposed into four equal loads applied on the vertices of the mesh.</li></ul></p><p id="p0037" num="0037">Given any linear combination of cases of basic load, it is possible to calculate the corresponding values of rotation of pitch and roll of the main carriage operating as follows:
<ul><li>extraction from the deformation map of the pitch and roll rotation values regarding each component of the linear combination (case of basic load, with unit force);<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --></li><li>proportioning on the basis of the effective value of the load; and</li><li>sum of all the components to obtain the total effect.</li></ul></p><p id="p0038" num="0038">The rotations thus calculated are used as correctioh (setting the sign appropriately) for updating the geometrical compensation map of the machine and then correcting the measurements carried out on the workpiece.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">The method is implemented as processing program according to the block diagram of <figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 6</figref>.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">A first input block 15 enables acquisition of the data regarding the load configuration.</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">Said acquisition can be carried out by manual input. In particular, the operator enters (by typing in from a keyboard or via graphic interface) the data regarding the load condition in the specific case:
<ul><li>the total weight loaded on the machine bed: manual input or else confirmation of a weight calculated automatically on the basis of the CAD solid model (if available);</li><li>the load configuration, chosen between the standard ones available;</li><li>according to the previous choice, the data necessary for the calculation:
<ul><li>co-ordinates of the resting points;</li><li>limits X and Y of the resting area (if rectangular);</li><li>co-ordinates of the centroid of the load;</li><li>meshes of the grid subjected to distributed load;</li><li>load per resting point (in the case of n resting points).</li></ul></li></ul></p><p id="p0042" num="0042">Alternatively, the step described above for acquisition of the data can be automatic: during the step of alignment prior to measurement, the points acquired by the measuring machine can be used for determining the position of the workpiece on the<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> working surface for the configurations b), d), e).</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">Control then passes to a subsequent processing block 16, in which the load data are processed on the basis of the rules described above for determining the basic load conditions necessary for representation of the standard load entered, as well as the coefficients of the linear combination of the basic loads equivalent to the standard load entered.</p><p id="p0044" num="0044">In a subsequent block 17, the program extracts from the pre-defined deformation map 14, for each basic load condition, the errors of rotations of pitch and roll as the position of the portal 5 varies.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045">In block 18, the values of correction to be made to the geometrical compensation map are calculated as linear combination of the errors of rotation determined in block 17, on the basis of the coefficients determined in block 16.</p><p id="p0046" num="0046">Finally, in block 19 the correction values are used for correcting the geometrical compensation map and thus calculating a corrected geometrical compensation map, which depends not only upon the model of the machine but also upon the specific condition of load, i.e., upon the workpiece measured and the conditions of constraint of the workpiece.</p><p id="p0047" num="0047">The set of the data entered and calculated during the step of compensation can be stored for a subsequent re-use in the case of measurement of a similar workpiece.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048">The machine 1 is now ready for execution of a measurement cycle.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">The block diagram of <figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 7</figref> illustrates a procedure of measurement of a workpiece.<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --></p><p id="p0050" num="0050">From a measurement block 20, in which the machine 1 acquires the "raw" co-ordinates, i.e., the ones not yet compensated and hence subject to errors of a geometrical nature, control passes to a block 21, in which the raw co-ordinates are compensated in a way similar to what occurs in conventional machines but, according to the present invention, via the corrected geometrical compensation map.</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">Consequently, the measurements will be purged of the negative effects of the phenomenon under examination.</p><p id="p0052" num="0052">The "corrected" co-ordinates thus calculated are stored in block 22.</p><p id="p0053" num="0053">At the end of the measurement, the operator can conveniently choose (block 23) whether to maintain the corrected map active, for measuring another workpiece of the same type, or else return to the previous situation (block 24 for reset of the compensation map).</p><p id="p0054" num="0054">Since the positions of the workpiece on the working surface and the possible modes of resting are theoretically infinite, the method can comprise, as integration of what has been described, the indication of guidelines for placing the workpiece, so as to render the actual working conditions as close as possible to the ones considered in the theoretical model, upon which the compensation is based.</p><p id="p0055" num="0055">From an examination of the characteristics of the compensation method described, the advantages that it affords are evident.</p><p id="p0056" num="0056">In particular, in addition to the usual geometrical compensation, also the geometrical errors induced by the deformation of the machine bed as a result of the load of the workpiece are compensated. This makes it possible to take into account, in the compensation, both the weight of the workpiece<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> and the conditions of constraint thereof on the machine bed.</p><p id="p0057" num="0057">In particular, even though the method has been described with reference to a portal machine, it is altogether general and can be applied to machines of any type, even non-cartesian ones.</p><p id="p0058" num="0058">Furthermore, even though the method has been described with reference to the compensation of the errors of rotation of the portal, it can be extended to the correction of any geometrical error induced by the load of the workpiece.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980169" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Verfahren zum Kompensieren der Messfehler einer Messmaschine (1), die sich durch die Verformungen eines Maschinenbetts (2) der Maschine (1) ergeben, die durch die Last verursacht werden, die durch ein zu messendes Werkstück auf das Maschinenbett (2) ausgeübt wird, umfassend einen ersten Erfassungsschritt (15), bei dem Daten bezüglich des Gewichts des Werkstücks und der Auflagebedingungen des Werkstücks auf dem Maschinenbett erfasst werden, und einen zweiten Berechnungsschritt (16, 17, 18, 19), bei dem Korrekturwerte in Abhängigkeit von diesen Daten berechnet werden,<br/>
<b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b><br/>
der erste Schritt (15) das Auswählen eines Standard-Belastungszustands aus einer Vielzahl von Standard-Belastungszuständen umfasst; und<br/>
der zweite Schritt folgende Schritte umfasst: Umwandeln des ausgewählten Standard-Belastungszustands in Linearkombinationen von Grundbelastungsfällen, und Berechnen von Werten, die mit der Verformung des Maschinenbetts (2) unter der Last des Werkstücks korrelieren, als Linearkombination von entsprechenden Werten, die aus vorbestimmten Grundbelastungszuständen resultieren.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> der zweite Schritt den Schritt (18) des Berechnens von Korrekturdaten zum Korrigieren einer vorab gespeicherten Karte zur geometrischen Kompensation (13) umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1 oder 2, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die vorbestimmten Belastungszustände definiert werden, indem eine voreingestellte Belastung (F) auf jeweilige voreingestellte Punkte einer Arbeitsfläche (3) des Maschinenbetts (2) ausgeübt wird.<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 3, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die voreingestellten Punkte ein Gitter auf einer Arbeitsfläche (3) des Maschinenbetts (2) definieren.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die Standard-Belastungszustände mindestens einen Zustand der Auflage auf drei Punkten umfassen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die Standard-Belastungszustände mindestens einen Zustand der Auflage auf vier Punkten an den Scheitelpunkten eines Rechtecks umfassen, das parallel zu zwei Koordinatenachsen (X, Y) der Arbeitsfläche (3) ausgerichtet ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die Standard-Belastungszustände mindestens einen Zustand der Auflage auf n Punkten mit einer bekannten Belastung auf jedem von ihnen umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 5, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die Standard-Belastungszustände mindestens einen Zustand der Auflage umfassen, die über einen rechteckigen Bereich verteilt ist, der parallel zu zwei Koordinatenachsen (X, Y) der Arbeitsfläche (3) ausgerichtet ist und annähernd einer ganzen Zahl von Maschen des Gitters entspricht.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 5, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die Standard-Belastungszustände mindestens einen Zustand der Auflage umfassen, die gleichmäßig über einen Bereich verteilt ist, der annähernd einer ganzen Zahl von Maschen des Gitters entspricht.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die Korrekturwerte auf der Basis eines<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> vereinfachten Modells der Maschine berechnet werden, das eine reduzierte Anzahl von Fehlerkomponenten berücksichtigt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 3 bis 9 zum Kompensieren der Fehler in einer kartesischen Messmaschine, umfassend einen Hauptschlitten (5), der in Bezug auf die Arbeitsfläche entlang einer ersten Achse (Y) beweglich ist, und mindestens einen zweiten Schlitten (9), der durch den Hauptschlitten (5) getragen wird und in Bezug auf diesen entlang einer zweiten Achse (X) beweglich ist, die rechtwinklig zur ersten Achse (Y) und parallel zur Arbeitsfläche (3) ist, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die Korrekturwerte auf der Basis eines vereinfachten Modells der Maschine berechnet werden, das nur die Drehungen des Hauptschlittens (5) um die Achsen (X, Y) berücksichtigt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Messmaschine, umfassend ein Maschinenbett (2) und eine bewegliche Einheit (4) zum Bewegen eines Messsensors (11) in Bezug auf das Maschinenbett (2), <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> sie ein Kompensationssystem zum Kompensieren der Messfehler umfasst, die sich aus den Verformungen des Maschinenbetts ergeben, die durch die Last verursacht werden, die durch das zu messende Werkstück auf das Maschinenbett ausgeübt wird, wobei das Kompensationssystem gemäß dem Verfahren nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche arbeitet.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980170" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A method of compensating the measurement errors of a measuring machine (1) deriving from the deformations of a machine bed (2) of the machine (1) caused by the load exerted by a workpiece to be measured on the machine bed (2), comprising a first acquisition step (15) in which data regarding the weight of the workpiece and the conditions of constraint of the workpiece on the machine bed are acquired and a second calculation step (16, 17, 18, 19) in which correction values depending upon said data are calculated,<br/>
<b>characterized in that</b>:
<claim-text>said first step (15) comprises selecting a standard load condition from among a plurality of standard load conditions; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>said second step comprises the steps of transforming the selected standard load condition into linear combinations of cases of basic load and calculating values correlated to the deformation of the machine bed (2) under the load of the workpiece as a linear combination of corresponding values resulting from predetermined basic load conditions .</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The method according to Claim 1, <b>characterized in that</b> said second step comprises the step (18) of calculating correction data for correcting a previously stored geometrical compensation map (13).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The method according to Claim 1 or 2, <b>characterized in that</b> the predetermined load conditions are defined by applying a pre-set load (F) in respective pre-set points of a working surface (3) of said machine bed (2).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The method according to Claim 3, <b>characterized in that</b> said pre-set points define a grid on a working surface (3) of said machine bed (2).<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The method according to Claim 1, <b>characterized in that</b> said standard load conditions comprise at least a condition of resting on three points.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The method according to Claim 1, <b>characterized in that</b> said standard load conditions comprise at least a condition of resting on four points at the vertices of a rectangle oriented parallel to two co-ordinate axes (X, Y) of the working surface (3).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The method according to Claim 1, <b>characterized in that</b> said standard load conditions comprise at least a condition of resting on n points with a known load on each of them.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The method according to Claim 5, <b>characterized in that</b> said standard load conditions comprise at least a condition of resting distributed over a rectangular area oriented parallel to two co-ordinate axes (X, Y) of the working surface (3) and approximated with an integer number of meshes of the grid.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The method according to Claim 5, <b>characterized in that</b> said standard load conditions comprise at least one condition of resting distributed uniformly over an area approximated with an integer number of meshes of said grid.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The method according to any one of the preceding claims, <b>characterized in that</b> said correction values are calculated on the basis of a simplified model of the machine that takes into account a reduced number of error components.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>The method according to any one of Claims 3 to 9 for compensation of the errors in a cartesian measuring machine comprising a main carriage (5) mobile with respect to said working surface along a first axis (Y), and at least one<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> second carriage (9) carried by said main carriage (5) and mobile with respect to this along a second axis (X) orthogonal to the first axis (Y) and parallel to said working surface (3), <b>characterized in that</b> said correction values are calculated on the basis of a simplified model of the machine that takes into account only the rotations of said main carriage (5) about said axes (X, Y).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>A measuring machine comprising a machine bed (2) and a mobile unit (4) for moving a measurement sensor (11) with respect to said machine bed (2), <b>characterized by</b> comprising a compensating system for compensating the measurement errors deriving from the deformations of the machine bed caused by the load exerted by the workpiece to be measured on the machine bed, the compensating system operating according to the method of any one of the preceding claims.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980171" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --><!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Procédé de compensation des erreurs de mesure d'une machine de mesure (1) découlant des déformations d'un banc de machine (2) de la machine (1) provoquées par la charge exercée par une pièce usinée devant être mesurée sur le banc de machine (2), comprenant une première étape d'acquisition (15) au cours de laquelle des données concernant le poids de la pièce usinée et les conditions de contrainte de la pièce usinée sur le banc de machine (2) sont acquises et une seconde étape de calcul (16, 17, 18, 19) au cours de laquelle des valeurs de correction dépendantes desdites données sont calculées,<br/>
<b>caractérisé en ce que</b> :
<claim-text>ladite première étape (15) comprend la sélection d'une condition de charge standard parmi une pluralité de conditions de charge standard ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>ladite seconde étape comprend les étapes consistant à transformer la condition de charge standard choisie en des combinaisons linéaires de cas de charge de base et à calculer des valeurs corrélées à la déformation du banc de machine (2) sous la charge de la pièce usinée comme étant une combinaison linéaire de valeurs correspondantes résultant des conditions de charge de base prédéterminées.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> ladite seconde étape comprend l'étape (18) de calcul de données correctives destinées à corriger une<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> carte de compensation géométrique préalablement mémorisée (13).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1 ou 2, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> les conditions de charge prédéterminées sont définies en appliquant une charge prédéfinie (F) en des points prédéfinis respectifs d'une surface de travail (3) dudit banc de machine (2).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 3, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> lesdits points prédéfinis définissent une grille sur une surface de travail (3) dudit banc de machine (2).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> lesdites conditions de charge standard comprennent au moins une condition d'appui sur trois points.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> lesdites conditions de charge standard comprennent au moins une condition d'appui sur au moins quatre points aux sommets d'un rectangle orienté parallèlement à deux axes de coordonnées (X, Y) de la surface de travail (3).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> lesdites conditions de charge standard comprennent au moins une condition d'appui sur n points, avec une charge connue sur chacun d'entre eux.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 5, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> lesdites conditions de charge standard comprennent au moins une condition d'appui réparti sur une zone rectangulaire orientée parallèlement à deux axes de coordonnées (X, Y) de la surface de travail (3)<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --> et estimée à l'aide d'un nombre entier de mailles de ladite grille.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 5, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> lesdites conditions de charge standard comprennent au moins une condition d'appui uniformément réparti sur une zone estimée à l'aide d'un nombre entier de mailles de ladite grille.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> lesdites valeurs de correction sont calculées sur la base d'un modèle simplifié de la machine qui prend en compte un nombre réduit de composantes d'erreur.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications 3 à 9 permettant la compensation des erreurs dans une machine de mesure cartésienne comprenant un chariot principal (5) mobile par rapport à ladite surface de travail le long d'un premier axe (Y), et au moins un second chariot (9) porté par ledit chariot principal (5) et mobile par rapport à celui-ci le long d'un second axe (X) orthogonal au premier axe (Y) et parallèle à ladite surface de travail (3), <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> lesdites valeurs de correction sont calculées sur la base d'un modèle simplifié de la machine qui prend en compte uniquement les rotations dudit chariot principal (5) autour desdits axes (X, Y).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Machine de mesure comprenant un banc de machine (2) et une unité mobile (4) permettant de déplacer un capteur de mesure (11) par rapport au dit banc de machine (2), <b>caractérisé en ce qu'</b>il comprend un système de compensation permettant de compenser les<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --> erreurs de mesure découlant des déformations du banc de machine (2) provoquées par la charge exercée par la pièce usinée devant être mesurée sur le banc de machine (2), le système de compensation fonctionnant selon le procédé de l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16669078" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="153" he="194" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2,3"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="99" he="205" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --><figure id="f0003" num="4,5"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="142" he="225" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --><figure id="f0004" num="6,7"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="165" he="194" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
