<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-1389732-B1" country="EP" doc-number="1389732" kind="B1" date="20140101" family-id="30770628" file-reference-id="242852" date-produced="20180822" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146554320" ucid="EP-1389732-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>1389732</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-03254888-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154828243" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>03254888</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20030806</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140453775" ucid="US-21852202-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>21852202</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20020815</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130730</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988096873" load-source="docdb">G01N  17/04        20060101AFI20051220RMJP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988108694" load-source="docdb">G01C  17/02        20060101ALI20031108BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988128922" load-source="docdb">G21C  17/003       20060101ALI20051220RMJP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988129780" load-source="docdb">G01N  17/02        20060101ALI20031108BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988133653" load-source="docdb">G21D   1/00        20060101ALI20051220RMJP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988134230" load-source="docdb">G01N  27/30        20060101AFI20031108BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988134597" load-source="docdb">G01N  27/26        20060101ALI20051220RMJP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2140473377" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G01N  17/02        20130101 FI20141106BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132195444" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Keramische Sonde zur Messung des elektrochemischen Korrosionspotentials</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132195445" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Ceramic electrochemical corrosion potential sensor probe</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132195446" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Sonde céramique pour mesurer le potentiel de corrosion électrochimique</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918163979" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>GEN ELECTRIC</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918136540" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>GENERAL ELECTRIC COMPANY</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918153021" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>JETT ROBERT</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918139449" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>JETT, ROBERT</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918999408" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>JETT, ROBERT</last-name><address><street>2941 Granby Circle</street><city>Twinsburg, Ohio 44087</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918170329" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>CLARKE LUCAS</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918171394" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>CLARKE, LUCAS</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918999407" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>CLARKE, LUCAS</last-name><address><street>171 Applegrove Street N.E., Apartment C-5</street><city>North Canton, Ohio 44720</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918999409" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>GENERAL ELECTRIC COMPANY</last-name><iid>100129092</iid><address><street>1 River Road</street><city>Schenectady, NY 12345</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918999410" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Cleary, Fidelma</last-name><iid>101356232</iid><address><street>GPO Europe GE International Inc. The Ark 201 Talgarth Road Hammersmith</street><city>London W6 8BJ</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548986491" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS548888280" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548888281" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548876366" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS548832846" load-source="docdb">LI</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63957727" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><p id="p0001" num="0001">Many nuclear reactors are typically constructed as boiling water reactors where suitable nuclear fuel is disposed in a reactor pressure vessel in which water is heated. The water and steam are carried through various components and piping which are typically formed of stainless steel, with other materials such as alloy 182 weld metal and alloy 600 used for various components directly inside the reactor pressure vessel.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002">Materials in the reactor core region are susceptible to irradiation assisted stress corrosion cracking. This is because the material in the core region is exposed to the highly oxidizing species generated by the radiolysis of water by both gamma and neutron radiation under normal water chemistry conditions, in addition to the effect of direct irradiation assisted stress corrosion cracking. The oxidizing species increases the electrochemical corrosion potential of the material, which in turn increases its propensity to undergo intergranular stress corrosion cracking or irradiation assisted stress corrosion cracking.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">Suppression of the oxidizing species carried within such materials is desirable in controlling intergranular stress corrosion cracking. An effective method of suppressing the oxidizing species coming into contact with the material is to inject hydrogen into the reactor water via the feedwater system so that recombination of the oxidants with hydrogen occurs within the reactor core.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">This method is called hydrogen water chemistry and is widely practiced for mitigating intergranular stress corrosion cracking of materials in boiling water reactors. When hydrogen water chemistry is practiced in a boiling water reactor, the electrochemical corrosion potential of the stainless steel material decreases from a positive value generally in the range of 0.060 to 0.200 V (Standard Hydrogen Electrode Potential, or "SHE") under normal water chemistry to a value less than -0.230 (SHE). When the electrochemical corrosion potential is below this negative value, intergranular stress corrosion cracking of stainless steel can be mitigated and its initiation can be prevented.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p><p id="p0005" num="0005">Considerable efforts have been made in the past decade to develop reliable electrochemical corrosion potential sensors to be used as reference electrodes that can determine the electrochemical corrosion potential of operating surfaces of reactor components.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">The typical electrochemical corrosion potential sensor experiences a severe environment in a view of the temperature of the water wall exceeding 288°C; relatively high flow rates of the water up to and exceeding several m/s; and the high nuclear radiation in the core region.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">A drawback of currently available sensors is that they have a limited lifetime in that some have failed after only three months of use while a few have shown evidence of operation for approximately six to nine months. Since many of the locations where these sensors are installed are inaccessible during plant operation, a lifetime of at least 24 months must be obtained to allow for continuous monitoring during the entire fuel cycle (fuel cycle length is plant-specific but can range between 12 months to 24 months).</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">The invention disclosed here is most closely associated with commonly owned <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US5043053A"><text>U.S. Patent Nos. 5,043,053</text></patcit> and <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="US6357284A"><text>6,357,284</text></patcit>. Of the various types of sensors currently available, one (as disclosed in the '053 patent) includes a ceramic probe packed with a mixture of metal and metal oxide powder. Predominant failure modes for this type of ECP sensor include degradation of the ceramic material (yttria partially-stabilized zirconia) and cracking and corrosive attack of the ceramic-to-metal braze used to attach the ceramic material to the balance of the sensor assembly.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">Accordingly, it is desired to develop an improved ceramic electrochemical corrosion potential sensor addressing the insufficient useful life.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">A ceramic electrochemical corrosion potential sensor is disclosed herein that includes a ceramic crucible, constructed of, for example, magnesia partially-stabilized zirconia. The crucible has a closed end and an open end. The outer diameter of the open end of the crucible includes a platinum metallized band fired into the ceramic for brazing the crucible to a first open end of a metal sleeve, thus forming a hermetic seal. A first conducting wire extends<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> from the mixture of metal and metal oxide powder through the ceramic crucible to the second end of the metal sleeve. The second end of the sleeve is welded to and closed by, a metal adapter or connector (also referred to as a signal transfer assembly) that connects the conducting wire to a metal coaxial cable.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">More specifically, the ceramic crucible contains a mixture of high purity metal and metal oxide powders (Fe/Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>, Cu/Cu<sub>2</sub>O, or Ni/NiO). A high purity metal wire (Fe, Cu, or Ni depending on metal/metal oxide powder used) is secured in the center of this mixture. Crushed zirconia felt is packed around the center wire and on top of the metal/metal oxide powder mixture. Further, high purity glass wool is wrapped around and pressed on top of the crushed zirconia felt. The crushed zirconia felt and the glass wool provides structural integrity to the metal/metal oxide powder mixture and helps maintain its location inside of the closed end of the ceramic crucible.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">The ceramic crucible is brazed to a first open end of a metal sleeve preferably constructed of a nickel alloy or other similar metal with a coefficient of thermal expansion that closely matches the coefficient of thermal expansion for magnesia partially-stabilized zirconia. The brazing process uses a braze alloy in an otherwise conventional practice that melts the braze alloy and forms a hermetic seal between the metal sleeve and the ceramic crucible in the region where the ceramic crucible has been metallized with platinum.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">The second open end of the metal sleeve is sealed by an adapter also made of stainless steel or other equivalent metal. This sleeve serves as a transition piece so that the sensor body can be welded to a coaxial cable with a stainless steel outer sheath. The coaxial cable may be mineral insulated with magnesia oxide or another suitable insulator surrounding the center wire. The coaxial cable may be terminated in a suitable electrical connector or may be sealed through the use of a suitable epoxy with the center wire allowed to extend a small distance beyond the termination point of the coaxial cable.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p><p id="p0014" num="0014">The present invention provides a sensor probe for use in monitoring electrochemical potentials, comprising: (a) a crucible made of zirconia ceramic material having a closed end and an open end, the closed end containing metal/metal oxide powder mixture retained therein by mineral insulation packing, said open end having a metallized band fired in the ceramic material; (b) an annular metal sleeve formed of a metal exhibiting a coefficient of thermal expansion compatible with said crucible, and having a distal open end brazed to said open end of said crucible, and a proximal open end; (c) an insulated electrical conductor having a distal end in electrical connection with said metal/metal oxide powder and extending through said mineral insulation packing and into said annular sleeve, and having a proximal end terminating near the proximal open end of said annular sleeve; and (d) a signal transfer assembly sealingly associated with said proximal end of said annular sleeve including an electrical cable connected to said electrical conductor, characterised in that the metallized band consists of platinum particles embedded in the crucible and the zirconia in the zirconia crucible is partially stabilized with approximately 8.0% by weight magnesia.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">The invention will now be described in greater detail, by way of example, with reference to the drawings, the single figure of which depicts in cross-sectional elevation view the sensor probe of the present invention.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">Referring to the drawing, the structure of the sensor probe includes four principal components: an electrode 10, an annular support sleeve assembly 12, a signal transfer assembly 14, and an electrical conductor 16. The electrode 10 includes a zirconia crucible 18 that has a closed end 20 and an open end 22. The zirconia crucible 18 desirably is partially stabilized,<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> e.g., with about 8.0% by weight magnesia. The ceramic crucible is preferably formed by extrusion, hot isostatic pressing or a similarly suitable ceramic forming technique. The closed end 20 of the crucible 18 is packed with a mixture 24 of metal/metal oxide powder.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">The mixture 24 includes high purity metal and metal oxide powders (Fe/Fe<sub>3</sub>O<sub>4</sub>, Cu/Cu<sub>2</sub>O, or Ni/NiO). The conductor 16, preferably a high purity metal wire (Fe, Cu, or Ni), is secured in the center of this mixture. A mineral insulation packing 26, e.g., crushed zirconia felt, is packed around the conductor wire 16 and on top of the metal/metal oxide powder mixture 24. The packing 26 may also contain high purity glass wool wrapped around and pressed on top of the crushed zirconia felt. The crushed zirconia felt and the glass wool packing will provide structural integrity to the metal/metal oxide powder mixture 24 and will help maintain its location inside of the closed end of the ceramic crucible 18. The mineral insulating packing 26 not only maintains the metal/metal oxide powder 24 within the ceramic 18, but also electrically isolates the metal/metal oxide powder 24 from contact with other metal housing components of the probe structure. Additionally, after having packed the crucible 18 with metal/metal oxide powder 24, the packing 26, when inserted in opening 22, wipes the interior surface of crucible 18 of any metal/metal oxide powder adhering to the interior walls.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">The supporting sleeve assembly 12 includes an annular metal sleeve. While sleeve assembly 12 could be fabricated to include a single sleeve 28, it also is possible to employ two abutting sleeve components as shown in the drawing. Specifically, the first annular metal sleeve component 28, having a distal open end 30, is welded at juncture 34 to a second annular metal sleeve component 36 having a proximal open end 32. Sleeve 28 desirably is manufactured from a material, e.g., a nickel alloy or other similar material, that exhibits a coefficient of thermal expansion that is compatible with the ceramic material forming the crucible 18. The material of construction for annular transition sleeve 36 preferably is stainless steel for providing corrosion resistance and minimizing costs associated to fabrication of the sensor probe of the present invention. The welding of sleeve 28 to sleeve 36 may be done in accordance<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> with conventional tungsten inert gas (TIG) or other suitable welding techniques. The distal end 30 of sleeve 28 has a land 38 supporting the open end 22 of crucible 18.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">Since the joining of crucible 18 to sleeve 28 should provide a hermetic seal, appropriate dimensional tolerances are maintained so that a snug fit between the proximal open end 22 of crucible 18 and the distal open end 30 of sleeve 28 is maintained. The outer diameter at the open end of the ceramic crucible 18 is metallized with platinum for a width of approximately 0.254 cm (0.100 inches). This is achieved by firing the Platinum particles in the ceramic during the "green" stage of forming the ceramic (as understood by those skilled in the art), to form a metallized "band" about the open end of the crucible 18.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">The brazing process utilizes a brazing alloy and standard brazing process to melt the braze alloy and form a hermetic seal between the metal sleeve 28 and the ceramic crucible 18 in the region where the ceramic has been metallized with platinum around its outer diameter.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">The signal transfer or adapter assembly 14 is positioned within the proximal opening 32 of sleeve 36. This assembly 14 may include a stainless steel collar 40 that is welded to sleeve 36, such as by TIG welding, to provide a hermetic seal. Ceramic support 42, inwardly adjacent to collar 40, serves as an electrical connection from the outside to the interior of the electrode probe. Specifically, an insulated retainer 44 houses a nickel tube which is connected at its proximal end to coax cable 46 and to its distal end to the electrical conductor 16 via conductor 47. The signal transfer assembly 14 is commercially available and marketed, for example, by Reuter-Stokes Inc., a wholly owned subsidiary of the General Electric Company, in Twinsburg, Ohio. Should the crucible 18 fail, water containing radioactive material will not leak to the outside by virtue of the seal provided by the connection of the collar 40 to the sleeve 36.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">The final component, conductor 16, has a distal end bent into a hook or ring-like configuration which is pushed near but not touching the closed end 20 of the ceramic crucible 18 (not shown in the drawing). The packing of<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> metal/metal oxide powders 24 about the conductor 16 provides good electrical contact therebetween. Electrical conductor 16 then passes through the packing 26 and out of the open end 22 of crucible 18 into the space provided within the annular sleeves 28 and 36. While the conductor 16 can be clad with ceramic insulation, preferably, an annular ceramic sleeve 48 (made of alumina, for example) is nested within the annular sleeves 28 and 36 and electrically insulates the conductor 16 from the metallic housing of the probe. A stress relief section 50 is incorporated into conductor 16 for insuring that the electrical connector is protected against conductor breakage by allowing for expansion and contraction of conductor 16 during heating and cooling cycles. The electrical conductor 16 terminates at a proximal end where it is welded to the conductor 47 projecting from the nickel tube 44 provided within the assembly 14. Conductor 16 may be formed of a material selected from the group consisting of iron, copper, or nickel depending on which metal/metal oxide powder is used.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">It will be appreciated that the components described preferably are cylindrical in shape, though other shapes may be used. For example, crucible 18, sleeves 28 and 36, and insulator 48 can be square, hexagonal, or of other geometric configuration.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">With respect to performance specifications of the inventive reference electrode probe, the probe is designed to operate at temperatures ranging up to about (316°C) 600°F. and pressures of up to about 138 bar (2,000 psi). The electrode should exhibit a voltage that is within ±0.020 volts of the theoretical value for the metal/metal oxide/zirconia electrode sensor used in constructing the probe. The electrode probe sensor is capable of measuring ECPs to within ±0.010 volts in constant water chemistry.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980670" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Sensorsonde zur Verwendung bei der Überwachung elektrochemischer Potentiale, welche Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>(a) einen Tiegel (18) hergestellt aus Zirkonia-Keramik-Material, welcher ein geschlossenes Ende (20) und ein offenes Ende (22) aufweist, wobei das geschlossene Ende eine Metall/Metalloxid-Pulvermischung (24) enthält, welche durch mineralische Isolierungsabdichtung (26) darin gehalten wird, wobei das offene Ende (22) ein metallisiertes Band eingebrannt in das keramische Material aufweist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) eine ringförmige Metallhülse (28) gebildet aus einem Metall, welche einen thermischen Ausdehnungskoeffizienten aufweist, der mit dem Tiegel kompatibel ist, und die ein distales offenes Ende (30) hartgelötet an das offene Ende (22) des Tiegels (18) und ein proximales offenes Ende (32) aufweist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) einen isolierten elektrischen Leiter (16), welcher ein distales Ende in elektrischer Verbindung mit dem Metall/Metalloxidpulver (24) aufweist und sich durch die mineralische Isolierungsabdichtung (26) und in die ringförmige Hülse (28) erstreckt und welcher ein proximales Ende aufweist, das nahe dem proximalen offenen Ende (32) der ringförmigen Hülse endet; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) eine Signalübertragungsbaugruppe (14), welche abdichtend mit dem proximalen Ende der ringförmigen Hülse in Zusammenhang steht, welche ein elektrisches Kabel (46) angeschlossen an den elektrischen Leiter (16) beinhaltet,<br/>
<b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> das metallisierte Band<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> aus Platinpartikeln eingebettet in den Tiegel besteht und das Zirkonia in dem Zirkonia-Tiegel teilweise mit etwa 8,0 Gew.% Magnesia stabilisiert ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Sensorsonde nach Anspruch 1, wobei der elektrische Leiter (16) durch einen ringförmigen elektrischen Isolator (48) isoliert ist, welcher innerhalb der ringförmigen Metallhülse untergebracht ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Sensorsonde nach Anspruch 2, wobei der ringförmige elektrische Isolator (48) aus Aluminiumoxid gebildet ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Sensorsonde nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Signalübertragungsbaugruppe (14) einen Metallkranz (40) beinhaltet, welcher an das proximale offene Ende (32) der Hülse geschweißt ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Sensorsonde nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Hülse erste und zweite Hülsenkomponenten (28, 36) umfasst, wobei die erste Hülsenkomponente (28) an das offene Ende des Tiegels (18) hartgelötet ist und die zweite Hülsenkomponente (36) zwischen der ersten Hülsenkomponente (28) und der Signalübertragungsbaugruppe (14) angeordnet ist, wobei die zweite Hülsenkomponente (36) aus einem anderen Material als die erste Hülsenkomponente gebildet ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Sensorsonde nach Anspruch 5, wobei die erste Hülsenkomponente (28) aus einer Eisennickellegierung gebildet ist und die zweite Hülsenkomponente (36) aus Edelstahl gebildet ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Sensorsonde nach Anspruch 1, wobei der elektrische Leiter (16) ein Draht gebildet aus einem Material ausgewählt aus der Gruppe bestehend aus Eisen, Kupfer und Nickel ist.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980671" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A sensor probe for use in monitoring electrochemical potentials, comprising:
<claim-text>(a) a crucible (18) made of zirconia ceramic material having a closed end (20) and an open end (22), the closed end containing metal/metal oxide powder mixture (24) retained therein by mineral insulation packing (26), said open end (22) having a metallized band fired in the ceramic material;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) an annular metal sleeve (28) formed of a metal exhibiting a coefficient of thermal expansion compatible with said crucible, and having a distal open end (30) brazed to said open end (22) of said crucible (18), and a proximal open end (32);</claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) an insulated electrical conductor (16) having a distal end in electrical connection with said metal/metal oxide powder (24) and extending through said mineral insulation packing (26) and into said annular sleeve (28), and having a proximal end terminating near the proximal open end (32) of said annular sleeve; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) a signal transfer assembly (14) sealingly associated with said proximal end of said annular sleeve including an electrical cable (46) connected to said electrical conductor (16),<br/>
<b>characterised in that</b> the metallized band consists of platinum particles embedded in the crucible and the zirconia in the zirconia crucible is partially stabilized with approximately 8.0% by weight magnesia.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The sensor probe of claim 1 wherein said electrical conductor (16) is insulated by an annular electrical insulator (48) housed within said annular metal sleeve.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The sensor probe of claim 2 wherein said annular electrical insulator (48) is formed of alumina.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The sensor probe of claim 1 wherein said signal transfer assembly (14) includes a metal collar (40) welded to the proximate open end (32) of said sleeve.<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The sensor probe of claim 1 wherein said sleeve comprises first and second sleeve components (28, 36), said first sleeve component (28) brazed to said open end of said crucible (18), and said second sleeve component (36) interposed between said first sleeve component (28) and said signal transfer assembly (14), said second sleeve component (36) being formed of a different material than said first sleeve component.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The sensor probe of claim 5 wherein said first sleeve component (28) is formed of iron-nickel alloy, and said second sleeve component (36) is formed of stainless steel.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The sensor probe of claim 1 wherein said electrical conductor (16) is a wire formed of a material selected from the group consisting of iron, copper, and nickel.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980672" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Sonde de capteur destinée à être utilisée dans le contrôle de potentiels électrochimiques, comprenant :
<claim-text>(a) un creuset (18) fait d'un matériau céramique de zircone ayant une extrémité fermée (20) et une extrémité ouverte (22), l'extrémité fermée contenant un mélange de poudre de métal / oxyde de métal (24) retenu en son sein par une garniture isolante minérale (26), ladite extrémité ouverte (22) ayant une bande métallisée cuite dans le matériau céramique ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) un manchon métallique annulaire (28) formé d'un métal présentant un coefficient de dilatation thermique compatible avec ledit creuset et ayant une extrémité distale ouverte (30) brasée sur ladite extrémité ouverte (22) dudit creuset (18), et une extrémité proximale ouverte (32) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(c) un conducteur électrique isolé (16) ayant une extrémité distale en connexion électrique avec ladite poudre de métal / oxyde de métal (24) et s'étendant à travers ladite garniture isolante minérale (26) et dans ledit manchon annulaire (28), et ayant une extrémité proximale se terminant près de l'extrémité proximale ouverte (32) dudit manchon annulaire ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>(d) un ensemble de transfert de signal (14) associé de manière étanche à ladite extrémité proximale dudit manchon annulaire incluant un câble électrique (46) relié audit conducteur électrique (16),<br/>
<b>caractérisé en ce que</b> la bande métallisée consiste en particules de platine incorporées dans le creuset et la zircone dans le creuset de zircone est partiellement stabilisée avec approximativement 8,0 % en poids de magnésie.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Sonde de capteur selon la revendication 1,<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> dans laquelle ledit conducteur électrique (16) est isolé par un isolateur électrique annulaire (48) logé à l'intérieur dudit manchon métallique annulaire.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Sonde de capteur selon la revendication 2, dans lequel ledit isolateur électrique annulaire (48) est formé d'alumine.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Sonde de capteur selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle ledit ensemble de transfert de signal (14) inclut un collier métallique (40) soudé à l'extrémité ouverte proche (32) dudit manchon.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Sonde de capteur selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle ledit manchon comprend des premier et second composants de manchon (28, 36), ledit premier composant de manchon (28) étant brasé sur ladite extrémité ouverte dudit creuset (18), et ledit second composant de manchon (36) étant interposé entre ledit premier composant de manchon (28) et ledit ensemble de transfert de signal (14), ledit second composant de manchon (36) étant formé d'un matériau différent de celui dudit premier composant de manchon.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Sonde de capteur selon la revendication 5, dans laquelle ledit premier composant de manchon (28) est formé d'un alliage de fer-nickel, et ledit second composant de manchon (36) est formé d'acier inoxydable.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Sonde de capteur selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle ledit conducteur électrique (16) est un fil métallique formé d'un matériau sélectionné à partir du groupe constitué par le fer, le cuivre et le nickel.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16669229" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --><figure id="f0001" num=","><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="84" he="219" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
