<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-1895357-B1" country="EP" doc-number="1895357" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="37835273" file-reference-id="290036" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146588837" ucid="EP-1895357-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>1895357</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-06026441-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154851029" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>06026441</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20061220</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP220101143" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>06026441.3</doc-number><date>20061220</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140547792" ucid="JP-2006232998-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>JP</country><doc-number>2006232998</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20060830</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130924</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989326770" load-source="docdb">G02F   1/225       20060101AFI20070323BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989326771" load-source="docdb">G02F   1/035       20060101ALI20070323BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989632901" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G02F   1/0356      20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989634639" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G02F2201/122       20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989637351" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G02F2203/25        20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989640497" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G02F   1/2255      20130101 FI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132371144" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Optischer Modulator und optischer Sender</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132371145" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Optical modulator and optical transmitter</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132371146" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Modulateur optique et transmetteur optique</invention-title><citations><non-patent-citations><nplcit><text>ERASME D ET AL: "Time-domain analysis of phase-reversal travelling-wave integrated-optic modulators", ELECTRONICS LETTERS UK, vol. 22, no. 19, 11 September 1986 (1986-09-11), pages 1024 - 1026, ISSN: 0013-5194</text><sources><source mxw-id="PNPL66865876" load-source="docdb" name="EXA"/></sources></nplcit><nplcit><text>THEODOR TAMIR (ED.): "Guided-Wave Optoelectronics", vol. 26, 1998, SPRINGER-VERLAG, Heidelberg, article R. C. ALFERNESS: "Velocity Matching Techniques (Chapter 4, Section 4.2.2)", pages: 164 - 167</text><sources><source mxw-id="PNPL66865877" load-source="docdb" name="EXA"/></sources></nplcit></non-patent-citations></citations></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919515538" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>FUJITSU LTD</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919505506" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>FUJITSU LIMITED</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919534214" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>SUGIYAMA MASAKI</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919510504" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>SUGIYAMA, MASAKI</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919025005" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>SUGIYAMA, MASAKI</last-name><address><street>c/o Fujitsu Limited 1-1 Kamikodanaka 4-chome Nakahara-ku Kawasaki-shi</street><city>Kanagawa 211-8588</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919025007" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>FUJITSU LIMITED</last-name><iid>100126513</iid><address><street>1-1, Kamikodanaka 4-chome, Nakahara-ku</street><city>Kawasaki-shi, Kanagawa 211-8588</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919025006" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>HOFFMANN EITLE</last-name><iid>100061036</iid><address><street>Patent- und Rechtsanwälte Arabellastrasse 4</street><city>81925 München</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549925532" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549885954" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549805850" load-source="docdb">GB</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63961255" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading><heading id="h0002">1. Field of the Invention</heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to an optical modulator and an optical transmitter used for optical transmission, and in particular relates to an optical modulator of a waveguide type which modulates light using an electro-optic effect, and to an optical transmitter which uses this.</p><heading id="h0003">2. Description of the Related Art</heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">For example, an optical waveguide device which uses an electro-optic crystal such as lithium niobate (LiNbO<sub>3</sub>), lithium tantalate (LiTaO<sub>2</sub>) or the like, is manufactured by forming a metal film on a part of a crystal substrate and thermal diffusing, or by proton exchanging in benzoic acid after patterning, to thereby form an optical waveguide, and afterwards providing electrodes in the vicinity of the optical waveguide. As one optical waveguide device which uses an electro-optic crystal, there is known an optical modulator as shown for example in <figref idrefs="f0014">FIG. 28</figref>.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">In general, the optical modulator, depending on the shape of the optical waveguide, is divided into a phase modulator as shown at the top of <figref idrefs="f0014">FIG. 28</figref>, and an intensity modulator as shown at the bottom of <figref idrefs="f0014">FIG. 28</figref>. In the case of the phase modulator, a signal electrode 131 is formed on one optical waveguide 102 which is formed on a substrate 101. Furthermore, in the case of the intensity modulator, the optical waveguide 102 comprises an input waveguide 121, a branching section 122, branching waveguides 123 and 124, a multiplexing section 125, and an output waveguide 126, and a coplanar electrode is formed with a signal electrode 131 provided on one branching waveguide 123, and a ground electrode 132 provided on the other branching waveguide 124.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">In such an optical modulator, for example in the case where a Z-cut substrate 101 is used, the refractive index change due to an electric field in the Z-direction is used. Therefore, the electrode is arranged directly above the-optical waveguide 102. More specifically, in the case of the intensity modulator at the bottom of <figref idrefs="f0014">FIG. 28</figref>, the<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> signal electrode 131 and the ground electrode 132 are respectively patterned on the branching waveguides 123 and 124. At this time, in order to prevent the light propagated through the respective branching waveguides 123 and 124 being absorbed by the signal electrode 131 and the ground electrode 132, a buffer layer (not shown in the figure) is provided between the substrate 101and the electrodes 131 and 132. For the buffer layer, an oxide silicon (SiO<sub>2</sub>) or the like of a thickness of 0.2 µm to 1 µm is used.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">In the case of driving the above optical modulator at a high speed, the output terminal of the signal electrode 131 is made a traveling-wave electrode by grounding via a resistance (not shown in the figure), and a high frequency electric signal E such as a microwave is applied from an input terminal of the signal electrode 131. At this time, due to the electric field generated between the signal electrode 131 and the ground electrode 132, the refractive index of the optical waveguide 102 changes. Therefore, in the phase modulator at the top of <figref idrefs="f0014">FIG. 28</figref>, the phase of the light L propagated through the optical waveguide 102 is modulated in accordance with the electric signal E. Furthermore, in the intensity modulator at the bottom of <figref idrefs="f0014">FIG. 28</figref>, the refractive index of the branching waveguides 123 and 124 is changed for each, so that the phase difference of the light L propagated through each of these is changed, and an intensity modulated signal light L is output from the output waveguide 126.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">In the optical modulator driven at high speed as described above, it is known that a wide band optical response characteristic is obtained by controlling the effective refractive index for the electric signal E by changing the cross-section shape of the signal electrode 131, and matching the propagation speed of the light L and the electric signal E. However, regarding the electric signal E propagated through the signal electrode 131, if the frequency thereof becomes high, the transmission losses increase. Therefore there is a problem in that the modulation band width is limited, so that high speed modulation becomes difficult.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">As previous technology related to widening the band width of the optical modulator, for example as shown in <figref idrefs="f0015">FIG. 29</figref>, a configuration has been proposed where, of the interaction section for the light L and the electric signal E, the direction of the refractive index change is reversed by inverting the polarization direction in the remaining part 111 (surrounded by the dotted line in the figure) with respect to the<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> polarization direction of the substrate 101 (direction of the crystal axis) of the part from the input side to a certain length (refer for example to Japanese Unexamined Patent Publication Nos. <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="JP2005284129A"><text>2005-284129</text></patcit>, <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="JP2005221874A"><text>2005-221874</text></patcit>, and <patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="JP2006047746A"><text>2006-47746</text></patcit>). By means of this configuration, when modulation in the non-inversed region where the polarization direction is not changed is the forward direction, then in the polarization inversed region, modulation in the opposite direction occurs. That is to say, the polarization inversed part becomes an inverse modulated section, and the other part becomes a forward modulated section. As described above, since the loss of the electric signal E is great at high frequency, the intensity of the inverse modulation in the polarization inversed region is great at low frequency, and is small at high frequency. As a result, in the overall optical modulator, the modulation at low frequency is suppressed, so that the high frequency dependency is reduced, that is, the modulation bandwidth becomes wide.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">Furthermore, as another conventional technology for improving the response characteristics of the optical modulator or the like, a configuration is also proposed where the electrode width of the signal electrode and the ground electrode is changed along the light propagation direction, to thereby prevent resonance of an acoustic wave (for example surface acoustic wave) which is produced when a modulating signal of a high pulse shape is applied between the electrodes, so that occurrence of ripple is suppressed, (refer for example to Japanese Unexamined Patent Publication No. <patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="JP2000275589A"><text>2000-275589</text></patcit>).</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">However, in the conventional technology which gives a wider band width by using the above inverse modulation, since the modulation component of the high frequency band in the polarization inversed region (inverse modulation section) has not become small enough, then in the high frequency band, a certain amount of inverse modulation occurs. Therefore there is a problem in that the amount of improvement in bandwidth is limited.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">Furthermore, in the conventional technology for improving the response characteristics by changing the electrode width of the signal electrode and the ground electrode along the light propagation direction, the influence on the light due to the resonance of the generated acoustic wave attributable to the piezoelectricity of the substrate can be reduced, but an increase in the propagation loss of the electrical signal in the high frequency as mentioned above cannot be effectively<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> suppressed. Therefore there is the problem that it is difficult to realize a wider band width.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">Background art of interest is also disclosed in the following documents.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012"><patcit id="pcit0005" dnum="EP1199593A2"><text>EP 1 199 593 A2</text></patcit> discloses a high-efficiency electro-optic modulator with an equalized frequency response. The modulator includes an optical waveguide formed in an electro-optic material that propagates an optical signal along a first direction of propagation. An electrical waveguide is formed on the electro-optic material and positioned generally co-linear relative to the optical waveguide and in electromagnetic communication with the optical waveguide. The geometry of the electrical waveguide is selected to achieve a modulation efficiency at a frequency in a bandwidth of a digital spectrum- A compensation network is electrically coupled to the electrical waveguide at a junction. The compensation network reduces an electro-optic response of the electro-optic modulator below the mean frequency bandwidth of the digital spectrum, thereby causing an increase of the electro-optic response above the mean frequency of the digital spectrum.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013"><patcit id="pcit0006" dnum="US20060029319A1"><text>US 2006/0029319 A1</text></patcit> discloses an optical modulator including a first electrode composed of an inverting area electrode portion formed on an upper portion of one of the first and second waveguides in the polarization inverting area, a non-inverting area electrode portion formed on an upper portion of the other one of the first and second waveguides in the other area, and a connection portion for making a connection between the inverting area electrode portion and the non-inverting area electrode portion at the boundary between the polarization inverting area and the other area.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014"><nplcit id="ncit0001" npl-type="s"><text>Viet Pham, A, Murata, H, Okamura, Y, "Electrooptic modulator with arbitrary frequency response utilizing nonperiodic polarization reversal", Lasers and Electro-Optics, 2005, CLEO/Pacific RIM 2005, Pacific RIM Conference on Tokyo, Japan August 2005</text></nplcit>, discloses a travelling wave electrooptic phase modulator with nonperiodic polarization reversal.</p><heading id="h0004">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading><p id="p0015" num="0015">The present invention addresses the abovementioned points with an object of providing an optical modulator which can realize a wider modulation bandwidth, and an optical transmitter which uses this.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">The present invention provides an optical modulators as set out in each of appended claims 1-3, and an optical transmitter as set out in claim 8. Optional features are set out in the remaining claims. In the following, background examples designates examples that are not according to the invention.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></p><p id="p0017" num="0017">Other objects, characteristics, and advantages of the present invention will become apparent from the following description of the embodiments, in conjunction with the appended drawings.</p><heading id="h0005">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading><p id="p0018" num="0018"><ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a plan view showing a configuration of an optical modulator according to a first background example, which is helpful for understanding the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 2</figref> is an enlarged view of section a-a' and section b-b' of <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 3</figref> is a diagram showing an example of change in electric field intensity in each region of the first background example.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 4</figref> is a diagram showing an example of optical response characteristics in the first background example.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 5</figref> is a diagram showing an example of a relationship between length of an inverse modulation section and an error rate in the first background example.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 6</figref> is a cross-section showing another configuration example related to the first background example.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 7</figref> is a cross-section showing yet another configuration example related to the first background example.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 8</figref> is a plan view showing a second background example, where the configuration of the first background example is applied to a phase modulator.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 9</figref> shows an enlarged cross-section of respective sections in an optical modulator according to an embodiment of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 10</figref> is a diagram showing a relation of modulation bandwidth with respect to tan δ of a substance constituting a buffer layer in the embodiment.<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></li><li><figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 11</figref> is a cross-section showing another configuration example related to the embodiment.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 12</figref> is a plan view showing a configuration of an optical modulator according to a third background example.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 13</figref> is an enlarged view of section a-a' and section b-b' of <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 12</figref>.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 14</figref> is a cross-section showing another configuration example related to the third background example.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 15</figref> is plan view showing a configuration example of a case where the configuration of the third background example is applied to a phase modulator.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 16</figref> is a plan view showing a configuration of an optical modulator according to a fourth background example.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 17</figref> is a plan view showing a configuration of an optical modulator according to a fifth background example.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 18</figref> is a plan view showing a configuration of an optical modulator according to a sixth background example.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0010">FIG. 19</figref> is a plan view showing a configuration of an optical modulator according to a seventh background example.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0010">FIG. 20</figref> is a diagram showing an example of change in electric field intensity in each region of the seventh background example.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0011">FIG. 21</figref> is a diagram showing an example of optical response characteristics in the seventh background example.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0011">FIG. 22</figref> is a plan view showing a configuration of an optical modulator according to an eight background example.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0012">FIG. 23</figref> is a cross-section showing another configuration example related to the eighth background example.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0012">FIG. 24</figref> is a plan view showing a configuration of an optical modulator according to a ninth background example.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0013">FIG. 25</figref> is an enlarged view of section a-a' and section c-c' in <figref idrefs="f0012">FIG. 24</figref>.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0013">FIG. 26</figref> is a cross-section showing another configuration example related to the ninth background example</li><li><figref idrefs="f0014">FIG. 27</figref> is a block diagram showing a configuration of an embodiment of an optical transmitter according to the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0014">FIG. 28</figref> is a plan view showing a configuration example of a general optical modulator.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0015">FIG. 29</figref> is a plan view showing a configuration example of a conventional optical modulator which uses inverse modulation.</li></ul><!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p><heading id="h0006">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF BACKGROUND EXAMPLES AND EMBODIMENTS</heading><p id="p0019" num="0019">There is described in the following an optical modulator which comprises a substrate having an electro-optic effect, an optical waveguide formed on the substrate, a signal electrode formed on the substrate, and a ground electrode formed on the substrate at a distance from the signal electrode, and in which in a first and second region set in an interaction section where light propagated through the optical waveguide, and an electrical signal propagated through the signal electrode interact with each other, a modulation direction in the first region positioned on an input side in a light propagation direction, and in the second region positioned on an output side, are reversed, and the first and second regions are configured such that a loss produced in the second region is relatively greater than a loss produced in the first region, with respect to a high frequency component of an electric signal propagated through the signal electrode.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">In an optical modulator of the abovementioned configuration, the loss with respect to the high frequency component of the electrical signal in the second region on the output side of the interaction section is made relatively greater than the loss with respect to the high frequency component of the electrical signal in the first region on the input side of the interaction section. As a result the inverse modulation in the high frequency band in the second region where the modulation direction is reversed to that of the first region is suppressed more than for a conventional optical modulator which uses inverse modulation. Therefore a wider modulation bandwidth is realized. In the optical modulators in accordance with the invention, the loss of the high frequency component of the electrical signal in the second region is made higher than in the first region by increasing the dielectric loss in the second region.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">Furthermore, there is described an optical transmitter, which uses the abovementioned optical modulator to externally modulate and transmit an outgoing beam from a light source. In such an optical transmitter, modulated signal light can be transmitted to the outside at a faster rate.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">According to the optical modulator as described above, by making the loss of the second region with respect to the high frequency component of the electrical signal propagated through the signal electrode relatively large, the modulation band in the overall optical modulator can be made a wider band, and modulation at a higher speed than heretofore is possible. According to the optical transmitter which uses such an optical modulator, optical signals having a wider bandwidth can be transmitted, and hence a characteristic improvement of the error rate and the like on the reception side becomes possible.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></p><p id="p0023" num="0023">Embodiments of the present invention, and background examples that are helpful for understanding the invention, will now be described with reference to the appended drawings. Throughout the drawings the same reference symbols denote the same or equivalent components.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024"><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a plan view showing a configuration of an optical modulator according to a first background example, which is helpful for understanding the present invention. Moreover, <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 2</figref> is an enlarged view of section a-a' and section b-b' in the optical modulator of <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">In <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1 and FIG. 2</figref>, the optical modulator of the first background example comprises for example a substrate 1 having an electro-optic effect, an optical waveguide 2 of a Mach-Zehnder type formed on the substrate 1, and an electrode 3 formed on the surface of the substrate 1.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">The substrate 1 uses a crystal substrate of for example Z-cut lithium niobate (LiNbO<sub>3</sub>) or Lithium Tantalate (LiTaO<sub>2</sub>) and in a region (hereunder interaction section) where light propagated through the optical waveguide 2 and an electric signal E propagated through the electrode 3 interact, a first region A on the input side which spans from the light input end over a predetermined length in the longitudinal direction (the light propagation direction) is made a forward modulation section 1A, and a second region B remaining on the output side is made an inverse modulation section 1B. In the inverse modulation section 1B is formed a polarization inversed region 11 enclosed by the dashed line in the figure. The polarization inversed region 11 is a region where the polarization direction (crystal axis direction) of the substrate 1 is inversed, and is formed for example by impressing a high pulse electric field on the substrate 1 which has been patterned with resist or the like.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">The optical waveguide 2 has an input waveguide 21, a branching section 22, branching waveguides 23 and 24, a multiplexing section 25, and an output waveguide 26, and constitutes a Mach-Zehnder interferometer. This optical waveguide 2 is formed on the surface of the substrate 1 by applying a process such as thermal diffusion of titanium (Ti) or the like, or proton exchange, Regarding the distance between the pair of branching waveguides 23 and 24 (hereunder the waveguide spacing), the waveguide spacing in the inverse<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> modulation section 1B is relatively narrower than the waveguide spacing in the forward modulation section 1A. At the boundary portion spreading from the forward modulation section 1A to the inverse modulation section 1B, the waveguide spacing becomes gradually narrower. Furthermore, the aforementioned waveguide spacing is designed so that it becomes wider than the spacing for where coupling is produced with the light propagating through the respective branching waveguides 23 and 24.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">The electrode 3 has a signal electrode 31 and a ground electrode 32. Opposite ends of the signal electrode 31 are positioned on one side of the substrate 1, and the central portion is patterned so as to follow along above one branching waveguide 23. The ground electrode 32 is arranged at a necessary distance apart from the signal electrode 31. A buffer layer 41 which uses SiO<sub>2</sub> or the like, is formed between the surface of the electrode 3 and the substrate 1 in order to prevent the light propagated through the optical waveguide 2 from being absorbed by the electrode 3.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">The signal electrode 31 is made a traveling-wave electrode by grounding one end positioned at the bottom right in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> via a resistance (not shown in the figure), and an electric signal E of a high frequency corresponding to the modulation data is applied from another terminal positioned at the bottom left in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>. The distance between the signal electrode 31 and the ground electrode 32 (hereunder the electrode spacing) is greater than the electrode spacing in the forward modulation section 1A, and the electrode spacing in the inverse modulation section 1B is made relatively narrow. Furthermore, the cross-section shape of the signal electrode 31 is designed so that speed matching conditions of the light propagated through the optical waveguide 2, and the electric signal E are satisfied. If the electrode spacing is made relatively narrow, the impedance drops. Therefore here, as shown by the cross-section in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 2</figref>, the cross-section area of a signal electrode 31B and a ground electrode 32B in the inverse modulation section 1B (at the bottom of <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 2</figref>) are each made smaller than the cross-section of a. signal electrode 31A and a ground electrode 32A in the forward modulation section 1A (the top of <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 2</figref>), so that a desired impedance (for example 50 Ω or the like) is obtained.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">In the case where the cross-section of the electrode is changed in the forward modulation section 1A and the inverse modulation section 1B, it is necessary to pay<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> attention to the connection with the outside. The connection with the outside is generally for example performed by bonding wire to an electrode pad provided on the substrate 1. However at this time, bonding is easier if the electrode pad on the input side and the terminal side are the same shape. Furthermore, it is better to arrange each of the cross-sections in order to also easily match the impedance from the interactive portion to the electrode pad, on the input side and the terminal side. Consequently, in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, it is preferable to design so that the cross-section of the signal electrode 31 from the input electrode pad which applies the electric signal E, up until the region A, and the cross-section of the signal electrode 31 which passes through the region B and extends to the terminal electrode pad are the same. Furthermore, in the signal electrode 31 of the boundary portion directed from the forward modulation section 1A to the inverse modulation section 1B, preferably the cross-section area is made gradually smaller, to suppress an increase in the series resistance.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">Next is a description of the operation of the optical modulator of the first background example.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">In the optical modulator of the aforementioned configuration, light Lin applied from the outside to the input waveguide 21 is branched into two by the branching section 22 and respectively sent to the branching waveguides 23 and 24. To the branching waveguides 23 and 24 is applied an electric field generated between the signal electrode 31 and the ground electrode 32 corresponding to the electric signal E which travels on the signal electrode 31, and due to the electro-optic effect of this electric field, the refractive index of the branching waveguides 23 and 24 changes. As a result, the phases of the respective beams propagated through the branching waveguides 23 and 24 are each changed.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">At this time, the electric signal E input to the signal electrode 31 is attenuated while propagating through the signal electrode 31, and the attenuation amount becomes greater at a high frequency. However, by forming the polarization inversed region 11 on the output side portion of the interaction section, and making the direction of modulation at the interaction section forward modulation in the input side region A, and inverse modulation in the output side region B, the intensity of the inverse modulation in the region B becomes greater at a low frequency, and is less<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> at a high frequency. As a result, the modulation at a low frequency for the overall optical modulator is suppressed and the modulation bandwidth becomes wilder.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">Furthermore, in the present background example, by making the electrode spacing of the inverse modulation section 1B (region B) narrow with respect to the electrode spacing of the forward modulation section 1A (region A), the transmission loss of the high frequency component of the electrical signal E in the inverse modulation section 1B due to the skin effect is intentionally increased. For example, in the case of an optical modulator of 10 Gb/s, it is good to increase the transmission loss of the electric signal E at a high frequency of 10 GHz or more. As a result, the inverse modulation in the high frequency band in the inverse modulation section 1B is suppressed, and hence it is possible to realize an seven wider modulation bandwidth. In addition, the spacing of the branching waveguides 23 and 24 also becomes relatively narrow corresponding to the electrode spacing of the inverse modulation section 1B. Therefore, the situation where the effect of applying the electric field is reduced in the inverse modulation section 1B is also avoided.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035"><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 3</figref> shows an example of change in electric field intensity in the regions A and B. Furthermore, <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 4</figref> shows an example of optical response characteristics of the present optical modulator.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 3</figref>, in the optical modulator, by making the electrode spacing of the region B relatively narrow, the electric field intensity corresponding to the high frequency component in the region B becomes generally greater at the boundary portion with the region A, and thereafter is attenuated considerably more than for the case of the conventional optical modulator (refer to the bottom of <figref idrefs="f0015">FIG. 29</figref>). As a result, the intensity of inverse modulation at a high frequency in the region B is less than heretofore. On the other hand, the electric field intensity for a low frequency (here shown by the DC component) becomes greater over the whole of the region B by making the electrode spacing narrow. Therefor the intensity of the inverse modulation at a low frequency is greater than heretofore. Consequently, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 4</figref>, the modulation bandwidth of the optical modulator of the first background example is an even wider bandwidth than for the case of the conventional optical modulator with inverse modulation<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></p><p id="p0037" num="0037">The modulation bandwidth of the present optical modulator becomes wider accompanying the increase in the proportion of the length of the inverse modulation section 1B with respect to the overall length of the interactive portion. However, if the proportion of the length of the inverse modulation section 1B becomes somewhat large, it is difficult for modulation at the low frequency. Therefore, it is necessary to optimally design the proportion of the length of the inverse modulation section 1B to realize a wider band, taking into consideration the necessary degree of modulation. <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 5</figref> is an example showing a relation between the length of the inverse modulation section 1B and error rate. The situation is apparent that when the inverse modulation section 1B is short, the effect of widening the band cannot be sufficiently obtained, and the error rate worsens, while when the inverse modulation section 1B is long, the degree of modulation becomes low, and hence the error rate worsens.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">As described above, the respective bearns which are propagated through the branching waveguides 23 and 24 of the forward modulation section 1A and the inverse modulation section 1B, and phase modulated, are multiplexed by the multiplexing section 25, so that an intensity modulated signal Lout is output from the output waveguide 26.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">According to the first background example as described above, by making the electrode spacing of the inverse modulation section 1B relatively narrow with respect to the electrode spacing of the forward modulation section 1A, and increasing the transmission loss of the electrical signal of a high frequency in the inverse modulation section 1B, it is possible to make the modulation bandwidth in the overall optical modulator even wider.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">In the above described first background example, by making the electrode spacing in the inverse modulation section 1B relatively narrow, the high frequency transmission loss is increased. However as shown for example in the cross-section of <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 6</figref>, also by making the width of the signal electrode 31B of the inverse modulation section 1B relatively narrower than the width of the signal electrode 31A of the forward modulation section 1A, it is possible to increase the high frequency transmission loss. In this case also, a similar operational effect to the case of the first background example can be obtained.<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --></p><p id="p0041" num="0041">Furthermore, in the first background example, an example was shown for preventing the drop in the impedance due to the relatively narrow electrode spacing, by respectively reducing the cross-sections of the signal electrode 31B and the ground electrode 32B of the inverse modulation section 1B, However, as shown for example in the cross-section b-b' of <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 7</figref>, even if just the cross-section area of the ground electrode 32B is reduced, but the cross-section area of the signal electrode 31B is substantially the same as on the forward modulation section 1A side, it is possible to realize a desired impedance. In this case, the problem of the increase in the series resistance in the boundary portion of the forward modulation section 1A and the inverse modulation section 1B does not arise.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">Furthermore, in the first background example, the case was explained where the present invention was applied to the beforementioned conventional intensity modulator shown at the bottom of <figref idrefs="f0015">FIG. 29</figref>. However, these principles are also applicable to the conventional phase modulator shown at the top of <figref idrefs="f0015">FIG. 29</figref>. The configuration example for this case is shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 8</figref>. Also in the second background example of <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 8</figref>, by making the electrode spacing of the inverse modulation section 1B (region B) relatively narrower than the electrode spacing of the forward modulation section 1A (region A), and increasing the transmission loss of the high frequency electric signal E in the inverse modulation section 1B, a wider phase modulation bandwidth can be realized.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">In addition, in the first background example, the example was shown for the case using a Z-cut substrate 1. However also in the case where the optical modulator is configured using an X-cut substrate, then similar to the case of the first background example, by adapting a configuration where the electrode spacing of the inverse modulation section is made narrow, an even wider modulation bandwidth can be realized.</p><p id="p0044" num="0044">Next is a description of an embodiment of the present invention.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045"><figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 9</figref> shows an enlarged cross-section of respective sections in an optical modulator according to the embodiment of the present invention. The plan view showing the configuration of the overall optical modulator of the embodiment is similar to the case of the first background example shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>. Therefore, illustration is omitted here.<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></p><p id="p0046" num="0046">The optical modulator of the embodiment is one where, for a buffer layer 41 formed between the surface of the substrate 1 and the signal electrode and the ground electrode, so that the dielectric loss of a buffer layer 41B (refer to the bottom of <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 9</figref>) positioned on the inverse modulation section 1B is greater than the dielectric loss of a buffer layer 41A (refer to the top of <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 9</figref>) positioned on the forward modulation section 1A, the substance constituting the respective buffer layers 41A and 41B is made different-The configuration other than for the buffer layers 41.A, and 41B is the same as for the case of the first background example.</p><p id="p0047" num="0047">It is known that the dielectric loss of the buffer layer changes corresponding to the value of the dielectric loss tangent (tan δ) of the substance constituting the buffer layer. More specifically, the greater the value of tan δ, the greater the dielectric loss of the buffer layer. If the buffer layer dielectric loss becomes greater, the high frequency electric field intensity is reduced. Therefore in the region where such a buffer layer is formed, the modulation bandwidth becomes narrow.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048"><figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 10</figref> is an example showing a relation of modulation bandwidth with respect to the value of tan δ of the substance constituting the buffer layer. In this manner, by configuring the buffer layer using a substance where the tan δ of the substance is large, it is possible to make the modulation intensity of the high frequency component in the region where the buffer layer is formed small. In this embodiment, by making the value of tan δ of the substance constituting the buffer layer 41B on the inverse modulation section 1B side greater than the value of tan δ of the substance constituting the buffer layer 41A, on the forward modulation section 1A side, the inverse modulation intensity of the high frequency component in the inverse modulation section 1B becomes smaller.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">Consequently, according to the optical modulator of the embodiment, similar to the case of the first background example, in addition to making the electrode spacing of the inverse modulation section 1B narrow so that the propagation loss of the high frequency electric signal is increased, by increasing the dielectric loss of the buffer layer 41B, it is possible to make the modulation bandwidth of the overall optical modulator even wider.<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --></p><p id="p0050" num="0050">In the abovementioned embodiment, the configuration example is shown where the dielectric loss of the buffer layer 41B formed between the substrate 1 and the electrode 3 is increased. However as shown for example in the cross-section b-b' at the top of <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 11</figref>, even if instead of the buffer layer 41B, a configuration is adopted where the surroundings of the signal electrode 31B in the inverse modulation section 1B, are covered by a substance 42 with a greater dielectric loss than the substrate 1, or a configuration is adopted where as shown in the cross-section b-b' at the bottom of <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 11</figref>, a film 42' with a large dielectric loss is provided between the electrode 3 and the buffer layer 41, it is possible to obtain a similar effect to the case of the embodiment.</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">Furthermore, as an application example related to the embodiment, even if the dielectric loss of the material constituting the signal electrode 31B of the inverse modulation section 1B is relatively large compared to the dielectric loss of the material constituting the signal electrode 31A of the forward modulation section 1A, it is possible to increase the bandwidth of the modulation bandwidth.</p><p id="p0052" num="0052">Moreover, in the abovementioned embodiment, for the configuration of the first background example where the electrode spacing of the inverse modulation section 1B is narrow, the example is shown where the dielectric loss of the buffer layer 41B of the inverse modulation section 1B is great. However even for the phase modulator shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 8</figref>, or for a configuration where the width of the abovementioned signal electrode shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 6</figref> is made narrow, by making the dielectric loss of the buffer layer of the inverse modulation section large, the modulation bandwidth can be made even wider.</p><p id="p0053" num="0053">In addition, in the abovementioned embodiment, it has been considered to combine this with a configuration where the transmission loss of the high frequency electrical signal is increased by making the electrode spacing narrow. However, even if only the dielectric loss of the buffer layer of the inverse modulation section in the conventional optical modulator such as shown before in <figref idrefs="f0015">FIG. 29</figref> is made large, the conventional modulation bandwidth can be made large.</p><p id="p0054" num="0054">Next is a description of a third background example.<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></p><p id="p0055" num="0055"><figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 12</figref> is a plan view showing a configuration of an optical modulator according to the third background example. Moreover, <figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 13</figref> is an enlarged view of section a-a' and section b-b' in the optical modulator of <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 12</figref>.</p><p id="p0056" num="0056">In <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 12</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 13</figref>, the point where the configuration of the optical modulator the third background example is significantly different to the configuration of the first background example shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1 and FIG. 2</figref> is that regarding the distance (electrode spacing) between the signal electrode 31 and the ground electrode 32, the electrode spacing in the inverse modulation section 1B is relatively greater than the electrode spacing in the forward modulation section 1A. Furthermore, since the impedance increases if the electrode spacing is relatively increased, then by making the sectional area of the signal electrode 31B and the ground electrode 32B in the inverse modulation section 1B (the bottom of <figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 13</figref>) respectively greater than the sectional area of the signal electrode 31A and the ground electrode 32A in the forward modulation section 1A, a desired impedance. (for example 50 Q or the like) is obtained. Furthermore, the spacing (waveguide spacing) of the branching waveguides 23B and 24B also becomes relatively wide corresponding to the electrode spacing of the inverse modulation section 1B. Other configuration of the optical modulator other than the configuration described above is similar to the configuration of the first background example. Therefore description is omitted here.</p><p id="p0057" num="0057">In the optical modulator of the abovementioned configuration, by relatively widening the electrode spacing of the inverse modulation section 1B, the high frequency component of the electric signal E propagated through the signal electrode 31B is easily radiated to the substrate 1 or to the atmosphere, so that the loss is increased. By increasing the radiation loss of the high frequency electric signal E in the inverse modulation section 1B, the inverse modulation in the high frequency band is suppressed. Therefore similarly to the case of the first background example, it is possible to realize an even wider modulation bandwidth. Furthermore, the spacing of the branching waveguides 23B and 24B also becomes relatively wide corresponding to the electrode spacing of the inverse modulation section 1B. Therefore the situation where the effect of applying the electric field is reduced in the inverse modulation section 1B is also avoided.</p><p id="p0058" num="0058">In the third background example, the example is shown for where the increase in the impedance due to making the electrode spacing relatively wider is prevented by<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> making the sectional area of the signal electrode 31B and the ground electrode 32B of the inverse modulation section 1B respectively greater. However, as shown for example in the cross-section b-b' of <figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 14</figref>, even if only the sectional area of the ground electrode 32B is made large, and the sectional area of the signal electrode 31B is made the same as for the forward modulation section 1A side, it is possible to realize a desired impedance.</p><p id="p0059" num="0059">Moreover, in the third background example, the case was explained where principles described herein were applied to the beforementioned conventional intensity modulator shown at the bottom of <figref idrefs="f0015">FIG. 29</figref>. However, these principles are also applicable to the conventional phase modulator shown at the top of <figref idrefs="f0015">FIG. 29</figref>. The configuration example, for this case is shown in <figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 15</figref>. Also in the configuration example of <figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 15</figref>, by making the electrode spacing of the inverse modulation section 1B relatively wider than the electrode spacing of the forward modulation section 1A, and increasing the transmission loss of the high frequency electric signal E in the inverse modulation section 1B, a wider phase modulation bandwidth can be realized.</p><p id="p0060" num="0060">Next is a description of a fourth background example.</p><p id="p0061" num="0061"><figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 16</figref> is a plan view showing a configuration of an optical modulator according to the fourth background example.</p><p id="p0062" num="0062">In <figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 16</figref>, the point where the configuration of the optical modulator of the fourth background example differs to the case of the first background example, is that patterning of the electrode 3 is changed so that instead of forming the polarization inversed region 11 on the substrate 1, the signal electrode 31 is arranged above one branching waveguide 23 in the region A, and is arranged above the other branching waveguide 24 in the region B. Other configuration of the optical modulator other than for the above described point is similar to the configuration of the first background example. Therefore description is omitted here.</p><p id="p0063" num="0063">In the optical modulator of the above described configuration, the electrical signal E applied to one end of the signal electrode 31 propagates along the one branching waveguide 23 in the region A, and propagates along the other branching waveguide 24 in the region B. As a result, the direction of modulation in the region B<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> is opposite to the direction of modulation in the region A, and hence the forward modulation section 1A (region A), and the inverse modulation section 1B (region B) are realized similarly to the case in the first background example where the polarization inversed region 11 is formed. Furthermore, in this background example however, since the electrode spacing of the inverse modulation section 1B is made relatively narrower than the electrode spacing of the forward modulation section 1A, the propagation loss of the high frequency electrical signal in the inverse modulation section 1B is increased, and the inverse modulation in the high frequency band is suppressed. Consequently an effect similar to the case of the first background example can be obtained, and also the step for forming the polarization inversed region on the substrate 1 becomes unnecessary so that inverse modulation in the region B can be realized by simply changing the pattern design of the electrode 3. Therefore, the configuration of the optical modulator becomes even simpler.</p><p id="p0064" num="0064">In the abovementioned fourth background example, the pattern of the electrode 3 in the configuration of the first background example is changed. However it is possible to apply a configuration similar to the fourth background example even for the configurations of the other embodiments and background examples.</p><p id="p0065" num="0065">Next is a description of a fifth background example.</p><p id="p0066" num="0066"><figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 17</figref> is a plan view showing a configuration of an optical modulator according to the fifth background example.</p><p id="p0067" num="0067">The optical modulator of the fifth background example is an application example for where a reduction in wavelength chirp in the optical modulator of, for example, the first embodiment is reduced. That is to say, in the optical modulator of the first background example, since the electric field intensity below the signal electrode 31, and the electric field intensity below the ground electrode 32 are different, the phase change of the respective lights propagating through the pair of branching waveguides 23 and 24 become unbalanced, and wavelength chirp (wavelength fluctuations) may occur. In order to suppress this wavelength chirp, it is effective to use movement between the branching waveguides 23 and 24 of the signal electrode 31 and use polarization inversion, together.<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --></p><p id="p0068" num="0068">More specifically, in the optical modulator of this background example, as shown for example in <figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 17</figref>, polarization inversed regions 11A and 11B surrounded by the dotted lines in the figure, are respectively formed on the forward modulation section 1A and the inverse modulation section 1B. The polarization inversed region 11A has a length in the propagation direction of the light of approximately half of the overall length L of the forward modulation section 1A, and is arranged in the approximate center of the forward modulation section 1A. Furthermore, the polarization inversed region 11B has a length in the propagation direction of the light of 1/2 of the overall length L' of the inverse modulation section 1B, and is arranged in the approximate center of the inverse modulation section 1B.</p><p id="p0069" num="0069">Moreover, the signal electrode 31 is patterned in a desired shape such that for the forward modulation section 1A, in the polarization inversed region 11A it passes above the branching waveguide 23, and outside of the polarization inversed region 11A it passes above the branching waveguide 24. Furthermore for the inverse modulation section 1B, in the polarization inversed region 11B it passes above the branching waveguide 24, and outside of the polarization inversed region 11B it passes above the branching waveguide 23. On the other hand, the ground electrode 32 is patterned in a desired shape such that for the forward modulation section 1A, in the polarization inversed region 11A it passes above the branching waveguide 24, and outside of the polarization inversed region 11A it passes above the branching waveguide 23. Furthermore, for the inverse modulation section 1B, in the polarization inversed region 11B it passes above the branching waveguide 23, and outside of the polarization inversed region 11B it passes above the branching waveguide 24. The distance (electrode spacing) between the signal electrode 31 and the ground electrode 32, similarly to the case of the first background example, is designed so that the electrode spacing in the inverse modulation section 1B is relatively narrower than the electrode spacing in the forward modulation section 1 A.</p><p id="p0070" num="0070">In the optical modulator of the above described configuration, if this is designed so that in the length direction (overall length L) of the forward modulation section 1A, the length of the polarization inversed region 11A and the length of the non inversed region are approximately the same, that is, so that the lengths of the respective non inversed regions positioned before and after the polarization inversed region 11A become U4, and the length of the polarization inversed region 11A becomes L/2, the phase of the light propagating through the branching waveguide<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> 23 of the forward modulation section 1A changes by only θ<sub>23</sub> as shown in the following equation (1), and the phase of the light propagating through the branching waveguide 24 of the forward modulation section 1A changes by only θ<sub>24</sub> as shown by the following equation (2). <maths id="math0001" num="(1)"><math display="block"><mtable columnalign="left"><mtr><mtd><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">θ</mi><mn mathvariant="normal">23</mn></msub></mtd><mtd><mo>=</mo><mfenced separators=""><mo>+</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">n</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">S</mi></msub></mfenced><mo>⋅</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">L</mi><mo>/</mo><mn mathvariant="normal">4</mn><mo>+</mo><mfenced separators=""><mo>+</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">n</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">G</mi></msub></mfenced><mo>⋅</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">L</mi><mo>/</mo><mn mathvariant="normal">2</mn><mo>+</mo><mfenced separators=""><mo>+</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">n</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">S</mi></msub></mfenced><mo>⋅</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">L</mi><mo>/</mo><mn mathvariant="normal">4</mn></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mspace width="1em"/></mtd><mtd><mo>=</mo><mfenced separators=""><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">n</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">S</mi></msub><mo>+</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">n</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">G</mi></msub></mfenced><mo>⋅</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">L</mi><mo>/</mo><mn mathvariant="normal">2</mn></mtd></mtr></mtable></math><img id="ib0001" file="imgb0001.tif" wi="93" he="14" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> <maths id="math0002" num="(2)"><math display="block"><mtable columnalign="left"><mtr><mtd><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">θ</mi><mn mathvariant="normal">24</mn></msub></mtd><mtd><mo>=</mo><mfenced separators=""><mo>-</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">n</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">G</mi></msub></mfenced><mo>⋅</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">L</mi><mo>/</mo><mn mathvariant="normal">4</mn><mo>+</mo><mfenced separators=""><mo>-</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">n</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">S</mi></msub></mfenced><mo>⋅</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">L</mi><mo>/</mo><mn mathvariant="normal">2</mn><mo>+</mo><mfenced separators=""><mo>-</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">n</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">G</mi></msub></mfenced><mo>⋅</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">L</mi><mo>/</mo><mn mathvariant="normal">4</mn></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mspace width="1em"/></mtd><mtd><mo>=</mo><mo>-</mo><mfenced separators=""><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">n</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">S</mi></msub><mo>+</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">n</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">G</mi></msub></mfenced><mo>⋅</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">L</mi><mo>/</mo><mn mathvariant="normal">2</mn></mtd></mtr></mtable></math><img id="ib0002" file="imgb0002.tif" wi="93" he="14" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths><br/>
where Δn<sub>S</sub> is the refractive index variation of the branching waveguides positioned below the signal electrode 31, and Δn<sub>G</sub> is the refractive index variation of the branching waveguides positioned below the ground electrode 32.</p><p id="p0071" num="0071">As is apparent from the above equation (1) and equation (2), the phase of the respective lights propagating through the branching waveguides 23 and 24 of the forward modulation section 1A respectively change by only (+Δn<sub>S</sub>) · L/2, and (-Δn<sub>G</sub>) · L/2 in the non inversed region, and respectively change by only (+Δn<sub>G</sub>) · L/2, and (-Δn<sub>S</sub>) · L/2 in the polarization inversed region 11A. Consequently, the phases of the respective lights which pass through the branching waveguides 23 and 24 and reach to the output end of the forward modulation section 1A change by only + (Δn<sub>S</sub> + Δn<sub>G</sub>) · L/2, and - (Δn<sub>S</sub> + Δn<sub>G</sub>) · L/2, giving a phase modulation where signals with the same absolute values are inverted. Therefore, in the forward modulation section 1A, wavelength chirp does not occur so that there is zero chirp.</p><p id="p0072" num="0072">Furthermore, also for the lengthwise direction (overall length L') of the inverse modulation section 1B, similar to the abovementioned forward modulation section 1A, if this is designed so that the length of the polarization inversed region 11B and the length of the non inversed region are approximately the same, the phase of the light propagating through the branching waveguide 23 of the inverse modulation section 1B changes by only θ<sub>23</sub>' as shown in the following equation (1)', and the phase of the light propagating through the branching waveguide 24 of the inverse modulation section 1B changes by only θ<sub>24</sub>' as shown by the following equation (2)'. <maths id="math0003" num="(1)'"><math display="block"><mtable columnalign="left"><mtr><mtd><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">θ</mi><mn mathvariant="normal">23</mn></msub><mo>⁢</mo><mi>ʹ</mi></mtd><mtd><mo>=</mo><mfenced separators=""><mo>+</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">n</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">G</mi></msub></mfenced><mo>⋅</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Lʹ</mi><mo>/</mo><mn mathvariant="normal">4</mn><mo>+</mo><mfenced separators=""><mo>+</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">n</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">S</mi></msub></mfenced><mo>⋅</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Lʹ</mi><mo>/</mo><mn mathvariant="normal">2</mn><mo>+</mo><mfenced separators=""><mo>+</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">n</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">G</mi></msub></mfenced><mo>⋅</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Lʹ</mi><mo>/</mo><mn mathvariant="normal">4</mn></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mspace width="1em"/></mtd><mtd><mo>=</mo><mfenced separators=""><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">n</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">S</mi></msub><mo>+</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">n</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">G</mi></msub></mfenced><mo>⋅</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Lʹ</mi><mo>/</mo><mn mathvariant="normal">2</mn></mtd></mtr></mtable></math><img id="ib0003" file="imgb0003.tif" wi="100" he="17" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> <maths id="math0004" num="(2)'"><math display="block"><mtable columnalign="left"><mtr><mtd><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">θ</mi><mn mathvariant="normal">24</mn></msub><mo>⁢</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">ʹ</mi></mtd><mtd><mo>=</mo><mfenced separators=""><mo>-</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">n</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">S</mi></msub></mfenced><mo>⋅</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Lʹ</mi><mo>/</mo><mn mathvariant="normal">4</mn><mo>+</mo><mfenced separators=""><mo>-</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">n</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">G</mi></msub></mfenced><mo>⋅</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Lʹ</mi><mo>/</mo><mn mathvariant="normal">2</mn><mo>+</mo><mfenced separators=""><mo>-</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">n</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">S</mi></msub></mfenced><mo>⋅</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Lʹ</mi><mo>/</mo><mn mathvariant="normal">4</mn></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><mspace width="1em"/></mtd><mtd><mo>=</mo><mo>-</mo><mfenced separators=""><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">n</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">S</mi></msub><mo>-</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">n</mi><mi mathvariant="normal">G</mi></msub></mfenced><mo>⋅</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Lʹ</mi><mo>/</mo><mn mathvariant="normal">2</mn></mtd></mtr></mtable></math><img id="ib0004" file="imgb0004.tif" wi="96" he="16" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0073" num="0073">As is apparent from the above equation (1)' and equation (2)', the phase of the respective lights propagating through the branching waveguides 23 and 24 of the inverse modulation section 1B respectively change by only (+Δn<sub>G</sub>) L'/2, and (-Δn<sub>S</sub>) L'/2 in the non inversed region, and respectively change by only (+Δn<sub>S</sub>) L'/2, and (-Δn<sub>G</sub>) L'/2 in the polarization inversed region 11B. Consequently, the phases of the respective lights which pass through the branching waveguides 23 and 24 and reach to the output end of the inverse modulation section 1B change by only + (Δn<sub>S</sub> + Δn<sub>G</sub>) L'/2, and - (Δn<sub>S</sub> + Δn<sub>G</sub>) L'/2, giving a phase modulation where signals with the same absolute values are inverted. Therefore, in the inverse modulation section 1B also, wavelength chirp does not occur so that there is zero chirp.</p><p id="p0074" num="0074">In addition to realizing zero chirp in the forward modulation section 1A and the inverse modulation section 1B as described above, in the optical modulator, similar to the case of the fourth background example, since the electrode 3 is patterned so that the modulation direction in the region B positioned on the light output side becomes the opposite with respect to the modulation direction in the region A positioned on the light input side of the interaction section, the modulation band width is widened. That is to say, the electric signal E input to the signal electrode 31 is attenuated while propagating through the signal electrode 31, and the attenuation amount becomes larger at high frequency. However, by making the modulation direction at the interactive portion, forward modulation in the region A on the input side, and inverse modulation in the region B on the output side, the intensity of the inverse modulation in the region B becomes large at low frequency, and becomes small at high frequency. As a result, the modulation at low frequency in the overall optical modulator is suppressed, and the bandwidth is widened.</p><p id="p0075" num="0075">Furthermore, in the optical modulator, by making the electrode spacing of the inverse modulation section 1B relatively narrow with respect to the electrode spacing of the forward modulation section 1A, the transmission loss of the high frequency component of the electric signal E in the region B is increased. As a result, the inverse modulation in the high frequency band in the inverse modulation section 1B is suppressed, and hence it is possible to realize an even wider modulation bandwidth. In addition the spacing of the branching waveguides 23 and 24 also<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> becomes relatively narrow corresponding to the electrode spacing of the inverse modulation section 1B. Therefore the situation where the effect of applying the electric field is reduced in the inverse modulation section 1B is also avoided.</p><p id="p0076" num="0076">Next is a description of a sixth background example.</p><p id="p0077" num="0077"><figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 18</figref> is a plan view showing a configuration of an optical modulator according to the sixth background example.</p><p id="p0078" num="0078">In <figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 18</figref>, the point where the configuration of this background example is different from the case of the fifth background example shown in <figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 17</figref> is that the position of the polarization inversed region in the inverse modulation section 1B is changed, so that the arrangement pattern of the signal electrode 31 is simplified. More specifically, a polarization inversed region 11B<sub>1</sub> is formed in an interval from one end of the inverse modulation section 1B contacting with the forward modulation section 1A to a length of L'/4, and a polarization inversed region 11B<sub>2</sub> of a length L'/4 is formed with a non inversed region of a length L'/2 sandwiched between the polarization inversed regions 11B<sub>1</sub> and 11B<sub>2</sub>. Furthermore, the pattern of the electrode 3 is changed so that in the respective polarization inversed regions 11B<sub>1</sub> and 11B<sub>2</sub>, the signal electrode 31 is arranged above the branching waveguide 24, and the ground electrode 32 is arranged above the branching waveguide 23, and in the non inversed region positioned between the polarization inversed regions 11B<sub>1</sub> and 11B<sub>2</sub>, the signal electrode 31 is arranged above the branching waveguide 23, and the ground electrode 32 is arranged above the branching waveguide 24.</p><p id="p0079" num="0079">According to the optical modulator of the above described configuration, a similar operational effect to the case of the fifth background example is obtained. Also it is not necessary to change over the arrangement pattern of the signal electrode 31 in the border portion of the forward modulation section 1A and the inverse modulation section 1B, from above the branching waveguide 24 to above the branching waveguide 23, as with the case of the fifth background example. Hence, the back and forth frequency of the signal electrode 31 between the respective branching waveguides 23 and 24 in the overall optical modulator can be reduced from three times to two times. By making the arrangement pattern of the signal electrode 31 simpler, an improvement effect of the propagation characteristic (for example loss or reflection<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> and the like) of the electric signal E can be expected, and hence it becomes possible to even further widen the band width of the modulation bandwidth.</p><p id="p0080" num="0080">Next is a description of a seventh background example.</p><p id="p0081" num="0081"><figref idrefs="f0010">FIG. 19</figref> is a plan view showing a configuration of an optical modulator according to the seventh background example.</p><p id="p0082" num="0082">In <figref idrefs="f0010">FIG. 19</figref>, the optical modulator of the seventh background example is one where for example in the configuration of the first background example, a non modulation section 1C where there is no phase modulation in the light propagated through the respective branching waveguides 23 and 24, is provided in a third region C between the forward modulation section 1A (region A) and the inverse modulation section 1B (region B). Other configuration apart from this non modulation section 1C is similar to the case of the first background example. Therefore description is omitted here.</p><p id="p0083" num="0083">In the non modulation section 1C, the branching waveguides 23 and 24 are formed in a similar condition to the forward modulation section 1A, whereas the signal electrode 31 is arranged in a position separated from above the branching waveguide 23 (a position separated to the upper side from the branching waveguide 23 in <figref idrefs="f0010">FIG. 19</figref>). The distance (electrode spacing) of the signal electrode 31 and the ground electrode 32 in the non modulation section 1C is similar to the electrode spacing in the inverse modulation section 1B, and narrower than the electrode spacing in the forward modulation section 1A.</p><p id="p0084" num="0084">In the case where the non modulation section 1C is provided between the forward modulation section 1A and the inverse modulation section 1B, it is important to match the speed of the electrical signal and the light so that the modulation bandwidth is not worsened. Therefore, the electrical length of the signal electrode 31 in the non modulation section 1C and the optical length of the branching waveguides 23 and 24 are made to approximately coincide.</p><p id="p0085" num="0085">In an optical modulator of the abovementioned configuration, the non modulation section 1C provided between the forward modulation section 1A and the inverse modulation section 1B is a low pass filter, and in the electric signal E propagated through the signal electrode 31, the high frequency component is<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --> attenuated from after passing through the forward modulation section 1A until it reaches the inverse modulation section 1B. <figref idrefs="f0010">FIG. 20</figref> shows an example of the change in the electric field intensity in the respective regions A through C. Due to the skin effect due to the electrode spacing of the region C being made relatively narrow, the electric field intensity corresponding to the high frequency component in the region C, becomes temporarily great at the boundary portion of the region A, and thereafter is significantly attenuated. Therefore, the electric field intensity of the high frequency in the input end of the region B becomes smaller than for the case of the first background example shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 4</figref>. As a result, the intensity of the inverse modulation at the high frequency in the region B becomes even smaller than for the case of the first background example. On the other hand, regarding the electric field intensity of the low frequency (here shown as a DC component), due to the electrode spacing being narrow, this becomes large over the whole of the region C and the region B. Therefore the intensity of the inverse modulation at the low frequency is increased. Consequently, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0011">FIG. 21</figref>, the modulation bandwidth of the optical modulator of the seventh background example is even wider than for the case of the optical modulator of the first background example.</p><p id="p0086" num="0086">Next is a description of an eighth background example.</p><p id="p0087" num="0087"><figref idrefs="f0011">FIG. 22</figref> is a plan view showing a configuration of an optical modulator according to the eight background example.</p><p id="p0088" num="0088">In <figref idrefs="f0011">FIG. 22</figref>, the optical modulator of the eight background example, is a modified example where in the configuration of the seventh background example shown in <figref idrefs="f0010">FIG. 19</figref>, the position of the signal electrode 31 in the non modulation section 1C is at the center of the pair of branching waveguides 23 and 24. In such a configuration, in the non modulation section 1C, an electric field of substantially the same size is applied to the branching waveguides 23 and 24. Therefore, the phase of the light propagating through each is maintained, and as a result there is no modulation. Consequently, according to the optical modulator of the eighth background example, even in the case where for example due to limitations in space on the substrate 1, it is difficult to have the situation as in the seventh background example where the signal electrode is away from above the branching waveguide, it is possible to achieve a similar operational effect to the case of the seventh background example.<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --></p><p id="p0089" num="0089">In the configuration of the eight background example, in the case where the pattern of the optical waveguide 2 and the electrode 3 is misaligned, the electric field applied to the branching waveguides 23 and 24 in the non modulation section 1C becomes different, so that there is the possibility of modulation being produced. In order to prevent such a situation, for example as shown in <figref idrefs="f0012">FIG. 23</figref>, the pattern of the optical waveguide may be modified so that the branching waveguides 23 and 24 in the non modulation section 1C are both positioned below the ground electrode 32. In this case, it is necessary to curve the branching waveguides 23 and 24 and widen the waveguide spacing. However a drop in the yield due to process error can be avoided.</p><p id="p0090" num="0090">Next is a description of a ninth background example.</p><p id="p0091" num="0091"><figref idrefs="f0012">FIG. 24</figref> is a plan view showing a configuration of an optical modulator according to the ninth background example. Furthermore, <figref idrefs="f0013">FIG. 25</figref> is an enlarged view of section a-a' and section c-c' in the optical modulator of <figref idrefs="f0012">FIG. 24</figref>.</p><p id="p0092" num="0092">In <figref idrefs="f0012">FIG. 24</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0013">FIG. 25</figref>, the optical modulator of the ninth background example is one where, as a separate configuration for realizing the non modulation section 1C provided between the forward modulation section 1A and the inverse modulation section 1B, a buffer layer 41C in the non modulation section 1C is made thicker than the buffer layer 41A in the forward modulation section 1A, and an electric field applied to branching waveguides 23C and 24C of the non modulation section 1C is decreased so that modulation does not occur. As a result, a signal electrode 31C of the non modulation section 1C is arranged above the branching waveguide 23 similar to with the other regions.</p><p id="p0093" num="0093">Also in the optical modulator of the above described configuration, it is possible to obtain a similar operational effect to the case of the seventh and eighth background examples.</p><p id="p0094" num="0094">In the ninth background example, modulation was eliminated by making the buffer layer 41C of the non modulation section 1C thick. However for example as shown in the section c-c' at the top of <figref idrefs="f0013">FIG. 26</figref>, in the non modulation section 1C, by providing a film 43 different to the buffer layer 41C between the buffer layer 41C and the signal electrode 31C and the ground electrode 32, or as shown in the section c-c' at the<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> bottom of <figref idrefs="f0013">FIG. 26</figref>, in the non modulation section 1C, by providing a film 43 which is different to the buffer layer 41 between the buffer layer 41C and the substrate 1, it is possible to realize a condition where it is even more difficult to have modulation. For the aforementioned film 43, a material may be used for which the dielectric loss at a high frequency is greater than that of the buffer layer 41C. In relation to applying either the configuration at the top or at the bottom of <figref idrefs="f0013">FIG. 26</figref>, the film 43 and the buffer layer 41C may be appropriately determined by considering the adhesion between these and the electrode 3 and the substrate 1.</p><p id="p0095" num="0095">Next is a description of an example of an optical transmitter which uses any of the aforementioned optical modulators of the embodiments.</p><p id="p0096" num="0096"><figref idrefs="f0014">FIG. 27</figref> is a block diagram showing a configuration of an embodiment of the optical transmitter.</p><p id="p0097" num="0097">In <figref idrefs="f0014">FIG. 27</figref>, an optical transmitter 50 comprises a light source (LD) 51 which generates continuous light, an LD control circuit 52 which controls the drive state of the light source 51, an optical modulator 53 to which continuous light Lin output from the light source 51 is inputted, a signal multiplexing circuit 54 which multiplexes a plurality of data signals and generates a modulating signal with a high bit rate, and a driver circuit 55 which drives the optical modulator 53 in accordance with a modulation signal output from the signal multiplexing circuit 54.</p><p id="p0098" num="0098">As the optical modulator 53 which is installed in the optical transmitter 50 of such a configuration, by applying any one of the above described optical modulators of the embodiments, it is possible to transmit an optical signal Lout having a wider band, so that a characteristic improvement in error rate or the like on the receiving side can be achieved.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56986505" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Optischer Modulator (53), welcher umfasst:
<claim-text>ein Kristallsubstrat (1), das einen elektrooptischen Effekt und eine entlang der optischen Kristallachse ausgerichtete Polarisation aufweist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Lichtwellenleiter (2), der auf dem Substrat (1) ausgebildet ist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Signalelektrode (31), die auf dem Substrat (1) ausgebildet ist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Erdelektrode (32), die auf dem Substrat (1) ausgebildet ist und von der Signalelektrode (31) beabstandet ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Interaktionsabschnitt, in dem während der Verwendung des optischen Modulators (53) Licht, das sich durch den Lichtwellenleiter (2) ausbreitet, und ein elektrisches Signal (E), das sich durch die Signalelektrode (31) ausbreitet, miteinander interagieren, wobei der Interaktionsabschnitt einen ersten Bereich (1A), der auf einer Eingangsseite in einer Lichtausbreitungsrichtung positioniert ist, und einen zweiten Bereich (1B), der auf einer Ausgangsseite in der Lichtausbreitungsrichtung positioniert ist, umfasst, wobei die Polarisationsrichtung des Substrats (1) in dem zweiten Bereich (1B) entgegengesetzt zu der Polarisationsrichtung des Substrats (1) in dem ersten Bereich (1A) ist, wobei<!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>die Signalelektrode (31) und die Erdelektrode (32) auf dem Substrat (1) über eine Pufferschicht (41A, 41B) ausgebildet sind, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>der Wert des dielektrischen Verlusttangens einer dielektrischen Substanz, welche die Pufferschicht (41B) in dem zweiten Bereich (1B) bildet, größer als der Wert des dielektrischen Verlusttangens einer Substanz ist, welche die Pufferschicht (41A) in dem ersten Bereich (1A) bildet.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Optischer Modulator (53), welcher umfasst:
<claim-text>ein Kristallsubstrat (1), das einen elektrooptischen Effekt und eine entlang der optischen Kristallachse ausgerichtete Polarisation aufweist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Lichtwellenleiter (2), der auf dem Substrat (1) ausgebildet ist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Signalelektrode (31), die auf dem Substrat (1) ausgebildet ist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Erdelektrode (32), die auf dem Substrat (1) ausgebildet ist und von der Signalelektrode (31) beabstandet ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Interaktionsabschnitt, in dem während der Verwendung des optischen Modulators (53) Licht, das sich durch den Lichtwellenleiter (2) ausbreitet, und ein elektrisches Signal (E), das sich durch die Signalelektrode (31) ausbreitet, miteinander interagieren, wobei der Interaktionsabschnitt einen ersten Bereich (1A), der auf einer Eingangsseite in einer Lichtausbreitungsrichtung positioniert ist, und einen zweiten Bereich (1B), der auf einer Ausgangsseite in der Lichtausbreitungsrichtung positioniert ist,<!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>umfasst, wobei die Polarisationsrichtung des Substrats (1) in dem zweiten Bereich (1B) entgegengesetzt zu der Polarisationsrichtung des Substrats (1) in dem ersten Bereich (1A) ist,</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>die Signalelektrode (31B) in dem zweiten Bereich (1B) mit einer dielektrischen Substanz (42) mit einem größeren dielektrischen Verlusttangens als das Substrat (1) bedeckt ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Optischer Modulator (53), welcher umfasst:
<claim-text>ein Kristallsubstrat (1), das einen elektrooptischen Effekt und eine entlang der optischen Kristallachse ausgerichtete Polarisation aufweist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Lichtwellenleiter (2), der auf dem Substrat (1) ausgebildet ist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Signalelektrode (31), die auf dem Substrat (1) ausgebildet ist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Erdelektrode (32), die auf dem Substrat (1) ausgebildet ist und von der Signalelektrode (31) beabstandet ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Interaktionsabschnitt, in dem während der Verwendung des optischen Modulators (53) Licht, das sich durch den Lichtwellenleiter (2) ausbreitet, und ein elektrisches Signal (E), das sich durch die Signalelektrode (31) ausbreitet, miteinander interagieren, wobei der Interaktionsabschnitt einen ersten Bereich (1A), der auf einer Eingangsseite in einer Lichtausbreitungsrichtung positioniert ist, und einen zweiten Bereich (1B), der auf einer Ausgangsseite<!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --> in der Lichtausbreitungsrichtung positioniert ist, umfasst, wobei die Polarisationsrichtung des Substrats (1) in dem zweiten Bereich (1B) entgegengesetzt zu der Polarisationsrichtung des Substrats (1) in dem ersten Bereich (1A) ist, wobei</claim-text>
<claim-text>die Signalelektrode (31) und die Erdelektrode (32) auf dem Substrat (1) über eine Pufferschicht (41) ausgebildet sind, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>ein dielektrischer Film (42') mit einem größeren dielektrischen Verlusttangens als die Pufferschicht (41) zwischen der Pufferschicht (41) und der Signalelektrode (31) und der Erdelektrode (32) in dem zweiten Bereich (1B) vorgesehen ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Optischer Modulator (53) nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 3, wobei der Lichtwellenleiter (2) eine Konfiguration eines Mach-Zehnder-Interferometers aufweist, wobei Licht, das in einen Eingangswellenleiter (21) eingekoppelt wird, in einem Verzweigungsabschnitt (22) in zwei Teile verzweigt wird und entsprechend zu einem Paar von Zweigwellenleitern (23, 24) geleitet wird, und Licht, das sich durch die Zweigwellenleiter (23, 24) ausbreitet, in einem Multiplexabschnitt (25) gemultiplext wird und aus einem Ausgangswellenleiter (26) ausgekoppelt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Optischer Modulator (53) nach Anspruch 4, wobei<br/>
ein Zwischenraum zwischen der Signalelektrode (31) und der Erdelektrode (32) in dem zweiten Bereich (1B) schmaler als ein Zwischenraum zwischen der Signalelektrode (31) und der Erdelektrode (32) in dem ersten Bereich (1A) ist,<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="36"> -->ein Zwischenraum zwischen den Zweigwellenleitern (23, 24) in dem zweiten Bereich (1B) schmaler als ein Zwischenraum zwischen den Zweigwellenleitern (23, 24) in dem ersten Bereich (1A) ist, und<br/>
Querschnittsflächen der Signalelektrode (31) und der Erdelektrode (32) in dem zweiten Bereich (1B) kleiner als Querschnittsflächen der Signalelektrode (31) bzw. der Erdelektrode (32) in dem ersten Bereich (1A) ausgebildet sind.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Optischer Modulator (53) nach Anspruch 4, wobei<br/>
ein Zwischenraum zwischen der Signalelektrode (31) und der Erdelektrode (32) in dem zweiten Bereich (1B) schmaler als ein Zwischenraum zwischen der Signalelektrode (31) und der Erdelektrode (32) in dem ersten Bereich (1A) ist,<br/>
ein Zwischenraum zwischen den Zweigwellenleitern (23, 24) in dem zweiten Bereich (1B) schmaler als ein Zwischenraum zwischen den Zweigwellenleitern (23, 24) in dem ersten Bereich (1A) ist, und<br/>
Querschnittsflächen der Signalelektrode (31) in dem ersten und dem zweiten Bereich (1A, 1B) im Wesentlichen gleich sind und eine Querschnittsfläche der Erdelektrode (32) in dem zweiten Bereich (1B) kleiner als Querschnittsfläche der Erdelektrode (32) in dem ersten Bereich (1A) ausgebildet ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Optischer Modulator (53) nach einem der Ansprüche 4 bis 6, wobei<br/>
die Signalelektrode (31) entlang eines der Zweigwellenleiter des Paares von Zweigwellenleitern (23,<!-- EPO <DP n="37"> --> 24) in dem ersten und dem zweiten Bereich (1A, 1B) ausgebildet ist,<br/>
die Erdelektrode (32) entlang des anderen Zweigwellenleiters des Paares von Zweigwellenleitern (23, 24) in dem ersten und dem zweiten Bereich (1A, 1B) ausgebildet ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Optischer Sender (50), der dafür eingerichtet ist, einen optischen Modulator (53) nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche zu verwenden, um einen Ausgangsstrahl von einer Lichtquelle extern zu modulieren und zu senden.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56986506" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>An optical modulator (53) comprising:
<claim-text>a crystal substrate (1) having an electro-optic effect and a polarization oriented along the crystal optical axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an optical waveguide (2) formed on said substrate (1);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a signal electrode (31) formed on said substrate (1);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a ground electrode (32) formed on said substrate (1) and spaced apart from said signal electrode (31); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an interaction section wherein, during use of the optical modulator (53), light propagated through said optical waveguide (2) and an electrical signal (E) propagated through said signal electrode (31) interact with each other, the interaction section comprising a first region (1A) positioned on an input side in a light propagation direction and a second region (1B) positioned on an output side in the light propagation direction, wherein the polarization direction of the substrate (1) in the second region (1B) is inversed with respect to the polarization direction of the substrate (1) in the first region (1A), wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>said signal electrode (31) and said ground electrode (32) are formed on said substrate (1) via a buffer layer (41A, 41B), <b>characterized in that</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>the value of the dielectric loss tangent of a dielectric substance constituting the buffer layer (41B) in the second region (1B) is greater than the value of the dielectric loss<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --> tangent of a substance constituting the buffer layer (41A) in the first region (1A).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>An optical modulator (53) comprising:
<claim-text>a crystal substrate (1) having an electro-optic effect and a polarization oriented along the crystal optical axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an optical waveguide (2) formed on said substrate (1);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a signal electrode (31) formed on said substrate (1);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a ground electrode (32) formed on said substrate (1) and spaced apart from said signal electrode (31); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an interaction section wherein, during use of the optical modulator (53), light propagated through said optical waveguide (2) and an electrical signal (E) propagated through said signal electrode (31) interact with each other, the interaction section comprising a first region (1A) positioned on an input side in a light propagation direction and a second region (1B) positioned on an output side in the light propagation direction, wherein the polarization direction of the substrate (1) in the second region (1B) is inversed with respect to the polarization direction of the substrate (1) in the first region (1A),</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>characterized in that</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>said signal electrode (31B) in said second region (1B) is covered by a dielectric substance (42) with a greater dielectric loss tangent than said substrate (1).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>An optical modultator (53) comprising:
<claim-text>a crystal substrate (1) having an electro-optic effect and a polarization oriented along the crystal optical axis;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an optical waveguide (2) formed on said substrate (1);<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>a signal electrode (31) formed on said substrate (1) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a ground electrode (32) formed on said substrate (1) and spaced apart from said signal electrode (31); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an interaction section wherein, during use of the optical modulator (53), light propagated through said optical waveguide (2) and an electrical signal (E) propagated through said signal electrode (31) interact with each other, the interaction section comprising a first region (1A) positioned on an input side in a light propagation direction and a second region (1B) positioned on an output side in the light propagation direction, wherein the polarization direction of the substrate (1) in the second region (1B) is inversed with respect to the polarization direction of the substrate (1) in the first region (1A), wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>said signal electrode (31) and said ground electrode (32) are formed on said substrate (1) via a buffer layer (41), <b>characterized in that</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>a dielectric film (42') with a greater dielectric loss tangent than said buffer layer (41) is provided between said buffer layer (41), and said signal electrode (31) and said ground electrode (32), in said second region (1B).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>An optical modulator (53) according to any of claims 1 to 3, wherein said optical waveguide (2) has a configuration of a Mach-Zehnder interferometer, where light input to an input waveguide (21) is branched into two in a branching section (22) and respectively sent to a pair of branching waveguides (23, 24), and light propagated through said branching waveguides (23, 24) is multiplexed in a multiplexing section (25) and output from an output waveguide (26).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>An optical modulator (53) according to claim 4, wherein<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> -->a spacing between said signal electrode (31) and said ground electrode (32) in said second region (1B) is narrower than a spacing between said signal electrode (31) and said ground electrode (32) in said first region (1A),<br/>
a spacing between said branching waveguides (23, 24; in said second region (1B) is narrower than a spacing between the branching waveguides (23, 24) in the first region (1A), and<br/>
cross-section areas of said signal electrode (31) and said ground electrode (32) in said second region (1B) are made smaller than respective cross-section areas of said signal electrode (31) and said ground electrode (32) in said first region (1A).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>An optical modulator (53) according to claim 4, wherein<br/>
a spacing between said signal electrode (31) and said ground electrode (32) in said second region (1B) is narrower than a spacing between said signal electrode (31) and said ground electrode (32) in said first region (1A),<br/>
a spacing between said branching waveguides (23, 24) in said second region (1B) is narrower than a spacing between the branching waveguides (23, 24) in the first region (1A), and<br/>
cross-section areas of said signal electrode (31) in said first and second regions (1A, 1B) are substantially the same, and a cross-section area of said ground electrode (32) in said second region (1B) is made smaller than a cross-section area of said ground electrode (32) in said first region (1A).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>An optical modulator (53) according to any of claims 4 to 6,<br/>
wherein<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="31"> -->said signal electrode (31) is formed along a branching waveguide of one of said pair of branching waveguides (23, 24) in said first and second regions (1A, 1B), and<br/>
said ground electrode (32) is formed along a branching waveguide of another of said pair of branching waveguides (23, 24) in said first and second regions (1A, 1B).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>An optical transmitter (50) arranged to use an optical modulator (53) according to any preceding claim to externally modulate and transmit an outgoing beam from a light source.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56986507" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="38"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Modulateur optique (53) comprenant :
<claim-text>un substrat en cristal (1) ayant un effet électro-optique et une polarisation orientée le long de l'axe optique du cristal ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un guide d'ondes optique (2) formé sur ledit substrat (1) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une électrode de signal (31) formée sur ledit substrat (1) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une électrode de masse (32) formée sur ledit substrat (1) et espacée de ladite électrode de signal (31) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>une section d'interaction dans laquelle, pendant l'utilisation du modulateur optique (53), la lumière qui s'est propagée à travers ledit guide d'ondes optique (2) et un signal électrique (E) qui s'est propagé à travers ladite électrode de signal (31) interagissent l'un avec l'autre, la section d'interaction comprenant une première région (1A) positionnée d'un côté d'entrée dans une direction de propagation de la lumière et une deuxième région (1B) positionnée d'un côté de sortie dans la direction de propagation de la lumière, dans lequel la direction de polarisation du substrat (1) dans la deuxième région (1B) est inversée par rapport à la direction de polarisation du substrat (1) dans la première région (1A), dans lequel</claim-text>
<claim-text>ladite électrode de signal (31) et ladite électrode de masse (32) sont formées sur ledit substrat (1) par l'intermédiaire d'une couche tampon (41A, 41B), <b>caractérisé en ce que</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>la valeur de la tangente de perte diélectrique d'une substance diélectrique constituant la couche tampon (41B) dans la deuxième région (1B) est supérieure à la valeur de la<!-- EPO <DP n="39"> --> tangente de perte diélectrique d'une substance constituant la couche tampon (41A) dans la première région (1A).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Modulateur optique (53) comprenant :
<claim-text>un substrat en cristal (1) ayant un effet électro-optique et une polarisation orientée le long de l'axe optique du cristal ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un guide d'ondes optique (2) formé sur ledit substrat (1) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une électrode de signal (31) formée sur ledit substrat (1) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une électrode de masse (32) formée sur ledit substrat (1) et espacée de ladite électrode de signal (31) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>une section d'interaction dans laquelle, pendant l'utilisation du modulateur optique (53), la lumière qui s'est propagée à travers ledit guide d'ondes optique (2) et un signal électrique (E) qui s'est propagé à travers ladite électrode de signal (31) interagissent l'un avec l'autre, la section d'interaction comprenant une première région (1A) positionnée d'un côté d'entrée dans une direction de propagation de la lumière et une deuxième région (1B) positionnée d'un côté de sortie dans la direction de propagation de la lumière, dans lequel la direction de polarisation du substrat (1) dans la deuxième région (1B) est inversée par rapport à la direction de polarisation du substrat (1) dans la première région (1A), <b>caractérisé en ce que</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>ladite électrode de signal (31B) dans ladite deuxième région (1B) est recouverte par une substance diélectrique (42) avec une tangente de perte diélectrique plus grande que celle dudit substrat (1).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Modulateur optique (53), comprenant :<!-- EPO <DP n="40"> -->
<claim-text>un substrat en cristal (1) ayant un effet électro-optique et une polarisation orientée le long de l'axe optique du cristal ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un guide d'ondes optique (2) formé sur ledit substrat (1) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une électrode de signal (31) formée sur ledit substrat (1) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une électrode de masse (32) formée sur ledit substrat (1) et espacée de ladite électrode de signal (31) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>une section d'interaction dans laquelle, pendant l'utilisation du modulateur optique (53), la lumière qui s'est propagée à travers ledit guide d'ondes optique (2) et un signal électrique (E) qui s'est propagé à travers ladite électrode de signal (31) interagissent l'un avec l'autre, la section d'interaction comprenant une première région (1A) positionnée d'un côté d'entrée dans une direction de propagation de la lumière et une deuxième région (1B) positionnée d'un côté de sortie dans la direction de propagation de la lumière, dans lequel la direction de polarisation du substrat (1) dans la deuxième région (1B) est inversée par rapport à la direction de polarisation du substrat (1) dans la première région (1A), dans lequel</claim-text>
<claim-text>ladite électrode de signal (31) et ladite électrode de masse (32) sont formées sur ledit substrat (1) par l'intermédiaire d'une couche tampon (41), <b>caractérisé en ce que</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>un film diélectrique (42') avec une tangente de perte diélectrique plus grande que celle de ladite couche tampon (41) est prévu entre ladite couche tampon (41) et ladite électrode de signal (31) et ladite électrode de masse (32), dans ladite deuxième région (1B).</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="41"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Modulateur optique (53) selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 3, dans lequel ledit guide d'ondes optique (2) a une configuration d'un interféromètre Mach-Zehnder, où la lumière appliquée dans un guide d'onde d'entrée (21) est divisée en deux dans une section de division (22), et envoyée respectivement à une paire de guides d'ondes de branchement (23, 24), et la lumière qui s'est propagée à travers lesdits guides d'ondes de branchement (23, 24) est multiplexée dans une section de multiplexage (25) et sortie d'un guide d'onde de sortie (26).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Modulateur optique (53) selon la revendication 4, dans lequel<br/>
un espacement entre ladite électrode de signal (31) et ladite électrode de masse (32) dans ladite deuxième région (1B) est plus petit qu'un espacement entre ladite électrode de signal (31) et ladite électrode de masse (32) dans ladite première région (1A),<br/>
un espacement entre lesdits guides d'ondes de branchement (23, 24) dans ladite deuxième région (1B) est plus petit qu'un espacement entre les guides d'ondes de branchement (23, 24) dans la première région (1A), et<br/>
les sections de ladite électrode de signal (31) et de ladite électrode de masse (32) dans ladite deuxième région (1B) sont réalisées de manière à être plus petites que les sections respectives de ladite électrode de signal (31) et de ladite électrode de masse (32) dans ladite première région (1A).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Modulateur optique (53) selon la revendication 4, dans lequel<br/>
un espacement entre ladite électrode de signal (31) et ladite électrode de masse (32) dans ladite deuxième région<!-- EPO <DP n="42"> --> (1B) est plus petit qu'un espacement entre ladite électrode de signal (31) et ladite électrode de masse (32) dans ladite première région (1A),<br/>
un espacement entre lesdits guides d'ondes de branchement (23, 24) dans ladite deuxième région (1B) est plus petit qu'un espacement entre les guides d'ondes de branchement (23, 24) dans la première région (1A), et<br/>
les sections de ladite électrode de signal (31) dans lesdites première et deuxième régions (1A, 1B) sont sensiblement les mêmes, et une section de ladite électrode de masse (32) dans ladite deuxième région (1B) est réalisée de manière à être plus petite qu'une section de ladite électrode de masse (32) dans ladite première région (1A).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Modulateur optique (53) selon l'une quelconque des revendications 4 à 6, dans lequel<br/>
ladite électrode de signal (31) est formée le long d'un guide d'ondes de branchement qui est l'un de ladite paire de guides d'ondes de branchement (23, 24) dans lesdites première et deuxième régions (1A, 1B), et<br/>
ladite électrode de masse (32) est formée le long d'un guide d'ondes de branchement qui est un autre de ladite paire de guides d'ondes de branchement (23, 24) dans lesdites première et deuxième régions (1A, 1B).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Emetteur optique (50) agencé pour utiliser un modulateur optique (53) selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes pour moduler extérieurement et transmettre un faisceau sortant d'une source de lumière.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16672469" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="43"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1,2"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="148" he="231" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="44"> --><figure id="f0002" num="3,4"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="146" he="224" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="45"> --><figure id="f0003" num="5,6"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="118" he="232" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="46"> --><figure id="f0004" num="7,8"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="161" he="227" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="47"> --><figure id="f0005" num="9,10"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="133" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="48"> --><figure id="f0006" num="11,12"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="159" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="49"> --><figure id="f0007" num="13,14"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="110" he="223" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="50"> --><figure id="f0008" num="15,16"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="165" he="224" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="51"> --><figure id="f0009" num="17,18"><img id="if0009" file="imgf0009.tif" wi="163" he="219" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="52"> --><figure id="f0010" num="19,20"><img id="if0010" file="imgf0010.tif" wi="149" he="227" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="53"> --><figure id="f0011" num="21,22"><img id="if0011" file="imgf0011.tif" wi="165" he="225" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="54"> --><figure id="f0012" num="23,24"><img id="if0012" file="imgf0012.tif" wi="157" he="229" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="55"> --><figure id="f0013" num="25,26"><img id="if0013" file="imgf0013.tif" wi="106" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="56"> --><figure id="f0014" num="27,28"><img id="if0014" file="imgf0014.tif" wi="114" he="222" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="57"> --><figure id="f0015" num="29"><img id="if0015" file="imgf0015.tif" wi="125" he="123" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
