<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2017616-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2017616" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="39930665" file-reference-id="318260" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146588715" ucid="EP-2017616-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2017616</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-08160802-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154850907" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>08160802</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20080721</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140552702" ucid="US-78118607-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>78118607</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20070720</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130926</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989326427" load-source="ipcr">G01N  33/00        20060101AFI20081112BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989638239" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G01N  33/0006      20130101 FI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370778" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Gassensor-test und -kalibrierungssystem</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370779" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">A gas sensor test and calibration system</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370780" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Test de capteur de gaz et système d'étalonnage</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919521108" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>HONEYWELL INT INC</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919518783" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>HONEYWELL INTERNATIONAL INC.</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919506070" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>GU YUANDONG</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919533105" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>GU, YUANDONG</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919024396" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>GU, YUANDONG</last-name><address><street>17105 12th Avenue N</street><city>Plymouth, MN 55447</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919512274" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>TOBIAS PETER</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919515143" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>TOBIAS, PETER</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919024394" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>TOBIAS, PETER</last-name><address><street>10761 Smetana Road</street><city>Minnetonka, MN 55343</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919522174" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>PETERSON ALEX L</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919503876" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>PETERSON, ALEX L.</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919024397" load-source="patent-office" sequence="3" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>PETERSON, ALEX L.</last-name><address><street>575 N. 4th Street</street><city>Platteville, WI 53818</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919529449" load-source="docdb" sequence="4" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>YANG WEI</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919508436" load-source="docdb" sequence="4" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>YANG, WEI</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919024395" load-source="patent-office" sequence="4" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>YANG, WEI</last-name><address><street>3812 Oak Road</street><city>Minnetonka, MN 55345</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919024399" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Honeywell International Inc.</last-name><iid>100141088</iid><address><street>101 Columbia Road</street><city>Morristown, NJ 07960</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919024398" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Buckley, Guy Julian</last-name><iid>100026757</iid><address><street>Patent Outsourcing Limited 1 King Street</street><city>Bakewell Derbyshire DE45 1DZ</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549895704" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549925179" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549895709" load-source="docdb">GB</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63961134" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001">Background</heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The invention relates to gas sensors, and particularly to testing and calibration of sensors.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="WO9004174A"><text>WO 90/04174</text></patcit> discloses a system for calibrating gas sensors including a plurality of gas-filled packets attached to a strip. A gas sensor is calibrated by releasing gas from one of the gas-filled packets in a test chamber while the gas-filled packet is brought in close contact with the gas sensor.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">In <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="US3740195A"><text>US 3740195</text></patcit>, release of calibration gas is done by evaporating solid material attached to a strip in a form of a spool.</p><heading id="h0002">Summary</heading><p id="p0004" num="0004">The present invention provides a system as defined in claim 1.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">The system may include the features of any one or more of dependent claims 2 to 4.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">The invention also provides a method as defined in claim 5.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">The method may include the features of claim 6.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">The invention is a mechanism that provides a stored amount of gas released into a defined volume of air. The gas and air mixture may be transported to a gas sensor for testing and/or calibration of the gas sensor.</p><heading id="h0003">Brief Description of the Drawing</heading><p id="p0009" num="0009"><ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> is a diagram of a storage unit for holding a defined amount of gas for sensor testing;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref> is a diagram of an overall mechanism for gas sensor testing;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3</figref> is a diagram showing a gas transport from a source to a gas sensor;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 4</figref> is a diagram of a thermal transport for gas from a source to a gas sensor; and</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005">Figure 5</figref> is a diagram of an example pump transport for gas from a source to a gas sensor.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0004">Description</heading><!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --><p id="p0010" num="0010">Gas sensors should be functionally tested and calibrated periodically. In some places, functional testing and some calibration may be a requirement for sensors, for example, personnel sensor badges in a facility where a potential for a presence of a harmful gas exists.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">A mechanism that is capable of providing multiple gases in one run for health determination and, in some instances, for calibration of one or more sensors is desired. The present invention may provide a mixture of test gases in air, and to check and also calibrate sensors for CO, H<sub>2</sub>S, combustible gases, and other gases.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">The gases of significant interest may include CO, CH<sub>4</sub>, and H<sub>2</sub>S. These three gases should not react with each other at ambient conditions. The three gases may be put together or mixed for incorporation and sealed inside of a blister pack. The pack may be made of low permeability plastics or their metalized derivatives. These blisters may be punctured open at one per run to test and calibrate a sensor module. A number of blister packs may be made and stored in the form of a strip and wound into a roll. Single blisters may be rolled off and punched or punctured open in a manner similar to a way that a cap gun pops small explosive-like and noisy caps. To assure reproducible gas pulses to the sensors, a release of the gases may be released into a fixed amount or volume of air. Then this volume of air, mixed with a determined or fixed amount of released gases, may be transported as a<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> particular air-gas mixture to a gas sensitive area of one or more sensors.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">Each single blister pack may be sealed or bonded with a cold working aluminum onto aluminum (for a good seal) or with an adhesive having a long diffusion length. A provision for transport of the gases to the sensors may also be provided.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">A generation or providing of gases for checking gas sensors may be effected electrochemically, thermally, or in some other manner. An illustrative example here may include a bubble foil, blister, or similar enclosure for holding and providing the gas. Gas is not necessarily generated but may be stored in a form that makes a release of the gas easy and reproducible.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">The present system may provide an alternative to gas generation. Current bump tests may be performed with a gas mixture from a tank (2.5 percent of CH<sub>4</sub>, 100ppm CO, 40ppm H<sub>2</sub>S, 15 percent of O<sub>2</sub>). One may provide for a similar gas mixture from a small unit. To fill 1mL of air with 1 percent of CH4, 100ppm CO, and 40ppm H<sub>2</sub>S, one may need a volume of 10uL of CH<sub>4</sub>.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">An approach of the present system may include the following items. First, one may make long band of bubble foil with bubbles of about 20uL out of aluminized polymer like Mylar, and fill them with a gas mixture without overpressure. Second, one may roll the band of bubbles onto a cylinder and pull off one bubble at a time. Third, for each bump test, one may puncture one bubble with a "hammer", like a cap gun does<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> when it generates a shooting sound from a roll, with chemicals. Fourth, one may let the gas mix with 2mL of air in an enclosed volume, and pump air through the volume. Fifth, one may pump the gas mixture over the sensors.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">A roll for 800 2mL-pulses could have a width of about one inch and a diameter of about two inches, which does not seem prohibitively large for fixed sensors. Bubble foil appears to be the easiest approach for fixed sensors. This approach may be used for testing portable sensors such as those implemented in personal badges.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">An alternative to gas generation may include some of the following items. <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> shows a blister pack or bubble foil 10. The bubble foil 10 may have bubbles 13 made out of aluminum foil 11 for a base and have aluminum or an aluminized polymer (e.g., Mylar) 12 for the bubble side. The aluminum foil 11 and the aluminum or aluminized polymer 12 may be joined and sealed by heat or ultrasound at a border 14 of the bubble to contain a gas 15. The bubble 13 may be filled with a desired gas or gases 15 before or after the sealing of the border 14. A design of the bubble or blister may be one among other approaches, packets or packages for keeping or storing gases until needed for testing and/or calibration of sensors.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">As indicated in <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref>, the foil 10 may be rolled up into a coil 16 and installed in a mechanism or source 20 on a coil or spool holder 17. The foil may be fed from coil 16 through a container 21 via slots 18 and 19, respectively. The<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> slots 18 and 19 are such so as to provide somewhat air tight integrity to container 21 with the foil 10 moving through the slots. Roller 24 may guide the foil 10 through slot 18. Roller 25 may guide a punctured foil 10 out of slot 19 to be wound as a coil 26 on a wind-up spool 26. Container 21 may have an input port 22 and an output port 23 for air to enter and for a gas air mixture to exit, respectively.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">For each bump test, one bubble 13 may be punctured and emptied into a defined volume 28 of container 21. There may be a plate 29 situated to keep foil 14 flat against an inside surface 31 of container 21. A device 32 may have a pointed object 33 attached and facing plate 29. Device 32 may be rotated about a hinge or anchor 34 towards the plate 29. During this rotation, pointed object 33 may puncture a bubble 13 formed by foil 12, or other material, by going through a hole 35 of plate 29 as the bubble passes by the hole. During this puncture of bubble 13, a certain or defined amount of a particular gas 15 may be released into the chamber 28. Upon the release of the gas, air may be pumped through port 22, for instance with an air mover 45, into the volume 28 and the certain or defined volume of air with the bubble 13 of gas 15 may be pushed out of volume 28 through port 23 to one or more gas sensors 30 to be tested (e.g., a health check) and/or calibrated.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">Permeability and chemical resistance of the bubble 13 may be noted for preservation of the gas 15. For instance, an<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> all-metal enclosure should keep CH<sub>4</sub> with traces of CO and H<sub>2</sub>S inside each bubble 13. A desired permeability of the material containing the bubble or blister 13 may about 10<sup>-15</sup>/cm<sup>2</sup>. Aluminum may be reported to be stable in conjunction with H<sub>2</sub>S. However, a question is whether the aluminum may deplete some of the H<sub>2</sub>S. Depending on layout and circumstances of the setup and testing, the answer may be no. However, if the answer is assumed to be yes, H<sub>2</sub>S might be generated separately and/or provided outside of bubble 13. Or bubble 13 may be made with other materials. One may further note whether H<sub>2</sub>S is safe and compatible, and whether H<sub>2</sub>S is sufficiently inexpensive for use with the present system in testing and/or calibration of sensors. The answer may depend on an application of the system or source 20.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">A gas transport 37 from a gas source 20 to a sensor 30 may be noted in <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3</figref>. Fixed and portable sensors may require different approaches. For fixed gas sensors, there may be transport of gases 15 through or from the ambient 36 to the sensor 30 by diffusion and/or convection. There may be some space available and full automatization may be desired. For portable gas sensors, transport of gases 15 from the ambient 36 to the sensor may often be effected by pumping. Space may be at a premium and human action possible or desirable for effecting transport.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">A flow design for fixed gas sensors might include reproducible gas pulses by an active transport, as diffusion<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> may appear unacceptably slow and convection be unpredictable. Heat convection for gas transport 38 is shown by a diagram of a setup in <figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 4</figref>. A heating element 39 may be placed proximate to the output port of gas source 20 to heat the gas 15 which will rise to follow the path of the gas transport 38 of the ambient 36. The gas 15 may eventually reach gas sensor 30 to be sensed. Heat convection appears easy but not necessarily optimal for reproducibility.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">A pumping of a gas pulse may result in the highest reproducibility for calibration. For example, a pump 41 may be included in a fixed gas sensor arrangement as shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">Figure 5</figref>. Pump 41 may take air from the ambient 36 and push the air into a gas container 42 via a channel 43. Container 42 may be for receiving gas 15 from a gas source 20. Gas 15 may be pushed from container 42 by air from pump 41 through a channel 44 to a gas sensor 30 for detection. A fixed volume of air may be determined and pumped according to a volume or amount of gas released into container 42. The overall system with the pump may relax space requirements for a gas source 20 (which could fit in a flameproof housing for safety purposes). Further, the present pump system may be economical if the pump 41 is inexpensive. An example of such a pump may be a Mesopump<sup>™</sup> produced in a 10,000 unit volume (by a company like Honeywell). A number of mesopump units may be connected together for increased capacity. A mesopump arrangement may have a capacity to provide 12 mL/min at about 40 uW. It may<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> have a size of about 10 x 10 x 2 mm and operate at a temperature up to 100°C. The pump may provide a 3 kPa pressure difference or differential.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">A flow design may be provided for portable gas sensors. The design may be more complex for portables than for fixed sensors. Reproducible gas pulses may be provided by an active transport in a portable design. It may be noted that dominant gases could include combustibles, H<sub>2</sub>S, and the like. An existing pump 41 may be utilized for gas transport from a gas source 20. Or, one may let a manual operator press a button that drives pumping (which may be difficult in that the sensor or sensors should feel the gas). An integration of a source 20 may need a stronger interaction with the design of a sensor system. One may instead begin with fixed sensors rather than portable sensors, and make frequent visits to them unnecessary.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56986142" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Test- und Kalibrierungssystem, das Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>ein Gehäuse (21), das Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>eine Kammer (28), die eine festgelegte Luftmenge enthält;</claim-text>
<claim-text>mehrere gasgefüllte Pakete (13), die eine festgelegte Gasmenge (15) enthalten; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Öffner (32, 33) zum Freisetzen von Gas (15) von einem Paket (13) der mehreren gasgefüllten Pakete (13) in die Kammer (28); und</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei:
<claim-text>die mehreren gasgefüllten Pakete an einem Band (10) befestigt sind, das in die Kammer führt; und <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b>:
<claim-text>das sich Band (10) in Form einer Rolle auf einer Spule befindet, die in die Kammer (28) eingeführt wird;</claim-text>
<claim-text>die festgelegten Gasmengen (15) und die festgelegte Luftmenge in der Kammer (28)</claim-text>
<claim-text>zu einem Luft-Gas-Gemisch in einem bestimmten Verhältnis von Gas (15) zu Luft werden; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>das bestimmte Verhältnis von Gas (15) zu Luft zum Testen und/oder Kalibrieren von einem oder mehreren Gassensoren (30) dient.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>System nach Anspruch 1, das ferner einen Luftbeweger (41, 45) umfasst, der mit einer Eingangsöffnung (22) verbunden ist; und<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> -->wobei:
<claim-text>der Luftbeweger (41, 45) Luft in die Kammer (28) liefert; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Freisetzen des Gases (15) von einem Paket (13) Gas (15) zum Mischen mit der Luft in der Kammer (28) zu einem Luft-Gas-Gemisch liefert.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>System nach Anspruch 1, wobei<br/>
die mehreren Pakete (13) ein oder mehrere Gase (15) enthalten;<br/>
die Kammer (28) ein definiertes Volumen besitzt;<br/>
der Öffner (32, 33) eine definierte Menge von einem oder mehreren Gasen (15) von einem Paket (13) der mehreren Pakete (13) in das definierte Volumen freisetzt; und<br/>
die Kammer (28) eine Ausgangsöffnung (23) zum Liefern des Luft-Gas-Gemisches besitzt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>System nach Anspruch 3, das ferner Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>einen Luftbeweger (41, 45), der mit einer Eingangsöffnung (22) der Kammer (28) verbunden ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei der Luftbeweger (41, 45) ein Luftvolumen liefert, das ungefähr gleich dem definierten Volumen für die Mischung mit der definierten Menge des einen oder der mehreren Gase (15), die von einem Paket (13) der mehreren Pakete (13) freigesetzt werden, ist, um das Luft-Gas-Gemisch zu ergeben.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Verfahren zum Testen von Gassensoren, das Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>Bereitstellen von mehreren gasgefüllten Paketen (13), wobei jedes gasgefüllte Paket (13) eine definierte Menge von einem oder mehreren Gasen (15) enthält;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Freisetzen des einen oder der mehreren Gase (15) von einem gasgefüllten Paket (13) in eine Kammer (28) mit einer definierten Luftmenge, resultierend in einem Luft-Gas-Gemisch mit einem definierten Verhältnis (15)<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> von Gas zu Luft in der Kammer (28); und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Bewegen des Luft-Gas-Gemischs von der Kammer (28) zu einem Gassensor (30) zum Testen und/oder Kalibrieren des Gassensors (30); und</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei:
<claim-text>die sich mehreren gasgefüllten Pakete (13) auf einem Band (10) befinden, das in die Kammer (28) einführbar ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>das Band (10) sich in Form einer Rolle auf einer Spule befindet, die in die Kammer (28) eingeführt wird.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 5, wobei das Freisetzen des einen oder der mehreren Gase (15) durch einen Mechanismus (32, 33) ausgeführt wird, der in ein gasgefülltes Paket (13) sticht.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56986143" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A test and calibration system comprising:
<claim-text>a housing (21) comprising:
<claim-text>a chamber (28) containing a fixed amount of air;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of gas-filled packets (13) containing a fixed amount of gas (15); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an opener (32, 33) for releasing gas (15) from a packet (13) of the plurality of gas-filled packets (13), into the chamber (28); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein:
<claim-text>the plurality of gas-filled packets is attached to a strip (10) that goes into the chamber; and <b>characterised in that</b>:</claim-text>
<claim-text>the strip (10) is in a form of a roll on a spool which is fed into the chamber (28);</claim-text>
<claim-text>the fixed amounts of gas (15) and fixed amount of air in the chamber (28) become an air-gas mixture having a determined ratio of gas (15) to air; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the determined ratio of gas (15) to air is for testing and/or calibrating one or more gas sensors (30).</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The system of claim 1, further comprising an air mover (41, 45) connected to an input port (22); and<br/>
wherein:
<claim-text>the air mover (41, 45) provides air into the chamber (28); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a releasing of gas (15) from a packet (13) provides gas (15) to be mixed with the air in the chamber (28) as an air-gas mixture.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The system of claim 1, wherein<br/>
the plurality of packets (13) contain one or more gases (15);<br/>
the chamber (28) has a defined volume;<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> -->the opener (32, 33) releases a defined amount of one or more gases (15) from a packet (13) of the plurality of packets (13) into the defined volume; and<br/>
wherein the chamber (28) has an output port (23) for providing the air-gas mixture.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The system of claim 3, further comprising:
<claim-text>an air mover (41, 45) connected to an input port (22) of the chamber (28); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the air mover (41, 45) provides a volume of air approximately equivalent to the defined volume for mixture with the defined amount of one or more gases (15) released from a packet (13) of the plurality of packets (13) to result in the air-gas mixture.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>A method for testing gas sensors comprising:
<claim-text>providing a plurality of gas-filled packets (13) wherein each gas-filled packet (13) contains a defined amount of one or more gases (15);</claim-text>
<claim-text>releasing the one or more gases (15) from a gas-filled packet (13) in a chamber (28) having a defined amount of air resulting in an air-gas mixture having a defined ratio of gas (15) to air in the chamber (28); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>moving the air-gas mixture from the chamber (28) to a gas sensor (30) for testing and/or calibration of the gas sensor (30); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein:
<claim-text>the plurality of gas-filled packets (13) is on a strip (10) feed-able into the chamber (28); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the strip (10) is in a form of a roll on a spool which is fed into the chamber (28).</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The method of claim 5, wherein the releasing of one or more gases (15) is effected by a mechanism (32, 33) which punctures a gas-filled packet (13).</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56986144" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Système de test et d'étalonnage comprenant :
<claim-text>un boîtier (21) comprenant :
<claim-text>une chambre (28) contenant une quantité d'air fixe ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une pluralité de paquets (13) remplis de gaz contenant une quantité de gaz fixe (15) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un dispositif d'ouverture (32, 33) pour libérer le gaz (15) d'un paquet (13) de la pluralité de paquets remplis de gaz (13) dans la chambre (28) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>et</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel</claim-text>
<claim-text>la pluralité de paquets remplis de gaz est attachée à une bande (10) qui entre dans la chambre ; et <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> :</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>la bande (10) se présente sous forme de rouleau sur une bobine qui est acheminée dans la chambre (28) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>les quantités de gaz fixes (15) et la quantité d'air fixe dans la chambre (28) devenant un mélange air-gaz ayant un rapport déterminé de gaz (15) à air ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>le rapport déterminé de gaz (15) à air étant utilisé pour tester et/ou étalonner un ou plusieurs capteurs de gaz (30).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Système selon la revendication 1, comprenant en outre un dispositif pour déplacer l'air (41, 45) connecté à un orifice d'entrée (22) ; et<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> -->dans lequel :
<claim-text>le dispositif pour déplacer l'air (41, 45) achemine de l'air dans la chambre (28) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>la libération de gaz (15) par un paquet (13) fournit du gaz (15) devant être mélangé avec l'air dans la chambre (28) sous forme de mélange air-gaz.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Système selon la revendication 1, dans lequel la pluralité de paquets (13) contient un ou plusieurs gaz (15) ;<br/>
la chambre (28) a un volume défini ;<br/>
le dispositif d'ouverture (32, 33) libère une quantité définie d'un ou de plusieurs gaz (15) depuis un paquet (13) de la pluralité de paquets (13) dans le volume défini ; et<br/>
dans lequel la chambre (28) a un orifice de sortie (23) pour fournir le mélange air-gaz.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Système selon la revendication 3, comprenant en outre :
<claim-text>un dispositif pour déplacer l'air (41, 45) connecté à un orifice d'entrée (22) de la chambre (28) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel le dispositif pour déplacer l'air (41, 45) fournit un volume d'air approximativement équivalent au volume défini pour le mélange avec la quantité définie d'un ou de plusieurs gaz (15) libérés par un paquet (13) de la pluralité de paquets (13) pour fournir le mélange air-gaz.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Procédé pour tester des capteurs de gaz, comprenant :
<claim-text>la fourniture d'une pluralité de paquets remplis de gaz (13), chaque paquet rempli de gaz (13) contenant une quantité définie d'un ou de plusieurs gaz (15) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>la libération du ou des gaz (15) depuis un paquet rempli de gaz (13) dans une chambre (28) ayant une<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> quantité définie d'air pour donner un mélange air-gaz ayant un rapport défini de gaz (15) à air dans la chambre (28) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>le déplacement du mélange air-gaz depuis la chambre (28) jusqu'à un capteur de gaz (30) pour tester et/ou étalonner le capteur de gaz (30) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel :
<claim-text>la pluralité de paquets remplis de gaz (13) est sur une bande (10) pouvant être acheminée dans la chambre (28) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>la bande (10) se présente sous la forme d'un rouleau sur une bobine qui est acheminée dans la chambre (28).</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 5, dans lequel la libération d'un ou de plusieurs gaz (15) est effectuée par un mécanisme (32, 33) qui perce un paquet rempli de gaz (13).</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16672366" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="122" he="148" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="147" he="172" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="110" he="116" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --><figure id="f0004" num="4"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="113" he="76" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --><figure id="f0005" num="5"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="110" he="136" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
