<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2160624-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2160624" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="39563592" file-reference-id="311124" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146588268" ucid="EP-2160624-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2160624</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-08731702-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154850460" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>08731702</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20080307</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140557558" ucid="US-2008056258-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>2008056258</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20080307</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140553597" ucid="US-69266507-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>69266507</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20070328</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130723</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989325128" load-source="ipcr">G01S  19/42        20100101AFI20130621BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989629424" load-source="ipcr">G01S  19/50        20100101AFI20100101RMUS        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989633292" load-source="ipcr">G01S   5/14        20060101A I20100710RMEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989629044" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G01S  19/42        20130101 FI20130621BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132369437" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">GEOFENCING UND ROUTENFESTHALTUNG IN EINEM GLOBALEN NAVIGATIONSSYSTEM MIT SIGNALEN VON WENIGER ALS DREI SATELLITEN</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132369438" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">GEOFENCING AND ROUTE ADHERENCE IN GLOBAL POSITIONING SYSTEM WITH SIGNALS FROM FEWER THAN THREE SATELLITES</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132369439" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">GARDIENNAGE VIRTUEL ET ADHÉSION À UN ITINÉRAIRE DANS UN SYSTÈME DE POSITIONNEMENT GLOBAL À L'AIDE DE SIGNAUX PROVENANT DE MOINS DE TROIS SATELLITES</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919538155" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>2201028 ONTARIO INC</last-name><address><country>CA</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919544373" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>2201028 ONTARIO INC.</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919542049" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>VERECHTCHIAGINE DIMITRI</last-name><address><country>CA</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919525256" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>VERECHTCHIAGINE, DIMITRI</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919022329" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>VERECHTCHIAGINE, DIMITRI</last-name><address><street>3100 Carling Avenue Apt. 613</street><city>Ottawa, Ontario</city><country>CA</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919022331" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>2201028 Ontario Inc.</last-name><iid>101323892</iid><address><street>368-750 Palladium Drive</street><city>Ottawa, Ontario K2V 2C7</city><country>CA</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919022330" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Talbot-Ponsonby, Daniel Frederick</last-name><iid>100048624</iid><address><street>Marks &amp; Clerk LLP Fletcher House Heatley Road The Oxford Science Park</street><city>Oxford OX4 4GE</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="US-2008056258-W"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2008056258</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20080307</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2008121494-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2008121494</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20081009</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549876411" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549871851" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549783418" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549923384" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549868761" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549876412" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549871852" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549868766" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549868767" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549800939" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549783419" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549783420" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549871853" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549868768" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549871858" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549876413" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549923385" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549868769" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549783429" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549868774" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549784237" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549876414" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549784238" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549784239" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549891249" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549871859" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549783430" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549784240" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549923386" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549871860" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549784245" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549923387" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549783431" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549868775" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63960693" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001"><b><u>Field of the Invention</u></b></heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention is directed to a system, method and article of manufacture for PS location and more particularly to such a system, method and article of manufacture in which a minimum distance from a GPS receiver to a nearby reference location is determined when there are fewer than three GPS satellites in view.</p><heading id="h0002"><b><u>Description of Related Art</u></b></heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">One of the major problems in the use of satellite navigation is blockage of the view of GPS satellites. The blockage is often only partial, with only a few satellites visible and the rest being blocked by trees, buildings and other obstacles. To obtain a GPS fix, a GPS receiver without an on-board atomic clock generally needs to have at least 4 satellites in view (this is called a 3D GPS fix.). With an assumed receiver altitude (typically from a previous 3 D fix), only 3 satellites are necessary (so called 2D fix.)</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">With only two satellites in view, it is impossible to determine the receiver's current location. However, a geometrical surface of the possible user locations, or the Solution Surface, can be determined. In general, knowing the Solution Surface is not very useful, since it is not a bounded area.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US20040021567A"><text>US patent application publication no. 2004/0021567</text></patcit> describes an apparatus for triggering an alarm when the receiver exceeds a certain distance from a reference<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> location. This patent depends on an ability to compute the position of the receiver from available satellite signals.</p><heading id="h0003"><b><u>Summary of the Invention</u></b></heading><p id="p0005" num="0005">A need therefore exists in the art to provide useful information in situations in which fewer than three satellites are in view.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">It is therefore an object of the invention to be able to derive such information.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">According to the present invention there is provided a method of geofencing or monitoring route adherence using no more than two global positioning satellites (SV<sub>1</sub>, SV<sub>2</sub>) of a global positioning system, the method comprising: (a) receiving in a global positioning system receiver a global positioning system signal from no more than two of the global positioning satellites (SV<sub>1</sub>, SV<sub>2</sub>); (b) computing, from the global positioning system signal(s) received in step (a), a solution surface (SS) containing a set of possible locations for the global positioning system receiver; and (c) determining the possible location (PUL) on the solution surface (SS) that is at the minimum distance to the reference location (Base Location); and (d) generating a departure event when the minimum distance exceeds a predetermined distance.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">Thus, embodiments of the present invention are directed to a technique in which, for a known reference (base) location (e.g. the receiver's location in the past, or some other position of interest), the distance from this location to the Solution Surface can be computed. That distance is equal to the minimum possible distance<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> between the base location and a current user position. In other words, that distance is how far from the base position the receiver is guaranteed to be.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">In a geofence application, the geofence anchor location is set to be the base location; comparing the distance from the anchor location to the Solution Surface with the geofence radius, we can generate a Departure Geofence Crossing Event.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">The route adherence algorithm is similar to the geofencing algorithm, except that the minimum-distance test is applied over a set of points or line segments defining a route.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">Given a reference (base) geographical location that is known to be relatively close to the current receiver's location compared to the distance to the satellites, the distance from this location to the solution surface can be computed, and that distance is the minimum possible distance from the base location to the current receiver's location. The present disclosure contains the formulae to compute that distance.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">In addition to covering the basic techniques for computing the distance from a base point of interest to the solution surface, some geofencing and route adherence applications are discussed and explored. Application of those algorithms would provide better availability of geofence monitoring and route adherence testing in limited GPS satellite visibility environments.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p><p id="p0013" num="0013">In other embodiments, an alternate derivation for the linearized solution space equation is shown, and a similar positioning technique with a single satellite and a high accuracy terminal clock is detailed.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">Throughout the present disclosure, the following terminology will be used:</p><p id="p0015" num="0015"><b>User</b> and <b>Receiver</b> are used interchangeably.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016"><b>Location</b> and <b>Position</b> are used interchangeably.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017"><b>ECEF -</b> Earth centered, Earth fixed coordinate system (e.g. WGS-84 or ITRF2000)</p><p id="p0018" num="0018"><b>Base Location -</b> A reference location the distance to which we are interested in.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019"><b>Geofence Anchor Position -</b> The geographical position where geofence monitored object is expected to be on average.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020"><b>User Coordinate Frame -</b> a coordinate system rotated so that the basis vectors point in cardinal directions (e.g. east, north and up) at the user or base location. The origin of the coordinate system does not need to be at the user or base location.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021"><b>Locally Horizontal Plane -</b> A horizontal plane in the user coordinate frame at the base location. This plane is parallel to the WGS-84 ellipsoid at the user location (tangent if the altitude is zero with respect to the WGS-84 ellipsoid).</p><p id="p0022" num="0022"><b>Solution Surface -</b> A geometrical surface of possible user positions obtained from the GPS equations for two satellites.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023"><b>Solution Plane -</b> A linearized approximation to the solution surface.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024"><b>Horizontal Solution Line -</b> The line formed by the intersection of the solution plane with the locally horizontal plane.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025"><b>Departure Geofence Crossing Event (DGCE) -</b> The event generated by a geofence software application indicating that a tracked object is moving outside of the circle with a given geofence radius.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">In addition, throughout the present disclosure, the following notation will be used:<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></p><p id="p0027" num="0027"><i><o>x</o><sub>S,i</sub></i> = [<i>x<sub>S,i</sub> y<sub>S,i</sub> z<sub>S,i</sub></i>] The <i>i</i>-th satellite position vector (typically but not necessarily in ECEF coordinates).</p><p id="p0028" num="0028"><i><o>x</o><sub>U</sub></i> = [<i>x<sub>U</sub> y<sub>U</sub> z<sub>U</sub></i>] The user's position vector (also typically in ECEF coordinates).</p><p id="p0029" num="0029"><i><o>r</o><sub>i</sub> = <o>x</o><sub>S,i</sub>-<o>x</o><sub>U</sub></i> The range vector from the user position to the <i>i</i>-th satellite.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030"><i><o>l</o><sub>i</sub></i> = <i><o>r</o><sub>i</sub></i>/|<i><o>r</o><sub>i</sub></i>| The line of sight vector from the user position to the <i>i</i>-th satellite position.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031"><i><o>x</o><sub>B</sub></i> The base position. This is often a previous user position but could be any location of interest in general.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032"><i><o>r</o><sub>i,B</sub></i> The range vector from base position to the <i>i</i>-th satellite.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033"><i><o>r</o><sub>B</sub></i> The line-of-sight vector from the base position to the <i>i</i>-th satellite position.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034"><i><o>δ</o><sub>U</sub> = <o>x</o><sub>U</sub> -<o>x</o><sub>B</sub></i> The displacement vector from the base position to the current user position.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035"><i>b<sub>U</sub></i> The clock bias of the receiver's clock.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036"><i>ρ<sub>i</sub></i> = <i>r<sub>i</sub></i>+<i>b<sub>U</sub></i> The pseudorange to the i-th satellite.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037"><i>N<sub>S</sub></i> The number of satellites used in computation.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038"><i>D<sub>(SPl,B)</sub></i> The distance from the base position to the Solution Plane.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039"><i>D<sub>(SLn,B)</sub></i> The distance from the base position to the Solution Line.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040"><i>λ</i><sub><i>S</i>1,2</sub> = ∠<o><i>l</i></o><sub>1</sub>,<o><i>l</i></o><sub>2</sub> The angle between the line-of-sight vectors of SV<sub>1</sub> and SV<sub>2</sub>.</p><p id="p0041" num="0041"><maths id="math0001" num=""><math display="inline"><msubsup><mi>λ</mi><msub><mi>S</mi><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>,</mo><mn>2</mn></mrow></msub><mi>min</mi></msubsup></math><img id="ib0001" file="imgb0001.tif" wi="9" he="8" img-content="math" img-format="tif" inline="yes"/></maths> The minimum angle between SV<sub>1</sub> and SV<sub>2</sub> allowing geofence monitoring.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042"><i>F<sub>conf</sub></i> The confidence factor used in the computation of <maths id="math0002" num=""><math display="inline"><msubsup><mi>λ</mi><msub><mi>S</mi><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>,</mo><mn>2</mn></mrow></msub><mi>min</mi></msubsup><mn>.</mn></math><img id="ib0002" file="imgb0002.tif" wi="10" he="9" img-content="math" img-format="tif" inline="yes"/></maths></p><p id="p0043" num="0043"><i>σ<sub>ρ</sub></i> The root-mean-square error of a pseudorange estimate.</p><p id="p0044" num="0044"><maths id="math0003" num=""><math display="inline"><msub><mi>σ</mi><msub><mi>ρ</mi><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>,</mo><mn>2</mn></mrow></msub></msub><mo>=</mo><msqrt><mn>2</mn></msqrt><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi>σ</mi><mi>ρ</mi></msub></math><img id="ib0003" file="imgb0003.tif" wi="26" he="9" img-content="math" img-format="tif" inline="yes"/></maths> The root-mean-square error of the pseudorange difference of <i>ρ</i><sub>2</sub>-<i>ρ</i><sub>1</sub>.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045"><i><o>n</o><sub>LHPl,B</sub></i> The unitary vector normal to the locally horizontal plane at the base location.<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></p><p id="p0046" num="0046">Δ<i>ρ = ρ</i><sub>2</sub> <i>- ρ</i><sub>1</sub> The pseudorange difference.</p><p id="p0047" num="0047">Δ<i>r<sub>B</sub></i> = <i>r</i><sub>2</sub><i><sub>,B</sub>-r</i><sub>1,<i>B</i></sub> The true range difference at the base location.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048"><i>λ</i><sub>(<i>SPl,LHPl</i>)</sub> The dihedral angle between the Solution Plane and the Locally Horizontal Plane.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p><heading id="h0004"><b><u>Brief Description of the Drawings</u></b></heading><p id="p0049" num="0049">Preferred embodiments of the invention will be set forth in detail with reference to the drawings, in which:
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figs. 1A and 1B</figref> are diagrams which show examples of a Solution Surface for a first preferred embodiment;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> is a diagram which shows the derivation of a solution line equation in a case in which the location of the receiver is assumed to be horizontally constrained;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> is a flow chart showing the computation of the minimum distance and its comparison to a given geofence radius;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4</figref> is a flow chart showing the computation of the minimum distance to one of a plurality of line segments in a route;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5</figref> is a block diagram showing an implementation of any of the preferred embodiments; and</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 6</figref> is a diagram which shows an example of a Solution Surface for another preferred embodiment.</li></ul><!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></p><heading id="h0005"><b><u>Detailed Description of the Preferred Embodiments</u></b></heading><p id="p0050" num="0050">Preferred embodiments of the invention will now be set forth in detail with reference to the drawings, in which like reference numerals refer to like elements throughout.</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">In a first preferred embodiment, the distance is determined to a user position on a plane in the case of two satellites and a GPS receiver with a standard clock. The basic GPS fix equation can be written as:<maths id="math0004" num="(E10)"><math display="block"><mfenced open="{" close="}" separators=""><msub><mi>ρ</mi><mi>i</mi></msub><mo>=</mo><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>i</mi></msub><mo>+</mo><msub><mi>b</mi><mi>U</mi></msub><mrow><mo>|</mo></mrow><mi>i</mi><mo>=</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>,</mo><mn>2</mn><mo>,</mo><mo>…</mo><mo>,</mo><msub><mi>N</mi><mi>S</mi></msub></mfenced></math><img id="ib0004" file="imgb0004.tif" wi="63" he="8" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> where<maths id="math0005" num="(E20)"><math display="block"><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>i</mi></msub><mo>=</mo><mfenced open="|" close="|" separators=""><msub><mover><mi>x</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mrow><mi>S</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>i</mi></mrow></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mover><mi>x</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mi>U</mi></msub></mfenced><mo>=</mo><msqrt><mfenced separators=""><msub><mover><mi>x</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mrow><mi>S</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>i</mi></mrow></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mover><mi>x</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mi>U</mi></msub></mfenced><mo>•</mo><mfenced separators=""><msub><mover><mi>x</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mrow><mi>S</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>i</mi></mrow></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mover><mi>x</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mi>U</mi></msub></mfenced></msqrt></math><img id="ib0005" file="imgb0005.tif" wi="89" he="10" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0052" num="0052">In Cartesian coordinates the equations in (E10) will take the following form:<maths id="math0006" num="(E30)"><math display="block"><msub><mi>ρ</mi><mi>i</mi></msub><mo>=</mo><msqrt><msup><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi>x</mi><mrow><mi>S</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>i</mi></mrow></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>x</mi><mi>U</mi></msub></mfenced><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>+</mo><msup><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi>y</mi><mrow><mi>S</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>i</mi></mrow></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>y</mi><mi>U</mi></msub></mfenced><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>+</mo><msup><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi>z</mi><mrow><mi>S</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>i</mi></mrow></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>z</mi><mi>U</mi></msub></mfenced><mn>2</mn></msup></msqrt><mo>+</mo><msub><mi>b</mi><mi>U</mi></msub></math><img id="ib0006" file="imgb0006.tif" wi="102" he="9" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0053" num="0053">Here <i>ρ<sub>i</sub></i> are known measurements, <i><o>x</o><sub>S,i</sub></i> are computed from GPS navigation and observation data values, and <i><o>x</o><sub>U</sub></i> and <i>b<sub>U</sub></i> are unknowns.</p><p id="p0054" num="0054">With two satellites in view, equation (E30) is a pair of dependent equations. By equating clock biases <i>b<sub>U</sub></i> in (E30) for the two satellites we obtain:<maths id="math0007" num="(E40)"><math display="block"><mtable columnalign="left"><mtr><mtd><msub><mi>ρ</mi><mn>1</mn></msub><mo>-</mo><msqrt><msup><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi>x</mi><mrow><mi>S</mi><mo>,</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>x</mi><mi>U</mi></msub></mfenced><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>+</mo><msup><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi>y</mi><mrow><mi>S</mi><mo>,</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>y</mi><mi>U</mi></msub></mfenced><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>+</mo><msup><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi>z</mi><mrow><mi>S</mi><mo>,</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>z</mi><mi>U</mi></msub></mfenced><mn>2</mn></msup></msqrt><mo>=</mo></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><msub><mi>ρ</mi><mn>2</mn></msub><mo>-</mo><msqrt><msup><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi>x</mi><mrow><mi>S</mi><mo>,</mo><mn>2</mn></mrow></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>x</mi><mi>U</mi></msub></mfenced><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>+</mo><msup><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi>y</mi><mrow><mi>S</mi><mo>,</mo><mn>2</mn></mrow></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>y</mi><mi>U</mi></msub></mfenced><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>+</mo><msup><mfenced separators=""><msubsup><mi>z</mi><mrow><mi>S</mi><mo>,</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mfenced><mn>2</mn></mfenced></msubsup><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>z</mi><mi>U</mi></msub></mfenced><mn>2</mn></msup></msqrt></mtd></mtr></mtable></math><img id="ib0007" file="imgb0007.tif" wi="102" he="19" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0055" num="0055">Equation (E40) thus defines the Solution Surface.</p><p id="p0056" num="0056">The two dimensional profile of this surface (intersection with a plane) is a curve. In a coordinate system where both satellites and the receiver lie in the <i>XY</i> plane we can write the profile curve equation as:<maths id="math0008" num="(E50)"><math display="block"><msub><mi>ρ</mi><mn>1</mn></msub><mo>-</mo><msqrt><msup><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi>x</mi><mrow><mi>S</mi><mo>,</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>x</mi><mi>U</mi></msub></mfenced><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>+</mo><msup><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi>y</mi><mrow><mi>S</mi><mo>,</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>y</mi><mi>U</mi></msub></mfenced><mn>2</mn></msup></msqrt><mo>=</mo><msub><mi>ρ</mi><mn>2</mn></msub><mo>-</mo><msqrt><msup><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi>x</mi><mrow><mi>S</mi><mo>,</mo><mn>2</mn></mrow></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>x</mi><mi>U</mi></msub></mfenced><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>+</mo><msup><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi>y</mi><mrow><mi>S</mi><mo>,</mo><mn>2</mn></mrow></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>y</mi><mi>U</mi></msub></mfenced><mn>2</mn></msup></msqrt></math><img id="ib0008" file="imgb0008.tif" wi="128" he="10" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths><!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --></p><p id="p0057" num="0057">We therefore have an implicit function <i>y<sub>u</sub></i> = <i>f</i>(<i>x<sub>u</sub></i>) that can be plotted to gain some intuitive understanding of the Solution Surface's behaviour.</p><p id="p0058" num="0058"><figref idrefs="f0001">Figs. 1A and 1B</figref> show examples of the Solution Surface profile curves for this case. In both of those figures, there are only two satellites visible, namely <i>SV</i><sub>1</sub> and <i>SV</i><sub>2</sub>. The actual user's position <i>AUP</i> on the earth's surface <i>ES</i> cannot be determined unequivocally. However, a solution surface <i>SS</i> can be determined as disclosed above. Further, if the actual user's position <i>AUP</i> is known to be on the earth's surface <i>ES,</i> as opposed to being at some other location such as an airplane over the earth's surface, the intersection of the solution surface <i>SS</i> and the earth's surface <i>ES</i> is a curve on which the actual user's position <i>AUP</i> must be located.</p><p id="p0059" num="0059">To derive the solution plane equation, we linearize equations (E10) around the base location <i><o>x</o><sub>B</sub></i>.<maths id="math0009" num=""><math display="block"><mtable columnalign="left"><mtr><mtd><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>i</mi></msub><mo>=</mo><mfenced open="|" close="|" separators=""><msub><mover><mi>x</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mrow><mi>S</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>i</mi></mrow></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mover><mi>x</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mi>U</mi></msub></mfenced><mo>=</mo><mfenced open="|" close="|" separators=""><msub><mover><mi>x</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mrow><mi>S</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>i</mi></mrow></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mover><mi>x</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mi>B</mi></msub><mo>+</mo><msub><mover><mi>δ</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mi>U</mi></msub></mfenced><mo>=</mo><mfenced open="|" close="|" separators=""><msub><mover><mi>r</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mrow><mi>i</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub><mo>+</mo><msub><mover><mi>δ</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mi>U</mi></msub></mfenced><mo>=</mo></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><msqrt><msubsup><mi>r</mi><mrow><mi>i</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow><mn>2</mn></msubsup><mo>+</mo><mn>2</mn><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi>r</mi><mrow><mi>i</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mover><mi>δ</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mi>U</mi></msub><mo>•</mo><msub><mover><mi>l</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mrow><mi>i</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub><mo>+</mo><msubsup><mi>δ</mi><mi>U</mi><mn>2</mn></msubsup></msqrt><mo>=</mo><msubsup><mi>r</mi><mrow><mi>i</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow><mfenced><mi>i</mi></mfenced></msubsup><mo>⁢</mo><msqrt><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>2</mn><mo>⁢</mo><mfrac><msub><mover><mi>δ</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mi>U</mi></msub><msub><mi>r</mi><mrow><mi>i</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub></mfrac><mo>•</mo><msub><mover><mi>l</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mrow><mi>i</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub><mo>+</mo><msup><mfenced><mfrac><msub><mi>δ</mi><mi>U</mi></msub><msub><mi>r</mi><mrow><mi>i</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub></mfrac></mfenced><mn>2</mn></msup></msqrt></mtd></mtr></mtable></math><img id="ib0009" file="imgb0009.tif" wi="92" he="26" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0060" num="0060">For linearization, the distance to a satellite is assumed to be much greater than the displacement from the base location:<maths id="math0010" num=""><math display="block"><mfrac><mfenced open="|" close="|"><msub><mi>δ</mi><mi>U</mi></msub></mfenced><mfenced open="|" close="|"><msub><mi>r</mi><mrow><mi>i</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub></mfenced></mfrac><mo>≪</mo><mn>1</mn></math><img id="ib0010" file="imgb0010.tif" wi="17" he="15" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0061" num="0061">We can then use the Taylor series approximation for the square root function:<maths id="math0011" num=""><math display="block"><msqrt><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mi>α</mi></msqrt><mo>≈</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>+</mo><mn>1</mn><mo>/</mo><mn>2</mn><mo>⁢</mo><mi>α</mi><mo>;</mo><mfenced open="|" close="|"><mi>α</mi></mfenced><mo>≪</mo><mn>1</mn></math><img id="ib0011" file="imgb0011.tif" wi="47" he="8" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> so<maths id="math0012" num=""><math display="block"><msub><mi>ρ</mi><mi>i</mi></msub><mo>≈</mo><msub><mi>r</mi><mrow><mi>i</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub><mo>+</mo><msub><mover><mi>δ</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mi>U</mi></msub><mo>•</mo><msub><mover><mi>l</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mrow><mi>i</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub></math><img id="ib0012" file="imgb0012.tif" wi="31" he="8" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0062" num="0062">And<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> <maths id="math0013" num="(E60)"><math display="block"><msub><mi>ρ</mi><mi>i</mi></msub><mo>≈</mo><msub><mi>r</mi><mrow><mi>i</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub><mo>+</mo><msub><mover><mi>δ</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mi>U</mi></msub><mo>•</mo><msub><mover><mi>l</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mrow><mi>i</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub><mo>+</mo><msub><mi>b</mi><mi>U</mi></msub></math><img id="ib0013" file="imgb0013.tif" wi="63" he="8" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0063" num="0063">In the two-satellite case this is a pair of equations. Eliminating the clock bias by equating it in the two equations for SV<sub>1</sub> and SV<sub>2</sub> in (E60) we obtain:<maths id="math0014" num=""><math display="block"><msub><mi>ρ</mi><mn>1</mn></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>r</mi><mn>1</mn></msub><mo>=</mo><msub><mi>ρ</mi><mn>2</mn></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>r</mi><mn>2</mn></msub></math><img id="ib0014" file="imgb0014.tif" wi="34" he="8" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths><maths id="math0015" num=""><math display="block"><mrow><msub><mrow><mi>ρ</mi></mrow><mrow><mn>1</mn></mrow></msub><mo>-</mo><mfenced separators=""><msub><mrow><mi>r</mi></mrow><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub><mo>+</mo><msub><mrow><mover><mrow><mi>δ</mi></mrow><mrow><mo>→</mo></mrow></mover></mrow><mrow><mi>U</mi></mrow></msub><mo>•</mo><msub><mrow><mover><mrow><mi>l</mi></mrow><mrow><mo>→</mo></mrow></mover></mrow><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub></mfenced><mo>=</mo><msub><mrow><mi>ρ</mi></mrow><mrow><mn>2</mn></mrow></msub><mo>-</mo><mfenced separators=""><msub><mrow><mi>r</mi></mrow><mrow><mn>2</mn><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub><mo>+</mo><msub><mrow><mover><mrow><mi>δ</mi></mrow><mrow><mo>→</mo></mrow></mover></mrow><mrow><mi>U</mi></mrow></msub><mo>•</mo><msub><mrow><mover><mrow><mi>l</mi></mrow><mrow><mo>→</mo></mrow></mover></mrow><mrow><mn>2</mn><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub></mfenced></mrow></math><img id="ib0015" file="imgb0015.tif" wi="73" he="11" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths><maths id="math0016" num=""><math display="block"><msub><mover><mi>δ</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mi>U</mi></msub><mo>•</mo><mfenced separators=""><msub><mover><mi>l</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mrow><mn>2</mn><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mover><mi>l</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub></mfenced><mo>=</mo><msub><mover><mi>δ</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mi>U</mi></msub><mo>•</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mover><mi>δ</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mi>B</mi></msub><mo>=</mo><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi>ρ</mi><mn>2</mn></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>ρ</mi><mn>1</mn></msub></mfenced><mo>-</mo><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi>r</mi><mrow><mn>2</mn><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>r</mi><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub></mfenced><mo>=</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><mi>ρ</mi><mo>-</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>B</mi></msub></math><img id="ib0016" file="imgb0016.tif" wi="105" he="9" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0064" num="0064">Dividing both parts by |Δ<i><o>l</o><sub>B</sub></i>| we have:<maths id="math0017" num="(E70)"><math display="block"><msub><mover><mi>δ</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mi>U</mi></msub><mo>•</mo><mfrac><mrow><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mover><mi>l</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mi>B</mi></msub></mrow><mfenced open="|" close="|" separators=""><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mover><mi>l</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mi>B</mi></msub></mfenced></mfrac><mo>=</mo><mfrac><mrow><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><mi>ρ</mi><mo>-</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>B</mi></msub></mrow><mfenced open="|" close="|" separators=""><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mover><mi>l</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mi>B</mi></msub></mfenced></mfrac><mo>=</mo><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>D</mi><mfenced separators=""><mi mathvariant="italic">SPl</mi><mo>⁢</mo><mi>B</mi></mfenced></msub></math><img id="ib0017" file="imgb0017.tif" wi="76" he="15" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0065" num="0065">Or<maths id="math0018" num="(E71)"><math display="block"><mfenced separators=""><msub><mover><mi>x</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mi>U</mi></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mover><mi>x</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mi>B</mi></msub></mfenced><mo>•</mo><mfrac><mrow><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mover><mi>l</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mi>B</mi></msub></mrow><mfenced open="|" close="|" separators=""><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mover><mi>l</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mi>B</mi></msub></mfenced></mfrac><mo>=</mo><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>D</mi><mfenced separators=""><mi mathvariant="italic">SPl</mi><mo>⁢</mo><mi>B</mi></mfenced></msub></math><img id="ib0018" file="imgb0018.tif" wi="63" he="15" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0066" num="0066">The obtained equation (E71) is the Hessian normal form of the plane equation, where |<i>D</i><sub>(<i>SPl,B</i>)</sub>| is the distance from the plane of possible user positions <i><o>x</o><sub>u</sub></i> to the point <i><o>x</o><sub>B</sub>.</i>|<i>D</i><sub>(<i>SPl,B</i>)</sub>| is the minimum possible distance from the base position <i><o>x</o><sub>B</sub></i> to the unknown current user position <i><o>x</o><sub>u</sub></i>.</p><p id="p0067" num="0067">We can rewrite <i>D</i><sub>(<i>SPl,B</i>)</sub>:<maths id="math0019" num="(E80)"><math display="block"><msub><mi>D</mi><mfenced separators=""><mi mathvariant="italic">SPl</mi><mo>⁢</mo><mi>B</mi></mfenced></msub><mo>=</mo><mfrac><mrow><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>B</mi></msub><mo>-</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><mi>ρ</mi></mrow><mfenced open="|" close="|" separators=""><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mover><mi>l</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mi>B</mi></msub></mfenced></mfrac><mo>=</mo><mfrac><mrow><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>B</mi></msub><mo>-</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><mi>ρ</mi></mrow><mrow><mn>2</mn><mo>⋅</mo><mfenced separators=""><mn>1</mn><mo>-</mo><mi>cos</mi><mo>∠</mo><mfenced separators=""><msub><mover><mi>l</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mover><mi>l</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mrow><mn>2</mn><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub></mfenced></mfenced></mrow></mfrac><mo>=</mo><mfrac><mrow><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>B</mi></msub><mo>-</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><mi>ρ</mi></mrow><mrow><mn>2</mn><mo>⋅</mo><mfenced separators=""><mn>1</mn><mo>-</mo><mi>cos</mi><msub><mi>λ</mi><mrow><msub><mi>S</mi><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>,</mo><mn>2</mn></mrow></msub><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub></mfenced></mrow></mfrac></math><img id="ib0019" file="imgb0019.tif" wi="128" he="14" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0068" num="0068">A solution line equation will now be disclosed. In many cases it may be useful to assume that the user positions are constrained within the locally horizontal plane defined at the same altitude as the base position. In cases where the Solution Plane is significantly inclined with respect to the locally horizontal plane, and where motion is essentially<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> horizontal, the minimum distance from the base position to the Solution Plane will greatly underestimate the actual distance of the user to the Solution Plane.</p><p id="p0069" num="0069">With the assumption that the receiver is constrained to move within the Locally Horizontal Plane, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>, we have the receiver's solution space narrowed to the line (Solution Line <i>SL</i>) formed by the intersection of the Solution Plane <i>SP</i> and the Locally Horizontal Plane <i>LHP.</i> The distance to the Solution Line <i>SL</i> can be computed from the diagram of <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> by the following equation:<maths id="math0020" num="(E90="><math display="block"><msub><mi>D</mi><mfenced separators=""><mi mathvariant="italic">SLn</mi><mo>⁢</mo><mi>B</mi></mfenced></msub><mo>=</mo><mfrac><msub><mi>D</mi><mfenced separators=""><mi mathvariant="italic">SPl</mi><mo>⁢</mo><mi>B</mi></mfenced></msub><mrow><mi>sin</mi><mo>∠</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mover><mi>l</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mi>B</mi></msub><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mover><mi>n</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mrow><mi mathvariant="italic">LHPl</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub></mrow></mfrac><mo>=</mo><mfrac><mrow><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>B</mi></msub><mo>-</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><mi>ρ</mi></mrow><mrow><mn>2</mn><mo>⋅</mo><mfenced separators=""><mn>1</mn><mo>-</mo><mi>cos</mi><msub><mi>λ</mi><mrow><msub><mi mathvariant="italic">SV</mi><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>,</mo><mn>2</mn></mrow></msub><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub></mfenced><mo>⋅</mo><mi>sin</mi><msub><mi>λ</mi><mfenced separators=""><mi mathvariant="italic">SPl</mi><mo>⁢</mo><mi mathvariant="italic">LHPl</mi></mfenced></msub></mrow></mfrac></math><img id="ib0020" file="imgb0020.tif" wi="115" he="14" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0070" num="0070">Note: the receiver position's constraining plane does not necessarily have to be the locally horizontal plane; however, this is the most likely scenario in realistic applications.</p><p id="p0071" num="0071">The sensitivity of <i>D</i><sub>(<i>SPl,B</i>)</sub> and <i>D</i><sub>(<i>SLn,B</i>)</sub> to pseudorange errors will now be considered. In satellite navigation it is common to define a constellation geometry quality factor known as dilution of precision. This unitless quantity is multiplied by the expected root-mean-square pseudorange error (assumed to be the same for all satellites) to estimate the positioning error.</p><p id="p0072" num="0072">The equivalents of the position dilution of precision (PDOP) used in a regular GPS fix in our case would be (for the distances to the Solution Plane and Solution Line respectively):<maths id="math0021" num="(E91)"><math display="block"><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">Γ</mi><mi mathvariant="italic">Pl</mi></msub><mo>=</mo><mfrac><msqrt><mn>2</mn></msqrt><mrow><mn>2</mn><mo>⋅</mo><mfenced separators=""><mn>1</mn><mo>-</mo><mi>cos</mi><mspace width="1em"/><msub><mi>λ</mi><mrow><msub><mi mathvariant="italic">SV</mi><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>,</mo><mn>2</mn></mrow></msub><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub></mfenced></mrow></mfrac></math><img id="ib0021" file="imgb0021.tif" wi="64" he="15" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths><maths id="math0022" num="(E92)"><math display="block"><mrow><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">Γ</mi><mi mathvariant="italic">Ln</mi></msub><mo>=</mo><mfrac><mrow><msqrt><mrow><mn>2</mn></mrow></msqrt></mrow><mrow><mn>2</mn><mo>⋅</mo><mfenced separators=""><mn>1</mn><mo>-</mo><mi>cos</mi><msub><mrow><mi>λ</mi></mrow><mrow><msub><mrow><mi mathvariant="italic">SV</mi></mrow><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>,</mo><mn>2</mn></mrow></msub><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub></mfenced><mo>⋅</mo><mi>sin</mi><mspace width="1em"/><msub><mrow><mi>λ</mi></mrow><mrow><mfenced separators=","><mi mathvariant="italic">SPl</mi><mo>⁢</mo><mi mathvariant="italic">LHPl</mi></mfenced></mrow></msub></mrow></mfrac></mrow></math><img id="ib0022" file="imgb0022.tif" wi="89" he="15" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0073" num="0073">The pseudorange estimate mean error would translate in the mean <i>D</i><sub>(<i>SPl,B</i>)</sub> error as:<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> <maths id="math0023" num="(E93)"><math display="block"><msub><mi>σ</mi><msub><mi>D</mi><mfenced separators=""><mi mathvariant="italic">SPl</mi><mo>⁢</mo><mi>B</mi></mfenced></msub></msub><mo>=</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">Γ</mi><mi mathvariant="italic">Pl</mi></msub><mo>⋅</mo><msub><mi>σ</mi><mi>ρ</mi></msub></math><img id="ib0023" file="imgb0023.tif" wi="50" he="8" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0074" num="0074">Similarly, the pseudorange estimate mean error would translate in the mean <i>D<sub>SLn,B</sub></i> error as:<maths id="math0024" num="(E93)"><math display="block"><msub><mi>σ</mi><msub><mi>D</mi><mfenced separators=""><mi mathvariant="italic">SLn</mi><mo>⁢</mo><mi>B</mi></mfenced></msub></msub><mo>=</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">Γ</mi><mi mathvariant="italic">Ln</mi></msub><mo>⋅</mo><msub><mi>σ</mi><mi>ρ</mi></msub></math><img id="ib0024" file="imgb0024.tif" wi="50" he="8" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0075" num="0075">The <maths id="math0025" num=""><math display="inline"><msqrt><mn>2</mn></msqrt></math><img id="ib0025" file="imgb0025.tif" wi="8" he="7" img-content="math" img-format="tif" inline="yes"/></maths> value in the numerators of E91 and E92 appears from an assumption that the pseudorange errors from each satellite are uncorrelated and have the same root-mean-square value σ<sub>ρ</sub>, in which case<maths id="math0026" num="(E95)"><math display="block"><msub><mi>σ</mi><msub><mi>ρ</mi><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>,</mo><mn>2</mn></mrow></msub></msub><mo>=</mo><msqrt><mn>2</mn></msqrt><mo>⋅</mo><msub><mi>σ</mi><mi>ρ</mi></msub></math><img id="ib0026" file="imgb0026.tif" wi="37" he="9" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0076" num="0076">A table of sample values for Γ<i><sub>Pl</sub></i>(<i>λ</i><sub><i>SV</i><sub2>1,2</sub2></sub>) is provided below, showing its dependence on the angle <i>λ</i><sub><i>SV</i><sub2>1,2</sub2></sub> between the two satellite line-of-sight vectors.
<tables id="tabl0001" num="0001"><table frame="all"><title><b>Table 1: Values of Γ(<i>λ</i><sub><i>SV</i><sub2>1,2</sub2></sub>)</b></title><tgroup cols="9"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="14mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="16mm"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="14mm"/><colspec colnum="4" colname="col4" colwidth="14mm"/><colspec colnum="5" colname="col5" colwidth="14mm"/><colspec colnum="6" colname="col6" colwidth="14mm"/><colspec colnum="7" colname="col7" colwidth="14mm"/><colspec colnum="8" colname="col8" colwidth="14mm"/><colspec colnum="9" colname="col9" colwidth="14mm"/><thead><row><entry valign="top"><i>λ</i><sub><i>SV</i><sub2>1,2</sub2></sub></entry><entry align="center" valign="top">1°</entry><entry align="center" valign="top">5°</entry><entry align="center" valign="top">7°</entry><entry align="center" valign="top">10°</entry><entry align="center" valign="top">20°</entry><entry align="center" valign="top">30°</entry><entry align="center" valign="top">45°</entry><entry align="center" valign="top">90°</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry>Γ</entry><entry>4642.71</entry><entry>185.82</entry><entry>94.86</entry><entry>46.54</entry><entry>11.73</entry><entry>5.28</entry><entry>2.41</entry><entry>0.707</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></tables></p><p id="p0077" num="0077">The table shows that the accuracy decreases dramatically for low values of <i>λ</i><sub><i>SV</i><sub2>1,2</sub2></sub>.</p><p id="p0078" num="0078">The departure geofence algorithm will now be derived. The purpose of the proposed algorithm is to generate an alarm when a tracked object departs from a known geofence anchor location (base location) for more than an allowed distance (geofence radius). The algorithm assumes only 2 GPS satellites are in view.</p><p id="p0079" num="0079">The algorithm is based on the computation of the <i>D</i><sub>(<i>SPl,B</i>)</sub> value and comparing its absolute value against a given geofence radius <i>R<sub>geof</sub></i>. The algorithm comprises the following steps, shown in the flow chart of <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>:<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --></p><p id="p0080" num="0080">Step 302: Decide whether we can use the current satellite geometry. Compute <i>λ</i><sub><i>SV</i><sub2>1,2</sub2></sub>. If <maths id="math0027" num=""><math display="inline"><msub><mi>λ</mi><mrow><msub><mi mathvariant="italic">SV</mi><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>,</mo><mn>2</mn></mrow></msub><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub><mo>&lt;</mo><msubsup><mi>λ</mi><msub><mi mathvariant="italic">SV</mi><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>,</mo><mn>2</mn></mrow></msub><mi>min</mi></msubsup></math><img id="ib0027" file="imgb0027.tif" wi="24" he="8" img-content="math" img-format="tif" inline="yes"/></maths>then <i>D</i><sub>(<i>SPl,B</i>)</sub> shall be assumed incomputable in step 304, and geofence monitoring will be declared unavailable.</p><p id="p0081" num="0081"><maths id="math0028" num=""><math display="inline"><msubsup><mi>λ</mi><msub><mi mathvariant="italic">SV</mi><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>,</mo><mn>2</mn></mrow></msub><mi>min</mi></msubsup></math><img id="ib0028" file="imgb0028.tif" wi="9" he="7" img-content="math" img-format="tif" inline="yes"/></maths>is a function of <i>R<sub>geof</sub></i>:<maths id="math0029" num=""><math display="block"><mfrac><msub><mi>σ</mi><mi>ρ</mi></msub><mrow><msqrt><mn>2</mn></msqrt><mo>⋅</mo><mfenced separators=""><mn>1</mn><mo>-</mo><mi>cos</mi><msubsup><mi>λ</mi><msub><mi mathvariant="italic">SV</mi><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>,</mo><mn>2</mn></mrow></msub><mi>min</mi></msubsup></mfenced></mrow></mfrac><mo>=</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="italic">R</mi><mi mathvariant="italic">geof</mi></msub><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi mathvariant="italic">F</mi><mi mathvariant="italic">conf</mi></msub></math><img id="ib0029" file="imgb0029.tif" wi="52" he="13" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0082" num="0082">Hence<maths id="math0030" num="(E100)"><math display="block"><msubsup><mi>λ</mi><msub><mi mathvariant="italic">SV</mi><mrow><mi>i</mi><mo>,</mo><mn>2</mn></mrow></msub><mi>min</mi></msubsup><mo>=</mo><mi>arccos</mi><mfenced separators=""><mn>1</mn><mo>-</mo><mfrac><msub><mi>σ</mi><mi>ρ</mi></msub><mrow><msqrt><mn>2</mn></msqrt><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi>R</mi><mi mathvariant="italic">geof</mi></msub><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi>F</mi><mi mathvariant="italic">conf</mi></msub></mrow></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0030" file="imgb0030.tif" wi="78" he="16" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0083" num="0083">Step 306: Compute <i>D</i><sub>(<i>SPl,B</i>)</sub><i>.</i> If it is determined in step 308 that<maths id="math0031" num="(E110)"><math display="block"><mfenced open="|" close="|"><msub><mi>D</mi><mfenced separators=""><mi mathvariant="italic">SPl</mi><mo>⁢</mo><mi>B</mi></mfenced></msub></mfenced><mo>&gt;</mo><msub><mi>R</mi><mi mathvariant="italic">geof</mi></msub></math><img id="ib0031" file="imgb0031.tif" wi="52" he="9" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0084" num="0084">generate the departure geofence crossing event in step 310. Otherwise, in step 312, the geofence crossing event is not generated.</p><p id="p0085" num="0085">The algorithm can be modified for use of <i>D</i><sub>(<i>SLn,B</i>)</sub> instead of <i>D</i><sub>(<i>SPl,B</i>)</sub><i>.</i></p><p id="p0086" num="0086">The performance of the algorithm will now be discussed. The probability of a missed geofence crossing event is quite large due to a 'stealth' factor. When the receiver is moving within the Solution Plane, the computed <i>D<sub>(SPl,,B)</sub></i> value does not change and the receiver's movement remains undetected. The 'stealth' factor contribution to the missed detection rate is proportional to <maths id="math0032" num=""><math display="inline"><mfrac><mn>1</mn><msubsup><mi>R</mi><mi mathvariant="italic">geof</mi><mn>2</mn></msubsup></mfrac><mn>.</mn></math><img id="ib0032" file="imgb0032.tif" wi="11" he="13" img-content="math" img-format="tif" inline="yes"/></maths> for the receiver moving on the horizontal plane. The other factors contributing to missed detection are the pseudorange and satellite position errors.<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></p><p id="p0087" num="0087">The probability of false geofence crossing events (false alarms) is fully determined by the errors in <i>D<sub>(SPl,B)</sub></i> caused by the errors in pseudorange estimates and satellite positions.</p><p id="p0088" num="0088">In a second preferred embodiment, a route adherence algorithm is used. The previous algorithm for geofencing, in which the minimum possible distance from a reference (base) position is computed, can be extended to route adherence testing by computing the minimum possible distance for a number of points along the route.</p><p id="p0089" num="0089">One approach is to approximate the route to be adhered to using a number of line segments in three-dimensional space, where the lengths of the line segments are short compared to the distance to the satellites (i.e. less than a few hundred kilometres). In that case, the linearized solution planes at each end of the line segment are approximately identical. For each line segment, there are four possible cases:
<ul><li>1. The line segment passes through the solution plane;</li><li>2. The line segment does not pass through the solution plane, and the first point on the segment is closest to the solution plane; or</li><li>3. The line segment does not pass through the solution plane, and the first point on the segment is closest to the solution plane; or</li><li>4. The line segment is exactly parallel to the solution plane</li></ul></p><p id="p0090" num="0090">In practice, the last case is extremely unlikely to occur, and for the purposes of determining the minimum distance over the segment, is equivalent to either case 2 or 3.</p><p id="p0091" num="0091">The route adherence algorithm computes the closest distance of approach of any solution plane to the entire route. If the minimum possible distance is greater than a selected threshold distance, then it is known that the user has not adhered to the route.</p><p id="p0092" num="0092">The minimum distance algorithm for a single line segment is as follows, as shown in the flow chart of <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4</figref>:<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --></p><p id="p0093" num="0093">Step 402: For the first point in each line segment, compute do = <i>D</i><sub>(<i>SPl,B</i>)</sub> and the normal vector <maths id="math0033" num=""><math display="inline"><msub><mover><mi>v</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mn>0</mn></msub><mo>=</mo><mfrac><mrow><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mover><mi>l</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mi>B</mi></msub></mrow><msub><mi mathvariant="italic">sign D</mi><mfenced separators=""><mi mathvariant="italic">SPI</mi><mo>⁢</mo><mi>B</mi></mfenced></msub></mfrac><mo>,</mo></math><img id="ib0033" file="imgb0033.tif" wi="33" he="15" img-content="math" img-format="tif" inline="yes"/></maths> with the first point of the segment used as the base</p><p id="p0094" num="0094">Step 404: For the second point in each line segment, compute d<sub>1</sub> = <i>D</i><sub>(<i>SPl,B</i>)</sub> and the normal vector <maths id="math0034" num=""><math display="inline"><msub><mover><mi>v</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mn>1</mn></msub><mo>=</mo><mfrac><mrow><mi mathvariant="normal">Δ</mi><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mover><mi>l</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mi>B</mi></msub></mrow><msub><mi mathvariant="italic">sign D</mi><mfenced separators=""><mi mathvariant="italic">SPI</mi><mo>⁢</mo><mi>B</mi></mfenced></msub></mfrac><mo>,</mo></math><img id="ib0034" file="imgb0034.tif" wi="33" he="17" img-content="math" img-format="tif" inline="yes"/></maths> with the second point of the segment used as the base</p><p id="p0095" num="0095">Step 406: Determine whether the line segment passes through the solution plane by computing the sign of <o><i>ν</i></o><sub>0</sub>•<o><i>ν</i></o><sub>1</sub>. If it is positive, the line segment doesn't pass through the solution plane. If it is negative, it is determined in step 408 that the line segment passes through the solution plane, and the minimum distance over the line segment is 0.</p><p id="p0096" num="0096">Step 410: If the line segment doesn't pass through the solution plane, then the minimum distance of the line segment to the solution plane is min(do, d<sub>1</sub>).</p><p id="p0097" num="0097">This basic algorithm could be applied over the full set of line segments describing the route in a number of ways. For example, the algorithm could be applied over each line segment and the global minimum could be found. Alternatively, the set of line segments to be searched could be restricted to a subset using side information such as the last known user position and the maximum possible speed.</p><p id="p0098" num="0098">No hardware modifications are necessary to realize the present invention in an existing GPS receiver. As for software modifications, the GPS fix computation software module should be augmented with the computation of the defined above <i>λ</i><sub><i>SV</i><sub2>1,2</sub2></sub> and <i>D</i><sub>(<i>SPl,B</i>)</sub> when only two satellites are in view. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5</figref>, a GPS receiver 500 includes an antenna 502, a microprocessor 504 and a storage medium 506, in communication with or integrated into the microprocessor 504, for storing the software. The software can be<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> supplied to the receiver 500 by way of any suitable medium 508. Geofence API functions utilizing the above values should be provided to the geofence application.</p><p id="p0099" num="0099">As for which parameter to use, <i>D<sub>(SPl,B)</sub></i> or <i>D<sub>(SLn,B)</sub>,</i> the user should use the horizontal case if the tracked object is expected to remain in the horizontal plane. The use of <i>D<sub>(SPl,B)</sub></i> is more generic.</p><p id="p0100" num="0100">The situation where only two satellites are visible quite often will correlate with a situation in which only a small aperture of the sky is visible; therefore, the angle between the two visible satellites will often be small. The disadvantage of the small angle between the two satellites is partially compensated by smaller ionospheric and tropospheric errors due to the fact that the ionospheric and tropospheric delays for both satellites will be close.</p><p id="p0101" num="0101">In the case of an unknown base location, instead of using the base location, we can use a previously computed Solution Plane (base Solution Plane) and measure the minimum distance between the base and current planes.</p><p id="p0102" num="0102">The best accuracy (precision) would be achieved if the base Solution Plane is originated by the same SVs as the current Solution Plane and the time difference between the computations is not more than a couple of minutes.</p><p id="p0103" num="0103">Pseudorange dynamic filtering for static receivers can be beneficial in removing thermal noise errors, especially in the case of small angle <i>λ</i><sub><i>SV</i><sub2>1,2</sub2></sub> where ionospheric error contribution is small. It probably will also filter out free motion receiver's movement around the anchor position.</p><p id="p0104" num="0104">Another approach to finding the solution plane is to approximate pseudoranges for the current user position with the pseudoranges for the base position using the formulae for the differential of a multivariable function:<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> <maths id="math0035" num=""><math display="block"><mtable columnalign="left"><mtr><mtd><msub><mi>ρ</mi><mi>i</mi></msub><mo>≈</mo><msub><mi>ρ</mi><mrow><mi>i</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub><mo>+</mo><msub><mfenced separators=""><mfrac><mo>∂</mo><mrow><mo>∂</mo><mi>x</mi></mrow></mfrac><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>i</mi></msub></mfenced><mi>B</mi></msub><mo>⁢</mo><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi>x</mi><mi>U</mi></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>x</mi><mi>B</mi></msub></mfenced><mo>+</mo><msub><mfenced separators=""><mfrac><mo>∂</mo><mrow><mo>∂</mo><mi>y</mi></mrow></mfrac><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>i</mi></msub></mfenced><mi>B</mi></msub><mo>⁢</mo><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi>y</mi><mi>U</mi></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>y</mi><mi>B</mi></msub></mfenced><mo>+</mo><msub><mfenced separators=""><mfrac><mo>∂</mo><mrow><mo>∂</mo><mi>z</mi></mrow></mfrac><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>i</mi></msub></mfenced><mi>B</mi></msub><mo>⋅</mo><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi>z</mi><mi>U</mi></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>z</mi><mi>B</mi></msub></mfenced><mo>+</mo><msub><mfenced separators=""><mfrac><mo>∂</mo><mrow><mo>∂</mo><mi>b</mi></mrow></mfrac><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi>ρ</mi><mi>i</mi></msub></mfenced><mi>B</mi></msub><mo>⋅</mo><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi>b</mi><mi>U</mi></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>b</mi><mrow><mi>U</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub></mfenced><mo>=</mo></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><msub><mi>r</mi><mrow><mi>i</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub><mo>+</mo><msub><mi>b</mi><mrow><mi>U</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub><mo>+</mo><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>x</mi><mrow><mi>S</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>i</mi></mrow></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>x</mi><mi>B</mi></msub></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mrow><mi>i</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub></mfrac><mo>⋅</mo><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi>x</mi><mi>U</mi></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>x</mi><mi>B</mi></msub></mfenced><mo>+</mo><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>y</mi><mrow><mi>S</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>i</mi></mrow></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>y</mi><mi>B</mi></msub></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mrow><mi>i</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub></mfrac><mo>⋅</mo><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi>y</mi><mi>U</mi></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>y</mi><mi>B</mi></msub></mfenced><mo>+</mo><mfrac><mrow><msub><mi>z</mi><mrow><mi>S</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>i</mi></mrow></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>z</mi><mi>B</mi></msub></mrow><msub><mi>r</mi><mrow><mi>i</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub></mfrac><mo>⋅</mo><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi>z</mi><mi>U</mi></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>z</mi><mi>B</mi></msub></mfenced><mo>+</mo><msub><mi>b</mi><mi>U</mi></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>b</mi><mrow><mi>U</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub><mo>=</mo></mtd></mtr><mtr><mtd><msub><mi>r</mi><mrow><mi>i</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub><mo>+</mo><msub><mover><mi>δ</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mi>U</mi></msub><mo>•</mo><msub><mover><mi>l</mi><mo>→</mo></mover><mrow><mi>i</mi><mo>,</mo><mi>B</mi></mrow></msub><mo>+</mo><msub><mi>b</mi><mi>U</mi></msub></mtd></mtr></mtable></math><img id="ib0035" file="imgb0035.tif" wi="164" he="36" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0105" num="0105">The obtained equation is the same as (E60).</p><p id="p0106" num="0106">The case of a GPS receiver with a normal accuracy on-board clock and two GPS satellites in view should be similar to the case of a GPS receiver with a high accuracy ideal (e.g. atomic) clock and a single GPS satellite in view. In the latter case, one satellite in view is sufficient to determine a distance from the base location to the Solution Surface. Since the receiver's clock ideally does not have a clock bias, we can estimate the true range to the satellite, rather than the pseudorange. The difference of the range to the current position and the range to the base location is the distance from the base location to the Solution Surface, which happens to be a sphere:<maths id="math0036" num=""><math display="block"><msub><mi>D</mi><mfenced separators=""><mi mathvariant="italic">SS</mi><mo>⁢</mo><mi>B</mi></mfenced></msub><mo>=</mo><mfenced open="|" close="|" separators=""><msub><mi>r</mi><mi mathvariant="italic">cur</mi></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>B</mi></msub></mfenced></math><img id="ib0036" file="imgb0036.tif" wi="33" he="8" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0107" num="0107">If the base location is the receiver's previous location, <i>D<sub>(SS,B)</sub></i> has the meaning of the minimum displacement of the receiver from the previous location.</p><p id="p0108" num="0108"><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 6</figref> shows the distance from the base location <i>BL</i> to the Solution Surface <i>SS</i> (which is a sphere) in the case of one satellite <i>SV</i> and a receiver with an ideal clock. The Solution Surface <i>SS</i> is the set of all possible user locations <i>PUL.</i> Any of the variations disclosed above for the preferred embodiment using two satellites can be implemented as well with the preferred embodiment using only one satellite.</p><p id="p0109" num="0109">While various preferred embodiments of the invention have been disclosed in detail above, those skilled in the art who have reviewed the present disclosure will readily appreciate that other embodiments can be realized within the scope of the invention. For example, a GPS receiver according to the present invention can either have a simple<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> software upgrade from existing receivers or be purpose built. Also, the present invention is not limited to a single example of a global positioning system, but can instead be used with other global positioning systems, such as GLONASS or the Galileo positioning system. Therefore, the present invention should be construed as limited only by the appended claims.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56984816" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Verfahren zur geografischen Eingrenzung (Geofencing) oder Überwachung der Routeneinhaltung unter Verwendung von nicht mehr als zwei Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Satelliten (SV<sub>1</sub>, SV<sub>2</sub>) eines Globalpositionsbestimmungssystems, wobei das Verfahren umfasst:
<claim-text>a: Empfangen eines Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Signals von nicht mehr als zwei der Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Satelliten (SV<sub>1</sub>, SV<sub>2</sub>) in einem Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Empfänger;</claim-text>
<claim-text>b: Berechnen einer Lösungsfläche (SS), die eine Menge möglicher Standorte für den Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Empfänger enthält, aus dem oder den in Schritt a empfangenen Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Signal(en); und</claim-text>
<claim-text>c: Bestimmen des möglichen Standorts (PUL) auf der Lösungsfläche (SS), die sich im Mindestabstand zu einem Referenzstandort (Basisstandort) befindet; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>d: Erzeugen eines Abweichungsereignisses, wenn der Mindestabstand einen vorgegebenen Abstand überschreitet.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, wobei in Schritt a das Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Signal von nur einem Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Satelliten (SV<sub>1</sub>) empfangen wird und wobei der Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Empfänger eine Uhr umfasst, die im Wesentlichen uhrenfehlerfrei ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, wobei in Schritt a das Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Signal von zwei Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Satelliten (SV<sub>1</sub>, SV<sub>2</sub>) empfangen wird, wobei angenommen wird, dass der Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Empfänger eine Standortbeschränkung hat, wobei die Menge möglicher Standorte (PUL) aus der Lösungsfläche und der Standortbeschränkung bestimmt wird, wobei angenommen wird, dass der Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Empfänger sich auf einer Beschränkungsfläche (ES) befindet, und wobei die Menge möglicher Standorte (PUL) aus einer Überschneidung der Beschränkungsfläche (ES) und der Lösungsfläche (SS) bestimmt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 3, wobei der Referenzstandort ein vorheriger Standort des Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Empfängers ist, wobei der Referenzstandort aus einer vorher bestimmten Lösungsfläche (SS) bestimmt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Verfahren wie nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 4, wobei der Referenzstandort ein Geofence-Ankerstandort (Basisstation) ist, wobei der Geofence-Ankerstandort einen entsprechenden Geofence-Radius hat und wobei das Verfahren ferner umfasst: Vergleichen des Mindestabstands mit dem Geofence-Radius, um zu bestimmen, ob ein Geofence-Überschreitungsereignis stattgefunden hat.<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 5, wobei der Referenzstandort auf einer Route liegt, und ferner umfassend: Verwenden des Mindestabstands, um zu bestimmen, ob der Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Empfänger der Route folgt, und wobei gegebenenfalls die Route als eine Vielzahl von Liniensegmenten modelliert wird und wobei der Mindestabstand zu jedem der Liniensegmente berechnet wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Globale Positionsbestimmungssystem-Empfänger, der für eine geografische Eingrenzung (Geofencing) oder Überwachung der Routeneinhaltung unter Verwendung von nicht mehr als zwei Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Satelliten (SV<sub>1</sub>, SV<sub>2</sub>) eines Globalpositionsbestimmungssystems eingerichtet ist, wobei der Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Empfänger umfasst: eine Antenne, die zum Empfangen eines Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Signals von nicht mehr als zwei Globalpositionsbestimmungsystem-Satelliten eingerichtet ist; und einen mit der Antenne in Kommunikation stehenden Prozessor, der eingerichtet ist zum Berechnen einer Lösungsfläche (SS), die eine Menge möglicher Standorte (PUL) für den Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Empfänger enthält, aus dem oder den durch die Antenne empfangenen Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Signal(en); zum Bestimmen des möglichen Standorts auf der Lösungsfläche (SS), die sich in der Mindestentfernung zu einem Referenzstandort befindet, und zum Erzeugen eines Abweichungsereignisses, wenn der Mindestabstand einen vorbestimmten Abstand überschreitet.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Empfänger nach Anspruch 7, wobei das Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Signal von nur einem Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Satelliten (SV<sub>1</sub>) empfangen wird und wobei der Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Empfänger ferner eine Uhr umfasst, die im Wesentlichen uhrenfehlerfrei ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Empfänger nach Anspruch 8, wobei ein Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Signal von jedem der beiden Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Satelliten (SV<sub>1</sub>, SV<sub>2</sub>) empfangen wird und der Prozessor eine Lösungsfläche (SS) bestimmt, die die Menge möglicher Standorte (PUL) umfasst, wobei der Prozessor einen Mindestabstand von der Lösungsfläche (SS) zum Referenzstandort (Basisstation) bestimmt und wobei angenommen wird, dass der Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Empfänger eine Standortbeschränkung (ES) hat, und wobei die Menge möglicher Standorte aus der Lösungsfläche (SS) und der Standortbeschränkung (ES) bestimmt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Empfänger nach Anspruch 9, wobei die Standortbeschränkung (ES) darin besteht, dass angenommen wird, dass der Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Empfänger sich auf einer Beschränkungsfläche befindet, und wobei die Menge möglicher Standorte aus der Überschneidung der Begrenzungsfläche (ES) und der Lösungsfläche (SS) bestimmt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Empfänger nach einem der Ansprüche 8 bis 10, wobei der Referenzstandort ein vorheriger Standort des<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Empfängers ist und wobei der Referenzstandort aus einer vorher bestimmten Lösungsfläche (SS) bestimmt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Empfänger nach Anspruch 7, wobei der Referenzstandort ein Geofence-Ankerstandort (Basisstation) ist und wobei der Geofence-Ankerstandort einen entsprechenden Geofence-Radius hat und wobei der Mindestabstand mit dem Geofence-Radius verglichen wird, um zu bestimmen, ob ein Geofence-Überschreitungsereignis stattgefunden hat.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Empfänger nach Anspruch 7, wobei der Referenzstandort auf einer Route liegt, und ferner umfassend: Verwenden des Mindestabstands, um zu bestimmen, ob der Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Empfänger den Routen folgt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Erzeugnis für eine geografischen Eingrenzung (Geofencing) oder Überwachung der Routeneinhaltung unter Verwendung von nicht mehr als zwei Globalpositionsbestimmungssatelliten eines Globalpositionsbestimmungssystems, wobei das Erzeugnis umfasst: ein computerlesbares Speichermedium; und im computerlesbaren Speichermedium gespeicherten Code, wobei der Code bei Ausführung in einem Prozessor des Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Empfängers den Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Empfänger steuert zum:
<claim-text>a: Empfangen eines Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Signals von nicht mehr als zwei Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Satelliten (SV<sub>1</sub>, SV<sub>2</sub>);</claim-text>
<claim-text>b: Berechnen einer Lösungsfläche (SS), die eine Menge möglicher Standorte (PUL) für den Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Empfänger enthält, aus dem oder den in Schritt a empfangenen Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Signal(en); und</claim-text>
<claim-text>c: Bestimmen des möglichen Standorts auf der Lösungsfläche (SS), die sich im Mindestabstand zu einem Referenzstandort befindet, und Erzeugen eines Abweichungsereignisses, wenn der Mindestabstand einen vorgegebenen Abstand überschreitet.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Erzeugnis nach Anspruch 14, wobei der Referenzstandort auf einer Route liegt und der Code bei Ausführung bewirkt, dass der Prozessor den Mindestabstand verwendet, um zu bestimmen, ob der Globalpositionsbestimmungssystem-Empfänger der Route folgt.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56984817" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A method of geofencing or monitoring route adherence using no more than two global positioning satellites (SV<sub>1</sub>, SV<sub>2</sub>) of a global positioning system, the method comprising:
<claim-text>a: receiving in a global positioning system receiver a global positioning system signal from no more than two of the global positioning satellites (SV<sub>1</sub>, SV<sub>2</sub>);</claim-text>
<claim-text>b: computing, from the global positioning system signal or signals received in step a, a solution surface (SS) containing a set of possible locations for the global positioning system receiver; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>c: determining the possible location (PUL) on the solution surface (SS) that is at the minimum distance to a reference location (Base Location); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>d: generating a departure event when the minimum distance exceeds a predetermined distance.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>A method as claimed in claim 1, wherein, in step a, the global positioning system signal is received from only one global positioning system satellite (SV<sub>1</sub>), and wherein the global positioning system receiver comprises a clock which is substantially free of clock bias.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>A method as claimed in claim 1, wherein, in step a, the global positioning system signal is received from two global positioning system satellites (SV<sub>1</sub>, SV<sub>2</sub>), wherein the global positioning system receiver is assumed to have a location constraint, wherein the set of possible locations (PUL) is determined from the solution surface and the location constraint, wherein the global positioning system<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> receiver is assumed to be on a constraint surface (ES), and wherein the set of possible locations (PUL) is determined from an intersection of the constraint surface (ES) and the solution surface (SS).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>A method as claimed in any one of claims 1 to 3, wherein the reference location is a previous location of the global positioning system receiver, wherein the reference location is determined from a previously determined solution surface (SS).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>A method as claimed in any one of claim 1 to 4, wherein the reference location is a geofence anchor location (base station), wherein the geofence anchor location has a corresponding geofence radius, and wherein the method further comprises comparing the minimum distance to the geofence radius to determine whether a geofence crossing even has taken place.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>A method as claimed in any one of claims 1 to 5, wherein the reference location is on a route, and further comprising using the minimum distance to determine whether the global positioning system receiver is following the route, and wherein optionally the route is modeled as a plurality of line segments, and wherein the minimum distance is calculated to each of the line segments.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>A global positioning system receiver adapted for geofencing or monitoring route adherence using no more than two global positioning satellites (SV<sub>1</sub>, SV<sub>2</sub>) of a global positioning system, the global positioning system receiver comprising: an antenna adapted for receiving a global positioning system signal from no more than two global positioning system satellites; and a processor, in communication with the antenna,<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> adapted: for computing, from the global positioning system signal or signals received by the antenna, a solution surface (SS) containing a set of possible locations (PUL) for the global positioning system receiver; for determining the possible location on the solution surface (SS) that is at the minimum distance to a reference location, and for generating a departure event when the minimum distance exceeds a predetermined distance.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>A global positioning system receiver as claimed in claim 7, wherein the global positioning system signal is received from only one said global positioning system satellite (SV<sub>1</sub>), and wherein said global positioning system receiver further comprises a clock which is substantially free of clock bias.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>A global positioning system receiver as claimed in claim 8, wherein a global positioning system signal is received from each of two said global positioning system satellites (SV<sub>1</sub>, SV<sub>2</sub>) and the processor determines a solution surface (SS) comprising the set of possible locations (PUL), wherein the processor determines a minimum distance from the solution surface (SS) to the reference location (Base station), and wherein the global positioning system receiver is assumed to have a location constraint (ES), and wherein the set of possible locations is determined from the solution surface (SS) and the location constraint (ES).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>A global positioning system receiver as claimed in claim 9, wherein the location constraint (ES) is that the global positioning system receiver is assumed to be on a constraint surface, and wherein the set of possible locations is determined from an intersection of the constraint surface (ES) and the solution surface (SS).<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>A global positioning system receiver as claimed in any one of claims 8 to 10, wherein the reference location is a previous location of the global positioning system receiver, and wherein the reference location is determined from a previously determined solution surface (SS).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>A global positioning system receiver as claimed in claim 7, wherein the reference location is a geofence anchor location (Base station), and wherein the geofence anchor location has a corresponding geofence radius, and wherein the minimum distance is compared to the geofence radius to determine whether a geofence crossing even has taken place.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>A global positioning system receiver as claimed in claim 7, wherein the reference location is on a route, and further comprising using the minimum distance to determine whether the global positioning system receiver is following the routes.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>An article of manufacture for geofencing or monitoring route adherence using no more than two global positioning satellites of a global positioning system, the article of manufacture comprising: a computer-readable storage medium; and code stored in the computer-readable storage medium, the code, when executed in a processor of the global positioning system receiver, controlling the global positioning system receiver for:
<claim-text>a: receiving a global positioning system signal from no more than two of the global positioning system satellites (SV<sub>1</sub>, SV<sub>2</sub>);<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>b: computing, from the global positioning system signal or signals received in step a, a solution surface (SS) containing a set of possible locations (PUL) for the global positioning system receiver; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>c: determining the possible location on the solution surface that is at the minimum distance to a reference location, and generating a departure event when the minimum distance exceeds a predetermined distance.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>An article of manufacture as claimed in claim 14, wherein the reference location is on a route, and the code when executed causes the processor to use the minimum distance to determine whether the global positioning system receiver is following the route.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56984818" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Procédé de surveillance ou de gardiennage virtuel d'une adhésion à un itinéraire en utilisant tout au plus deux satellites de positionnement mondial (SV<sub>1</sub>, SV<sub>2</sub>) d'un système de positionnement mondial, le procédé consistant à :
<claim-text>a : recevoir, sur un récepteur de système de positionnement mondial, un signal de système de positionnement mondial en provenance de tout au plus deux des satellites de positionnement mondial (SV<sub>1</sub>, SV<sub>2</sub>) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>b : calculer, à partir du signal ou des signaux de système de positionnement mondial reçus à l'étape a, une surface de solution (SS) contenant un ensemble d'emplacements possibles pour le récepteur de système de positionnement mondial ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>c: déterminer l'emplacement possible (PUL), sur la surface de solution (SS), qui se situe à la distance minimale jusqu'à un emplacement de référence (emplacement de base) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>d: générer un événement de déviation lorsque la distance minimale est supérieure à une distance prédéterminée.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, dans lequel, à l'étape a, le signal de système de positionnement mondial est reçu à partir d'un unique satellite de système de positionnement mondial (SV<sub>1</sub>), et dans lequel le récepteur de système de positionnement mondial comprend une horloge qui est sensiblement exempte de décalage d'horloge.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, dans lequel, à l'étape a, le signal de système de positionnement mondial est reçu à partir de deux satellites de système de positionnement mondial (SV<sub>1</sub>, SV<sub>2</sub>), dans lequel le récepteur de système de positionnement mondial est supposé présenter une contrainte de localisation, dans lequel l'ensemble d'emplacements possibles (PUL) est déterminé à partir de la surface de solution et de la contrainte de localisation, dans lequel le récepteur de système de positionnement mondial est supposé être sur une surface de contrainte (ES), et dans lequel l'ensemble d'emplacements possibles (PUL) est déterminé à partir d'une intersection de la surface de contrainte (ES) et de la surface de solution (SS).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 3, dans lequel l'emplacement de référence est un emplacement précédent du récepteur de système de positionnement mondial, dans lequel l'emplacement de référence est déterminé à partir d'une surface de solution déterminée précédemment (SS).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 4, dans lequel l'emplacement de référence est un emplacement d'ancrage de zone de gardiennage virtuel (station de base), dans lequel l'emplacement d'ancrage de zone de gardiennage virtuel présente un rayon de zone de gardiennage virtuel correspondant, et dans lequel le procédé consiste en outre à comparer la distance minimale au rayon de zone de gardiennage virtuel en vue de déterminer si un événement de franchissement de zone de gardiennage virtuel a eu lieu.<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 5, dans lequel l'emplacement de référence est sur un itinéraire, et consistant en outre à utiliser la distance minimale en vue de déterminer si le récepteur de système de positionnement mondial suit l'itinéraire, et facultativement, dans lequel l'itinéraire est modélisé sous la forme d'une pluralité de segments de ligne, et dans lequel la distance minimale est calculée jusqu'à chacun des segments de ligne.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Récepteur de système de positionnement mondial apte à surveiller ou à effectuer un gardiennage virtuel d'une adhésion à un itinéraire en utilisant tout au plus deux satellites de positionnement mondial (SV<sub>1</sub>, SV<sub>2</sub>) d'un système de positionnement mondial, le récepteur de système de positionnement mondial comprenant : une antenne apte à recevoir un signal de système de positionnement mondial en provenance de tout au plus deux satellites de système de positionnement mondial ; et un processeur, en communication avec l'antenne, apte à : calculer, à partir du signal ou des signaux de système de positionnement mondial reçus par l'antenne, une surface de solution (SS) contenant un ensemble d'emplacements possibles (PUL) pour le récepteur de système de positionnement mondial ; déterminer l'emplacement possible, sur la surface de solution (SS), qui se situe à la distance minimale jusqu'à un emplacement de référence ; et générer un événement de déviation lorsque la distance minimale est supérieure à une distance prédéterminée.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Récepteur de système de positionnement mondial selon la revendication 7, dans lequel le signal de système de positionnement mondial est reçu à partir d'un unique dit satellite de système de positionnement mondial (SV<sub>1</sub>), et dans lequel ledit récepteur de système de positionnement mondial comprend en outre une horloge qui est sensiblement exempte de décalage d'horloge.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Récepteur de système de positionnement mondial selon la revendication 8, dans lequel un signal de système de positionnement mondial est reçu à partir de chacun desdits deux satellites de système de positionnement mondial (SV<sub>1</sub>, SV<sub>2</sub>), et le processeur détermine une surface de solution (SS), comprenant l'ensemble d'emplacements possibles (PUL), dans lequel le processeur détermine une distance minimale de la surface de solution (SS) à l'emplacement de référence (station de base), et dans lequel le récepteur de système de positionnement mondial est supposé présenter une contrainte de localisation (ES), et dans lequel l'ensemble d'emplacements possibles est déterminé à partir de la surface de solution (SS) et de la contrainte de localisation (ES).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Récepteur de système de positionnement mondial selon la revendication 9, dans lequel la contrainte de localisation (ES) est que le récepteur de système de positionnement mondial est supposé être sur une surface de contrainte, et dans lequel l'ensemble d'emplacements possibles est déterminé à partir d'une intersection de la surface de contrainte (ES) et de la surface de solution (SS).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Récepteur de système de positionnement mondial selon l'une quelconque des revendications 8 à 10, dans lequel l'emplacement de référence est un emplacement<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --> précédent du récepteur de système de positionnement mondial, et dans lequel l'emplacement de référence est déterminé à partir d'une surface de solution déterminée précédemment (SS).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Récepteur de système de positionnement mondial selon la revendication 7, dans lequel l'emplacement de référence est un emplacement d'ancrage de zone de gardiennage virtuel (station de base), et dans lequel l'emplacement d'ancrage de zone de gardiennage virtuel présente un rayon de zone de gardiennage virtuel correspondant, et dans lequel la distance minimale est comparée au rayon de zone de gardiennage virtuel en vue de déterminer si un événement de franchissement de zone de gardiennage virtuel a eu lieu.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Récepteur de système de positionnement mondial selon la revendication 7, dans lequel l'emplacement de référence est sur un itinéraire, et consistant en outre à utiliser la distance minimale en vue de déterminer si le récepteur de système de positionnement mondial suit les itinéraires.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Article fabriqué destiné à surveiller ou à effectuer un gardiennage virtuel d'une adhésion à un itinéraire en utilisant tout au plus deux satellites de positionnement mondial d'un système de positionnement mondial, l'article de fabrication comprenant : un support de stockage lisible par ordinateur, et un code stocké dans le support de stockage lisible par ordinateur, dans lequel le code, lorsqu'il est exécuté dans un processeur du récepteur de système de positionnement mondial, commande le récepteur de système de positionnement mondial de sorte à:
<claim-text>a : recevoir un signal de système de positionnement mondial en provenance de tout au plus deux des satellites de positionnement mondial (SV<sub>1</sub>, SV<sub>2</sub>) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>b : calculer, à partir du signal ou des signaux de système de positionnement mondial reçus à l'étape a, une surface de solution (SS) contenant un ensemble d'emplacements possibles (PUL) pour le récepteur de système de positionnement mondial ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>c: déterminer l'emplacement possible, sur la surface de solution, qui se situe à la distance minimale à un emplacement de référence, et générer un événement de déviation lorsque la distance minimale est supérieure à une distance prédéterminée.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Article fabriqué selon la revendication 14, dans lequel l'emplacement de référence est sur un itinéraire, et le code, lorsqu'il est exécuté, amène le processeur à utiliser la distance minimale en vue de déterminer si le récepteur de système de positionnement mondial suit l'itinéraire.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16671967" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1A,1B"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="143" he="217" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2,6"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="148" he="226" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="158" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --><figure id="f0004" num="4,5"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="160" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
