<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2131645-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2131645" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="38007637" file-reference-id="306752" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146588974" ucid="EP-2131645-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2131645</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-07834619-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154851166" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>07834619</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20071004</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP252968438" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>07834619.4</doc-number><date>20071004</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140550047" ucid="NL-2000258-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>NL</country><doc-number>2000258</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20061004</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140555940" ucid="NL-2007050481-W" linkage-type="W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>NL</country><doc-number>2007050481</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20071004</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130729</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989327233" load-source="docdb">A01G   9/22        20060101ALI20130516BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989327234" load-source="docdb">E06B   9/264       20060101AFI20130516BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1710200627" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">E06B   9/264       20130101 LI20180106BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1710210689" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A01G   9/222       20130101 FI20180106BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1713631000" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y02A  40/26        20180101 LA20180104BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132371555" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">STREIFENANORDNUNG</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132371556" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">STRIP ASSEMBLY</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132371557" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">ENSEMBLE DE BANDES</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919542720" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>RUITER JACOBUS CHRISTIAAN GERARDUS MARIA</last-name><address><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919505069" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>RUITER, JACOBUS CHRISTIAAN GERARDUS MARIA</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919538786" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>RUITER JACOBUS CHRISTIAAN GERARDUS MARIA</last-name><address><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919530902" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>RUITER, JACOBUS CHRISTIAAN GERARDUS MARIA</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919025705" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>RUITER, JACOBUS CHRISTIAAN GERARDUS MARIA</last-name><address><street>Shakespearezijde 22</street><city>2725 NN Zoetermeer</city><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919025707" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Ruiter, Jacobus Christiaan Gerardus Maria</last-name><iid>101062602</iid><address><street>Shakespearezijde 22</street><city>2725 NN Zoetermeer</city><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919025706" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Nederlandsch Octrooibureau</last-name><iid>101379333</iid><address><street>P.O. Box 29720</street><city>2502 LS The Hague</city><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="NL-2007050481-W"><document-id><country>NL</country><doc-number>2007050481</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20071004</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2008041848-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2008041848</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20080410</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549926027" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549790253" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549874719" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549883025" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549806786" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549926028" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549790254" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549806787" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549806788" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549898610" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549874720" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549874721" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549790255" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549806789" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549926029" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549883030" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549806790" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549874726" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549806791" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549792349" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549926030" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549792350" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549792351" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549889778" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549926031" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549806792" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549792352" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549926032" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549806793" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549792357" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549790256" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549889779" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63961390" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to a strip assembly comprising a carrier provided with a number of tiltable strips.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002">A strip assembly of this type is generally known in the art, such as disclosed in <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US5850861A"><text>US-A-5850861</text></patcit>. In greenhouses, in particular, ever more stringent requirements are being placed on screening. This concerns the prevention of both undesirable irradiation of sunlight and undesirable emission of growth light. Strips or slats are one possibility for regulating the desired amount of passing light. Known in the art are mechanical constructions which, owing to their complexity, have never been used on a large scale. A further known construction consists of the use of magnets, as a result of which the tilting movement of the strips is generated by magnetic action. Therein c oils are in some way made electrically magnetic and this can (temporarily) during use on large surface areas such as greenhouses require substantial current intensity, necessitating the laying of cables of considerable thickness. In addition, the operational safety of constructions of this type is limited.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">The object of the present invention is to provide a strip assembly which does not have the drawbacks of the prior art, is simple to install and highly regulable and requires few additional measures in a building construction.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">In an above-described strip assembly, this object is achieved with the features of claim 1.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">According to the present invention, displacement of the strips is controlled electrostatically. Providing the strips or a portion thereof with a polarity and providing the further electrodes with the same or, conversely, a different polarity will cause the strips of the further electrodes to move away from or toward said strips respectively. In addition, the various elements can operate in combination with gravity, i.e. the strips return of their own accord to a specific rest position as a result of a potential difference no longer being present.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p><p id="p0006" num="0006">With the current technologies, it is relatively simple to generate high potential differences without complex constructions being necessary for this purpose. That is to say, a simple low-voltage activator allows, a simple power source which may or may not be present on site, a high potential difference to be generated, as a result of which the strips can move into a different position. Power consumption is very limited, so the intended displacement can be carried out using very little energy.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">This high voltage can be transmitted via conduction but in a particular embodiment of the present invention it is possible to dispense with electrical connections between, for example, two remote foil layers between which the strips are attached. In such a case, power can be transmitted wirelessly with induction. This induction can comprise both the low-voltage part and the high-voltage part. In addition, it is possible, if two remote (foil) layers or other plates are used, to attach the supply in the edge zone separating these foil layers/plates. Apart from conventional technologies and the above-described induction-based transfer of energy, ceramic or magnetic systems can also be used to generate short-term voltage peaks.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">The strips can comprise any material known in the art. Examples include foil material or rigid material. In the case of rigid material, a hinge has to be attached to allow the strip to be displaced. In the case of foil material, a film hinge made of the foil material can be used. Examples of materials which can be used include polycarbonate, polyester or types of foil based on aromatics.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">The strip can be configured as a function of the desired change in the through-light. It may thus be desired to remove, absorb or reflect merely a specific portion of the light spectrum or, conversely, to allow through just a specific portion. The strip may be coloured accordingly or be provided with a corresponding coating. It is also possible that complete reflection is aimed for in a specific direction. In this case, the strips are either metallic (aluminium) or provided with a metallic reflective coating. It is also possible to influence the path of the light by reflection, by positioning the strips. If a series of strips is used in a surface, it is possible to displace one or more of said strips, allowing a specific effect to be obtained. It is thus possible to provide gradual darkening or illumination.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p><p id="p0010" num="0010">Each strip or slat can comprise a single part. However, it is also possible for each strip to consist of a number of foil parts attached so as to overlap. Overlapping arrangement can counteract effects of temperature changes resulting in shrinkage and expansion. The strips may, for example, be approximately 2 cm wide. The strips may, in principle, be long, a length of tens of centimetres to tens of metres being preferred.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">The strips can be used not only in greenhouses but also in other applications. In many locations there are problems with incident light and, in particular, solar radiation which is undesirable at specific moments. In addition, in shopping centres or the like, the strips can be used to obtain colouring effects by configuring the strips in various ways or by positioning merely specific groups of strips in the light path and leaving other groups out. A person skilled in the art will be able to think of numerous variations.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">In all cases, it is advantageous to integrate the assembly between two externally attached plates or the like. These may be two parallel plates between which the strip assembly is positioned but it is also possible to use what is known as a cushion foil and to attach the strip assembly according to the invention in the cushion. Obviously, other constructions are also possible. Attachment between two protective layers largely prevents the infiltration of dirt and moisture and ensures operation of the strip assembly even over a relatively longer period of time.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">The further electrodes can contain any construction conceivable in the art. According to a particular embodiment, the further electrodes are configured as wires (grid). This has the advantage of not impeding or scarcely impeding the passage of light. In addition, this has the advantage that the thickness of these wires allows them to act as spacers with respect to a surface, thus preventing the strips from sticking.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">When used in greenhouses, the strip assembly is preferably used in the roof construction, the panels attached therein consisting of plates which are set apart parallel to one another and between which the strips are attached. The panels are preferably oriented in such a way that at the moment at which they have to be most effective (closing off) they are positioned substantially perpendicularly to the direction of the<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> incident solar radiation.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">Apart from folding or tilting between two positions, an opened and closed position, it is possible in a particular embodiment of the invention to provide a number of intermediate positions between completely open and completely closed, thus allowing the incident light to be regulated, for example.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">The invention will be described in greater detail hereinafter with reference to the illustrative embodiments shown in the drawings, in which:
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> shows a greenhouse provided with the strip assembly according to the invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> shows detail II from <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> shows an altered embodiment of the construction according to <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 4</figref> shows a strip constructed from overlapping strip parts.</li></ul></p><p id="p0017" num="0017">In <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, reference numeral 1 denotes a greenhouse. The greenhouse consists of a number of roofsections 2 and each roofsections is constructed from panels 3. The panels 3 are preferably oriented such that the angle which the panels form with respect to incident solar radiation at the moment at which the protection has to be most effective is approximately 90 degrees.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018"><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> shows a detail of the panel 3. The panel consists of two remote translucent plates 4 and 5. The plates may be glass plates but also plastics materials plates and the like. The strip or slat assembly according to the invention is attached between these plates. The strip assembly consists of a number of translucent further electrodes 6 and strips or electrodes 10 - 13. In <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>, the strips 10 - 13 are shown in all cases in a different position for the sake of clarity. The further electrodes 6 are configured as grid and connected to the first pole of a schematically illustrated voltage source, whereas the strips 10 - 13 are connected to the other pole of a voltage source via the line 8 and switch 7. The voltage source may be located close to the panel and be any construction<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> known in the art with which high voltage can be generated. The voltage source can be operated remotely, i.e. the switch 7 can be a remotely operated switch.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">The particular embodiment of the strips allows the strips to be electrostatically drawn toward the further electrodes or driven away therefrom respectively. The movement will also be influenced by gravity. In the presence of a potential difference as shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>, the strips will move toward the further electrodes 6. With the same polarity on the strips 10 - 13 and further electrodes 6, repulsion will take place. However, it is also possible to give the strips a shape memory, as a result of which the strips move, when no voltage is applied, in a specific direction, preferably in the direction for the complete passage of light (perpendicular direction). This position can also be obtained by gravity.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">If use is made of, for example, plastics materials plates, it is possible to allow the strips and plates to be assembled by common extrusion. Therein the plastics material used is, in particular, polycarbonate. During extrusion of the plate material, there are at the same time introduced the strips which have already been (partially) produced and are in this way clamped in the extruded plastics material. It is also possible to use other types of plastics material which may or may not be conductive. A combination of plastics materials for the plates is also conceivable for obtaining specific optical properties. In addition, coatings can be attached for influencing the light, absorbing, reflecting or displacing of spectra or the conversion of, for example, ultraviolet light to visible light.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021"><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> shows a variation of the invention used in what is known as a foil cushion. The foil cushion consists of two foil layers 14, 15 which are held apart from each other by compressed air or another gas. A cushion of this type can be used as a roof of greenhouses or other spaces. A construction of this type is especially simple to produce. Reference numeral 20 denotes the strips and reference numeral 6 the further electrodes and in this case the folding or tilting effect can be obtained in the same way. This further electrode is configured as a coating attached to the foil layer 14 which is substantially translucent.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022"><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 4</figref> shows a strip 23 constructed from strip parts 25 - 28 which overlap one another<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> in the closed position. The overlapping is in this case such as to not impede operation of the separate electrodes/strips.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">Changes in the dimensions have no effect whatsoever on the operation of the strip assembly. The electrode and further electrodes respectively can be made from any conceivable material. Examples include a metallic layer, a layer of non-conductive material to which a conductive additive is added, a conductive coating or an intrinsically conductive layer. Electrets are a further possibility for producing the electrode and further electrodes respectively.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">Depending on the use, it is possible to make the strips from any desired material in any desired state. Foil material is preferred because it is in this case not necessary to provide a separate hinge construction. The strips may or may not be translucent or filter merely specific portions of the light spectrum. This can be achieved by the presence of coatings and the presence or non-presence of the metal layer.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">Obviously, it is possible to attach the strips in groups. That is to say, one group of strips is activated separately in relation to a further group of strips. These groups can be dispersed from one another, i.e. strips can, in turns, be controlled using different controllers. It is thus, for example, possible to simulate a dawning effect or to obtain various colouring effects.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">After the above, a person skilled in the art will immediately think of variations which are within the scope of the appended claims.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56986910" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Streifenanordnung, welche einen Träger (4) umfasst, welcher mit einer Anzahl von faltbaren Streifen (10-13, 20) breitgestellt ist, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die Streifen Elektroden umfassen, dadurch, dass die Anordnung mit den Elektroden weitere zusammenwirkende Elektroden (6) umfasst, wobei jede Elektrode aus einem statisch aufladbares/entladbares Material besteht und wobei die Elektroden elektrische Spannungsanschlüsse (8, 9) umfassen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Streifenanordnung nach Anspruch 1, welche eine Spannungsquelle umfasst, welche mit den Spannungsanschlüssen verbunden ist, wobei der Anschluss der Streifen eine andere Spannung/Polarität als jener der weiteren Elektroden aufweist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Streifenanordnung nach einem der vorstehenden Ansprüche, wobei der Streifen eine Folie (10-13, 20) mit einem Filmgelenk mit der Stütze umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Streifenanordnung nach Anspruch 3, wobei die Folie mit einer Beschichtung bereitgestellt ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Streifenanordnung nach Anspruch 3 oder 4, wobei die Folie eine Polykarbonat-, Polyesterfolie oder eine Folie basierend auf Aromaten umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Streifenanordnung nach einem der Ansprüche 3 bis 5, wobei die Folie eine Metallfolie umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Streifenanordnung nach einem der Ansprüche 3 bis 6, wobei die Folie einen Oberflächenwiderstand von höchstens 1000 MΩ umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Streifenanordnung nach einem der vorstehenden Ansprüche, wobei die Streifen (10-13) unterschiedlich zueinander konfiguriert sind.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Streifenanordnung nach einem der vorstehenden Ansprüche, wobei ein Streifen eine Anzahl von Folienteilen (25-28) umfasst, welche befestigt sind, um zu überlappen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Streifenanordnung nach einem der vorstehenden Ansprüche, wobei die Breite der Streifen ungefähr 2 cm beträgt.<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Streifenanordnung nach einem der vorstehenden Ansprüche, welche zwischen zwei optisch permeablen Schichten (4, 5; 14, 15) befestigt ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Streifenanordnung nach Anspruch 11, wobei die Schichten transparente Kunststoffmaterial- oder Glasschichten umfassen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Streifenanordnung nach einem der vorstehenden Ansprüche, wobei der Streifen und/oder weitere Elektroden durch Elektrete elektrostatisch aufgeladen sind.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Treibhaus (1), welches eine obere Konstruktion (2) mit oberen Paneelen (3) und eine Streifenanordnung nach Anspruch 1 umfasst, wobei die Streifenanordnung in den Paneelen befestigt ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Treibhaus nach Anspruch 14, wobei der Winkel der Paneele bezüglich der Horizontalen derart gewählt ist, dass, während der intensivsten Sonneneinstrahlung, die Paneele im Wesentlichen senkrecht zu der Richtung der Strahlung positioniert sind.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56986911" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Strip assembly comprising a carrier (4) provided with a number of foldable strips (10 - 13, 20), <b>characterized in that</b> said strips comprise electrodes, <b>in that</b> said assembly with said electrodes comprises cooperating further electrodes (6), each electrode consisting of a statically chargeable/dischargeable material and said electrodes comprising electrical voltage connections (8, 9).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Strip assembly according to Claim 1, comprising a voltage source connected to said voltage connections, wherein the connection of said strips has a different voltage/polarity to that of said further electrodes.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Strip assembly according to either of the preceding claims, wherein said strip comprises a foil (10 - 13, 20) with a film hinge with said support.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Strip assembly according to Claim 3, wherein said foil is provided with a coating.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Strip assembly according to either Claim 3 or Claim 4, wherein said foil comprises a polycarbonate, polyester foil or foil based on aromatics.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Strip assembly according to any one of claims 3 to 5, wherein said foil comprises a metal foil.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Strip assembly according to any one of claims 3 to 6, wherein said foil comprises a surface resistance of at most 1000 MΩ.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Strip assembly according to any one of the preceding claims, wherein said strips (10 - 13) are configured differently from one another.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Strip assembly according to any one of the preceding claims, wherein a strip comprises a number of foil parts (25 - 28) attached so as to overlap.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Strip assembly according to any one of the preceding claims, wherein the width<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> of said strips is approximately 2 cm.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Strip assembly according to any one of the preceding claims, attached between two optically permeable layers (4, 5; 14, 15).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Strip assembly according to Claim 11, wherein said layers comprise transparent plastics material or glass layers.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Strip assembly according to any one of the preceding claims, wherein said strip and/or further electrodes are electrostatically charged by electrets.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Greenhouse (1) comprising a top construction (2) with top panels (3) and a strip assembly according to claim 1, wherein said strip assembly is attached in said panels.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Greenhouse according to Claim 14, wherein the angle of said panels with respect to the horizontal is such that, during the most intensive solar irradiation, the panels are positioned substantially perpendicularly to the direction of irradiation.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56986912" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Ensemble de bandes comprenant un porteur (4) pourvu de plusieurs bandes pliables (10-13, 20), <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> lesdites bandes comprennent des électrodes, <b>en ce que</b> ledit ensemble avec lesdites électrodes comprend des électrodes supplémentaires coopérantes (6), chaque électrode étant constituée d'un matériau statiquement chargeable/déchargeable et lesdites électrodes comprenant des connexions de tension électrique (8, 9).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Ensemble de bandes selon la revendication 1, comprenant une source de tension connectée auxdites connexions de tension, dans lequel la connexion desdites bandes a une tension/polarisation différente de celle desdites électrodes supplémentaires.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Ensemble de bandes selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans lequel ladite bande comprend une feuille (10-13, 20) avec un film charnière avec ledit support.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Ensemble de bandes selon la revendication 3, dans lequel ladite feuille est pourvue d'un revêtement.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Ensemble de bandes selon la revendication 3 ou la revendication 4, dans lequel ladite feuille comprend un poly(carbonate), une feuille de poly(ester) ou une feuille à base d'aromatiques.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Ensemble de bandes selon l'une quelconque des revendications 3 à 5, dans lequel ladite feuille comprend une feuille de métal.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Ensemble de bandes selon l'une quelconque des revendications 3 à 6, dans lequel ladite feuille comprend une résistance de surface d'au plus 1 000 MΩ.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Ensemble de bandes selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans lequel lesdites bandes (10-13) sont configurées différemment les unes des autres.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Ensemble de bandes selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans lequel une bande comprend plusieurs parties de feuilles (25-28) attachées de façon à se chevaucher.<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Ensemble de bandes selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans lequel la largeur desdites bandes est d'approximativement 2 cm.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Ensemble de bandes selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, attaché entre deux couches optiquement perméables (4, 5 ; 14, 15).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Ensemble de bandes selon la revendication 11, dans lequel lesdites couches comprennent un matériau plastique transparent ou des couches de verre.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Ensemble de bandes selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans lequel ladite bande et/ou les électrodes supplémentaires sont chargées électrostatiquement par des électrets.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Serre (1) comprenant une construction de dessus (2) avec des panneaux de dessus (3) et un ensemble de bandes selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle ledit ensemble de bandes est attaché dans lesdits panneaux.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Serre selon la revendication 14, dans laquelle l'angle desdits panneaux par rapport à l'horizontale est tel que, pendant l'irradiation solaire la plus intense, les panneaux sont positionnés sensiblement perpendiculairement à la direction d'irradiation.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16672591" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="155" he="231" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="162" he="207" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3,4"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="151" he="226" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
