<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2683133-A1" country="EP" doc-number="2683133" kind="A1" date="20140108" family-id="40885063" file-reference-id="318263" date-produced="20180824" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146585116" ucid="EP-2683133-A1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2683133</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-13186563-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154847308" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>13186563</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20081126</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP175460628" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>13186563.6</doc-number><date>20081126</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140553543" ucid="CN-200810002762-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>CN</country><doc-number>200810002762</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20080116</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140547201" ucid="EP-08870552-A" linkage-type="3" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>08870552</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20081126</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1915458615" load-source="docdb">H04W  68/02        20090101AFI20160718BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1915461666" load-source="docdb">H04W  76/02        20090101ALN20160718BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1915463248" load-source="docdb">H04W  36/00        20090101ALI20160718BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1697566923" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04W  76/18        20180201 LA20180216BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1984036849" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04W  24/02        20130101 LI20160114BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2049527774" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04W  68/02        20130101 LI20150530BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989637673" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04W  36/0022      20130101 FI20131017BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132359981" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Verfahren und Vorrichtung zur Verarbeitung von leitungsvermittelten Diensten in einem Evolved-Packet-Netzwerk</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132359982" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Method and device for processing circuit switched services in an evolved packet network</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132359983" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Procédé et dispositif de traitement de services à commutation de circuits dans un réseau par paquets évolué</invention-title><citations><patent-citations><patcit mxw-id="PCIT242943059" load-source="docdb" ucid="EP-1081971-A1"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>1081971</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20010307</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="I" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT242943060" load-source="docdb" ucid="US-20030026245-A1"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>20030026245</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20030206</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="A" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT242943061" load-source="docdb" ucid="WO-2009000315-A1"><document-id format="epo"><country>WO</country><doc-number>2009000315</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20081231</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="E" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit></patent-citations><non-patent-citations><nplcit><text>3GPP-STANDARDS, 2500 WILSON BOULEVARD, SUITE 300, ARLINGTON, VIRGINIA 22201 USA, 31 December 2007 (2007-12-31), XP040278941</text><sources><source mxw-id="PNPL59403705" load-source="docdb" name="SEA" category="I"/></sources></nplcit><nplcit><text>None</text><sources><source mxw-id="PNPL45210881" load-source="docdb" name="APP"/></sources></nplcit></non-patent-citations></citations></technical-data><related-documents><relation type="division"><child-doc ucid="EP-13186563-A"><document-id load-source="patent-office" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>13186563</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20081126</date></document-id></child-doc><parent-doc ucid="EP-08870552.0"><document-id load-source="patent-office" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>08870552.0</doc-number><date>20081126</date></document-id><parent-grant-document ucid="EP-2228970-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2228970</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20131023</date></document-id></parent-grant-document></parent-doc></relation></related-documents><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919543713" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>HUAWEI TECH CO LTD</last-name><address><country>CN</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919530297" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>HUAWEI TECHNOLOGIES CO., LTD.</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919013375" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Huawei Technologies Co., Ltd.</last-name><iid>101403841</iid><address><street>Intellectual Property Department B1-3A, Bantian Longgang District Shenzhen</street><city>Guangdong 518129</city><country>CN</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919513822" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>YU YIJUN</last-name><address><country>CN</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919537872" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>YU, YIJUN</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919011699" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>YU, YIJUN</last-name><address><street>Huawei Technologies Co., Ltd. Intellectual Property Department B1-3A, Bantian, Longgang District</street><city>Shenzhen, Guangdong</city><country>CN</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919012164" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Kreuz, Georg Maria</last-name><suffix>et al</suffix><iid>101240889</iid><address><street>Huawei Technologies Dessauerstrasse 3</street><city>80992 Munich</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549744633" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549818733" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549815858" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549814824" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549818746" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549744634" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549816685" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549818747" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549818748" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549744925" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549815859" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549814825" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549816706" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549818749" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549816707" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549744635" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549814830" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549818762" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549815860" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549818763" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549815861" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549908565" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549815886" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549815887" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549908566" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549908567" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549744636" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549908568" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549818764" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549742655" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549908569" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549816708" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549744645" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549744926" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA128673288" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p id="pa01" num="0001">The present invention discloses a method, system and device for processing circuit switched (CS) services in an evolved packet network. The method includes: receiving, by a User Equipment, UE, a mobile terminated, MT, service indication from a mobility management entity, MME; notifying, by the UE, the user of the MT service after the UE receives the MT service indication; and sending, by the UE, an MT service response to the MME, wherein the MT service response carries a user choice result. In the method of the present invention, when an MT service arrives, the MME does not trigger the evolved NodeB (eNodeB) to hand over the packet switched (PS) services of the UE but notifies the UE of the MT service and performs subsequent operations according to the MT service response returned by the UE, thus avoiding the waste of network resources caused by a meaningless handover of PS services.
<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="156" he="91" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA128737439" lang="EN" source="EPO" load-source="docdb"><p>The present invention discloses a method, system and device for processing circuit switched (CS) services in an evolved packet network. The method includes: receiving, by a User Equipment, UE, a mobile terminated, MT, service indication from a mobility management entity, MME; notifying, by the UE, the user of the MT service after the UE receives the MT service indication; and sending, by the UE, an MT service response to the MME, wherein the MT service response carries a user choice result. In the method of the present invention, when an MT service arrives, the MME does not trigger the evolved NodeB (eNodeB) to hand over the packet switched (PS) services of the UE but notifies the UE of the MT service and performs subsequent operations according to the MT service response returned by the UE, thus avoiding the waste of network resources caused by a meaningless handover of PS services.</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES63959276" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001"><b><u>Field of the Invention</u></b></heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to communications technologies, and in particular, to a method, system and device for processing circuit switched services in an evolved packet network.</p><heading id="h0002"><b><u>Background of the Invention</u></b></heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">To answer the challenge of wireless broadband technologies and maintain the leadership of the 3<sup>rd</sup> Generation Partnership Project (3GPP) networks, the 3GPP organization prepared a long term evolution (LTE) plan at the end of 2004. Directed by the LTE plan, new mobile communications network architecture is defined, where only the packet switched (PS) domain remains. The architecture is called an evolved packet system (EPS).</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">To enable circuit switched (CS) services in an EPS network, a prior art provides a method for processing CS services in an EPS network, which may be described as a CS fallback method.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">When a mobile switching center (MSC) receives a mobile terminated (MT) service, such as a CS voice call, the MSC sends a page message to a mobility management entity (MME) and the MME pages user equipment (UE) via the EPS network. When an evolved NodeB (eNodeB) receives the page message, the eNodeB first executes a PS service handover, that is, the eNodeB hands over the ongoing PS service of the UE to the PS domain of a general packet radio service/universal mobile telecommunications system (GPRS/UMTS) network. Then, the eNodeB hands over the UE to a 2<sup>nd</sup> generation/3<sup>rd</sup> generation (2G/3G) network, that is, the UE chooses a 2G/3G cell to camp. When the UE<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> returns a page response to the MGC in the GPRS/UMTS network, the eNodeB completes processing of the MT service.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">During research and practice of the prior art, the inventor finds that the prior art has at least the following weaknesses:</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">By using the CS fallback method in the prior art, the eNodeB executes a PS service handover immediately when receiving the page message from the MME, which results in the following problems:
<ol><li>1. Waste of network resources. According to the prior art, when an MT service arrives, the eNodeB hands over the PS service to the PS domain of a 2G/3G network and connects the MT service. In practice, the following case often happens: When the UE is handed over to a 2G/3G network and an MT service is connected, the user rejects the MT service because the user is unwilling or unable to answer. The eNodeB regards such MT services as services that have been completed and the eNodeB then hands over the PS services of the UE to the EPS network. Two PS service handovers are performed for an MT service that is not normally executed, and therefore network resources are wasted.</li><li>2. Impact on the ongoing PS service of the UE. For example, a UE is in a PS service (such as a video conference) in an EPS network when it receives a CS MT service (such as a private call). According to the prior art, the eNodeB hands over the video conference to the PS domain a 2G/3G network, but because the PS domain of the 2G/3G network does not support certain PS services in the EPS network, such as the video conference, the PS service will fail. Thus, the prior art impacts the ongoing PS services.</li></ol></p><heading id="h0003"><b><u>Summary of the Invention</u></b></heading><p id="p0007" num="0007">Embodiments of the present invention provide a method, system and device for processing CS services in an evolved packet network so as to avoid the waste of network resources and not to impact the current PS services of a UE.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p><p id="p0008" num="0008">For the above purpose, the embodiments of the present invention are implemented via the following technical solution:</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">A method for processing CS services in an EPS network includes:
<ul><li>receiving, by a User Equipment, UE, a mobile terminated, MT, service indication from a mobility management entity, MME;</li><li>notifying, by the UE, the user of the MT service after the UE receives the MT service indication; and</li><li>sending, by the UE, an MT service response to the MME, wherein the MT service response carries a user choice result.</li></ul></p><p id="p0010" num="0010">A UE includes:
<ul><li>a notification receiving unit, configured to receive an MT service indication sent by an MME;</li><li>an notifying unit, configured to notify the user of the MT service after the notification receiving unit receives the MT service indication; and</li><li>a response sending unit, configured to return an MT service response to the MME according to a choice of the user regarding the MT service, wherein the MT service response carries a user choice result.</li></ul></p><p id="p0011" num="0011">The technical solution provides the following benefits:</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">In the embodiments of the present invention, when a CS MT service arrives, the MME sends an MT service indication to notify the UE of the MT service and then performs subsequent operations according to an MT service response received from the UE. When the MT service arrives, the MME does not trigger the eNodeB to hand over the PS service of the UE, but notifies the UE of the MT service and carries out subsequent processing according to the MT service response returned by the UE. Thus, the embodiments of the present invention avoid the waste of network resources caused by a meaningless PS service handover and do not impact the ongoing PS services of the UE.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p><heading id="h0004"><b><u>Brief Description of the Drawings</u></b></heading><p id="p0013" num="0013"><ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a flowchart of a CS fallback method provided in an embodiment of the present invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> is a signaling flow of a CS fallback method provided in Embodiment 1 of the present invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> is a signaling flow where a UE is activated and notified of an incoming MT service in Embodiment 1 of the present invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 4</figref> is a signaling flow of a CS fallback method provided in Embodiment 2 of the present invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 5</figref> is a signaling flow where a UE is activated and notified of an incoming MT service in Embodiment 2 of the present invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 6</figref> is a signaling flow of an MT service restoring method provided in an embodiment of the present invention; and</li><li><figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 7</figref> shows a structure of a CS fallback system provided in an embodiment of the present invention.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0005"><b><u>Detailed Description of the Invention</u></b></heading><p id="p0014" num="0014">To better explain the purpose, technical solution and advantages of the present invention, the embodiments of the present invention are hereinafter described in detail with reference to the accompanying drawings.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">When a CS MT service arrives, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, a CS fallback method provided in an embodiment of the present invention includes:
<ul><li>Step 101: An MME receives an MT service indication from an MSC.</li><li>Step 102: The MME forwards the MT service indication to a UE.</li><li>The MT service indication notifies the UE of an MT service.</li><li>Step 103: The MME receives an MT service response from the UE.</li></ul><!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></p><p id="p0016" num="0016">Step 104: The MME carries out subsequent processing according to the MT service response.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">The above is a CS fallback method provided in an embodiment of the present invention. In the embodiment, when a CS MT service arrives, the MME first sends an MT service indication to notify the UE of the MT service and after reception of the MT service response from the UE, the MME carries out subsequent processing according to the MT service response. In the method provided in the embodiment of the present invention, when an MT service arrives, the MME does not trigger the eNodeB to hand over the PS service of the UE, but notifies the UE of the MT service and carries out subsequent processing according to the MT service response returned by the UE. Thus, the method avoids the waste of network resources caused by a meaningless PS service handover and does not impact the ongoing PS service of the UE.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">In a specific implementation of the embodiment of the present invention, the MT service response may carry a user choice result. If the use chooses to reject the MT service, the MME returns an MT service Reject message to the MSC when the MME carries out subsequent processing according to the MT service response.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">If the user chooses to accept the MT service, the MME sends a PS service handover request to the eNodeB and the eNodeB executes a PS service handover when the eNodeB receives the handover request and hands the UE over to a 2G/3G network. After the UE is handed over to the 2G/3G network, the eNodeB sends a first page response to the MSC and completes MT service processing.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">In another embodiment of the present invention, if the user chooses to accept the MT service, the MME does not hand over the current PS service of the UE according to a configured network operation policy and therefore, the MME does not need to send a PS service handover request to the eNodeB and the eNodeB does not need to execute a PS handover later. In this case, after the UE sends the response indicating acceptance of the MT service, or receives a response from the MME regarding the UE's acceptance of the<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> MT service, the UE accesses the 2G/3G network directly to complete the MT service processing.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">The above describes the CS fallback method provided in an embodiment of the present invention. The following describes specific signaling flows of the method.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>, a signaling flow of the CS fallback method in Embodiment 1 of the present invention includes:
<ul><li>Step 201: The MSC receives an MT service indication and sends a first page message to the MME.</li></ul></p><p id="p0023" num="0023">In practice, the first page message may carry an international mobile subscriber identity (IMSI) of the UE.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">Step 202: When receiving the first page message, the MME queries the UE state. If the UE is in idle mode, the MME sends a second page message to the eNodeB. If the UE is in active mode, the process proceeds to step 205.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">In practice, the first page message may carry the MT service indication sent by the MSC to the MME. Therefore, the first page message may be named MT service request or alike. In addition, if the first page message carries the MT service indication, in step 302, after the MME receives the first page message, the MME needs to parse the first page message and query the UE state after the MT service indication is obtained.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">In addition, the first page message may not carry the MT service indication. In this case, the MME is set to query the UE state once it receives the first page message. In this case, the first page message is equivalent to an MT service indication.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">Step 203: The eNodeB broadcasts the second page message in the cell it manages.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">Step 204: The UE receives the second page message and returns a service request to the MME.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">The MME sends the second page message via the eNodeB to activate the idle UE.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p><p id="p0030" num="0030">Step 205: After receiving of the service request, the MME sends an MT service indication to the UE. The MT service indication is intended to notify the UE of the MT service.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">The MT service indication shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> is a non access stratum (NAS) message and therefore it may be sent to the UE directly from the MME. In another embodiment of the present invention, the MT service indication is an access stratum message (such as Page). The access stratum message may carry the MT service indication and is sent by the MME to the eNodeB and forwarded by the eNodeB to the UE. This does not impact the implementation of the present invention.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">Step 206: After the UE receives the MT service indication, the UE notifies the user of the MT service.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">In practice, the UE notifies the user of the MT service according to the presetting of the user. For example, the UE may ring, or vibrate, or ring and vibrate, or give a text notify, to notify the user of the MT service.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">After the user makes a choice regarding the MT service, the UE executes step 207.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">Step 207: The UE sends an MT service response to the MME.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">The MT service response may carry the user choice result (accept or reject) or the MT service response does not carry a user choice result, that is, the user choice result is null. If the MT service response does not carry a user choice result, the MME may decide the user choice according to default settings. A common scenario is that, if the MT service response does not carry the choice result, the MME thinks that the user accepts the MT service by default.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">Step 208: The MME obtains the choice result carried in the MT service response. If the user chooses to reject the MT service, the MME sends a first page reject message (the foregoing MT service reject). If the user chooses to accept the MT service, the process proceeds to step 209.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></p><p id="p0038" num="0038">If the UE rejects the MT service, it is unnecessary to execute the MT service and the MME returns a first page reject message to the MSC to end the MT service. In the method provided in the embodiment of the present invention, if the UE does not execute the MT service, the eNodeB does not hand over the PS service of the UE. Thus the method avoids the waste of network resources caused by a meaningless PS handover and will not impact the current PS service of the UE.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">The first page reject message may carry a cause value indicating the reason for rejecting the MT service or the message may not carry the cause value. Whether the message carries the cause value does not impact the implementation of the present invention.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">In addition, the case often happens in daily life that the user does not see or feel the notifying of the UE in a long time. To improve the work efficiency of the MME, it may be defined in advance that, if the MME does not receive the MT service response from the UE within a preset time T, the MME thinks that the user rejects the MT service. And in this case, the MME sends the first page reject message to the MSC to reject the MT service.</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">Step 209: The MME sends a PS service handover request to the eNodeB.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">Step 210: The eNodeB receives the PS service handover request and initiates a PS service handover procedure to hand the UE over to the 2G/3G network.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">Step 211: After the UE is handed over to the 2G/3G network, the UE sends a first page response and completes the MT service processing.</p><p id="p0044" num="0044">In another embodiment of the present invention, after the MME receives the first page message, the MME may not query the UE state but thinks the UE is in idle mode by default. Then, the MME sends a second page message and an MT service indication to the UE to notify the active or idle UE of the MT service.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045">The above is a signaling flow provided in Embodiment 1 of the present invention. When the MME receives the first page message sent by the MSC in step 201, the MME<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> may notify an idle or active UE of the MT service via steps 202-205 in Embodiment 1 of the present invention or via the signaling flow shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3</figref>. The signaling flow includes:
<ul><li>Step 301: The MME receives a first page message from the MSC and sends a third page message to the eNodeB. The third page message carries at least an MT service indication.</li></ul></p><p id="p0046" num="0046">In practice, the MT service indication may be a page cause value in the third page message or an independent information element in the third page message, which will not impact the implementation of the present invention.</p><p id="p0047" num="0047">Step 302: The eNodeB broadcasts the third page message in the cell it manages.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048">Step 303: After the UE receives the third page message, the UE notifies the user of the MT service.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">The signaling flow shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> is different from steps 202-205 in Embodiment 1 of the present invention in the following aspects:</p><p id="p0050" num="0050">In Embodiment 1 of the present invention, the MME sends a message to notify the UE of an MT service only when the UE is in active mode. The UE may be already in active mode when the MME receives the first page message, or the UE may be activated through paging by the MME. In the signaling flow shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3</figref>, however, the MME does not check whether the UE is in active mode but notifies the UE of an MT service directly via a third page message.</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">Specifically, in Embodiment 1 of the present invention, when the UE is in idle mode, the MME sends the second page message and the MT service indication to notify the UE of the MT service; when the UE is in active mode, the MME sends the MT service indication directly to notify the UE of the MT service. The benefit of this signaling flow is that it does not impact the paging mechanism in the existing EPS network.<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></p><p id="p0052" num="0052">In the signaling flow shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3</figref>, the MME sends a third page message that carries the MT service indication to notify the UE of the MT service. The benefit is that it increases the processing efficiency of the MME and reduces the call delay.</p><p id="p0053" num="0053">To let the UE know information of the MT service originator to help the user make a choice regarding the MT service, in the preceding and following embodiments of the present invention, the first page message sent by the MSC to the MME may further carry MT service related information.</p><p id="p0054" num="0054">The MT service related information includes: a mobile station ISDN (MSISDN) of the originator, or a service type indication, such as short message service (SMS), location service (LCS), and unstructured supplementary service data (USSD). In addition, to help the MSC determine the MT service associated with the received MT service response, the MT service related information may further include an MT service ID that is allocated by the MSC or an existing ID (like a call number).</p><p id="p0055" num="0055">Because the first page message sent by the MSC to the MME carries the MT service related information, the page message or MT service indication sent by the MME to the UE may further carry the MT service related information. In this case, the UE notifies the user of the MT service according to the received MT service related information according to the presetting of the user. For example, the UE may display the MSISDN of the originator to the user or notify the user of the service type.</p><p id="p0056" num="0056">In the foregoing method, the user may choose to accept or reject the service. In certain scenarios, however, the user wishes to process the MT service after waiting for some time. It is therefore necessary to hold the MT service. Embodiment 2 of the present invention provides another CS fallback method. The method includes the following step based on the method shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>:</p><p id="p0057" num="0057">If the user chooses to hold the MT service, the MME sends an MT service Hold message to the MSC.<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --></p><p id="p0058" num="0058">In addition, to guarantee that the MT service is restorable, the method further includes:</p><p id="p0059" num="0059">If the UE requests restoration of the held MT service, the MME notifies the MSC to restore the MT service; the MSC judges whether the MT service can be restored and if the service can be restored, the MSC notifies the UE of accessing the 2G/3G network via the MME and the UE then completes the MT service, or the MME triggers the eNodeB to hand the UE over to the 2G/3G network to complete the MT service according to a configured operation policy. If the MSC cannot restore the MT service, the restoration procedure is ended.</p><p id="p0060" num="0060"><figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 4</figref> shows a signaling flow of the CS fallback method in Embodiment 2 of the present invention. The signaling flow allows the user to choose to hold the MT service. The signaling flow includes:</p><p id="p0061" num="0061">Step 401: The MSC receives an MT service request and sends a first page message to the MME.</p><p id="p0062" num="0062">To avoid long-term MT service holding that consumes system resources, the method may further include a step of presetting a call hold timer and the first page message further carries the call hold timer length.</p><p id="p0063" num="0063">Step 402: The MME queries the state of the UE associated with the IMSI. If the UE is in idle mode, the MME sends a fourth page message to the eNodeB. If the UE is in active mode, the process proceeds to step 405.</p><p id="p0064" num="0064">Step 403: The eNodeB broadcasts the fourth page message in the cell it manages.</p><p id="p0065" num="0065">Step 404: The UE receives the fourth page message and returns a service request to the MME.</p><p id="p0066" num="0066">Step 405: The MME sends an MT service indication to the UE to notify the UE of an MT service.<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></p><p id="p0067" num="0067">The ME service indication may or may not carry the MT service related information and/or the call hold timer length, which does not impact the implementation of the present invention.</p><p id="p0068" num="0068">Step 406: After the UE receives the MT service indication, the UE notifies the user of the MT service.</p><p id="p0069" num="0069">In practice, if the MT service indication carries the MT service related information, the UE notifies the user of the MT service according to the received MT service related information according to the presetting of the user. For example, the UE may display the MSISDN of the originator to the user or notify the user of the service type. The UE may ring, or vibrate, or ring and vibrate, or give a text notify to notify the user of the MT service.</p><p id="p0070" num="0070">After the user makes a choice regarding the MT service, the UE executes step 407.</p><p id="p0071" num="0071">Step 407: The UE sends an MT service response to the MME.</p><p id="p0072" num="0072">The MT service response may carry the user choice result (accept or reject) or the MT service response does not carry a user choice result, that is, the user choice result is null. If the MT service response does not carry a user choice result, the MME may decide the user choice according to default settings. A common scenario is that, if the MT service response does not carry the choice result, the MME thinks that the user accepts the MT service by default.</p><p id="p0073" num="0073">If the user chooses to hold the service, the UE starts the associated timer according to the call hold timer length.</p><p id="p0074" num="0074">Step 408: The MME obtains the choice result carried in the MT service response. If the user chooses to hold the MT service, the MME sends an MT service Hold message to the MSC; if the user chooses to reject or accept the MT service, the subsequent steps are the same as the procedure provided in Embodiment 1 of the present invention.</p><p id="p0075" num="0075">Step 409: The MSC starts the associated timer according to the preset call hold timer length.<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --></p><p id="p0076" num="0076">In another embodiment of the present invention, after the MME receives the first page message, the MME may not query the UE state but thinks the UE is in idle mode by default. Then, the MME sends the fourth page message and the MT service indication to the UE to notify the active or idle UE of the MT service.</p><p id="p0077" num="0077">The above is a specific signaling flow of the CS fallback method provided in Embodiment 2 of the present invention. The active or idle UE may be notified of the MT service via steps 402-405. In another embodiment of the present invention, the signaling flow shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 5</figref> may be adopted to notify an active or idle UE of an MT service. The signaling flow includes:
<ul><li>Step 501: The MME receives a first page message from the MSC and sends a fifth page message to the eNodeB. The fifth page message carries at least an MT service indication.</li></ul></p><p id="p0078" num="0078">To avoid long-term MT service holding that consumes system resources and help the user make a choice regarding the MT service, the MT service request may further carry a preset call hold timer length and/or MT service related information.</p><p id="p0079" num="0079">Step 502: The eNodeB broadcasts the fifth page message in the cell it manages.</p><p id="p0080" num="0080">Step 503: After the UE receives the fifth page message, the UE notify the user of the MT service.</p><p id="p0081" num="0081">The CS fallback method provided in the embodiments of the present invention and the specific implementation procedures are described above.</p><p id="p0082" num="0082">For a user-held MT service, if the user chooses to continue the service, the MT service needs to be restored. When the user requests restoration of the MT service, if the UE starts a timer when the MT service is held, the UE needs to check whether the timer has expired. If the timer has expired, the restoration procedure is over. If the timer has not expired, the restoration procedure is executed. With respect to the above MT service restoration procedure, an embodiment of the present invention provides a signaling flow for MT service restoration. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 6</figref>, the signaling flow includes:<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> -->
<ul><li>Step 601: If the UE is currently in idle mode, the UE sends a service request to the MME. When the UE becomes active from the idle mode, step 602 is executed. If the UE is in active mode, step 602 is executed directly.</li><li>Step 602: The UE sends a first MT service activation request to the MME, requesting to restore the held MT service.</li></ul></p><p id="p0083" num="0083">The MT service activation request may carry the ID of the MT service to be activated so that the MME can determine the MT service. In certain scenarios (if the UE holds only one service), the MT service ID may not be carried, which does not impact the implementation of the present invention.</p><p id="p0084" num="0084">Step 603: The MME sends a second MT service activation request to the MSC.</p><p id="p0085" num="0085">Step 604: After the MSC receives the second MT service activation request, the MSC matches the MT service ID with the held MT service. If the service exists, the MSC accepts the activation request, stops the call hold timer, allocates the requested resource, and sends a second MT service activation response to the MME. The second MT service activation response carries a cause value of the successful operation. Otherwise, the MSC rejects the activation request and sends a second MT service activation response to the MME. The second MT service activation response carries a cause value of the failed operation.</p><p id="p0086" num="0086">In addition, if the call hold timer in the MSC expires, the MSC stops holding the MT service, releases the held resource, and stops the timer.</p><p id="p0087" num="0087">Optionally, different response messages may be sent to the MME in the scenarios of success and failure. The response message may also carry the MT service ID to help the UE determine the MT service.</p><p id="p0088" num="0088">Step 605: When the MME receives the second MT service activation response, the MME may send a first MT service activation response to the UE.</p><p id="p0089" num="0089">The first MT service activation response may carry the MT service ID carried in the second MT service activation response. Alternatively, the MME may not send the first<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> MT service activation response and the implementation of the present invention will not be impacted.</p><p id="p0090" num="0090">Step 606: The MME sends a PS service handover request to the eNodeB.</p><p id="p0091" num="0091">In practice, the MME may proceed without handing over the current PS service of the UE according to the configured network operation policy and therefore the MME does not need to send a PS service handover request to the eNodeB and the eNodeB does not need to execute the PS handover procedure.</p><p id="p0092" num="0092">Step 607: The eNodeB receives the PS service handover request and initiates a PS service handover procedure to hand the UE over to the 2G/3G network.</p><p id="p0093" num="0093">Step 608: After the UE is handed over to the 2G/3G network, the UE sends the first page response and completes the MT service processing.</p><p id="p0094" num="0094">The above describes the CS fallback method provided in the embodiments of the present invention. In the CS fallback scenario, an SMS MT service may be sent to the UE via signaling of the UE in the EPS network without the need to hand over the UE to a 2G/3G network. For example, the first page message may carry the short message content and then the short message is sent to the UE via the EPS network. The UE receives the short message and completes related processing.</p><p id="p0095" num="0095">Those skilled in the art may understand that all or part of the steps of the method in the above embodiments of the present invention may be implemented by hardware under instructions of a program. The program may be stored in a computer-readable storage medium. When the program is executed, the following steps are performed:
<ul><li>by an MME, receiving an MT service indication from an MSC;</li><li>sending the MT service indication to a UE; and</li><li>receiving an MT service response returned by the UE and performing subsequent operations according to the MT service response.</li></ul></p><p id="p0096" num="0096">The storage medium may be a read-only memory, a magnetic disk or a compact disk.<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></p><p id="p0097" num="0097"><figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 7</figref> shows a CS fallback system provided in an embodiment of the present invention. The system includes: an MME 701, an MSC 702, and an eNodeB 703.</p><p id="p0098" num="0098">The MSC 702 includes a service indication sending unit 7021.</p><p id="p0099" num="0099">The service indication sending unit 7021 is configured to send an MT service indication to the MME 701 after receiving the MT service indication.</p><p id="p0100" num="0100">The MME 701 provided in the embodiment of the present invention includes:
<ul><li>a page message receiving unit 7011, configured to receive the MT service indication from the MSC 702;</li><li>an MT service notifying unit 7012, configured to send the MT service indication to a UE 704;</li><li>a response receiving unit 7013, configured to receive the MT service response returned by the UE 704; and</li><li>a response processing unit 7014, configured to perform subsequent operations according to the MT service response.</li></ul></p><p id="p0101" num="0101">In practice, the MT service response carries a user choice result and the response processing unit 7014 includes:
<ul><li>a first response processing unit, configured to return an MT service Reject message to the MSC 702 if the user chooses to reject the MT service;</li><li>a second response processing unit, configured to return an MT service Hold message to the MSC 702 if the user chooses to hold the MT service; and</li><li>a third response processing unit, configured to trigger the UE 704 to access a 2G/3G network if the user chooses to accept the MT service or if the user choice result is null.</li></ul></p><p id="p0102" num="0102">To enable the UE to restore the held MT service, the MME 701 further includes:
<ul><li>an activation request receiving unit, configured to receive a first MT service activation request sent by the UE 704, requesting to restore the held MT service;</li><li>an activation request sending unit, configured to send a second MT service activation request to the MSC 702; and<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></li><li>an activation response receiving unit, configured to receive a second MT service activation response returned by the MSC 702 and indicates to the UE 704 that the UE 704 should access the 2G/3G network.</li></ul></p><p id="p0103" num="0103">The MSC 702 further includes:
<ul><li>an activation request receiving unit, configured to receive the second MT service activation request from the MME; and</li><li>an activation response sending unit, configured to return the second MT service activation response after the activation request receiving unit receives the request.</li></ul></p><p id="p0104" num="0104">Because some UEs are in idle mode in the EPS network, to activate the UEs, the MT service notifying unit 7012 includes:
<ul><li>a UE activating unit, configured to activate the UE 704 via the eNodeB 703;</li><li>a state querying unit, configured to: query the state of the UE 704, and trigger a sending unit if the UE 704 is in active mode, or trigger the UE activating unit if the UE 704 is in idle mode; and</li><li>the sending unit, configured to send the MT service indication to the UE 704 if the UE 704 is in active mode.</li></ul></p><p id="p0105" num="0105">In practice, the UE activating unit has two implementations.</p><p id="p0106" num="0106">In the first implementation, the unit includes:
<ul><li>a page message sending unit, configured to send a second page message to the eNodeB 703; and</li><li>a service request receiving unit, configured to trigger the MT service notifying unit 7012 after receiving the service request returned by the UE 704.</li></ul></p><p id="p0107" num="0107">In the second implementation, the UE activating unit is an activating and notifying unit.</p><p id="p0108" num="0108">The activating and notifying unit is configured to send a third page message that carries an MT service indication to the eNodeB 703. By sending the third page message to the eNodeB 703, the UE is activated and the MT service indication is sent to the UE.<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --></p><p id="p0109" num="0109">An embodiment of the present invention provides an MME for processing of the SMS MT service in a CS fallback scenario. The MME may include:
<ul><li>a receiving unit, configured to receive a short message from an MSC;</li><li>a state judging unit, configured to judge whether a UE is in active or idle mode;</li><li>a sending unit, configured to send the short message received by the receiving unit to the UE when the state judging unit determines that the UE is in active mode;</li><li>an activating and sending unit, configured to activate the UE when the state judging unit determines that the UE is in idle mode and send the short message received by the receiving unit to the activated UE; and</li><li>a short message response receiving unit, configured to receive a short message response from the UE.</li></ul></p><p id="p0110" num="0110">The activating and sending unit may include:
<ul><li>a page sending unit, configured to send a second page message to the eNodeB;</li><li>a returned message receiving unit, configured to receive a service request returned by the UE; and</li><li>a short message sending unit, configured to send the short message to the UE according to the service request received by the returned message receiving unit.</li></ul></p><p id="p0111" num="0111">Or, the activating and sending unit may include:
<ul><li>a page sending unit, configured to send a third page message that carries the short message to the eNodeB.</li></ul></p><p id="p0112" num="0112"><figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 7</figref> shows the UE 704 provided in an embodiment of the present invention. The UE 704 includes:
<ul><li>a notification receiving unit 7041, configured to receive the MT service indication sent by the MME 701;</li><li>an notifying unit 7042, configured to notify the user of the MT service after the notification receiving unit 7041 receives the MT service indication; and<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --></li><li>a response sending unit 7043, configured to return an MT service response to the MME according to the choice of the user regarding the MT service.</li></ul></p><p id="p0113" num="0113">To make the held MT service restorable, the UE may further include:
<ul><li>an activation request sending unit, configured to send a first MT service activation request to the MME, requesting to restore the held MT service.</li></ul></p><p id="p0114" num="0114">Further, the UE may include an MT service processing unit, configured to process the MT service.</p><p id="p0115" num="0115">Although the present invention has been described through several exemplary embodiments, the invention is not limited to such embodiments. It is apparent that those skilled in the art can make various modifications and variations to the invention without departing from the spirit and scope of the present invention. The invention is intended to cover the modifications and variations provided that they fall within the scope of protection defined by the following claims or their equivalents.</p><p id="p0116" num="0116">Below examples for processing CS services in an EPS network are provided.</p><heading id="h0006">Example 1:</heading><p id="p0117" num="0117">A method for processing CS services in an evolved packet network, comprising: receiving, by a MME, a MT service indication from a MSC; sending, by the MME, the MT service indication to a UE; and receiving, by the MME, an MT service response returned by the UE and performing subsequent operations according to the MT service response.</p><heading id="h0007">Example 2:</heading><p id="p0118" num="0118">The method of Example 1, wherein the MT service response carries a user choice result and the step of performing subsequent operations comprises: if the user choice result is to reject the MT service, returning, by the MME, an MT service reject message<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> to the MSC; if the user choice result is to hold the MT service, returning, by the MME, an MT service hold message to the MSC; if the user choice result is to accept the MT service, triggering, by the MME, the UE to access a 2G/3G network; and if the user choice result is null, judging, by the MME, the user choice result according to default settings.</p><heading id="h0008">Example 3:</heading><p id="p0119" num="0119">The method of Example 2, wherein, after the MME returns an MT service hold message to the MSC, if the user requests restoration of the held MT service, the method further comprises: receiving, by the MME, a first MT service activation request from the UE that requests restoration of the held MT service; sending, by the MME, a second MT service activation request to the MSC; and returning, by the MSC, a second MT service activation response to the MME, notifying the UE to access the 2G/3G network.</p><heading id="h0009">Example 4:</heading><p id="p0120" num="0120">The method of Example 3, wherein the MT service activation request carries an MT service ID and the step of returning the second MT service activation response to the MME comprises: by the MSC, matching the MT service ID with a held MT service, and if the MT service exists, accepting the activation request and sending the second MT service activation response to the MME.</p><heading id="h0010">Example 5:</heading><p id="p0121" num="0121">The method of any of Examples 1-4, wherein the MT service indication comprises MT service related information.</p><heading id="h0011">Example 6:</heading><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --><p id="p0122" num="0122">The method of any of Examples 1-4, further comprising: by the UE, receiving the MT service indication, notifying the user of the MT service, and returning an MT service response to the MME according to a choice of the user.</p><heading id="h0012">Example 7:</heading><p id="p0123" num="0123">The method of any of Examples 1-4, wherein the step of sending the MT service indication to the UE comprises: by the MME, querying a state of the UE, and sending the MT service indication to the UE if the UE is in active mode or activating the UE via an eNodeB and sending the MT service indication to the UE if the UE is in idle mode.</p><heading id="h0013">Example 8:</heading><p id="p0124" num="0124">The method of Example 7, wherein the step of activating the UE via the eNodeB and sending the MT service indication to the UE comprises: sending, by the MME, a second page message to the eNodeB; broadcasting, by the eNodeB, the second page message to UEs in a cell managed by the eNodeB and receiving, by the MME, a service request returned by the UE; and sending, by the MME, the MT service indication to the UE.</p><heading id="h0014">Example 9:</heading><p id="p0125" num="0125">The method of Example 7, wherein the step of activating the UE via the eNodeB and sending the MT service indication to the UE comprises: sending, by the MME, a third page message that carries the MT service indication to the eNodeB; and broadcasting, by the eNodeB, the third page message to UEs in a cell managed by the eNodeB.</p><heading id="h0015">Example 10:</heading><p id="p0126" num="0126">A method for processing CS services in an evolved packet network, comprising: receiving, by a MME, a short message from a MSC; by the MME, sending the short message to a UE if the UE is active and activating the UE and sending the short message<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> to the UE if the UE is idle; and receiving, by the MME, a short message response from the UE.</p><heading id="h0016">Example 11:</heading><p id="p0127" num="0127">The method of Example 10, wherein the step of activating the UE and sending the short message to the UE comprises: sending, by the MME, a second page message to an eNodeB; broadcasting, by the eNodeB, the second page message to UEs in a cell managed by the eNodeB; receiving, by the MME, a service request from the UE; and sending, by the MME, the short message to the UE according to the service request.</p><heading id="h0017">Example 12:</heading><p id="p0128" num="0128">The method of Example 10, wherein the step of activating the UE and sending the short message to the UE comprises: sending, by the MME, a third page message that carries the short message to an eNodeB; and broadcasting, by the eNodeB, the third page message to UEs in a cell managed by the eNodeB.</p><heading id="h0018">Example 13:</heading><p id="p0129" num="0129">A MME, comprising: a page message receiving unit, configured to receive a MT service indication from a MSC; an MT service notifying unit, configured to send the MT service indication to a UE; a response receiving unit, configured to receive an MT service response returned by the UE; and a response processing unit, configured to perform subsequent operations according to the MT service response.</p><heading id="h0019">Example 14:</heading><p id="p0130" num="0130">The MME of Example 13, wherein the MT service response carries a user choice result and the response processing unit comprises: a first response processing unit, configured to return an MT service Reject message to the MSC if the user choice result is<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> to reject the MT service; and/or a second response processing unit, configured to return an MT service Hold message to the MSC if the user choice result is to hold the MT service; and/or a third response processing unit, configured to trigger the UE to access a 2G/3G network if the user choice result is to accept the MT service or if the user choice result is null.</p><heading id="h0020">Example 15:</heading><p id="p0131" num="0131">The MME of Example 14, after the MME returns an MT service hold message to the MSC, if the user requests restoration of the held MT service, further comprising: an activation request receiving unit, configured to receive a first MT service activation request sent by the UE that requests restoration of the held MT service; an activation request sending unit, configured to send a second MT service activation request to the MSC; and an activation response receiving unit, configured to receive a second MT service activation response returned by the MSC and notify the UE to access the 2G/3G network.</p><heading id="h0021">Example 16:</heading><p id="p0132" num="0132">The MME of any of Examples 13-15, wherein the MT service notifying unit comprises: a UE activating unit, configured to activate the UE via an eNodeB; a state querying unit, configured to: query a state of the UE and trigger a sending unit if the UE is in active mode, or trigger the UE activating unit if the UE is in idle mode; and the sending unit, configured to send the MT service indication to the UE if the UE is in active mode.</p><heading id="h0022">Example 17:</heading><p id="p0133" num="0133">The MME of Example 16, wherein the MT service notifying unit comprises: a page message sending unit, configured to send a second page message to the eNodeB; and a<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --> service request receiving unit, configured to trigger the MT service notifying unit after receiving a service request returned by the UE.</p><heading id="h0023">Example 18:</heading><p id="p0134" num="0134">The MME of Example 17, wherein the UE activating unit is an activating and notifying unit, configured to: send a third page message that carries the MT service indication to the eNodeB.</p><heading id="h0024">Example 19:</heading><p id="p0135" num="0135">A MME, comprising: a receiving unit, configured to receive a short message from a MSC; a state judging unit, configured to judge whether a user equipment (UE) is active or idle; a sending unit, configured to send the short message received by the receiving unit to the UE when the state judging unit determines that the UE is active; an activating and sending unit, configured to activate the UE when the state judging unit determines that the UE is idle and send the short message received by the receiving unit to the activated UE; and a short message response receiving unit, configured to receive a short message response from the UE.</p><heading id="h0025">Example 20:</heading><p id="p0136" num="0136">The MME of Example 19, wherein: the activating and sending unit comprises: a page sending unit, configured to send a second page message to an eNodeB; a returned message receiving unit, configured to receive a service request returned by the UE; a short message sending unit, configured to send the short message to the UE according to the service request received by the returned message receiving unit; or the activating and sending unit comprises: a page sending unit, configured to send a third page message that carries the short message to the eNodeB.<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --></p><heading id="h0026">Example 21:</heading><p id="p0137" num="0137">A UE, comprising: a notification receiving unit, configured to receive a MT service indication sent by a MME; an notifying unit, configured to notify the user of the MT service after the notification receiving unit receives the MT service indication; and a response sending unit, configured to return an MT service response to the MME according to a choice of the user regarding the MT service.</p><heading id="h0027">Example 22:</heading><p id="p0138" num="0138">The UE of Example 21, further comprising: an activation request sending unit, configured to send a first MT service activation request to the MME, requesting to restore a held MT service.</p><heading id="h0028">Example 23:</heading><p id="p0139" num="0139">The UE of Example 21 or 22, further comprising: an MT service processing unit, configured to process the MT service.</p><heading id="h0029">Example 24:</heading><p id="p0140" num="0140">A system for processing CS services in an evolved packet network, comprising a MSC and a MME, wherein: the MSC comprises a service indication sending unit, configured to send a MT service indication to the MME after receiving the MT service indication; the MME comprises: a page message receiving unit, configured to receive the MT service indication from the MSC; an MT service notifying unit, configured to send the MT service indication to a UE; a response receiving unit, configured to receive an MT service response returned by the UE; and a response processing unit, configured to perform subsequent operations according to the MT service response.</p><heading id="h0030">Example 25:</heading><!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --><p id="p0141" num="0141">The system of Example 24, wherein the MT service response carries a user choice result and the response processing unit comprises: a first response processing unit, configured to return an MT service Reject message to the MSC if the user choice result is to reject the MT service; a second response processing unit, configured to return an MT service Hold message to the MSC if the user choice result is to hold the MT service; and a third response processing unit, configured to trigger the UE to access a 2G/3G network if the user choice result is to accept the MT service or if the user choice result is null.</p><heading id="h0031">Example 26:</heading><p id="p0142" num="0142">The system of Example 25, after the second response processing unit returns an MT service hold message to the MSC, if the user requests restoration of the held MT service, further comprising: an activation request receiving unit, configured to receive a first MT service activation request sent by the UE that requests restoration of the held MT service;<br/>
an activation request sending unit, configured to send a second MT service activation request to the MSC; and an activation response receiving unit, configured to receive a second MT service activation response returned by the MSC and notify the UE to access the 2G/3G network.</p><heading id="h0032">Example 27:</heading><p id="p0143" num="0143">The system of Example 24, wherein the MSC further comprises: an activation request receiving unit, configured to receive the second MT service activation request from the MME; and an activation response sending unit, configured to return the second MT service activation response after the activation request receiving unit receives the request.</p><heading id="h0033">Example 28:</heading><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --><p id="p0144" num="0144">The system of any of Examples 24-27, further comprising an eNodeB and the MME further comprises: a UE activating unit, configured to activate the UE via the eNodeB; and a state querying unit, configured to: query a state of the UE and trigger the MT service notifying unit if the UE is in active mode, or trigger the UE activating unit if the UE is in idle mode.</p><heading id="h0034">Example 29:</heading><p id="p0145" num="0145">The system of Example 28, wherein the UE activating unit comprises: a page message sending unit, configured to send a second page message to the eNodeB; and a service request receiving unit, configured to trigger the MT service notifying unit after receiving a service request returned by the UE.</p><heading id="h0035">Example 30:</heading><p id="p0146" num="0146">The system of Example 28, wherein the UE activating unit is an activating and notifying unit, configured to send a third page message that carries the MT service indication to the eNodeB.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56982307" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --><claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A method for processing circuit switched, CS, services in an evolved packet system, EPS, network, comprising:
<claim-text>receiving (205, 405), by a User Equipment, UE, a mobile terminated, MT, service indication from a mobility management entity, MME;</claim-text>
<claim-text>notifying (206, 406), by the UE, the user of the MT service after the UE receives the MT service indication; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>sending (207, 407), by the UE, an MT service response to the MME, wherein the MT service response carries a user choice result.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The method of claim 1, further comprising:
<claim-text>processing, by the UE, the MT service.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The method of claim 1 or 2, further comprising:
<claim-text>receiving (101), by the MME, the service indication from a mobile switching center, MSC.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The method of any of claims 1-3, further comprising:
<claim-text>performing (104), by the MME, subsequent operations according to the MT service response.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The method of any of claims 1-4, wherein the step of performing subsequent operations according to the MT service response comprises:
<claim-text>if the user choice result is to reject the MT service, returning, by the MME, an MT service reject message to the MSC; or</claim-text>
<claim-text>if the user choice result is to accept the MT service, triggering, by the MME, the UE to access a 2<sup>nd</sup> generation or 3<sup>rd</sup> generation, 2G/3G, network.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The method of any of claims 1-5, wherein the MT service indication comprises MT service related information.<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The method of any of claims 1-6, further comprising:
<claim-text>receiving, by the UE, the MT service indication, notifying the user of the MT service, and returning the MT service response to the MME according to a choice of the user.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>A user equipment, UE, comprising:
<claim-text>a notification receiving unit (7041), configured to receive a mobile terminated, MT service indication sent by a mobility management entity, MME;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an notifying unit (7042), configured to notify the user of the MT service after the notification receiving unit receives the MT service indication; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a response sending unit (7043), configured to return an MT service response to the MME according to a choice of the user regarding the MT service, wherein the MT service response carries a user choice result.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The UE of claim 8, further comprising:
<claim-text>an MT service processing unit, configured to process the MT service.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16670690" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="116" he="140" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="143" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="152" he="84" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --><figure id="f0004" num="4"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="141" he="222" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --><figure id="f0005" num="5,6"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="160" he="211" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --><figure id="f0006" num="7"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="165" he="179" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><search-report-data><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="158" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="155" he="233" type="tif"/></search-report-data><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
