<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2959753-A1" country="EP" doc-number="2959753" kind="A1" date="20151230" family-id="49935273" file-reference-id="254717" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="160452348" ucid="EP-2959753-A1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2959753</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20151230</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-14845147-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP193867664" load-source="patent-office" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>14845147.9</doc-number><date>20140903</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP193867665" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>14845147</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20140903</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC162029753" ucid="CN-201310429592-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>CN</country><doc-number>201310429592</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20130918</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC162031335" ucid="CN-2014085872-W" linkage-type="W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>CN</country><doc-number>2014085872</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20140903</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1871694550" load-source="docdb">H05B  37/02        20060101AFI20161125BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1871694551" load-source="docdb">H05B  33/08        20060101ALI20161125BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1987771442" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H05B  37/02        20130101 LI20150819BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1987788066" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H05B  33/0845      20130101 FI20150813BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT165548510" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">LED-ANTRIEBS- UND DIMMERSCHALTUNG SOWIE KONFIGURATIONSVERFAHREN</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT165548511" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">LED DRIVING AND DIMMING CIRCUIT AND CONFIGURATION METHOD</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT165548512" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">CIRCUIT D'ATTAQUE ET DE GRADATION D'INTENSITÉ DE DEL ET PROCÉDÉ DE CONFIGURATION</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR1103332560" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>ZHEJIANG SHENGHUI LIGHTING CO</last-name><address><country>CN</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR1103334810" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>ZHEJIANG SHENGHUI LIGHTING CO., LTD</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR1101641494" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Zhejiang Shenghui Lighting Co., Ltd</last-name><iid>101500790</iid><address><street>West Jiachuang Road Xiuzhou Industrial Park</street><city>Jiaxing, Zhejiang 314015</city><country>CN</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1103306666" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>LOU JUNSHAN</last-name><address><country>CN</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1103317976" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>LOU, JUNSHAN</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1101643913" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>LOU, JUNSHAN</last-name><address><street>Zhejiang Shenghui Lighting Co. Ltd West Jiachuang Road Xiuzhou Industrial Park</street><city>Jiaxing Zhejiang 314015</city><country>CN</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1103316229" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>SHEN JINXIANG</last-name><address><country>CN</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1103344913" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>SHEN, JINXIANG</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1101649859" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>SHEN, JINXIANG</last-name><address><street>Zhejiang Shenghui Lighting Co. Ltd West Jiachuang Road Xiuzhou Industrial Park</street><city>Jiaxing Zhejiang314015</city><country>CN</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR1101647580" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Jöstingmeier, Martin</last-name><iid>101285990</iid><address><street>Lohr, Jöstingmeier &amp; Partner Junkersstraße 3</street><city>82178 Puchheim</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="CN-2014085872-W"><document-id><country>CN</country><doc-number>2014085872</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20140903</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2015039561-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2015039561</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20150326</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS660700186" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS660787843" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS660620965" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS660706082" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS660700791" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS660620966" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS660787844" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS660700192" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS660620975" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS660620976" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS660717931" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS660706087" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS660700792" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS660700193" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS660620977" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS660700194" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS660787845" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS660700793" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS660620978" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS660706088" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS660620987" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS660706089" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS660622871" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS660706090" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS660706095" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS660622872" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS660622873" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS660620988" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS660700200" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS660620989" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS660706096" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS660787846" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS660706097" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS660620990" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS660700794" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS660700201" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS660700202" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS660622874" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states><ep-extended-states><ep-extended-state-data><country>BA</country></ep-extended-state-data><ep-extended-state-data><country>ME</country></ep-extended-state-data></ep-extended-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA152011713" ref-ucid="WO-2015039561-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p num="0000">An LED driving and dimming circuit and configuration method are provided. The circuit can include a switch connected to an AC power supply, an LED driver circuit connected to the switch, a switch-status detection circuit connected to the switch, and a brightness- selection circuit having one end connected to the switch- status detection circuit and another end connected to the LED driver circuit. The switch- status detection circuit is configured to detect whether the switch is open or closed and to output a detected result to the brightness-selection circuit. The LED driver circuit is configured to control a brightness level of the LED lighting device, according to a voltage result from the brightness-selection circuit.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA152368906" ref-ucid="WO-2015039561-A1" lang="EN" source="national office" load-source="docdb"><p>An LED driving and dimming circuit and configuration method are provided. The circuit can include a switch connected to an AC power supply, an LED driver circuit connected to the switch, a switch-status detection circuit connected to the switch, and a brightness- selection circuit having one end connected to the switch- status detection circuit and another end connected to the LED driver circuit. The switch- status detection circuit is configured to detect whether the switch is open or closed and to output a detected result to the brightness-selection circuit. The LED driver circuit is configured to control a brightness level of the LED lighting device, according to a voltage result from the brightness-selection circuit.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA152011714" ref-ucid="WO-2015039561-A1" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><p num="0000">La présente invention concerne un circuit d'attaque et de gradation d'intensité de DEL et un procédé de configuration. Le circuit peut comprendre un commutateur connecté à une alimentation en courant alternatif, un circuit d'attaque de DEL connecté au commutateur, un circuit de détection d'état de commutateur connecté au commutateur, et un circuit de sélection de luminosité comportant une extrémité connectée au circuit de détection d'état de commutateur et une autre extrémité connectée au circuit d'attaque de DEL. Le circuit de détection d'état de commutateur est conçu pour détecter si le commutateur se trouve ouvert ou fermé et pour émettre un résultat détecté vers le circuit de sélection de luminosité. Le circuit d'attaque de DEL est conçu pour réguler un niveau de luminosité du dispositif d'éclairage à DEL, en fonction d'un résultat de tension en provenance du circuit de sélection de luminosité.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA152368907" ref-ucid="WO-2015039561-A1" lang="FR" source="national office" load-source="docdb"><p>La présente invention concerne un circuit d'attaque et de gradation d'intensité de DEL et un procédé de configuration. Le circuit peut comprendre un commutateur connecté à une alimentation en courant alternatif, un circuit d'attaque de DEL connecté au commutateur, un circuit de détection d'état de commutateur connecté au commutateur, et un circuit de sélection de luminosité comportant une extrémité connectée au circuit de détection d'état de commutateur et une autre extrémité connectée au circuit d'attaque de DEL. Le circuit de détection d'état de commutateur est conçu pour détecter si le commutateur se trouve ouvert ou fermé et pour émettre un résultat détecté vers le circuit de sélection de luminosité. Le circuit d'attaque de DEL est conçu pour réguler un niveau de luminosité du dispositif d'éclairage à DEL, en fonction d'un résultat de tension en provenance du circuit de sélection de luminosité.</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES88807711" ref-ucid="WO-2015039561-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><invention-title lang="EN"> LED DRIVING AND DIMMING CIRCUIT AND CONFIGURATION METHOD 
	 </invention-title><technical-field><heading id="h01">Technical Field</heading><p id="p02" num="1"> The present disclosure generally relates to the
		field of LED (i.e., light emitting diode) lighting technology and, more
		particularly, relates to a driving and dimming circuit for an LED lighting
		device and a method for configuring the driving and dimming circuit. </p></technical-field><background-art><heading id="h03">Background Art</heading><p id="p32" num="2">LED lighting may generally provide advantages in
		energy conservation, environmental protection, controllable lighting, solid
		state lighting, and long operational lifetime. LED lamps thus have been widely
		used in various areas for public, commercial, and/or indoor lighting. </p><p id="p31" num="3">Often, LED lamps may have lamp-head structures
		generally-designed similar to incandescent lamps, energy saving lamps, and
		other conventional lamps. Presumably, LED lamps may be used to directly replace
		other conventional lamps by an easy installation without changing original
		structures of a lighting system including other conventional lamps.</p><p id="p30" num="4">However, when other conventional lamps are replaced
		by conventional LED lamps, dimming feature of the LED lamps may not be applied,
		because those other conventional lamps do not include any dimmers to implement
		the dimming feature of the replaced LED lamps. To add a dimmer in those
		conventional systems can increase cost in use and can require complicated,
		additional installation.</p><p id="p29" num="5">In some LED lamps, a switch may be used to replace a
		dimmer to control brightness of an LED lamp. One method of using a switch for
		dimming control includes a step-less dimming process. When a user presses the
		switch for a first time, lighting brightness of the lamp may gradually change
		from a minimum brightness level to a maximum brightness level, which may take a
		few seconds. During this gradual changing process, if the user presses the
		switch for a second time, the lamp may be turned off and the brightness level
		at this point may be memorized by the LED lamp. When the user presses the
		switch for a third time, the lamp may provide the previously-memorized
		brightness. When the user presses the switch for a fourth time, the lamp may
		then be turned off. When the switch is pressed again, the process may be
		repeated. In some cases, after pressing the switch for the first time, the user
		may not press the switch during the time interval for gradually changing
		brightness from the minimum level to the maximum level. The lamp may then be
		operated at the maximum brightness level until the switch is pressed again to
		turn off the lamp. </p><p id="p28" num="6">In another method of using a switch for dimming
		control, a brightness level may be selected from several set-brightness levels.
		In a two-level dimming process, the lamp may be operated at a first
		set-brightness level when the switch is pressed for a first time. When the
		switch is pressed for a second time, the lamp may be turned off. When the
		switch is pressed for a third time, the lamp may be operated at a second
		set-brightness level. When the switch is pressed for a fourth time, the lamp
		may be turned off. When the switch is pressed for a fifth time, the lamp may be
		operated at the first set-brightness level, which is the same as for the step
		when the switch is pressed for the first time. Such a process may then be
		repeated.</p><p id="p27" num="7">In other cases, the brightness level may be selected
		using a dimming chip or a microcontroller (MCU). Such designs, however, require
		complicated circuit and increase the cost for the LED lamps.</p></background-art><disclosure><tech-solution><heading id="h07">Technical Solution</heading><p id="p47" num="8"> One aspect or embodiment of the present disclosure
		  includes a driving and dimming circuit for driving an LED lighting device. The
		  circuit can include a switch connected to an AC power supply, an LED driver
		  circuit connected to the switch, a switch-status detection circuit connected to
		  the switch, and a brightness-selection circuit having one end connected to the
		  switch-status detection circuit and another end connected to the LED driver
		  circuit. The switch-status detection circuit is configured to detect whether
		  the switch is open or closed and to output a detected result to the
		  brightness-selection circuit. The LED driver circuit is configured to control a
		  brightness level of the LED lighting device, according to a voltage result from
		  the brightness-selection circuit. </p><p id="p46" num="9"> The switch-status detection circuit includes a
		  first comparator, a second comparator, and a first capacitor. The first
		  comparator has an output end connected to an input end of the second
		  comparator. The first capacitor has one end connected to the output end of the
		  first comparator and has another end grounded. </p><p id="p45" num="10"> The brightness-selection circuit includes a
		  self-latching circuit and a second capacitor configured in parallel with the
		  self-latching circuit. The self-latching circuit includes a first transistor, a
		  second transistor, a first resistor, a second resistor, a third resistor, and a
		  fourth resistor. Optionally, the first transistor is a PNP type transistor, and
		  the second transistor is an NPN type transistor. The first transistor, the
		  third resistor, and the fourth resistor are connected in series. The second
		  transistor, the first resistor, and the second resistor are configured in
		  series. </p><p id="p44" num="11"> The first transistor has a collector connected to
		  the third resistor, and has an emitter and a base respectively connected to
		  both ends of the first resistor. The second transistor has a collector
		  connected to the second resistor, and has an emitter and a base respectively
		  connected to both ends of the fourth resistor. </p><p id="p43" num="12"> Alternatively, the switch-status detection
		  circuit includes a first comparator, a second comparator, a capacitor, and a
		  resistor. The brightness-selection circuit includes a T’-counter. The first
		  comparator has an output end connected to a CP (clock pulse) terminal of the
		  T’-counter. The second comparator has an output end connected to a reset
		  terminal of the T’-counter. The capacitor has one end connected to supply power
		  to the first and second comparators. The capacitor has another end be grounded
		  and also connected to a non-inverting input end of the second comparator via
		  the resistor. </p><p id="p42" num="13"> Another aspect or embodiment of the present
		  disclosure includes a method for configuring a driving and dimming circuit for
		  driving an LED lighting device. A switch is connected to an AC power supply in
		  the driving and dimming circuit. Each of an LED driver circuit and a
		  switch-status detection circuit is connected to the switch. A
		  brightness-selection circuit is configured to have one end connected to the
		  switch-status detection circuit and another end connected to the LED driver
		  circuit. The switch-status detection circuit detects whether the switch is open
		  or closed and outputs a detected result to the brightness-selection circuit.
		  The LED driver circuit controls a brightness level of the LED lighting device,
		  according to a voltage result of the brightness-selection circuit. </p><p id="p41" num="14"> The switch-status detection circuit includes a
		  first comparator, a second comparator, and a first capacitor. The first
		  comparator has an output end connected to an input end of the second
		  comparator. The first capacitor has one end connected to the output end of the
		  first comparator and has another end grounded. </p><p id="p40" num="15"> The brightness-selection circuit includes a
		  self-latching circuit and a second capacitor configured in parallel with the
		  self-latching circuit. The self-latching circuit includes a first transistor, a
		  third resistor, and a fourth resistor connected in series. The self-latching
		  circuit also includes a second transistor, a first resistor, and a second
		  resistor configured in series. The first transistor has a collector connected
		  to the third resistor, and has an emitter and a base respectively connected to
		  both ends of the first resistor. The second transistor has a collector
		  connected to the second resistor, and has an emitter and a base respectively
		  connected to both ends of the fourth resistor. </p><p id="p39" num="16"> The circuit is configured such that: when the
		  switch is pressed for a first time to close the circuit, the self-latching
		  circuit does not operate, and the brightness-selection circuit outputs a
		  voltage to the LED driver circuit to operate the LED lighting device at a first
		  set-brightness level. When the switch is pressed for a second time to open the
		  circuit, the second comparator outputs a high level voltage to trigger the
		  self-latching circuit and to output a low level voltage to the LED driver
		  circuit. </p><p id="p38" num="17"> When the switch is pressed for a third time to
		  close the circuit within a time period of TL, counted from a time when the
		  switch is pressed for the second time to a time that the second capacitor is
		  depleted to reset the self-latching circuit, the LED driver circuit receives a
		  voltage to operate the LED lighting device at a second set-brightness level.
		  </p><p id="p37" num="18"> When the switch is pressed for a third time to
		  close the circuit after a time period of TL, counted from a time when the
		  switch is pressed for the second time to a time that the second capacitor is
		  depleted to reset the self-latching circuit, the LED driver circuit receives a
		  voltage to operate the LED lighting device back at the first set-brightness
		  level. </p><p id="p36" num="19"> Alternatively, the switch-status detection
		  circuit includes a first comparator, a second comparator, a capacitor, and a
		  resistor. The brightness-selection circuit includes a T’-counter. The first
		  comparator has an output end connected to a CP (clock pulse) terminal of the
		  T’-counter. The second comparator has an output end connected to a reset
		  terminal of the T’-counter. The capacitor has one end connected to supply power
		  to the first and second comparators. The capacitor has another end be grounded
		  and also connected to a non-inverting input end of the second comparator via
		  the resistor.</p><p id="p35" num="20"> The circuit is configured such that: when the
		  switch is pressed for a first time to close the circuit, the LED driver circuit
		  operates the LED lighting device at a first set-brightness level. After the
		  switch is pressed for a second time to open the circuit and when the switch is
		  pressed for a third time to close the circuit within a time period of TL,
		  counted from a time when the switch is pressed for the second time to a time
		  that the first capacitor is depleted, the LED driver circuit receives a high
		  level voltage to operate the LED lighting device at a second set-brightness
		  level. </p><p id="p34" num="21"> Alternatively, after the switch is pressed for
		  the second time to open the circuit, and when the switch is pressed for the
		  third time to close the circuit after the time period of TL, counted from a
		  time when the switch is pressed for the second time to a time that the first
		  capacitor is depleted, the LED driver circuit receives a low voltage to operate
		  the LED lighting device back at the first set-brightness level. </p><p id="p33" num="22"> Other aspects or embodiments of the present
		  disclosure can be understood by those skilled in the art in light of the
		  description, the claims, and the drawings of the present disclosure.</p></tech-solution></disclosure><description-of-drawings><heading id="h11">Description of Drawings</heading><p id="p51" num="23"> The following drawings are merely examples for
		illustrative purposes according to various disclosed embodiments and are not
		intended to limit the scope of the present disclosure. </p><p id="p50" num="24"> FIG. 1 depicts an exemplary LED driving and dimming
		circuit consistent with various disclosed embodiments;</p><p id="p49" num="25"> FIG. 2 depicts an exemplary circuit block including
		a switch-status detection circuit and a brightness-selection circuit in an LED
		driving and dimming circuit consistent with various disclosed embodiments;
		and</p><p id="p48" num="26">FIG. 3 depicts another exemplary circuit block
		including a switch-status detection circuit and a brightness-selection circuit
		in an LED driving and dimming circuit consistent with various disclosed
		embodiments.</p></description-of-drawings><mode-for-invention><heading id="h15">Mode for Invention</heading><p id="p85" num="27"> Reference will now be made in detail to exemplary
		embodiments of the disclosure, which are illustrated in the accompanying
		drawings. Wherever possible, the same reference numbers will be used throughout
		the drawings to refer to the same or like parts.</p><p id="p84" num="28"> An LED driving and dimming circuit and
		configuration method are provided. An exemplary driving and dimming circuit for
		driving an LED lighting device can include, for example, an AC power supply, a
		switch connected to the AC power supply, an LED driver circuit connected to the
		switch, a switch-status detection circuit connected to the switch, and/or a
		brightness-selection circuit having one end connected to the switch-status
		detection circuit and having another end connected to the LED driver circuit.
		</p><p id="p83" num="29"> The switch-status detection circuit can be
		configured to detect whether the switch is closed or opened and to output a
		detected result to the brightness-selection circuit. The brightness-selection
		circuit can have an output end connected to the LED driver circuit. The LED
		driver circuit can be configured to control a brightness level of the LED
		lighting device, according to a voltage result from the brightness-selection
		circuit. </p><p id="p82" num="30"> In one embodiment, the switch-status detection
		circuit can include a first comparator, a second comparator, and/or a first
		capacitor. The first comparator can have an output end connected to an input
		end of the second comparator. The first capacitor can have one end connected to
		the output end of the second comparator and can have another end be grounded.
		</p><p id="p81" num="31"> The brightness-selection circuit can include a
		self-latching circuit and a second capacitor configured in parallel with the
		self-latching circuit. The self-latching circuit can include a first
		transistor, a second transistor, a first resistor, a second resistor, a third
		resistor, and a fourth resistor. </p><p id="p80" num="32"> In another embodiment, the switch-status detection
		circuit can include a first comparator and a second comparator. In this case,
		the brightness-selection circuit may include a T’-counter. The first comparator
		can have an output end connected to a CP (clock pulse) terminal of the
		T’-counter, and the second comparator can have an output end connected to a
		reset terminal of the T’-counter. </p><p id="p79" num="33"> As such, a switch-status detection circuit and a
		brightness-selection circuit can be included in the disclosed LED driving and
		dimming circuit. Further, the switch-status detection circuit and a
		brightness-selection circuit can be included into the LED lighting device. Each
		of the switch-status detection circuit and the brightness-selection circuit can
		be formed by discrete components. Compared with a conventional LED driver
		circuit, the added switch-status detection circuit and brightness-selection
		circuit can provide desired function with a low cost while adding little extra
		changes to conventional circuit lines. Embodiments consistent with the present
		disclosure thus may decrease the cost of the LED lighting devices. </p><p id="p78" num="34"> FIG. 1 depicts an exemplary LED driving and dimming
		circuit consistent with various disclosed embodiments. As shown in FIG. 1, the
		LED driving and dimming circuit can be used to drive an LED lighting device 6.
		</p><p id="p77" num="35"> The LED driving and dimming circuit can include an
		AC power supply 1, a switch 2, an LED driver circuit 3, a switch-status
		detection circuit 4, and/or a brightness-selection circuit 5. Among them, each
		of the AC power supply 1, the switch 2, and the LED driver circuit 3 can
		include any suitable control structure(s) for LED lighting devices as desired.
		</p><p id="p76" num="36"> As disclosed herein, the switch-status detection
		circuit 4 can be configured to detect whether the switch 2 is turned on or
		turned off, and to output detected result to the brightness-selection circuit
		5. The brightness-selection circuit 5 can have an output end connected to the
		LED driver circuit 3. According to a voltage result from the
		brightness-selection circuit 5, the LED driver circuit 3 can thus control
		brightness level of the LED lighting device 6. </p><p id="p75" num="37"> FIG. 2 depicts an exemplary circuit block including
		a switch-status detection circuit and a brightness-selection circuit configured
		in an LED driving and dimming circuit consistent with various disclosed
		embodiments. As shown in FIG. 2, the switch-status detection circuit 4 can
		include a first comparator 41, a second comparator 42, and/or a first capacitor
		43. </p><p id="p74" num="38"> The first comparator 41 can have an output end
		connected to an input end of the second comparator 42. The first capacitor 43
		can have one end connected to the output end of the first comparator 41 and can
		have another end be grounded. </p><p id="p73" num="39"> The brightness-selection circuit 5 can include a
		self-latching circuit 51 and a second capacitor 52, configured in parallel with
		the self-latching circuit 51. The self-latching circuit 51 can include a first
		transistor 53 and a second transistor 54, e.g., configured in series. The
		self-latching circuit 51 can further include a first resistor 55, a second
		resistor 56, a third resistor 57, and/or a fourth resistor 58. </p><p id="p72" num="40"> In one embodiment, the first transistor 53 can be a
		PNP type transistor, while the second transistor 54 can be an NPN type
		transistor. The first transistor 53, the third resistor 57, and/or the fourth
		resistor 58 can be connected in series. The second transistor 54, the second
		resistor 56, and/or the first resistor 55 can also be configured in series. The
		first transistor 53 can have a collector connected to the third resistor 57.
		The first transistor 53 can also have an emitter and a base respectively
		connected to both ends of the first resistor 55. The second transistor 54 can
		have a collector connected to the second resistor 56. The second transistor 54
		can also have an emitter and a base respectively connected to both ends of the
		fourth resistor 58. </p><p id="p71" num="41"> In operation, when the switch 2 is pressed for a
		first time, the switch 2 can close the circuit. Voltage VA at point A as shown
		in FIG. 1 can be at a high level and can be greater than a reference voltage
		Vref of the first comparator 41 as shown in FIG. 2. The first comparator 41 can
		output a low level voltage VB, while the second comparator 42 can also output a
		low level voltage. Voltage VC at point C shown in FIGS. 1-2 can be at a high
		level. When the LED driver circuit 3 receives a voltage VC, the LED lighting
		device 6 can be operated at a first set-brightness level. </p><p id="p70" num="42"> When the switch 2 is pressed for a second time, the
		switch 2 can open the circuit. Voltage VA at point A can be reduced. When the
		voltage VA is lower than the reference voltage Vref of the first comparator 41,
		the first comparator 41 can output voltage VB at a high level. After a time
		delay Td, the first capacitor 43 can be charged to have a potential Vcl higher
		than reference voltage Vref of the second comparator 42. The second comparator
		42 can output a high level voltage to trigger the self-latching circuit 51 and
		to change voltage VC from the high level to a low level. The self-latching
		circuit 51 can be powered by the second capacitor 52 as shown in FIG. 2. After
		a period of time TL, the second capacitor 52 can be depleted, and the
		self-latching circuit 51 can be restored (or reset). The period of time TL can
		be counted from the time when the switch 2 is pressed for the second time to
		the time when the second capacitor 52 is fully depleted. </p><p id="p69" num="43"> In one embodiment, when the switch 2 is pressed for
		a third time to close the circuit before the time period of TL when the second
		capacitor 52 is depleted, the LED driver circuit 3 can receive the low level
		voltage VC, and the LED lighting device 6 can be operated at a second
		set-brightness level. </p><p id="p68" num="44"> In another embodiment when the switch 2 is pressed
		for the third time to close the circuit after the time period of TL, as the
		self-latching circuit 51 is restored, the voltage VC can be at a high level and
		the LED driver circuit 3 can operate the LED lighting device 6 at the first
		set-brightness level. In various embodiments, the first set-brightness level
		may require a low voltage VC, while the second set-brightness level may require
		a high voltage VC; or vice versa, depending on specific applications. </p><p id="p67" num="45"> Likewise, when the switch 2 is pressed for a fourth
		time to open the circuit (e.g., as similar to when the switch 2 is pressed for
		the second time) and for a fifth time to close the circuit (e.g., as similar to
		when the switch 2 is pressed for the third time) with a time interval less than
		the time period of TL, the LED driver circuit 3 can operate the LED lighting
		device 6 at the second set-brightness level. In another case, when the switch 2
		is pressed for a fourth time and fifth time with a time interval greater than
		the time period of TL, the LED driver circuit 3 can operate the LED lighting
		device 6 at the first set-brightness level. </p><p id="p66" num="46"> Such a dimming control process of the LED lighting
		device between the first and second set-brightness levels can be repeated. In
		various embodiments, Td and TL for charging and/or depleting a corresponding
		capacitor can be configured according to specific applications. </p><p id="p65" num="47"> Note that although two levels of set-brightness are
		primarily described in the present disclosure, the disclosed driving and
		dimming circuit can be used to control dimming of the LED lighting device for
		more than two levels of set-brightness. For example, the time period TL counted
		from a time for pressing the switch for the second time to the time for the
		second capacitor 52 to be depleted can be controlled sufficiently long, such
		that, during the time period of TL, the switch 2 can pressed not only for the
		third time, but also for an additional fourth time, an additional fifth time,
		an additional sixth time, etc. Accordingly, the LED driver circuit 3 can
		receive the voltage VC at various levels to control the LED lighting device 6
		to be operated at the second set-brightness level and also at a third
		set-brightness level, a fourth set-brightness level, a fifth set-brightness
		level, etc. </p><p id="p64" num="48"> FIG. 3 depicts another exemplary circuit block
		including a switch-status detection circuit and a brightness-selection circuit
		in an LED driving and dimming circuit consistent with various disclosed
		embodiments. </p><p id="p63" num="49"> As shown, the switch-status detection circuit 4a in
		FIG. 3 can include a first comparator 41a, a second comparator 42a, a first
		capacitor 43a, and/or a fifth resistor 44a. The first capacitor 43a can have
		one end connected to supply power to the first and second comparators 41a and
		42a. The first capacitor 43a can have other end be grounded and also be
		connected to a non-inverting input end of the second comparator 42a via the
		fifth resistor 44a. </p><p id="p62" num="50"> The brightness-selection circuit 5a can include a
		T’-counter. The output end of the first comparator 41a can be connected to a CP
		(clock pulse) terminal of the T’-counter. The output end of the second
		comparator 42a can be connected to a reset terminal of the T’-counter, as shown
		in FIG. 3. </p><p id="p61" num="51"> In operation, when the switch 2 is pressed for a
		first time, the switch 2 can close the circuit. The first capacitor 43a can be
		charged. When voltage Vr5 of the fifth resistor 44a is lower than the reference
		voltage Vref of the second comparator 42a, the second comparator 42a can output
		a low level voltage. The T’-counter can be reset. Thereafter, when voltage Vr5
		of the fifth resistor 44a is increased to be higher than the reference voltage
		Vref of the second comparator 42a, the second comparator 42a can output a high
		level voltage. When voltage VA at point A as shown in FIGS. 1 and 3 is greater
		than Vref of the first comparator 41a, the first comparator 41a can output a
		voltage VB at a low level, while the second comparator 42a can still output the
		high level voltage. In this case, the T’-counter does not operate and maintains
		at an initial state, and voltage VC is outputted at a low level by the
		brightness-selection circuit 5a to the LED driver circuit 3. When the LED
		driver circuit 3 receives the low level voltage VC, the lighting device 6 can
		be operated at a first set-brightness level. </p><p id="p60" num="52"> When the switch 2 is pressed for a second time, the
		switch 2 can open the circuit. Voltage VA at point A can be reduced. When the
		voltage VA is lower than the reference voltage Vref of the first comparator
		41a, the first comparator 41a can output a voltage VB that becomes a high
		level. After a time delay Td for the T’-counter to flip, voltage VC can change
		from the low level to a high level. After the switch 2 is pressed for the
		second time, the voltage of the first capacitor 43a is reduced. After a time
		length TL, voltage Vr5 of the fifth resistor 44a is less than Vref of the
		second comparator 42a, voltage outputted by the second comparator 42a can
		change from the high level to a low level. T’-counter can then be reset. </p><p id="p59" num="53"> In an embodiment when the switch 2 is pressed for a
		third time during the time period of TL, the LED driver circuit 3 can receive
		the high level voltage VC and the LED lighting device can operate at a second
		set-brightness level. </p><p id="p58" num="54"> However, in the case when the switch 2 is pressed
		for the third time following the time period of TL, as the T’-counter is reset
		and voltage VC is at a low level, the LED driver circuit 3 can operate the LED
		lighting device 6 at the first set-brightness level. </p><p id="p57" num="55"> Likewise, when the switch 2 is pressed for a fourth
		time (which is similar to the case when the switch 2 is pressed for the second
		time), the first comparator 41a can output a voltage at a high level. The
		T’-counter can flip. Voltage VC can change from one level to another level. In
		one embodiment, when a time interval between the fourth time and a fifth time
		of pressing the switch 2 falls within the time period of TL, the LED driver
		circuit 3 can operate the LED lighting device 6 back at the first
		set-brightness level. As such, the LED driver circuit 3 can operate the LED
		lighting device 6 between the two set-brightness levels. </p><p id="p56" num="56"> In this manner, such a dimming control process of
		the LED lighting device between the first and second set-brightness levels can
		be repeated. In various embodiments, Td and TL for corresponding counter and
		capacitor can be configured according to specific applications. </p><p id="p55" num="57"> Note that although two levels of set-brightness are
		primarily described in the present disclosure, the disclosed driving and
		dimming circuit can be used to control dimming of the LED lighting device for
		more than two levels of set-brightness. For example, the time period TL counted
		from a time for pressing the switch for the second time to the time for the
		first capacitor 43a to be depleted can be controlled sufficiently long, such
		that, during the time period of TL, the switch 2 can pressed not only for the
		third time, but also for an additional fourth time, an additional fifth time,
		an additional sixth time, etc. Accordingly, the LED driver circuit 3 can
		receive the voltage VC at various levels to control the LED lighting device 6
		to be operated at the second set-brightness level and also at a third
		set-brightness level, a fourth set-brightness level, a fifth set-brightness
		level, etc. </p><p id="p54" num="58"> In addition, the disclosed driving and dimming
		circuit and the LED lighting device can be used to directly replace other
		lighting sources (e.g., incandescent lamps and/or halogen lamps) without
		changing their layout of lighting systems. For example, the driving and dimming
		circuit can be installed within a lamp-head structure of the LED lighting
		device. Such a lamp-head structure can be easily transported and installed with
		the LED lighting device to replace other lighting sources in any lighting
		system.</p><p id="p53" num="59"> Note that, the term "comprising", "including" or
		any other variants thereof are intended to cover a non-exclusive inclusion,
		such that the process, method, article, or apparatus containing a number of
		elements also include not only those elements, but also other elements that are
		not expressly listed; or further include inherent elements of the process,
		method, article or apparatus. Without further restrictions, the statement
		"includes a ......" does not exclude other elements included in the process,
		method, article, or apparatus having those elements.</p><p id="p52" num="60"> The embodiments disclosed herein are exemplary
		only. Other applications, advantages, alternations, modifications, or
		equivalents to the disclosed embodiments are obvious to those skilled in the
		art and are intended to be encompassed within the scope of the present
		disclosure.</p><p id="p114" num="61">Reference Sign List：</p><p id="p113" num="62">AC power supply 1</p><p id="p112" num="63">Switch 2</p><p id="p111" num="64">LED driver circuit 3</p><p id="p110" num="65">Switch-status detection circuit 4</p><p id="p109" num="66">Brightness-selection circuit 5 </p><p id="p108" num="67">LED lighting device 6</p><p id="p107" num="68">First comparator 41</p><p id="p106" num="69">Second comparator 42</p><p id="p105" num="70">First capacitor 43 </p><p id="p104" num="71">Self-latching circuit 51</p><p id="p103" num="72">Second capacitor 52</p><p id="p102" num="73">First transistor 53</p><p id="p101" num="74">Second transistor 54</p><p id="p100" num="75">First resistor 55</p><p id="p99" num="76">Second resistor 56</p><p id="p98" num="77">Third resistor 57</p><p id="p97" num="78">Fourth resistor 58</p><p id="p96" num="79">Switch-status detection circuit 4a</p><p id="p95" num="80">Brightness-selection circuit 5a </p><p id="p94" num="81">First comparator 41a</p><p id="p93" num="82">Second comparator 42a</p><p id="p92" num="83">First capacitor 43a</p><p id="p91" num="84">Fifth resistor 44a</p></mode-for-invention><industrial-applicability><heading id="h17">Industrial Applicability And Advantageous Effects
		  </heading><p id="p89" num="85"> Without limiting the scope of any claim and/or the
		specification, examples of industrial applicability and certain advantageous
		effects of the disclosed embodiments are listed for illustrative purposes.
		Various alternations, modifications, or equivalents to the technical solutions
		of the disclosed embodiments can be obvious to those skilled in the art and can
		be included in this disclosure.</p><p id="p88" num="86"> An LED driving and dimming circuit and
		configuration method are provided. The circuit can include a switch connected
		to an AC power supply, an LED driver circuit connected to the switch, a
		switch-status detection circuit connected to the switch, and a
		brightness-selection circuit having one end connected to the switch-status
		detection circuit and another end connected to the LED driver circuit. The
		switch-status detection circuit is configured to detect whether the switch is
		open or closed and to output a detected result to the brightness-selection
		circuit. The LED driver circuit is configured to control a brightness level of
		the LED lighting device, according to a voltage result from the
		brightness-selection circuit. </p><p id="p87" num="87"> As such, a switch-status detection circuit and a
		brightness-selection circuit can be included in the disclosed LED driver
		circuit. Each of the switch-status detection circuit and the
		brightness-selection circuit can be formed by discrete components. Compared
		with a conventional LED driver circuit, the added switch-status detection
		circuit and brightness-selection circuit can provide desired function at a low
		cost without much additional changes over conventional circuit lines.
		Embodiments consistent with the present disclosure thus may decrease the cost
		of the LED lighting devices. </p><p id="p86" num="88"> In addition, the disclosed driving and dimming
		circuit and the LED lighting device can be used to directly replace other
		lighting sources (e.g., incandescent lamps and/or halogen lamps) without
		changing their layout of lighting systems. For example, the driving and dimming
		circuit can be installed within a head structure of the LED lighting device.
		Such head structures can be easily transported to replace other lighting
		sources in any lighting system. </p></industrial-applicability></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM80535135" ref-ucid="WO-2015039561-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><claim id="c21" num="1"><claim-text> 1.A driving and dimming circuit for driving an LED lighting
		  device, comprising: </claim-text><claim-text>a switch connected to an AC power supply;</claim-text><claim-text>an LED driver circuit connected to the switch;</claim-text><claim-text>a switch-status detection circuit connected to the switch;
		  and</claim-text><claim-text>a brightness-selection circuit having one end connected to
		  the switch-status detection circuit and another end connected to the LED driver
		  circuit, wherein:</claim-text><claim-text>the switch-status detection circuit is configured to detect
		  whether the switch is open or closed and to output a detected result to the
		  brightness-selection circuit, and </claim-text><claim-text>the LED driver circuit is configured to control a brightness
		  level of the LED lighting device, according to a voltage result from the
		  brightness-selection circuit. </claim-text><claim-text>2.The circuit according to claim 1, wherein the switch-status
		  detection circuit comprises a first comparator, a second comparator, and a
		  first capacitor, wherein the first comparator has an output end connected to an
		  input end of the second comparator, and the first capacitor has one end
		  connected to the output end of the first comparator and has another end
		  grounded. </claim-text><claim-text>3.The circuit according to claim 2, wherein the
		  brightness-selection circuit comprises a self-latching circuit and a second
		  capacitor configured in parallel with the self-latching circuit.</claim-text><claim-text>4.The circuit according to claim 3, wherein the self-latching
		  circuit comprises a first transistor, a second transistor, a first resistor, a
		  second resistor, a third resistor, and a fourth resistor. </claim-text><claim-text>5.The circuit according to claim 4, wherein the first
		  transistor is a PNP type transistor, and the second transistor is an NPN type
		  transistor. </claim-text><claim-text>6.The circuit according to claim 4, wherein the first
		  transistor, the third resistor, and the fourth resistor are connected in
		  series, and wherein the second transistor, the first resistor, and the second
		  resistor are configured in series. </claim-text><claim-text>7.The circuit according to claim 4, wherein the first
		  transistor has a collector connected to the third resistor, and has an emitter
		  and a base respectively connected to both ends of the first resistor.
		  </claim-text><claim-text>8.The circuit according to claim 4, wherein the second
		  transistor has a collector connected to the second resistor, and has an emitter
		  and a base respectively connected to both ends of the fourth resistor.
		  </claim-text><claim-text>9.The circuit according to claim 1, wherein the switch-status
		  detection circuit comprises a first comparator, a second comparator, a
		  capacitor, and a resistor.</claim-text><claim-text>10.The circuit according to claim 9, wherein the
		  brightness-selection circuit comprises a T’-counter, wherein the first
		  comparator has an output end connected to a CP (clock pulse) terminal of the
		  T’-counter, and the second comparator has an output end connected to a reset
		  terminal of the T’-counter. </claim-text><claim-text>11.The circuit according to claim 9, wherein the capacitor
		  has one end connected to supply power to the first and second comparators, and
		  the capacitor has another end be grounded and also connected to a non-inverting
		  input end of the second comparator via the resistor. </claim-text><claim-text>12.A method for configuring a driving and dimming circuit for
		  driving an LED lighting device, comprising: </claim-text><claim-text>configuring a switch connected to an AC power supply in the
		  driving and dimming circuit;</claim-text><claim-text>connecting an LED driver circuit to the switch;</claim-text><claim-text>connecting a switch-status detection circuit to the switch;
		  and</claim-text><claim-text>configuring a brightness-selection circuit having one end
		  connected to the switch-status detection circuit and another end connected to
		  the LED driver circuit, </claim-text><claim-text>wherein the switch-status detection circuit detects whether
		  the switch is open or closed and outputs a detected result to the
		  brightness-selection circuit, and wherein the LED driver circuit controls a
		  brightness level of the LED lighting device, according to a voltage result of
		  the brightness-selection circuit. </claim-text><claim-text>13.The method according to claim 12, wherein the
		  switch-status detection circuit comprises a first comparator, a second
		  comparator, and a first capacitor, wherein the first comparator has an output
		  end connected to an input end of the second comparator, and the first capacitor
		  has one end connected to the output end of the first comparator and has another
		  end grounded. </claim-text><claim-text>14.The method according to claim 13, wherein the
		  brightness-selection circuit comprises a self-latching circuit and a second
		  capacitor configured in parallel with the self-latching circuit.</claim-text><claim-text>15.The method according to claim 14, wherein the
		  self-latching circuit comprises a first transistor, a third resistor, and a
		  fourth resistor connected in series, and comprises a second transistor, a first
		  resistor, and a second resistor configured in series; wherein the first
		  transistor has a collector connected to the third resistor, and has an emitter
		  and a base respectively connected to both ends of the first resistor; and
		  wherein the second transistor has a collector connected to the second resistor,
		  and has an emitter and a base respectively connected to both ends of the fourth
		  resistor. </claim-text><claim-text>16.The method according to claim 15, wherein the circuit is
		  configured such that:</claim-text><claim-text>when the switch is pressed for a first time to close the
		  circuit, the self-latching circuit does not operate, and the
		  brightness-selection circuit outputs a voltage to the LED driver circuit to
		  operate the LED lighting device at a first set-brightness level;
		  and</claim-text><claim-text>when the switch is pressed for a second time to open the
		  circuit, the second comparator outputs a high level voltage to trigger the
		  self-latching circuit and to output a low level voltage to the LED driver
		  circuit. </claim-text><claim-text>17.The method according to claim 16, wherein the circuit is
		  configured such that:</claim-text><claim-text>when the switch is pressed for a third time to close the
		  circuit within a time period of TL, counted from a time when the switch is
		  pressed for the second time to a time that the second capacitor is depleted to
		  reset the self-latching circuit, the LED driver circuit receives a voltage to
		  operate the LED lighting device at a second set-brightness level. </claim-text><claim-text>18.The method according to claim 16, wherein the circuit is
		  configured such that:</claim-text><claim-text>when the switch is pressed for a third time to close the
		  circuit after a time period of TL, counted from a time when the switch is
		  pressed for the second time to a time that the second capacitor is depleted to
		  reset the self-latching circuit, the LED driver circuit receives a voltage to
		  operate the LED lighting device back at the first set-brightness level.
		  </claim-text><claim-text>19.The method according to claim 12, wherein the
		  switch-status detection circuit comprises a first comparator, a second
		  comparator, a capacitor, and a resistor, and the brightness-selection circuit
		  comprises a T’-counter; wherein the first comparator has an output end
		  connected to a CP (clock pulse) terminal of the T’-counter, and the second
		  comparator has an output end connected to a reset terminal of the T’-counter;
		  and wherein the capacitor has one end connected to supply power to the first
		  and second comparators, and the capacitor has another end be grounded and also
		  connected to a non-inverting input end of the second comparator via the
		  resistor.</claim-text><claim-text>20.The method according to claim 19, wherein the circuit is
		  configured such that:</claim-text><claim-text>when the switch is pressed for a first time to close the
		  circuit, the LED driver circuit operates the LED lighting device at a first
		  set-brightness level; and</claim-text><claim-text>after the switch is pressed for a second time to open the
		  circuit and when the switch is pressed for a third time to close the circuit
		  within a time period of TL, counted from a time when the switch is pressed for
		  the second time to a time that the first capacitor is depleted, the LED driver
		  circuit receives a voltage to operate the LED lighting device at a second
		  set-brightness level; or </claim-text><claim-text>after the switch is pressed for the second time to open the
		  circuit, and when the switch is pressed for the third time to close the circuit
		  after the time period of TL, counted from a time when the switch is pressed for
		  the second time to a time that the first capacitor is depleted, the LED driver
		  circuit receives a voltage to operate the LED lighting device back at the first
		  set-brightness level. </claim-text></claim></claims><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
