<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2960720-A1" country="EP" doc-number="2960720" kind="A1" date="20151230" family-id="53476785" file-reference-id="313470" date-produced="20180824" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="160451557" ucid="EP-2960720-A1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2960720</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20151230</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-15173449-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP193866082" load-source="patent-office" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>15173449.8</doc-number><date>20150623</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP193866083" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>15173449</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20150623</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC162034315" ucid="KR-20140130330-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>KR</country><doc-number>20140130330</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20140929</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC162031359" ucid="US-201462017473-P" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>201462017473</doc-number><kind>P</kind><date>20140626</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1988520754" load-source="docdb">H05B  33/08        20060101ALI20151116BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1988523423" load-source="docdb">G06K  15/12        20060101ALI20151116BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1988524026" load-source="docdb">B41J   2/45        20060101ALI20151116BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1988525195" load-source="docdb">G03G  15/04        20060101ALI20151116BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1988526502" load-source="docdb">G03G  15/043       20060101AFI20151116BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1923982975" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G06K  15/1247      20130101 LA20151106BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1984701139" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B41J   2/45        20130101 LI20160106BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1984702528" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B41J   2/47        20130101 FI20151231BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1987766352" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G03G  15/043       20130101 LI20151106BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1987788322" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G03G  15/04054     20130101 LI20151110BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT165546137" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">LEUCHTELEMENT-ARRAYMODUL UND VERFAHREN ZUR STEUERUNG VON LEUCHTELEMENT-ARRAYCHIPS</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT165546138" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">LIGHT-EMITTING ELEMENT ARRAY MODULE AND METHOD OF CONTROLLING LIGHT-EMITTING ELEMENT ARRAY CHIPS</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT165546139" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">MODULE A RESEAU D'ELEMENTS ELECTROLUMINESCENTS ET PROCEDE DE COMMANDE D'UN RESEAU DE PUCES D'ELEMENTS ELECTROLUMINESCENTS</invention-title><citations><patent-citations><patcit mxw-id="PCIT335742390" load-source="docdb" ucid="EP-1186427-A1"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>1186427</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20020313</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="A" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT389043394" load-source="docdb" ucid="JP-2003170625-A"><document-id format="epo"><country>JP</country><doc-number>2003170625</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20030617</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="XAI" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT355548083" load-source="docdb" ucid="WO-2015115713-A1"><document-id format="epo"><country>WO</country><doc-number>2015115713</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20150806</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="E" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit></patent-citations><non-patent-citations><nplcit><text>None</text><sources><source mxw-id="PNPL62360125" load-source="docdb" name="APP"/></sources></nplcit></non-patent-citations></citations></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR1103325108" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>SAMSUNG ELECTRONICS CO LTD</last-name><address><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR1103304638" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>SAMSUNG ELECTRONICS CO., LTD.</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR1101653432" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Samsung Electronics Co., Ltd.</last-name><iid>101425680</iid><address><street>129, Samsung-ro Yeongtong-gu</street><city>Suwon-si, Gyeonggi-do</city><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1103323036" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>KIM SU-HWAN</last-name><address><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1103324260" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>KIM, SU-HWAN</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1101648426" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>KIM, SU-HWAN</last-name><address><street>611-1602, 30, Bongyeong-ro 1517beon-gil, Yeongtong-gu, Suwon-si</street><city>Gyeonggi-do</city><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1103321936" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>KIM WAN-CHIN</last-name><address><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1103311839" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>Kim, Wan-chin</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1101647952" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Kim, Wan-chin</last-name><address><street>210-301, 137, Majang-ro, Seongdong-gu</street><city>Seoul</city><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR1101645731" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Walaski, Jan Filip</last-name><suffix>et al</suffix><iid>101130805</iid><address><street>Venner Shipley LLP 200 Aldersgate</street><city>London EC1A 4HD</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS660611588" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS660687607" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS660611590" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS660783904" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS660687106" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS660612078" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS660687608" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS660607409" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS660611595" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS660612083" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS660689154" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS660783905" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS660783906" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS660611596" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS660611597" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS660611598" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS660612084" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS660687115" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS660611603" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS660783907" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS660612085" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS660607410" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS660687609" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS660607415" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS660607416" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS660694349" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS660694350" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS660687610" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS660689159" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS660687615" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS660689160" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS660687616" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS660689161" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS660687617" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS660607418" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS660687116" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS660687117" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS660694371" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states><ep-extended-states><ep-extended-state-data><country>BA</country></ep-extended-state-data><ep-extended-state-data><country>ME</country></ep-extended-state-data></ep-extended-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA166479927" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p id="pa01" num="0001">A light-emitting element array module (100) includes a control driver (110) configured to receive print data and operate, and light-emitting element array chips (125) configured to receive a signal from the control driver, respectively, and operate, wherein the light-emitting element array chips are connected to the control driver through respective data lines, and the control driver controls an operation point in time of each of the light-emitting element array chips by adjusting input points in time of a start signal and a data signal according to a registration error of each of the light-emitting element array chips.
<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="134" he="97" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA166759739" lang="EN" source="EPO" load-source="docdb"><p>A light-emitting element array module (100) includes a control driver (110) configured to receive print data and operate, and light-emitting element array chips (125) configured to receive a signal from the control driver, respectively, and operate, wherein the light-emitting element array chips are connected to the control driver through respective data lines, and the control driver controls an operation point in time of each of the light-emitting element array chips by adjusting input points in time of a start signal and a data signal according to a registration error of each of the light-emitting element array chips.</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES98404628" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><p id="p0001" num="0001">The following description relates to light-emitting element array modules and methods of controlling light-emitting element array chips.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002">An image forming apparatus using light-emitting element array chips receives print data from a personal computer (PC) and forms an image by using light-emitting elements. When the light-emitting elements emit light, an electrostatic latent image is formed on a photoconductor drum in the image forming apparatus. Thereafter, a print image is output through development, transfer, and fusing processes.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">The light-emitting element array chips are connected to a control unit by wire bondings. Therefore, as many wire bondings as the number of signals output from the control unit are required.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">One or more embodiments include light-emitting element array modules wherein the number of wire bondings is reduced, and methods of controlling light-emitting element array chips.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">One or more embodiments include a method of applying an additional signal to a light-emitting element in order to smoothly operate a transfer element which is included in a light-emitting element array module.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">Additional aspects will be set forth in part in the description which follows and, in part, will be apparent from the description, or may be learned by practice of the presented embodiments.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">According to one or more embodiments, a light-emitting element array module includes a control driver configured to receive print data and operate, and light-emitting element array chips configured to receive a signal from the control driver, respectively, and operate, wherein the light-emitting element array chips are connected to the control driver through respective data lines, and the control driver controls an operation point in time of each of the light-emitting element array chips by adjusting input points in time of a start signal and a data signal according to a registration error of each of the light-emitting element array chips.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">According to one or more embodiments, a method of controlling light-emitting element array chips includes receiving print data, applying a start signal to each of the light-emitting element array chips through data lines, and applying a data signal to each of the light-emitting element array chips through the data lines after the start signal is applied, wherein the start signal is applied at an operation point in time of each of the light-emitting element array chips according to a registration error of each of the light-emitting element array chips.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p><p id="p0009" num="0009">According to one or more embodiments, a method of controlling light-emitting element array chips includes receiving print data, applying a transfer signal operating a transfer element array, applying a data signal operating a light-emitting element array, and applying an additional signal emitting a light-emitting element at a point in time when the transfer signal is changing from a high-level to a low-level.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">According to one or more embodiments, a light-emitting element array module includes a light-emitting element array chip having a light-emitting element array and a transfer element array, and a control driver applying a transfer signal operating a transfer element array by receiving print data, and a data signal operating a light-emitting element array, wherein the control driver applies an additional signal emitting a light-emitting element at a point in time when the transfer signal is changing from a high-level to a low-level.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">These and/or other aspects will become apparent and more readily appreciated from the following description of the embodiments, taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings in which:
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a diagram illustrating a process of outputting an image by using a light-emitting element array;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> is a diagram illustrating a light-emitting element array module according to an embodiment;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> is a diagram illustrating an example of a light-emitting element array module according to an embodiment;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 4</figref> is a diagram illustrating an example of a light-emitting element array module according to an embodiment;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 5</figref> is a block diagram of a light-emitting element array module according to an embodiment;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 6</figref> is a block diagram of a light-emitting element array module according to an embodiment;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 7</figref> is a diagram illustrating an example of a light-emitting element array chip according to an embodiment;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 8</figref> is a timing diagram of signals output from a control driver;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 9</figref> is a timing diagram of signals output from the control driver;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0009">FIGS. 10, 11, and 12</figref> are diagrams illustrating an applying timing of a start signal;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0010">FIG. 13</figref> is a diagram illustrating compensating for a registration error of light-emitting element array chips;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0011">FIG. 14</figref> is a flowchart of a method of controlling light-emitting element array chips according to an embodiment;<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></li><li><figref idrefs="f0012">FIG. 15</figref> is a timing diagram of a method of controlling operation of a transfer element by applying an additional signal;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0013">FIG. 16</figref> is a timing diagram of a method of controlling operation of the transfer element by applying the additional signal; and</li><li><figref idrefs="f0014">FIG. 17</figref> is a flowchart of a method of controlling light-emitting element array chips according to an embodiment.</li></ul></p><p id="p0012" num="0012">Reference will now be made in detail to embodiments, examples of which are illustrated in the accompanying drawings, wherein like reference numerals refer to like elements throughout.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013"><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a diagram illustrating a process of outputting an image by using a light-emitting element array. Referring to <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, upon receiving print data from a personal computer (PC) 50, an image forming apparatus performs operations for outputting an image.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">The image forming apparatus forms an electrostatic latent image on a photoconductor drum 300 by using light-emitting elements and outputs an image through development, transfer, and fusing processes.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">The image forming apparatus includes a control driver 110, a chip array 120, a lens array 200, and the photoconductor drum 300.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">The control driver 110 controls the chip array 120 according to the print data received from the PC 50. The chip array 120 includes a plurality of light-emitting element array chips. The control driver 110 may separately control the light-emitting element array chips. A method of controlling light-emitting element array chips by the control driver 110 is illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">The lens array 200 is arranged in an axial direction (i.e., a main scanning direction) of the photoconductor drum 300. Light having passed through the lens array 200 forms an image on a surface of the photoconductor drum 300.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">The photoconductor drum 300 is exposed to light to form an electrostatic latent image. A developer (not shown) develops the electrostatic latent image formed on the photoconductor drum 300.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019"><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> is a diagram illustrating a light-emitting element array module according to an embodiment. Referring to <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>, the light-emitting element array module 100 may compensate for (or correct) a registration error of light-emitting element array chips 125. A registration error in a main scanning direction may exist between the light-emitting element array chips 125. When the light-emitting element array chips 125 emit light at an identical point in time, the registration error between the light-emitting element array chips 125 may not be compensated for. Thus, the light-emitting element array module 100 according to an embodiment may compensate for the registration error of the light-emitting<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> element array chips 125 by separately controlling the light-emitting element array chips 125. In other words, the light-emitting element array module 100 adjusts a point in time to apply a start signal to each of the light-emitting element array chips 125, thereby controlling operation points in time of the light-emitting element array chips 125.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">The control driver 110 receives print data and operates. The control driver 110 receives print data from a central processing unit (CPU) or a main board included in the image forming apparatus, and controls the on/off of light-emitting elements according to the received print data. The print data is data representing an image to be formed. The control driver 110 controls the on/off of the light-emitting elements according to the print data, and controls the operation points in time of the light-emitting element array chips 125 in consideration of the registration error of the light-emitting element array chips 125.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">The control driver 110 further includes a memory (not shown) for storing information about the operation points in time of the light-emitting element array chips 125. In other words, the control driver 110 pre-stores information about the operation points in time of the light-emitting element array chips 125 in the memory in consideration of the registration error.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">The control driver 110 controls the operation points in time of the light-emitting element array chips 125 by separately applying start signals to the light-emitting element array chips 125. According to the registration error in the main scanning direction of the light-emitting element array chips 125, the control driver 110 compensates for the registration error by adjusting a timing to apply the start signals to the light-emitting element array chips 125. In other words, the control driver 110 adjusts an exposure timing by adjusting a timing of the start signals input to the light-emitting element array chips 125, thereby correcting an image in the main scanning direction.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">The control driver 110 does not output the start signal to the light-emitting element array chip 125, for example, whose print data is all white, from among the light-emitting element array chips 125. When the light-emitting element array chip 125 does not need to emit light, the control driver 110 does not output the start signal to the light-emitting element array chip 125. Because the control driver 110 may separately control the light-emitting element array chips 125, the control driver 110 does not output the start signal to the light-emitting element array chip 125, for example, whose print data is all white, thereby reducing unnecessary power consumption. When print data is all white, there may be no print data, that is, there may be no image to be formed.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">The light-emitting element array module 100 includes the control driver 110 and the chip array 120. The chip array 120 includes a plurality of light-emitting element array chips 125. The control driver 110 and the light-emitting element array chips 125 may be connected by wires.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></p><p id="p0025" num="0025">The light-emitting element array chips 125 receive a signal from the control driver 110, respectively, and operate. The light-emitting element array chips 125 operate according to the start signals separately received from the control driver 110, and emit light according to a data signal (or an on signal). The light-emitting element array chips 125 may be arranged in a zigzag manner, and in two lines.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026"><figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> is a diagram illustrating an example of a light-emitting element array module according to an embodiment.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">The control driver 110 outputs the start signal and the data signal to the light-emitting element array chips 125 through terminals Φi1 to Φi5. The terminals Φi1 to Φi5 in the control driver 110 are independently connected to the light-emitting element array chips 125, respectively. Thus, the control driver 110 may separately control the light-emitting element array chips 125 by applying the start signal to each of the light-emitting element array chips 125 through the terminals Φi1 to Φi5.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">The control driver 110 outputs the start signal and the data signal through data lines. The start signal is input through the data lines wherein the start signal is input, before the data signal is input through the data lines. A transfer element array operates after the start signal is applied. The data lines refer to wires connecting the terminals Φi1 to Φi5 of the control driver 110 to the respective light-emitting element array chips 125. The control driver 110 adjusts input points in time of the start signal and the data signal according to a registration error of each of the light-emitting element array chips 125, thereby controlling an operation point in time of each of the light-emitting element array chips 125. The control driver 110 applies the start signal and data signal to each of the light-emitting element array chips 125 at a delay time according to the registration error of each of the light-emitting element array chips 125, thereby compensating for the registration error. The delay time is a multiple of a cycle of a transfer signal that is applied in each of the light-emitting element array chips 125.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">The control driver 110 or the image forming apparatus may further include a memory for storing the registration error and the delay time of each of the light-emitting element array chips 125.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">Start signal input terminals Φs1 to Φs5 of the light-emitting element array chips 125 may be connected in parallel to the data signal input terminals Φi1 to Φi5 of the light-emitting element array chips 125, respectively. For example, the terminals Φi1 and Φs1 of the light-emitting element array chips 125 may be connected in parallel to each other. Thus, a separate wire for connecting the control driver 110 and each of the terminals Φs1 to Φs5 of the light-emitting element array chips 125 is not necessary. The start signal input terminals Φs1 to Φs5 represent a gate of a transfer element. The data signal input terminals Φi1 to Φi5 represent a cathode of a light-emitting element.<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></p><p id="p0031" num="0031">The control driver 110 outputs transfer signals through terminals Φ1 and Φ2. The same transfer signals Φ1 and Φ2 are received by the light-emitting element array chips 125. Vga refers to ground.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032"><figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 4</figref> is a diagram illustrating an example of a light-emitting element array module according to an embodiment. Referring to <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 4</figref>, start signal input terminals Φs1 to Φs5 and data signal input terminals Φi1 to Φi5 respectively corresponding to the start signal input terminals Φs1 to Φs5 are connected to each other inside the light-emitting element array chips 125. Therefore, the number of wire bondings outside the light-emitting element array chips 125 may be reduced.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033"><figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 5</figref> is a block diagram of a light-emitting element array module according to an embodiment. Referring to <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 5</figref>, a terminal Φi of a light-emitting element array 127 and a terminal Φs of a transfer element array 126 may be connected in parallel to each other.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">The control driver 110 applies signals to the transfer element array 126 and a light-emitting element array 127 of the light-emitting element array chips 125. The control driver 110 applies the start signal to control an operation point in time of the transfer element array 126 through a terminal Φi of the control driver 110.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">The transfer element array 126 includes a plurality of transfer elements that operate based on a start signal and a transfer signal. The transfer element array 126 starts operation when the start signal is applied through the terminal Φs. The plurality of transfer elements that are included in the element array 126 sequentially operate.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">The light-emitting element array 127 includes a plurality of light-emitting elements that operate based on a data signal.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">The light-emitting conditions of the light-emitting elements may be determined according to the states of the transfer elements. The transfer elements and the light-emitting elements may be one-to-one matched. In order for a light-emitting element to emit light, a transfer element corresponding to the light-emitting element has to be in a standby state. When the transfer element is in a standby state, the on/off of the light-emitting element may be determined according to the data signal input to the light-emitting element. When a start signal is input to the transfer elements, the transfer elements sequentially enter a standby state according to a transfer signal.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">The control driver 110 outputs a start signal to the transfer element array 126 by using the data signal applied to the light-emitting element array 127. The control driver 110 outputs a start signal to the transfer element array 126 through the terminal Φi of the control driver 110. After outputting the start signal, the control driver 110 outputs the data signal to the light-emitting element array 127 through the terminal Φi of the light-emitting element array 127 from the terminal Φi of the control driver 110.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p><p id="p0039" num="0039">A start signal input terminal (terminal Φs) of the transfer element array 126 and a data signal input terminal (terminal Φi) of the light-emitting element array 127 may be connected to an output terminal (terminal Φi) of the control driver 110. Thus, the signal (Φi signal) output from the control driver 110 may be input simultaneously to the transfer element array 126 and the light-emitting element array 127. Thus, the start signal input terminal Φs of the transfer element array 126 and the control driver 110 are not connected by a separate wire.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">The transfer element array 126 includes a plurality of transfer elements, and the light-emitting element array 127 includes a plurality of light-emitting elements. The transfer elements may be controlled by a start signal and transfer signals (that is, Φ1 and Φ2). The transfer elements start operating when the start signal and the transfer signal Φ1 are applied at the same time. In other words, the transfer elements start operating when the start signal is applied through the terminal Φs of the transfer element array 126 while the transfer signal Φ1 is applied. The light-emitting element array 127 may be turned on according to the state of the data signal and the transfer element.</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">The transfer signal may have two alternate potentials. When a first voltage is a high-level voltage, a second voltage is a low-level voltage.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">The start signal may have a voltage level opposite to that of the transfer signal Φ1. For example, if the transfer signal Φ1 has a low-level voltage, the start signal may have a high-level voltage. On the other hand, if the transfer signal Φ1 has a high-level voltage, the start signal may have a low-level voltage. The control driver 110 may control operations of the transfer elements by applying the start signal according to a cycle of the transfer signals Φ1 and Φ2.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043"><figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 6</figref> is a block diagram of a light-emitting element array module according to an embodiment. Referring to <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 6</figref>, the terminal Φi of the light-emitting element array 127 and the terminal Φs of the transfer element array 126 may be connected to each other inside the light-emitting element array chip 125.</p><p id="p0044" num="0044"><figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 7</figref> is a diagram illustrating an example of a light-emitting element array chip according to an embodiment. Referring to <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 7</figref>, a start signal and a data signal are input through the same terminal Φi. The light-emitting element array chip 125 includes a diode Ds that is connected in forward direction and a resistor Rs. The start signal and the data signal are input to the terminal Φi of the light-emitting element array chip 125. The level of the voltage of the start signal is the same as the maximum level of the voltage of the data signal. Thus, transfer elements or light-emitting elements do not operate before the start signal is input to the light-emitting element array chip 125.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045">Operations of the transfer elements and the light-emitting elements are disclosed.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></p><p id="p0046" num="0046">The light-emitting element array 127 includes a plurality of light-emitting thyristors, and the transfer element array 126 includes a plurality of transfer thyristors. In other words, the light-emitting elements may be light-emitting thyristors, and the transfer elements may be transfer thyristors. The light-emitting elements are represented as L1 to L256 and the transfer elements are represented as T1 to T256.</p><p id="p0047" num="0047">The thyristor has a PNPN junction structure and includes a gate. In <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 7</figref>, 256 thyristors are included in one light-emitting element array chip 125, and G1 through G256 respectively denote gate terminals of the thyristors. When a voltage of a determined level or more is applied to a gate of the thyristor, a breakdown voltage of the thyristor is lowered, and thus an operation voltage of the thyristor is lowered. Thus, by applying a voltage to the gate of the thyristor, the thyristor may be operated by a lower driving voltage.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048">The start signal supplies a voltage to a gate G1 of a transfer thyristor T1. The start signal is supplied to the gate G1 through the diode Ds. The transfer thyristor T1 starts operating when the start signal and the transfer signal Φ1 are applied at the same time. After that, the transfer thyristors T2 to T256 sequentially enter an operating state according to the transfer signals Φ1 and Φ2.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">When the transfer thyristor T1 is in an operating state, the light-emitting thyristor L1 enters a light-emitting state. The gate G1 of the transfer thyristor T1 is equal to the gate of the light-emitting thyristor L1. Thus, when the transfer thyristor T1 enters an operating state, the light-emitting thyristor L1 also enters an operating state. When the light-emitting thyristor L1 is in an operating state, the light-emitting thyristor L1 emits light according to the data signal input through the terminal Φi.</p><p id="p0050" num="0050">By repetition of the process, the transfer thyristors T1 to T256 sequentially enter an operating state, and the light-emitting thyristors L1 to L256 enter an operating state, and sequentially emit light or do not emit light.</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">The start signal and the data signal are input through the terminal Φi. The start signal is applied to the gate G1 of the transfer thyristor T1 through the resistor Rs and the diode Ds. The start signal is input before the data signal is input. The start signal is applied to each of the light-emitting element array chips 125 while the transfer signal Φ1 is input, thus determining an input point in time of the start signal according to the registration error of each of the light-emitting element array chips 125.</p><p id="p0052" num="0052"><figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 8</figref> is a timing diagram of signals output from a control driver. Referring to <figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 8</figref>, the control driver 110 may drive transfer elements without a separate start signal.</p><p id="p0053" num="0053">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 8</figref>, the control driver 110 maintains a high-level voltage through the terminal Φi. The control driver 110 outputs a data signal while maintaining the high-level voltage. The control driver 110 outputs a first data signal when a Φ1 signal is in a low<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> state. Therefore, the light-emitting element array module 100 may drive the transfer elements without applying a separate start signal.</p><p id="p0054" num="0054">A first transfer signal Φ1 may be applied to odd-numbered transfer thyristors, and a second transfer signal Φ2 may be applied to even-numbered transfer thyristors.</p><p id="p0055" num="0055">The first transfer signal Φ1 and the second transfer signal Φ2 have two potentials of a high-level and a low-level and alternately enter a high state and a low state. The first transfer signal Φ1 and the second transfer signal Φ2 overlap with each other during a time ta. This is to allow the next transfer thyristor to enter a standby state before an operation of the previous transfer thyristor is ended. A time tb is a time determined for stable operation of the light-emitting element, and a time tw is a time when the light-emitting element actually operates.</p><p id="p0056" num="0056"><figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 9</figref> is a timing diagram of signals output from the control driver. Referring to <figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 9</figref>, the control driver 110 may separately control the light-emitting element array chips 125 by applying a separate start signal.</p><p id="p0057" num="0057">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 9</figref>, the control driver 110 applies a start signal before outputting the data signal through the terminal Φi. The part represented as "start" in <figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 9</figref> corresponds to the start signal. The control driver 110 may apply the start signal by maintaining the high-level voltage for a certain period of time before outputting the data signal. However, the control driver 110 may apply the start signal when the transfer signal Φ1 is in a low state.</p><p id="p0058" num="0058">The control driver 110 may determine a point in time to apply the start signal according to each of the light-emitting element array chips 125. Because the light-emitting element array chips 125 have mutually different registration errors, the control driver 110 may determine the point in time to apply the start signal according to the registration error. In addition, the start signal is applied when the transfer signal Φ1 is in a low-level. Therefore, the control driver 110 may apply the start signal that is delayed by a cycle of the transfer signal Φ1.</p><p id="p0059" num="0059">For example, if duration in a high-level or in a low-level of the transfer signal Φ1 is T, the control driver 110 may apply the start signal for every 2T. This will be described in detail in <figref idrefs="f0009">FIGS. 10 through 12</figref>.</p><p id="p0060" num="0060">The start signal Φs is applied when the first transfer signal Φ1 is in a low state, and a first transfer thyristor T1 turns on. At this time, the control driver 110 turns on the first light-emitting thyristor L1 by using the data signal Φi. Thereafter, when the first transfer signal Φ1 enters a high state and the second transfer signal Φ2 enters a low state, the control driver 110 turns on the second light-emitting thyristor L2 by using the data signal Φi. By repetition of the process, the control driver 110 may turn on the first to 256th light-emitting thyristors L1 to L256.<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></p><p id="p0061" num="0061"><figref idrefs="f0009">FIGS. 10 through 12</figref> are diagrams illustrating an applying timing of a start signal. Referring to <figref idrefs="f0009">FIGS. 10 through 12</figref>, the control driver 110 may apply a start signal and a data signal that are delayed, according to a registration error of the light-emitting element array chips 125. The control driver 110 may apply the delayed start signal according to a cycle of the transfer signal Φ1. Because the control driver 110 is required to apply a start signal in a high-level when the transfer signal Φ1 is in a low-level, the control driver 110 applies the start signal at a point in time when the transfer signal Φ1 enters a low state.</p><p id="p0062" num="0062"><figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 10</figref> illustrates an example of applying a start signal and a data signal without delay. A high-level signal represented as "start" is a start signal, and the control driver 110 applies the start signal without delay. In other words, the control driver 110 applies the start signal at a point in time when the transfer signal Φ1 is applied. The control driver 110 sequentially applies the data signal after the start signal is applied.</p><p id="p0063" num="0063"><figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 11</figref> illustrates an example of applying a start signal and a data signal that are delayed by 2T. The control driver 110 applies the start signal and the data signal at the time delayed by 2T to compensate for the registration error of the light-emitting element array chips 125. Because the control driver 110 applies the start signal through the terminal Φi, the control driver 110 may separately apply the start signal to each of the light-emitting element array chips 125. For example, if there is a registration error of 2T in the light-emitting element array chip 125, the control driver 110 may apply the start signal at the time delayed by 2T.</p><p id="p0064" num="0064"><figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 12</figref> illustrates an example of applying a start signal and a data signal that are delayed by 4T. The control driver 110 applies the start signal and the data signal at the time delayed by 4T to compensate for the registration error of the light-emitting element array chips 125.</p><p id="p0065" num="0065">Although <figref idrefs="f0009">FIGS. 10 through 12</figref> illustrate examples wherein delay times are o to 4T, the delay times may change according to the registration error of the light-emitting element array chips 125. In addition, if a compensation time for the registration error does not correspond to a multiple of 2T, the control driver 110 may determine a multiple of 2T that is the closest to the compensation time for the registration error as delay times, and may apply the start signal according to the delay times.</p><p id="p0066" num="0066"><figref idrefs="f0010">FIG. 13</figref> is a diagram illustrating compensating for a registration error of light-emitting element array chips. Positions of the light-emitting element array chips 125 may not properly arranged during the process. Therefore, offset of the light-emitting element array chips 125 needs to be compensated for.</p><p id="p0067" num="0067">On the basis of a first light-emitting element array chip 1301, a 2-dot offset was generated in a second light-emitting element array chip 1302, a 4-dot offset was generated<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> in a third light-emitting element array chip 1303, and a 6-dot offset was generated in a fourth light-emitting element array chip 1304.</p><p id="p0068" num="0068">The control driver 110 adjusts an applying point in time of data according to the offset. The control driver 110 checks offsets of the first to fourth light-emitting element array chips 1301 to 1304, and determines delay times corresponding to the offsets. When the control driver 110 applies a data signal to the second light-emitting element array chip 1302, the control driver 110 applies the data signal by compensating for time by 2T. When the control driver 110 applies a data signal to the third light-emitting element array chip 1303, the control driver 110 applies the data signal by compensating for time by 4T. When the control driver 110 applies a data signal to the fourth light-emitting element array chip 1304, the control driver 110 applies the data signal by compensating for time by 6T.</p><p id="p0069" num="0069">Because data lines are separately connected between the control driver 110 and the first to fourth light-emitting element array chips 1301 to 1304, the control driver 110 may determine a point in time when the data signal is applied to each of the light-emitting element array chips 1301 to 1304. Therefore, the control driver 110 may determine a delay time corresponding to each of the first to fourth light-emitting element array chips 1301 to 1304, and adjust the point in time when the data signal is applied according to the determined delay time. In addition, the delay times may be determined in advance during the process and stored in a memory so that the control driver 110 may apply the data signal by referring to the delay times of the light-emitting element array chips 125 that are stored in the memory.</p><p id="p0070" num="0070"><figref idrefs="f0011">FIG. 14</figref> is a flowchart of a method of controlling light-emitting element array chips according to an embodiment.</p><p id="p0071" num="0071">In operation 1410, the control driver 110 receives print data. The print data may be received from the CPU or the PC 50. The print data is data about an image that is to be printed by the image forming apparatus.</p><p id="p0072" num="0072">In operation 1420, the control driver 110 applies a start signal to each of the light-emitting element array chips through the data lines. The control driver 110 applies a start signal to the transfer element array 126 by using a signal applied to the light-emitting element array 127 of the light-emitting element array chips 125.</p><p id="p0073" num="0073">The control driver 110 controls operation points in time of the light-emitting element array chips 125 by separately applying start signals to the light-emitting element array chips 125. The chip array 120 includes the plurality of light-emitting element array chips 125. The control driver 110 may apply the start signal to each of the light-emitting element array chips 125 at different points in time.</p><p id="p0074" num="0074">According to the registration error in a main scanning direction of the light-emitting element array chips 125, the control driver 110 compensates for the registration<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> error by adjusting a timing to apply the start signal to each of the light-emitting element array chips 125. A registration error exists between the light-emitting element array chips 125, and the control driver 110 controls the operation points in time of the light-emitting element array chips 125 in order to compensate for the registration errors. In other words, the control driver 110 adjusts an exposure timing by adjusting a timing of the start signal input to each of the light-emitting element array chips 125, thereby correcting an image in the main scanning direction.</p><p id="p0075" num="0075">The control driver 110 transfers a data signal indicating an image to the light-emitting element array 127. The data signal indicates the on/off of the light-emitting elements.</p><p id="p0076" num="0076">In operation 1430, the control driver 110 applies the data signal to each of the light-emitting element array chips 125 through the data lines after the start signal is applied. The control driver 110 applies the data signal to each of the light-emitting element arrays 127 after the start signals are applied and transfer elements start operating.</p><p id="p0077" num="0077"><figref idrefs="f0012">FIG. 15</figref> is a timing diagram of a method of controlling operation of a transfer element by applying an additional signal. Referring to <figref idrefs="f0012">FIG. 15</figref>, the control driver 110 may apply an additional signal emitting the light-emitting elements for a certain period of time (ton).</p><p id="p0078" num="0078">The additional signal, a signal to cause each of the light-emitting elements to emit light, is applied through data lines during the time ton. Time ton may be a very short time of about a few nanoseconds. In addition, the additional signal may be applied at a point in time when a transfer signal is changing from a high-level to a low-level. The point in time when the transfer signal is changing from a high-level to a low-level may refer to a point in time when the transfer signal is lowered from a high-level voltage to a low-level voltage. The additional signal may be applied at a point in time when the transfer signal Φ1 is changing from a high-level to a low-level, or at a point in time when the transfer signal Φ2 is changing from a low-level to a high-level. In addition, the additional signals may be applied at all points in time when the transfer signals Φ1 and Φ2 are changing from a high-level to a low-level. <figref idrefs="f0012">FIG. 15</figref> illustrates that the point in time when the transfer signal Φ1 is lowered from a high-level and the point in time when the additional signal is applied coincide with each other, but the points do not always coincide with each other.</p><p id="p0079" num="0079">The control driver 110 determines applying time of the additional signal in order to avoid forming a latent image on a photoconductor drum, and applies the additional signal during the determined time ton. The latent image is not formed on the photoconductor drum even if the light-emitting elements are turned on by the additional signal. In other words, the control driver 110 determines a time during which a latent image may not be<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> formed on the photoconductor drum even if the light-emitting element emits light, and applies the additional signal during the determined time ton.</p><p id="p0080" num="0080">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 7</figref>, because the gates of the light-emitting elements L1 to L256 are connected to each of the gates of the transfer elements T1 to T256, operation of the light-emitting elements L1 to L256 may affect the transfer elements T1 to T256. Therefore, applying the additional signals to the light-emitting elements L1 to L256 at points in time when the transfer signals Φ1 and Φ2 that are applied to the transfer elements T1 to T256 are changing from a high-level to a low-level, may affect the operations of the transfer elements T1 to T256. When the light-emitting elements emit light, a gate potential of the light-emitting element becomes 3.3 V (Vcc). A gate potential of the transfer element connected to the light-emitting element also becomes 3.3 V. The gate potential of the transfer element is sequentially transferred to the next transfer element, and a gate potential of the next transfer element becomes about 1.8 V. The light-emitting element helps operation of the transfer element when the gate potential is transferred to the next transfer element.</p><p id="p0081" num="0081">Another method of helping operation of the transfer element is to make the gate voltage of each of the transfer elements higher than that of the first transfer element. In other words, a voltage that is higher than a high-level voltage of the transfer signal is applied to an anode of the transfer element to be VG2, VG3, VG4,..., and VG256 &gt; VG1.</p><p id="p0082" num="0082">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0012">FIG. 15</figref>, when only a data signal is applied, the only data signal indicating whether the light-emitting element is turned on/off according to the transfer signals Φ1 and Φ2, may be applied to the light-emitting elements. A low-level voltage is applied to a data signal turning on the light-emitting element during the time t1 or t2. An emitting time of the light-emitting element is changed according to the length of the time t1 or t2 and the size of the latent image that is formed on the photoconductor drum becomes greater as the emitting time of the light-emitting element becomes longer.</p><p id="p0083" num="0083">When the data signal and the additional signal are applied, the additional signal is applied to the light-emitting elements according to the changes of the transfer signals Φ1 and Φ2. The additional signal may be applied before or after the data signal is applied.</p><p id="p0084" num="0084"><figref idrefs="f0013">FIG. 16</figref> is a timing diagram of a method of controlling operation of the transfer element by applying the additional signal. <figref idrefs="f0013">FIG. 16</figref> illustrates an example wherein the control driver 110 applies the additional signal when a data signal is turned off.</p><p id="p0085" num="0085">Because the data signal is turned off in <figref idrefs="f0013">FIG. 16</figref>, the data signal maintains high-level voltage.</p><p id="p0086" num="0086">The control driver 110 may further apply the additional signal when the data signal is turned off. In other words, the control driver 110 may apply the additional signal not only at points in time when the transfer signals Φ1 and Φ2 are changing from a high-level<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> voltage to a low-level voltage, but also during the time when the transfer signals Φ1 and Φ2 maintain a low-level.</p><p id="p0087" num="0087">The additional signals are further applied one time during the time when the transfer signals Φ1 and Φ2 maintain a low-level in <figref idrefs="f0013">FIG. 16</figref>, but the additional signal may be applied at least two times. In addition, the additional signals have a rectangular pulse shape in <figref idrefs="f0013">FIG. 16</figref>, but the additional signals may be applied in various shapes, such as a triangle pulse and so on.</p><p id="p0088" num="0088"><figref idrefs="f0014">FIG. 17</figref> is a flowchart of a method of controlling light-emitting element array chips according to an embodiment.</p><p id="p0089" num="0089">In operation 1710, the control driver 110 receives print data.</p><p id="p0090" num="0090">In operation 1720, the control driver 110 applies transfer signals operating the transfer element array 126. The transfer signals indicate the first transfer signal Φ1 operating odd-numbered transfer elements, and the second transfer signal Φ2 operating even-numbered transfer elements.</p><p id="p0091" num="0091">In operation 1730, the control driver 110 applies the data signal operating the light-emitting element array 127, and the additional signal emitting (turning on or operating) the light-emitting element at a point in time when the transfer signal is changing from a high-level to a low-level. In addition, the control driver 110 further applies the additional signal during the time when the data signal is applied or when the data signal is turned off.</p><p id="p0092" num="0092">As described above, according to the one or more of the above embodiments, because the start signal input terminals of the transfer element array are connected in parallel to the data signal input terminals of the light-emitting element array, the number of wire bondings in the light-emitting array module may be reduced.</p><p id="p0093" num="0093">According to a method of controlling the light-emitting element array chips, the light-emitting element array chips may be separately controlled by adjusting the point in time when the start signal is output to each of the light-emitting element array chips.</p><p id="p0094" num="0094">According to a method of controlling the light-emitting element array chips, the registration errors of the light-emitting element array chips may be compensated for by separately controlling the light-emitting element array chips.</p><p id="p0095" num="0095">According to a method of controlling the light-emitting element array chips, operations of transfer elements may be affected by applying an additional signal and a data signal to the light-emitting elements.</p><p id="p0096" num="0096">The apparatuses according to an embodiment may include a processor, a memory for storing and executing program data, a permanent storage such as a disk drive, a communication port for communicating with an external device, and user interface (UI) devices such as a touch panel, keys, and buttons. Methods implemented by a software module or algorithm may be stored on a non-transitory computer-readable recording<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> medium as computer-readable codes or program commands that are executable on the processor. Examples of the computer-readable recording medium include magnetic storage media (e.g., read-only memories (ROMs), random-access memories (RAMs), floppy disks, and hard disks) and optical recording media (e.g., compact disc-read only memories (CD-ROMs) and digital versatile discs (DVDs)). The computer-readable recording medium may also be distributed over network-coupled computer systems so that the computer-readable codes may be stored and executed in a distributed fashion. The computer-readable recording medium is readable by a computer, and may be stored in a memory and executed in a processor.</p><p id="p0097" num="0097">The embodiments may be described in terms of functional block components and various processing operations. A functional block may be implemented by hardware and/or software components. For example, an embodiment may employ various integrated circuit (IC) components, such as memory elements, processing elements, logic elements, and lookup tables, which may execute various functions under the control of one or more microprocessors or other control devices. An element may be implemented by software programming or software elements, and implemented by a programming or scripting language such as C, C++, Java, or assembly language, with various algorithms being implemented by a combination of data structures, processes, routines, or other programming elements. A functional aspect may be implemented by an algorithm that is executed in one or more processors. A "mechanism," "element," "unit," and "configuration" are not limited to mechanical and physical configurations, and may include software routines in conjunction with processors or the like.</p><p id="p0098" num="0098">Particular implementations described herein are merely exemplary, and do not limit the scope of the inventive concept. Connection lines or connection members illustrated in the drawings represent functional connections and/or physical or logical connections between the various elements, and various alternative or additional functional connections, physical connections, or logical connections may be used.</p><p id="p0099" num="0099">The use of the terms "a," "an," and "the" and similar referents in the context of the specification (especially in the context of the following claims) may be construed to cover both the singular and the plural. Also, recitation of a range of values herein refer separately to each separate value falling within the range, unless otherwise indicated herein, and each separate value is incorporated into the specification as if it were separately recited herein. The operations of the method described herein may be performed in any suitable order unless otherwise indicated herein or otherwise clearly contradicted by the context. The scope of the inventive concept is not limited to the above-described operation order. Examples or terms (e.g., "such as") provided herein are used to describe the embodiments in detail, and the scope is not limited by the examples<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> or terms unless otherwise claimed. Also, those of ordinary skill in the art will readily understand that various modifications and combinations may be made according to design conditions and factors without departing from the scope of the invention as defined by the following claims.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM90459569" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --><claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A light-emitting element array module comprising:
<claim-text>a control driver configured to receive print data; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a plurality of light-emitting element array chips, each configured to receive a signal from the control driver,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each of the plurality of light-emitting element array chips is connected to the control driver through a respective data line, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the control driver is arranged to control an operation point in time of each of the plurality of light-emitting element array chips by adjusting input points in time of a start signal and a data signal according to a registration error of each of the plurality of light-emitting element array chips.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The light-emitting element array module of claim 1, wherein the control driver is arranged to compensate for the registration error by applying the start signal and data signal to each of the plurality of light-emitting element array chips at a delay time according to the registration error of each of the plurality of light-emitting element array chips.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The light-emitting element array module of claim 2, wherein the delay time is a multiple of a cycle of each of transfer signals that are applied in the plurality of light-emitting element array chips.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The light-emitting element array module of any one of the preceding claims, wherein<br/>
each of the plurality of light-emitting element array chips include a transfer element array and a light-emitting element array, and<br/>
start signal input terminals of the transfer element array are connected in parallel to the data line.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The light-emitting element array module of claim 4, wherein the control driver is arranged to apply the start signal operating the transfer element array through the data line.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The light-emitting element array module of any one of the preceding claims, further comprising a memory for storing information about the operation points in time of the plurality of light-emitting element array chips.<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>A method of controlling a plurality of light-emitting element array chips, the method comprising:
<claim-text>receiving print data;</claim-text>
<claim-text>applying a start signal to each of the plurality of light-emitting element array chips through a data line; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>applying a data signal to each of the plurality of light-emitting element array chips through the data line after the start signal is applied,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the applying of the start signal comprises applying the start signal at an operation point in time of each of the plurality of light-emitting element array chips according to a registration error of each of the plurality of light-emitting element array chips.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The method of claim 7, wherein the applying of the start signal comprises compensating for the registration error by applying the start signal to each of the plurality of light-emitting element array chips at a delay time according to the registration error of each of the plurality of light-emitting element array chips.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The method of claim 8, wherein the delay time is a multiple of a cycle of each of transfer signals that are applied in the plurality of light-emitting element array chips.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The method of claim 7, 8 or 9, wherein a voltage level of the start signal is the same as a high-level voltage of the data signal.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>A method of controlling a plurality of light-emitting element array chips included in an image forming apparatus, the method comprising:
<claim-text>receiving print data;</claim-text>
<claim-text>applying a transfer signal operating a transfer element array;</claim-text>
<claim-text>applying a data signal operating a light-emitting element array; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>applying an additional signal operating a light-emitting element at a point in time when the transfer signal is changing from a high-level to a low-level.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>A method of claim 11, wherein the applying of the additional signal comprises determining the applying time of the additional signal to avoid forming a latent image on a photoconductor drum, and applying the additional signal during the determined time.<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>A light-emitting element array module included in an image forming apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a light-emitting element array chip configured to have a light-emitting element array and a transfer element array; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a control driver configured to apply a transfer signal operating a transfer element array by receiving print data, and a data signal operating a light-emitting element array,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the control driver applies an additional signal that causes the light-emitting element to emit light at a point in time when the transfer signal is changing from a high-level to a low-level.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>The light-emitting element array module of claim 13, wherein the control driver determines the applying time of the additional signal to avoid forming a latent image on a photoconductor drum, and applies the additional signal during the determined time.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW20422291" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="141" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="165" he="129" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="125" he="213" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --><figure id="f0004" num="4"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="125" he="213" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --><figure id="f0005" num="5,6"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="165" he="231" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --><figure id="f0006" num="7"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="165" he="231" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --><figure id="f0007" num="8"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="165" he="231" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --><figure id="f0008" num="9"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="165" he="231" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --><figure id="f0009" num="10,11,12"><img id="if0009" file="imgf0009.tif" wi="162" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --><figure id="f0010" num="13"><img id="if0010" file="imgf0010.tif" wi="165" he="229" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --><figure id="f0011" num="14"><img id="if0011" file="imgf0011.tif" wi="145" he="141" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --><figure id="f0012" num="15"><img id="if0012" file="imgf0012.tif" wi="142" he="209" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --><figure id="f0013" num="16"><img id="if0013" file="imgf0013.tif" wi="142" he="209" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --><figure id="f0014" num="17"><img id="if0014" file="imgf0014.tif" wi="147" he="140" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><search-report-data><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="159" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="159" he="233" type="tif"/></search-report-data><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
