<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2681868-A1" country="EP" doc-number="2681868" kind="A1" date="20140108" family-id="46022621" file-reference-id="305010" date-produced="20180823" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146586420" ucid="EP-2681868-A1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2681868</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-12717914-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154848612" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12717914</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120224</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP220440097" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12717914.1</doc-number><date>20120224</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140554630" ucid="US-201113040458-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>201113040458</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20110304</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140551320" ucid="US-2012026437-W" linkage-type="W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>2012026437</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20120224</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989323119" load-source="docdb">H04L   5/00        20060101AFI20121212BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1846796825" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04L   5/06        20130101 LI20170216BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1846796826" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04L   5/0044      20130101 FI20170216BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1846796827" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04L   5/001       20130101 LA20170216BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132363893" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">VIRTUELLE AGGREGATION EINES DRAHTLOSEN FRAGMENTIERTEN SPEKTRUMS</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132363894" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">VIRTUAL AGGREGATION OF FRAGMENTED WIRELESS SPECTRUM</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132363895" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">AGRÉGATION VIRTUELLE DE SPECTRE SANS FIL FRAGMENTÉ</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919538042" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>ALCATEL LUCENT</last-name><address><country>FR</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919507961" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>ALCATEL LUCENT</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919013446" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Alcatel-Lucent</last-name><iid>101311164</iid><address><street>3, Avenue Octave Gréard</street><city>75007 Paris</city><country>FR</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919523332" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>PUROHIT VINAY</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919544065" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>PUROHIT, VINAY</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919011532" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>PUROHIT, VINAY</last-name><address><street>4 Dakota Trail</street><city>Branchburg, NJ 08876</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919539479" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>WILFORD PAUL A</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919521349" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>WILFORD, PAUL, A.</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919018344" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>WILFORD, PAUL, A.</last-name><address><street>52 Rippling Brook Way</street><city>Bernardsville, NJ 07924</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919005886" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>2SPL Patentanwälte</last-name><iid>101239684</iid><address><street>Postfach 15 17 23</street><city>80050 München</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="US-2012026437-W"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2012026437</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20120224</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2012161784-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2012161784</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20121129</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549838552" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS549770723" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549838553" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549838408" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549838624" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549851992" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549770724" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549838566" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549851993" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549851998" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549760710" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549838409" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549838625" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549838567" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549851999" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549838568" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549770733" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549760711" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549852000" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549838634" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549852001" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549838442" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549914792" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549838443" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549838444" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549914793" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS549914794" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549914795" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549770734" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549914796" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549852006" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549760336" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549852007" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS549914797" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549838569" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549770735" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549770736" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS549760712" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA102688257" ref-ucid="WO-2012161784-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p num="0000">Method and apparatus for aggregating spectrum in which multiple disjoint blocks of spectrum may be configured as one virtual contiguous block of spectrum by modulating onto each disjoint blocks of spectrum a respective portion of a data stream in which the data rate associated with the modulated portion is compatible with the available bandwidth of the disjoint spectrum block upon which is modulated.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA102883381" ref-ucid="WO-2012161784-A1" lang="EN" source="national office" load-source="docdb"><p>Method and apparatus for aggregating spectrum in which multiple disjoint blocks of spectrum may be configured as one virtual contiguous block of spectrum by modulating onto each disjoint blocks of spectrum a respective portion of a data stream in which the data rate associated with the modulated portion is compatible with the available bandwidth of the disjoint spectrum block upon which is modulated.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA102688258" ref-ucid="WO-2012161784-A1" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><p num="0000">L'invention concerne un procédé et un appareil servant à agréger un spectre dans lequel une pluralité de blocs de spectre disjoints peut être configurée sous la forme d'un bloc de spectre contigu virtuel unique par modulation sur chacun des blocs de spectre disjoints d'une partie respective d'un train de données dans lequel la vitesse des données associée à la partie modulée est compatible avec la largeur de bande disponible du bloc de spectre disjoint sur lequel le train de données est modulé.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA102883382" ref-ucid="WO-2012161784-A1" lang="FR" source="national office" load-source="docdb"><p>L'invention concerne un procédé et un appareil servant à agréger un spectre dans lequel une pluralité de blocs de spectre disjoints peut être configurée sous la forme d'un bloc de spectre contigu virtuel unique par modulation sur chacun des blocs de spectre disjoints d'une partie respective d'un train de données dans lequel la vitesse des données associée à la partie modulée est compatible avec la largeur de bande disponible du bloc de spectre disjoint sur lequel le train de données est modulé.</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES52885446" ref-ucid="WO-2012161784-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="2"/>--><p id="p0001" num="0001"> VIRTUAL AGGREGATION OF FRAGMENTED WIRELESS SPECTRUM </p><p id="p0002" num="0002">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </p><p id="p0003" num="0003"> The invention relates generally to communication networks and, more specifically, but not exclusively, to satellite- and microwave-based point-to-point communication and backhaul links. </p><p id="p0004" num="0004">BACKGROUND Traditional wireless systems assume the availability of a contiguous block of spectrum with bandwidth proportional to the amount of data to be transmitted. Transmission systems are thus frequently designed for worst-case bandwidth requirements with the typical or average use-case, in some instances, requiring much less bandwidth (i.e., spectrum). </p><p id="p0005" num="0005"> Within the context of satellite communications systems and other point-to- point communications systems, available spectrum allocated to customers may become fragmented over time, which leads to unused blocks between allocated blocks of spectrum. When the blocks of unused spectrum are too small, it is necessary to reallocate spectrum among customers or "move" a customer from existing spectral allocation to a new spectral allocation so that the unused blocks of spectrum may be coalesced into a single spectral region. Unfortunately, such reallocation is very disruptive. </p><p id="p0006" num="0006">BRIEF SUMMARY </p><p id="p0007" num="0007"> Various deficiencies of the prior art are addressed by the present invention of systems, methods and apparatus aggregating spectrum in which multiple disjoint blocks of spectrum may be configured as one virtual contiguous block of spectrum by modulating onto each disjoint blocks of spectrum a respective portion of a data stream in which the data rate associated with the modulated 
<!-- EPO <DP n="3"/>-->
 portion is compatible with the available bandwidth of the disjoint spectrum block upon which is modulated. </p><p id="p0008" num="0008"> A method according to one embodiment comprises dividing a data stream into a plurality of sub-streams, each of the sub-streams associated a respective spectral fragment and having a data rate compatible with a bandwidth of the respective spectral fragment; modulating each of the sub-streams to provide a modulated signal adapted for transmission via the respective spectral fragment; and upconverting the modulated signals onto respective spectral fragments of at least one carrier signal; wherein the sub-streams included within the upconverted modulated signals are adapted to be demodulated and combined at a receiver to recover thereby data stream. </p><p id="p0009" num="0009"> An apparatus according to one embodiment comprises a splitter, for dividing a data stream into a plurality of sub-streams, each of the sub-streams associated a respective spectral fragment and having a data rate compatible with a bandwidth of the respective spectral fragment; a plurality of modulators, each modulator configured to modulate a respective sub-stream to provide a modulated signal adapted for transmission via the respective spectral fragment; and at least one upconverter, for upconverting the modulated signals onto respective spectral fragments of at least one carrier signal; wherein the sub- streams included within the upconverted modulated signals are adapted to be demodulated and combined at a receiver to recover thereby data stream. </p><p id="p0010" num="0010"> The splitting function of the method or apparatus may include </p><p id="p0011" num="0011">encapsulating sequential portions of the data stream into payload portions of respective encapsulating packets, each of the sequential portions of the data stream being associated with a respective sequence number included within a header portion of the respective encapsulating packet; and selectively routing encapsulated packets towards demodulators. </p><p id="p0012" num="0012"> The selective routing may be based on routing encapsulating packets according any of a random routing algorithm, a round robin routing algorithm, a 
<!-- EPO <DP n="4"/>-->
 customer preference algorithm, a service provider preference algorithm and so on where each sub-stream is associated with a respective weight. </p><p id="p0013" num="0013"> The various sub-streams may be modulated and up converted onto a carrier signal for transmission via one or more transponders within a satellite medication system, one or more microwave links within a microwave </p><p id="p0014" num="0014">communications system and/or one or more wireless channels within a wireless communication system. </p><p id="p0015" num="0015"> In various embodiments, encapsulated packets are routed multiple times to add resiliency/redundancy. </p><p id="p0016" num="0016">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </p><p id="p0017" num="0017"> The teachings of the present invention can be readily understood by considering the following detailed description in conjunction with the </p><p id="p0018" num="0018">accompanying drawings, in which: </p><p id="p0019" num="0019"> FIG. 1 depicts a block diagram of a communication system according to one embodiment; </p><p id="p0020" num="0020"> FIG. 2 depicts a graphical representation of a spectral allocation useful in understanding the present embodiments; </p><p id="p0021" num="0021"> FIG. 3 depicts a high-level block diagram of a general purpose computing device suitable for use in various embodiments; </p><p id="p0022" num="0022"> FIGS. 4-6 depicts flow diagrams of methods according to various embodiments; </p><p id="p0023" num="0023"> FIGS. 7-9 depicts block diagrams of communication systems according to various embodiments; </p><p id="p0024" num="0024"> FIG. 10 depicts a high-level block diagram of a slicer/de-multiplexer suitable for use in various embodiments; and </p><p id="p0025" num="0025"> FIG. 1 1 depicts a flow diagram of a method according to one embodiment.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">To facilitate understanding, identical reference numerals have been used, where possible, to designate identical elements that are common to the figures. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="5"/>-->
 DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION </p><p id="p0027" num="0027"> The invention will be primarily described within the context of a satellite communications system. However, those skilled in the art and informed by the teachings herein will realize that the invention is also applicable to any system benefiting from flexible spectral allocation, such as microwave communications systems, wireless communications systems and the like. </p><p id="p0028" num="0028"> One embodiment provides an efficient and general-purpose technique for aggregating multiple, fragmented blocks of wireless spectrum into one contiguous virtual block such that the cumulative bandwidth is almost equal to the sum of the bandwidths of the constituent blocks. The fragmented blocks are optionally separated from each other by blocks of spectrum, such as guard blocks, blocks owned by other parties, blocks prohibited by the wireless spectrum regulatory authority of a region or country and so on. </p><p id="p0029" num="0029"> FIG. 1 depicts a block diagram of a communication system benefiting from various embodiments. The communication system 100 of FIG. 1 comprises a point-to-point link including a virtual spectrum aggregator transmitter 1 10, a power amplifier 120, a satellite uplink 130, a satellite 140, a satellite downlink 150, a virtual spectrum aggregator receiver 160 and, optionally, a control module 170. Data to be transmitted over the point-to-point link is provided as a stream of data packets D, such as 188-byte transport stream (TS) packets, 64-1500 bytes Ethernet packets and so on. The specific packet structure, data conveyed within a packet structure and so on is readily adapted to the various embodiments described herein. </p><p id="p0030" num="0030"> The input data stream D is received by the virtual spectrum aggregated transmitter 1 10, where it is processed by a slicer/demultiplexer 1 1 1 to provide N sub-streams (D<sub>0</sub>... D<sub>N-</sub>i), where N corresponds to a number of spectral fragments denoted as S<sub>0</sub>, ST and so on up to S<sub>N-</sub>i. </p><p id="p0031" num="0031"> As depicted in FIG. 1 , N = 3 such that the slicer/demultiplexer 1 1 1 slices, the multiplexes and/or divides the input data stream D into (illustratively) three sub-streams denoted as D<sub>0</sub>, D-i and D<sub>2</sub>. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="6"/>-->
 Each of the sub-streams D<sub>0</sub>, D-i and D<sub>2</sub> is coupled to a respective modulator 1 12 (i.e., modulators 1 12<sub>0</sub>, 1 12-1 and 1 12<sub>2</sub>). Each of the modulators 1 12<sub>0</sub>, 1 12-1 and 1 12<sub>2</sub> modulates its respective sub-stream D<sub>0</sub>, D-i and D<sub>2</sub> to provide corresponding modulated signals to be carried by respective spectral fragments S<sub>0</sub>, S-i and S<sub>2</sub>. </p><p id="p0032" num="0032"> The modulators 1 12 may comprise modulators having the same characteristics or having different characteristics, such as the characteristics of waveform type, constellation maps, forward error correction (FEC) settings and so on. Each modulator may be optimized according to a specific type of traffic (e.g., streaming media, non-streaming data and the like), the specific channel conditions associated with its corresponding spectral fragment S, and/or other criteria. </p><p id="p0033" num="0033"> Generally speaking, the amount of data allocated by the </p><p id="p0034" num="0034">slicer/demultiplexer 1 1 1 to any sub-stream D, is proportional to the data carrying capacity of the corresponding spectral fragment S,. In various embodiments, each of the sub-streams D, comprises the same amount of data, while in other embodiments the various sub-streams D, may comprise different amounts of data. </p><p id="p0035" num="0035"> As depicted in FIG. 1 , the first modulator 1 12<sub>0</sub> provides a 6 MHz signal associated with a first spectral fragment S<sub>0</sub>; the second modulator 1 12-i provides a 1 MHz signal associated with a second spectral fragment S-i ; and third modulator 112<sub>2</sub> provides a 1 MHz signal associated with a third spectral fragment S<sub>2</sub>. </p><p id="p0036" num="0036"> A frequency multiplexer (i.e., signal combiner) 1 13 operates to combine the modulated signals to produce a combined modulated signal S<sub>c</sub>, which is modulated onto a carrier signal by up-converter 1 14 to provide a modulated carrier signal C. It is noted that multiple frequency multiplexers / signal combiners 1 13 may be used to multiplex respective groups of modulated signals to be transported via common transponders, microwave links, wireless channels and the like. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="7"/>-->
 In the embodiment of FIG. 1 , the spectrum associated with the modulated carrier signal C is logically or virtually divided into the plurality of spectral fragments used to convey the modulated data sub-streams. The spectral fragment allocation table or other data structure is used to keep track of which spectral fragments have been defined, which spectral fragments are in use (and by which data sub-streams), and which spectral fragments are available. </p><p id="p0037" num="0037">Generally speaking, each transponder/transmission channel may be divided into a plurality of spectral fragments or regions. Each of these spectral fragments or regions may be assigned to a particular data sub-stream. Each of the data sub- streams may be modulated according to a unique or common modulation technique. </p><p id="p0038" num="0038"> As depicted in FIG. 1 , a single satellite transponder is used and, therefore, all of the modulated signals may be combined by frequency multiplexer 1 13 prior to up-conversion and transmission via a single satellite channel. In various embodiments, multiple transponders within one or more satellites may be used. In these embodiments, only those modulated signals to be transmitted via a common transponder within a satellite are combined and then converted together. In various embodiments, modulate waveforms are transmitted independently. </p><p id="p0039" num="0039"> The modulated carrier signal C produced by up-converter 1 14 is amplified by power amplifier 120 and transmitted to satellite 140 via satellite uplink 130. Satellite 140 transmits a modulated carrier signal including the modulated sub- streams D<sub>0</sub>, D-i and D<sub>2</sub> to satellite downlink 150, which propagates the signal to the virtual spectrum aggregator receiver 160. </p><p id="p0040" num="0040"> Virtual spectrum aggregator receiver 160 includes a downconverter (165) which downconverts a combined spectral fragment signal S<sub>c</sub>' from a received carrier signal C, and a frequency demultiplexer (164) which operates to separate the spectral fragments S<sub>0</sub>', S-i ' and S<sub>2</sub>' from the combined spectral fragment signal S<sub>c</sub>'. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="8"/>-->
 Each of the spectral fragments S<sub>0</sub>\ S-i' and S<sub>2</sub>' is coupled to a separate demodulator (i.e., demodulators 162<sub>0</sub>, 162-1 and 162<sub>2</sub>). Each of the demodulators 162<sub>0</sub>, 162i and 162<sub>2</sub> demodulates its respective spectral fragments So', S-i' and S<sub>2</sub>' to provide corresponding demodulated sub-streams D<sub>0</sub>\ Di' and D<sub>2</sub>'. </p><p id="p0041" num="0041"> The demodulated sub-streams D<sub>0</sub>\ Di' and D<sub>2</sub>' are processed by a combiner 161 to produce an output data stream D' representative of the input data stream D initially processed by the virtual spectrum aggregator transmitter 1 10. It is noted that each of the demodulators 162 operates in a manner compatible with its corresponding modulator 1 12. </p><p id="p0042" num="0042"> Optionally, virtual spectrum aggregator receiver 160 includes buffers 166<sub>0</sub>,</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">166-1 and 166<sub>2</sub> which provide an elastic buffering function for the various demodulated sub-streams such that alignment errors induced by different propagation delays associated with the various sub-streams may be avoided prior to combining the sub-streams. The buffers in 166 are depicted as functional elements disposed between the demodulators (162) and combiner 161. In various embodiments, the buffers 166 or their functional equivalent are included within the combiner 161. For example, combiner 161 may include a single buffer which receives data from all of the demodulators (162) and subsequently rearranges that data as output stream D'. Packet ID and/or other information within the sub-streams may be used for this purpose. </p><p id="p0044" num="0044"> Optional control module 170 interacts with an element management system (EMS), a network management system (NMS) and/or other management or control system suitable for use in managing network elements implementing the functions described herein with respect to FIG. 1. The control module 170 may be used to configure various modulators, demodulators and/or other circuitry within the elements described herein with respect FIG. 1. Moreover, the control module 170 may be remotely located with respect to the elements controlled thereby, located proximate transmission circuitry, located proximate receiver circuitry and so on. The control module 170 may be implemented as a general purpose computer programmed to perform specific control functions such as 
<!-- EPO <DP n="9"/>-->
 described herein. In one embodiment, control module 170 adapts the </p><p id="p0045" num="0045">configuration and/or operation of the virtual spectrum aggregator transmitter 1 10 and the virtual spectrum aggregator receiver 160 via, respectively, a first control signal TXCONF and a second control signal RXCONF. In this embodiment, multiple control signals may be provided in the case of multiple transmitters and receivers. </p><p id="p0046" num="0046"> FIG. 2 depicts a graphical representation of a spectral allocation useful in understanding the present embodiments. Specifically, FIG. 2 graphically depicts a 36 MHz spectral allocation in which a first customer is allocated a first portion 210 of the spectrum, illustratively a single 10 MHz block; a second customer is allocated a second portion 220 of the spectrum, illustratively single 8 MHz block; a third customer is allocated a third portion 230 of the spectrum, illustratively single 10 MHz block; and a fourth customer is allocated is allocated a fourth portion 240 of the spectrum, illustratively three noncontiguous spectrum blocks comprising a first 1 MHz block 240-,, a second 1 MHz block 240-, and a 6 MHz block 240<sub>3</sub>. </p><p id="p0047" num="0047"> Within the context of the various embodiments discussed herein, the data stream associated with the fourth customer is divided into two different 1 MHz spectral fragments in a single 6 MHz spectral fragment, each of which is processed in substantially the same manner as described above with respect to FIG. 1. </p><p id="p0048" num="0048"> FIG. 3 depicts a high-level block diagram of a general purpose computing device 300 suitable for use in various embodiments described herein. For example, the computing device 300 depicted in FIG. 3 may be used to execute programs suitable for implementing various transmitter processing functions, receiver processing functions and/or management processing functions as will be described herein. </p><p id="p0049" num="0049"> As depicted in FIG. 3, the computing device 300 includes input/output (I/O) circuitry 310, a processor 320 and memory 330. The processor 320 is coupled to each of the I/O circuitry 310 and memory 330. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="10"/>-->
 The memory 330 is depicted as including buffers 332, transmitter (TX) programs 334, receiver (RX) programs 336 and or management programs 338. The specific programs stored in memory 330 depend upon the function implemented using the computing device 300. </p><p id="p0050" num="0050"> In one embodiment, the slicer/demultiplexer 1 1 1 described above with respect to FIG. 1 is implemented using a computing device such as the computing device 300 of FIG. 3. Specifically, the processor 320 executes the various functions described above with respect to the slicer/demultiplexer 1 1 1. In this embodiment the I/O circuits 310 receive the input data stream D from a data source (not shown) and provide the N sub-streams (D<sub>0</sub>... D<sub>N-</sub> ) to the </p><p id="p0051" num="0051">demodulators 1 12. </p><p id="p0052" num="0052"> In one embodiment, the combiner 161 described above with respect to FIG. 1 is implemented using a computing device such as the computing device 300 of FIG. 3. Specifically, the processor 320 executes the various functions described above with respect to the combiner 161. In this embodiment the I/O circuits 310 receive the demodulated sub-streams D<sub>0</sub>', D-i ' and D<sub>2</sub>' from the demodulators 162 (optionally via buffers 166) and provide the output data stream D' representative of the input data stream D initially processed by the virtual spectrum aggregator transmitter 1 10. </p><p id="p0053" num="0053"> In one embodiment, the optional control module 170 described above with respect to FIG. 1 is implemented using a computing device such as the computing device 300 of FIG. 3. </p><p id="p0054" num="0054"> Although primarily depicted and described as having specific types and arrangements of components, it will be appreciated that any other suitable types and/or arrangements of components may be used for computing device 300. The computing device 300 may be implemented in any manner suitable for implementing the various functions described herein. </p><p id="p0055" num="0055"> It will be appreciated that computer 300 depicted in FIG. 3 provides a general architecture and functionality suitable for implementing functional elements described herein and/or portions of functional elements described 
<!-- EPO <DP n="11"/>-->
 herein. Functions depicted and described herein may be implemented in software and/or hardware, e.g., using a general purpose computer, one or more application specific integrated circuits (ASIC), and/or any other hardware equivalents. </p><p id="p0056" num="0056"> It is contemplated that some of the steps discussed herein as software methods may be implemented within hardware, for example, as circuitry that cooperates with the processor to perform various method steps. Portions of the functions/elements described herein may be implemented as a computer program product wherein computer instructions, when processed by a computer, adapt the operation of the computer such that the methods and/or techniques described herein are invoked or otherwise provided. Instructions for invoking the inventive methods may be stored in fixed or removable media, transmitted via a data stream in a broadcast or other signal bearing medium, transmitted via tangible media and/or stored within a memory within a computing device operating according to the instructions. </p><p id="p0057" num="0057"> FIG. 4 depicts a flow diagram of a method according to one embodiment. Specifically, the method 400 of FIG. 4 is suitable for processing a data stream D for transmission, such as described above with respect to FIG. 1. </p><p id="p0058" num="0058"> At step 410, the data stream including data from one or more customers is received, such as by the virtual spectrum aggregated transmitter 1 10. </p><p id="p0059" num="0059"> At step 420, the received data stream is sliced into N sub-streams, where each sub-streams is associated with a respective spectral fragment. Referring to box 425, the slicing of data streams into sub-streams may be performed using any of the following criteria, alone or in any combination: per customer, per fragment, for data type, fixed size, variable size, combination of various slicing methods and/or other criteria. </p><p id="p0060" num="0060"> At step 430, each of the sub-streams is modulated using a respective modulator. Referring to box 435, demodulators may be optimized for data type, optimized for channel conditions, they share common characteristics, they have various/different characteristics and so on. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="12"/>-->
 At optional step 440, where one or more modulated sub-streams are to be transmitted using the same transponder or transmission channel, these modulated sub-streams are combined. </p><p id="p0061" num="0061"> At step 450, the modulated sub-streams are up converted and transmitted. Referring to box 455, the up conversion/transmission process may be within the context of a satellite communication system, microwave communication system, wireless communication system/channel or other medium. </p><p id="p0062" num="0062"> FIG. 5 depicts a flow diagram of a method according to one embodiment. Specifically, the method 500 of FIG. 5 is suitable for processing one or more received sub-streams, such as described above with respect to FIG. 1. </p><p id="p0063" num="0063"> At step 510, one or more modulated sub-streams are received and down converted. Referring to box 515, one or more modulated sub-streams may be received via a satellite communication system, wireless communication system, wireless communication system/channel or other medium. </p><p id="p0064" num="0064"> At step 520, any sub-streams previously combined at the transmitter are separated to provide individual sub-streams, and at step 530 each of the individual sub-streams is demodulated using a respective appropriate </p><p id="p0065" num="0065">demodulator. </p><p id="p0066" num="0066"> At step 540, one or more of the demodulated sub-streams are selectively delayed so that the resulting demodulated data streams may be temporally aligned. </p><p id="p0067" num="0067"> At step 550, the demodulated and selectively delayed sub-streams are combined to provide a resulting data stream such as a data stream D' </p><p id="p0068" num="0068">representative of an input data stream D initially processed by the virtual spectrum aggregator transmitter. </p><p id="p0069" num="0069"> FIG. 6 depicts a flow diagram of a method according to one embodiment. Specifically, the method 600 of FIG. 6 is suitable for configuring various transmitter and receiver parameters in accordance with the various </p><p id="p0070" num="0070">embodiments. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="13"/>-->
 At step 610, a request is received for the transmission of customer data. Referring to box 615, the request may provide a specified bandwidth, a specified data rate, a specified data type, specified modulation type and/or other information describing the bandwidth and/or service requirements associated with the customer data transmission request. </p><p id="p0071" num="0071"> At step 620, a determination is made as to the spectrum allocation suitable for satisfying the customer data transmission request. </p><p id="p0072" num="0072"> At step 630, an optional determination is made as to whether any specific spectrum related criteria is suitable for satisfying the customer data transmission request. Referring to box 635, such spectrum related criteria may include a minimum bandwidth block size, a requirement for contiguous bandwidth blocks and/or other criteria. </p><p id="p0073" num="0073"> At step 640, available spectrum fragments are identified. Referring to box 645, the identification of available spectrum fragments may be made with respect to an allocation table, a management system and/or other source of such information. In one embodiment, an allocation table defines the spectral allocation associated with each customer served by a satellite communications system; namely, the bandwidth allocation of each customer, the transponder(s) supporting the bandwidth, the satellite(s) supporting the transponder(s) and so on. Additionally, available spectrum fragments are defined in terms of size and spectral region for each transponder of each satellite. </p><p id="p0074" num="0074"> At step 650, available spectrum fragments are allocated to satisfy the customer data transmission request. Referring to box 655, the available spectrum fragments may be allocated as available, optimized for the customer, optimized for the carrier, optimized to reduce spectrum fragment count, optimized to provide resiliency or redundancy, and/or optimized based on other criteria. </p><p id="p0075" num="0075"> At step 660, transmitter/receiver systems are configured to provide the correct number and type of modulators/demodulators to support the customer data transmission request and adapt to any changes to spectrum fragment allocations for the requesting customer and/or other customers. That is, based 
<!-- EPO <DP n="14"/>-->
 upon optimization and/or other criteria, it may be appropriate to modify the spectral fragment allocations of multiple customers to optimize in favor of a particular customer, service provider and the like. </p><p id="p0076" num="0076"> At step 670, billing data, service agreements and the like are updated as appropriate. At step 680, system configuration, provisioning and/or other management data is updated. </p><p id="p0077" num="0077"> In various embodiments, spectral fragment available on different satellite transponders and/or different satellites are aggregated to form a virtual contiguous block. In other embodiments, the entire bandwidth of multiple transponders is used to support high data-rate pipes (e.g., OC-3/12c) over satellite links. </p><p id="p0078" num="0078"> FIGS. 7-9 depict block diagrams of communication systems according to various embodiments. Each of the various components within the </p><p id="p0079" num="0079">communication systems depicted in FIGS. 7-9 operates in substantially the same manner as described above with respect to corresponding components within the communication system of FIG. 1. For example, in each of the embodiments of FIGS. 7-9, an input data stream D is received by a virtual spectrum aggregated transmitter 1 10, where it is processed by a slicer/de-multiplexer x1 1 to provide N sub-streams (D<sub>0</sub>... D<sub>N-</sub>i), where each of the N sub-streams is modulated by respective modulator x12. Other differences and similarities between the various figures will now be described more detail. </p><p id="p0080" num="0080"> FIG. 7 depicts a single transponder embodiment in which a single transponder is used to transport each of a plurality of data streams denoted as streams A, B, C and D. FIG. 7A depicts an uplink portion of the system, while FIG. 7B depicts a downlink portion of the system. </p><p id="p0081" num="0081"> Referring to FIG. 7A, data streams A, B and C are modulated by respective modulators 712 to produce respective modulated streams which are then combined by a first signal combiner 1 13i to provide a combined modulated signal ABC. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="15"/>-->
 Data stream D is processed by a slicer/de-multiplexer 71 1 to provide N sub-streams (D<sub>0</sub>... D<sub>N-</sub>i) which are then modulated by respective modulators 712 (i.e., modulators 712<sub>0</sub>, 712 and 712<sub>2</sub>) to provide corresponding modulated signals to be carried by respective spectral fragments S<sub>0</sub>, Si and S<sub>2</sub>. The corresponding modulated signals are combined by a second signal combiner 713<sub>2</sub> to provide a combined modulated signal DDD, which is combined with modulated signal ABC by a third signal combiner 713<sub>3</sub>. The resulting combined modulated signals are converted by an up converter 714 to produce a carrier signal C which is amplified by a power amplifier 720 and transmitted towards a satellite 740 via a satellite uplink 730. </p><p id="p0082" num="0082"> Referring to FIG. 7B, satellite 740 transmits a modulated carrier signal including the modulated streams A through D to satellite downlink 750, which propagates the signal to a down-converter, 765. The down-converted signal is processed by a frequency de-multiplexer 164<sub>3</sub> which operates to separate the signal into the ABC and DDD signal components. </p><p id="p0083" num="0083"> The ABC signal components are separated by a second frequency demultiplexer 764 to recover the modulated signals and then demodulated by respective demodulators 752. </p><p id="p0084" num="0084"> The DDD signal components are separated by a third frequency de- multiplexer 764<sub>2</sub> to recover the modulated signals which are demodulated by respective demodulators 752. </p><p id="p0085" num="0085"> The demodulated sub-streams D<sub>0</sub>', D and D<sub>2</sub>' are processed by a combiner 761 to produce an output data stream D' representative of the input data stream D. It is noted that each of the demodulators 162 operates in a manner compatible with its corresponding modulator 1 12. </p><p id="p0086" num="0086"> FIG. 8 depicts a dual transponder embodiment in which a first transponder is used to transport each of a plurality of data streams denoted as streams A, B, and C, as well as two of three sub-streams associated with a data stream D, while a second transponder is used to transport each of a plurality of data stream denoted as E and F, as well as the third sub-stream associated with the data 
<!-- EPO <DP n="16"/>-->
 stream D. FIG. 8A depicts an uplink portion of the system, while FIG. 8B depicts a downlink portion of the system. </p><p id="p0087" num="0087"> Referring to FIG. 8A, data streams A, B, C, E and F are modulated by respective modulators 812 to produce respective modulated streams. </p><p id="p0088" num="0088"> Data streams E and F are modulated by respective modulators 812 to produce respective modulated signals. </p><p id="p0089" num="0089"> Data stream D is processed by a slicer/de-multiplexer 71 1 to provide N sub-streams (D<sub>0</sub>... D<sub>N-</sub>i) which are then modulated by respective modulators 712 (i.e., modulators 712<sub>0</sub>, 712-1 and 712<sub>2</sub>) to provide corresponding modulated signals to be carried by respective spectral fragments S<sub>0</sub>, ST and S<sub>2</sub>. </p><p id="p0090" num="0090"> The modulated signals associated with data streams A, B and C are combined by a first signal combiner 813i to provide a combined modulated signal ABC. </p><p id="p0091" num="0091"> The modulated signals associated with sub-streams D<sub>0</sub> and D-i are combined by a second signal combiner 813<sub>2</sub> to provide a combined modulated signal D <sub>2</sub>. </p><p id="p0092" num="0092"> The combined modulated signals produced by the first 813i and second 813<sub>2</sub> signal combiners are then combined by a third signal combiner 813<sub>3</sub> and converted by a first upconverter 814i to produce a first carrier signal C1. </p><p id="p0093" num="0093"> The modulated signals associated with sub-stream D<sub>3</sub> and streams E and</p><p id="p0094" num="0094">F are combined by a fourth signal combiner 813<sub>3</sub> and converted by a second upconverter 814<sub>2</sub> to produce a second carrier signal C2. </p><p id="p0095" num="0095"> The C1 and C2 carrier signals are combined by a fourth signal combiner, 813<sub>4</sub>, amplified by a power amplifier, 820, and transmitted towards a satellite, 840, via respective transponders (A and B) of a satellite uplink 830. </p><p id="p0096" num="0096"> Referring to FIG. 8B, satellite 840 transmits the two modulated carrier signals including the modulated streams A through F via respective transponders (A and B) to satellite downlink 850, which propagates the signal to a down- converter 865. The down-converted signal is separated into its two carrier signals by frequency demultiplexer 864<sub>4</sub>. The two carrier signals are processed using 
<!-- EPO <DP n="17"/>-->
 various demultiplexers in 864, demodulators in 862 and combiner 861 to produce the various output data streams A' through F' representative of the input data stream A through F. </p><p id="p0097" num="0097"> FIG. 9 depicts a dual satellite embodiment in which one satellite (940i) is used to transport a plurality of data streams denoted as streams A, B, and C, as well as two of the three sub-streams associated with data stream D.A second satellite (940<sub>2</sub>) is used to transport a plurality of data streams denoted E and F as well as the third sub-stream associated with data-stream D. FIG. 9A depicts an uplink portion of the system while FIG. 9B depicts a downlink portion of the system. </p><p id="p0098" num="0098"> Referring to FIG. 9A, data streams A, B, C, E and F are processed in substantially the same manner as described above with respect to FIG. 8A, except that the two carrier signals are not combined for transport via respective transponders of a single satellite. Rather, FIG. 9 shows two carrier signals amplified by separate power amplifiers (920-I and 920<sub>2</sub>) and transmitted to satellites 940-I and 940<sub>2</sub>, respectively, using uplinks 930-I and 930<sub>2</sub>. </p><p id="p0099" num="0099"> Referring to FIG. 9B, the two satellites 940 transmit their respective modulated carrier signals including modulated streams A through F via respective downlinks 950, which are then fed to respective down-converters 965. The two down-converted carrier signals are processed using de-multiplexers (964), demodulators (962) and a combiner (961 ) to produce the output data streams A' through F' representative of the input data streams A through F. </p><p id="p0100" num="0100"> FIG. 10 depicts a high-level block diagram of a slicer/de-multiplexer suitable for use in the various embodiments described herein. Specifically, the slicer/de-multiplexer 1000 of FIG. 10 comprises a packet encapsulator 1010, a master scheduler 1020 including a buffer memory 1022, and a plurality of slave schedulers 1030 including buffer memories 1032. </p><p id="p0101" num="0101"> The packet encapsulator 1010 operates to encapsulate packets received from data-stream D into a packet structure having a predefined or normalized format. While various encapsulating packet formats may be used, it is important 
<!-- EPO <DP n="18"/>-->
 that the combiner at a downlink side of a system be configured to combine packets according to the encapsulating format used by the slicer/de-multiplexer at an uplink side of the system. </p><p id="p0102" num="0102"> In one embodiment, encapsulating packets comprise 188 byte packets having a 185-byte payload section and a three-byte header section. The packet encapsulator 1010 extracts a sequence of 185 byte portions from the original data stream D, and encapsulates each extracted portion to form encapsulating packet (EP). The header portion of each encapsulating packet stores a user sequence number associated with payload data such that the sequence of 185 byte portions of the data stream may be reconstructed by a combiner, such as described above with respect to the various figures. </p><p id="p0103" num="0103"> In one embodiment, the user sequence number comprises a 14-bit number that is continually incremented and used to stamp encapsulated packets provided by the packet encapsulator 1010. In one embodiment, the header portion of the packet provided by the packet encapsulator 1010 comprises a first byte storing 47 hexadecimal (i.e. 47h), followed by 2 zero bits, followed by 14 bits associated with the user sequence number. </p><p id="p0104" num="0104"> A larger sequence number field (e.g., 24 or 32 bits) may be used when the aggregate data rate being transported is higher. The size of the sequence number field is related to the amount of buffering that takes place at the receiving combiner element described in various figures above. The size of the buffer, in turn, is related to the ratio of the largest sub-stream bandwidth to the smallest sub-stream bandwidth. Thus, various embodiments may adjust the sequence number field size (and the resulting overhead) based on total aggregate bandwidth and/or the ratio of the highest to smallest bandwidth sub-streams. </p><p id="p0105" num="0105"> In various embodiments, more or fewer than 188 bytes are used to construct encapsulating packets. In various embodiments, more or fewer than three bytes are used to construct encapsulating packet headers. For example, by allocating additional header bits to the user sequence number a larger user 
<!-- EPO <DP n="19"/>-->
 sequence number may be used. In this case, the likelihood of processing at a receiver two encapsulating packets having the same sequence is reduced. </p><p id="p0106" num="0106"> In the embodiments described herein, the fixed packet size of 188 bytes is used for the encapsulating packets. However, in various alternate embodiments different fixed-sized packets and/or different variable sized packets may be used for different sub-streams as long as such packet sizes are compatible with the input interfaces of the respective modulators used for those sub-streams. </p><p id="p0107" num="0107"> The master scheduler 1020 routes encapsulated packets to the various slave schedulers 1030. The slave schedulers 1030 in turn route their packets to respective output ports of the slicer/demultiplexer, thereby providing respective sub-streams to, illustratively, modulators or other components. </p><p id="p0108" num="0108"> Generally speaking, each slave scheduler 1030 accepts packets conforming to the bandwidth of the spectral fragment assigned to that scheduler. Thus, the slave scheduler servicing a 1 MHz spectral fragment channel accepts packets at a data rate approximately 1/10 that of a slave scheduler serving a 10 MHz spectral fragment or region. </p><p id="p0109" num="0109"> The master scheduler 1020 communicates with the slave schedulers 1030 to identify which slave scheduler 1030 is (or should be) capable of receiving the next encapsulated packet. Optionally, the master scheduler 1020 receives status and other management information from the slave schedulers 1030, and some of this status information may be propagated to various management entities (not shown). </p><p id="p0110" num="0110"> In one embodiment, the slave schedulers 1030 provide a control signal to the master scheduler 1020 indicative of an ability to accept the packet. In one embodiment, the master scheduler 1020 allocates packets to the slave schedulers 1030 in a round robin fashion. In one embodiment, where certain transmission channels or spectral regions are preferred based upon customer and/or service provider requirements, the allocation of encapsulated packet by the master scheduler 1020 is weighted in favor of providing more encapsulated 
<!-- EPO <DP n="20"/>-->
 packets to those slave schedulers 1030 servicing the preferred transmission channels. </p><p id="p0111" num="0111"> In one embodiment, each of the slave schedulers is associated with a predefined bandwidth or other indicators of channel capacity associated with the corresponding spectral fragment. In this embodiment, the master scheduler 1020 routes packets according to a weighting assignment for each slave scheduler 1030. </p><p id="p0112" num="0112"> Generally speaking, the master scheduler routes packets according to one or more of a random routing algorithm, a round robin routing algorithm, a customer preference algorithm and a service provider preference algorithm. Such routing may be accommodated by associating a weighting factor with each modulator, spectral fragment, communications channel (e.g., transponder, microwave links, wireless channel etc.) and so on. For example, a preferred spectral fragment may comprise a fragment having a minimum or maximum size, a fragment associated with a relatively low error or relatively high error channel, a fragment associated with a preferred communications type (e.g., satellite, microwave link, wireless network and so on), a fragment associated with a preferred customer and the like. Other means of weighting channels, </p><p id="p0113" num="0113">communication systems, spectral regions and so on may also be used within the context of the various embodiments. </p><p id="p0114" num="0114"> FIG. 1 1 depicts a flow diagram of a method according to one embodiment. At step 1 1 10, packets are received from data stream D. At step 1 120, received packets are encapsulated. Referring to box 1 125, the packet may comprise 185 byte payload and three byte header packets. Other header formats with a different sequence number field size and/or additional control information may be used within the context of the present embodiments. </p><p id="p0115" num="0115"> At step 1 130 the encapsulated packets are buffered by, illustratively, the master scheduler 1020, a separate buffer (not shown) within the packet encapsulator 1010 and so on. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="21"/>-->
 At step 1 140, encapsulates packets are forwarded (or caused to be forwarded) to the slave schedulers 1030 by the master scheduler 1020. </p><p id="p0116" num="0116"> In the various embodiments described herein, each encapsulated packet is coupled to a respective modulator as part of a respective sub-stream. </p><p id="p0117" num="0117">However, in embodiments adapted to provide increased data resiliency and/or backup, encapsulated packets may be coupled to multiple modulators as part of multiple respective sub-streams. In these embodiments, the sequence number associated with the encapsulated packet remains the same. </p><p id="p0118" num="0118"> In these embodiments, a receiver will process the first encapsulated packet (or error-free encapsulated packet) having the appropriate sequence number and ignore other packets having the same sequence number. That is, when re-ordering encapsulating packets at the receiver, those encapsulating packets having a sequence number matching a sequence number of a recently ordered encapsulating packet are discarded. Since sequence numbers are cyclical or repeated (e.g., every 16,384 encapsulating packets in the case of a 14-bit sequence number), an encapsulating packet having the same sequence number of encapsulating packet processed several thousand packets ago is likely a duplicate of that previously processed encapsulating packet and, therefore, should be dropped or discarded as being redundant. </p><p id="p0119" num="0119"> Various embodiments described herein provide dynamic spectrum aggregation of disjoint blocks of spectrum such that spectrum may be added to or subtracted from existing spectrum allocations as customer bandwidth requirements change. Additionally, small or orphaned spectrum blocks (i.e., those spectrum blocks too small to generally be useful) may be virtually combined to form larger blocks of bandwidth. </p><p id="p0120" num="0120"> The above-described embodiments provide a number of advantages, including improved system resiliency since the loss of any one spectral fragment will likely not cause a complete loss of service. In addition, when spectral fragments are mapped across multiple transponders, the loss of any one transponder does not result in a complete loss of service; rather, a graceful 
<!-- EPO <DP n="22"/>-->
 degradation of service is provided. Older/existing schemes utilizing contiguous spectrum are capable of using only one transponder which becomes a potential single point of failure. </p><p id="p0121" num="0121"> Various benefits of the embodiments include significantly higher spectral usage efficiency as well as the ability to use orphaned spectral fragments that are too small to use otherwise. The various embodiments are applicable to satellite applications, point-to-point wireless links such as those used in bent-pipe</p><p id="p0122" num="0122">SatCom applications, wireless backhaul infrastructure such as provided using microwave towers and so on. </p><p id="p0123" num="0123"> The various embodiments provide a mechanism wherein bandwidth may be allocated by "appending" additional blocks of bandwidth to those bandwidth blocks already in use, thereby facilitating a "pay-as-you-grow" business model for service providers and consumers. </p><p id="p0124" num="0124"> In various embodiments, a single transponder in a satellite system is used to propagate a carrier signal including a plurality of modulated sub-streams, each of the modulated sub-streams occupying its respective spectral fragment region.</p><p id="p0125" num="0125">In other embodiments, multiple carrier signals are propagated via respective transponders. </p><p id="p0126" num="0126"> In various embodiments, a single microwave link within a microwave communication system is used to propagate a carrier signal including a plurality of modulated sub-streams, each modulated sub-stream occupying its respective spectral fragment region. In other embodiments, multiple carrier signals are propagated via respective microwave links. </p><p id="p0127" num="0127"> In various embodiments, a single wireless channel within a wireless communication system is used to propagate a carrier signal including a plurality of modulated sub-streams, each modulated sub-stream occupying its respective spectral fragment region. In other embodiments, multiple carrier signals are propagated via respective wireless channels. </p><p id="p0128" num="0128"> While the foregoing is directed to various embodiments of the present invention, other and further embodiments of the invention may be devised 
<!-- EPO <DP n="23"/>-->
 without departing from the basic scope thereof and those skilled in the art can readily devise many other varied embodiments that still incorporate these teachings. As such, the appropriate scope of the invention is to be determined according to the claims, which follow. 
</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM46552967" ref-ucid="WO-2012161784-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><claim-statement><!-- EPO <DP n="24"/>-->What is claimed is: </claim-statement><claim id="clm-0001" num="1"><claim-text>1. A method, comprising: </claim-text><claim-text> dividing a data stream into a plurality of sub-streams, each of said sub- streams associated a respective spectral fragment and having a data rate compatible with a bandwidth of the respective spectral fragment; </claim-text><claim-text> modulating each of the sub-streams to provide a modulated signal adapted for transmission via the respective spectral fragment; and </claim-text><claim-text> upconverting said modulated signals onto respective spectral fragments of at least one carrier signal; </claim-text><claim-text> wherein the sub-streams included within the upconverted modulated signals are adapted to be demodulated and combined at a receiver to recover thereby data stream. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0002" num="2"><claim-text>2. The method of claim 1 , further comprising combining two or more of the modulated sub-streams to form respective combined sub-streams, each of said combined sub-streams being modulated onto a modulated signal adapted for transmission via a spectral fragment having a bandwidth compatible with the total effective data rate of combined sub-streams. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0003" num="3"><claim-text>3. The method of claim 1.further comprising transmitting said carrier signals via respective channels within a communications system, wherein each of said one or more carrier signals is supported by a respective transponder within a satellite communications system, a respective microwave link within a microwave communications system, or a respective wireless channel within a wireless communications system. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0004" num="4"><claim-text>4. The method of claim 1 , wherein said dividing a data stream into a plurality of sub-streams comprises: <!-- EPO <DP n="25"/>--> encapsulating sequential portions of said data stream into payload portions of respective encapsulating packets, each of said sequential portions of said data stream being associated with a respective sequence number included within a header portion of the respective encapsulating packet; and </claim-text><claim-text> including each encapsulating packet within one or more of said sub- streams. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0005" num="5"><claim-text>5. The method of claim 1 , further comprising: </claim-text><claim-text> receiving each of the modulated sub-streams via respective spectral fragments; </claim-text><claim-text> demodulating each of the modulated sub-streams; </claim-text><claim-text> ordering encapsulating packets received via one or more sub-streams according to their respective sequence numbers; and </claim-text><claim-text> extracting sequential portions of said data stream from said ordered encapsulating packets to recover thereby said data stream. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0006" num="6"><claim-text>6. Apparatus, comprising: </claim-text><claim-text> a splitter, for dividing a data stream into a plurality of sub-streams, each of said sub-streams associated a respective spectral fragment and having a data rate compatible with a bandwidth of the respective spectral fragment; </claim-text><claim-text> a plurality of modulators, each modulator configured to modulate a respective sub-stream to provide a modulated signal adapted for transmission via the respective spectral fragment; and </claim-text><claim-text> at least one upconverter, for upconverting said modulated signals onto respective spectral fragments of at least one carrier signal; </claim-text><claim-text> wherein the sub-streams included within the upconverted modulated signals are adapted to be demodulated and combined at a receiver to recover thereby data stream. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0007" num="7"><claim-text>7. The apparatus of claim 6, wherein said splitter comprises: <!-- EPO <DP n="26"/>--> an encapsulate^ for encapsulating sequential portions of said data stream into payload portions of respective encapsulating packets, each of said sequential portions of said data stream being associated with a respective sequence number included within a header portion of the respective </claim-text><claim-text>encapsulating packet; </claim-text><claim-text> a master scheduler, for selectively routing encapsulated packets towards the demodulators; and </claim-text><claim-text> a plurality of sub schedulers, each of said sub schedulers adapted to route packets received from the master scheduler toward a respective modulator. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0008" num="8"><claim-text>8. The apparatus of claim 7, wherein said master scheduler routes packets according to one of a random routing algorithm, a round robin routing algorithm. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0009" num="9"><claim-text>9. The apparatus of claim 7, wherein: </claim-text><claim-text> said master scheduler routes packets according to one of a customer preference algorithm and a service provider preference algorithm, wherein each sub-stream is associated with a respective weight; and </claim-text><claim-text> the respective weight of a sub-stream is defined by one or more of a preferred spectral fragment, a preferred spectral fragment type, the preferred communication channel, a preferred communication channel type, a preferred traffic type and a preferred customer. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0010" num="10"><claim-text>10. A computer readable medium including software instructions which, when executed by a processer, perform a method comprising: </claim-text><claim-text> dividing a data stream into a plurality of sub-streams, each of said sub- streams associated a respective spectral fragment and having a data rate compatible with a bandwidth of the respective spectral fragment; </claim-text><claim-text> modulating each of the sub-streams to provide a modulated signal adapted for transmission via the respective spectral fragment; and <!-- EPO <DP n="27"/>--> upconverting said modulated signals onto respective spectral fragments of at least one carrier signal; </claim-text><claim-text> wherein the sub-streams included within the upconverted modulated signals are adapted to be demodulated and combined at a receiver to recover thereby data stream. </claim-text></claim></claims><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
