<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2206362-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2206362" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="39495320" file-reference-id="299951" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146588195" ucid="EP-2206362-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2206362</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-07819038-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154850387" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>07819038</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20071016</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP220287803" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>07819038.6</doc-number><date>20071016</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140554303" ucid="EP-2007008970-W" linkage-type="W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>2007008970</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20071016</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130801</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989324937" load-source="docdb">H04R  25/00        20060101AFI20090511BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2079248612" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04R2225/43        20130101 LA20140529BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2079248956" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04R  25/407       20130101 LI20140527BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2079249975" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04R  25/43        20130101 LA20140527BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2079251014" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04R  25/405       20130101 FI20140529BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2079257257" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04R2225/41        20130101 LA20140529BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132369218" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">VERFAHREN UND SYSTEM FÜR DRAHTLOSE HÖRHILFE</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132369219" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">METHOD AND SYSTEM FOR WIRELESS HEARING ASSISTANCE</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132369220" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">PROCÉDÉ ET SYSTÈME POUR UNE ASSISTANCE AUDITIVE SANS FIL</invention-title><citations><patent-citations><patcit mxw-id="PCIT370791922" load-source="docdb" ucid="EP-1326478-A2"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>1326478</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20030709</date></document-id><sources><source name="EXA" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT370794434" load-source="docdb" ucid="US-6330339-B1"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>6330339</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20011211</date></document-id><sources><source name="EXA" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit></patent-citations></citations></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919537944" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>PHONAK AG</last-name><address><country>CH</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919508966" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>PHONAK AG</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919542990" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>BIUNDO LOTITO GIUSEPPINA</last-name><address><country>CH</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919518315" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>BIUNDO LOTITO, GIUSEPPINA</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919021982" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>BIUNDO LOTITO, GIUSEPPINA</last-name><address><street>Rue des Poudrieres 29</street><city>CH-2000 Neuchâtel</city><country>CH</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919505505" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>DIJKSTRA EVERT</last-name><address><country>CH</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919531163" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>DIJKSTRA, EVERT</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919021981" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>DIJKSTRA, EVERT</last-name><address><street>Au Ruz Baron 2</street><city>CH-2046 Fontaines</city><country>CH</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919524688" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>MUELDER HANS</last-name><address><country>CH</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919538552" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>MUELDER, HANS</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919021983" load-source="patent-office" sequence="3" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>MÜLDER, Hans</last-name><address><street>Steinackerstrasse 21</street><city>CH-3184 Wünnewil</city><country>CH</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919514446" load-source="docdb" sequence="4" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>PLATZ RAINER</last-name><address><country>CH</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919537545" load-source="docdb" sequence="4" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>PLATZ, RAINER</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919021980" load-source="patent-office" sequence="4" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>PLATZ, RAINER</last-name><address><street>Chemin des Battieux 6c</street><city>CH-2013 Colombier</city><country>CH</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919021984" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Phonak AG</last-name><iid>100752602</iid><address><street>Laubisrütistrasse 28</street><city>8712 Stäfa</city><country>CH</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919021985" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Schwan - Schwan - Schorer</last-name><iid>100061171</iid><address><street>Bauerstrasse 22</street><city>80796 München</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="EP-2007008970-W"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2007008970</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20071016</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2009049646-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2009049646</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20090423</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549799734" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549782506" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549870863" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549868026" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549782507" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549923083" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549783584" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549782508" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549782521" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549874722" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549870864" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549870865" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549783589" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549782522" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549923084" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549868027" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549782523" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549870910" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549782524" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549870911" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549799735" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549870912" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549870913" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549799736" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549874723" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549874724" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549870918" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549923085" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549874725" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549868028" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549890301" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549799741" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63960623" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to a system for providing hearing assistance to a user, comprising a microphone arrangement for capturing audio signals, an central signal processing unit for processing the captured audio signals, and means for transmitting the processed audio signals via a wireless audio link to means worn at or in at least one of the user's ears for stimulating the hearing of the user according to the processed audio signals.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002">Usually in such systems the wireless audio link is an FM radio link. The benefit of such systems is that sound captured by a remote microphone at the transmission unit can be presented at a high sound pressure level and good signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) to the hearing of the user wearing the receiver unit at his ear(s).</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">According to one typical application of such wireless audio systems, the stimulating means is a loudspeaker which is part of a receiver unit or is connected thereto. Such systems are particularly helpful for being used in teaching e.g. (a) normal-hearing children suffering from auditory processing disorders (APD), (b) children suffering a unilateral loss (one deteriorated ear), or (c) children with a mild hearing loss, wherein the teacher's voice is captured by the microphone of the transmission unit, and the corresponding audio signals are transmitted to and reproduced by the receiver unit worn by the child, so that the teacher's voice can be heard by the child at an enhanced level, in particular with respect to the background noise level prevailing in the classroom. It is well known that presentation of the teacher's voice at such enhanced level supports the child in listening to the teacher.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">According to another typical application of wireless audio systems the receiver unit is connected to or integrated into a hearing instrument, such as a hearing aid. The benefit of such systems is that the microphone of the hearing instrument can be supplemented with or replaced by the remote microphone which produces audio signals which are transmitted wirelessly to the FM receiver and thus to the hearing instrument. FM systems have been standard equipment for children with hearing loss (wearing hearing aids) and deaf children (implanted with a cochlear implant) in educational settings for many years.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">Hearing impaired adults are also increasingly using FM systems. They typically use a sophisticated transmitter which can (a) be pointed to the audio-source of interest (during e.g. cocktail parties), (b) put on a table (e.g. in a restaurant or a business meeting), or (c) put around the neck of a partner/speaker and receivers that are connected to or integrated into the<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> hearing aids. Some transmitters even have an integrated Bluetooth module giving the hearing impaired adult the possibility to connect wirelessly with devices such as cell phones, laptops etc.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">The merit of wireless audio systems lies in the fact that a microphone placed a few inches from the mouth of a person speaking receives speech at a much higher level than one placed several feet away. This increase in speech level corresponds to an increase in signal-to-noise ratio (SNR) due to the direct wireless connection to the listener's amplification system. The resulting improvements of signal level and SNR in the listener's ear are recognized as the primary benefits of FM radio systems, as hearing-impaired individuals are at a significant disadvantage when processing signals with a poor acoustical SNR.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="CA2422449A2"><text>CA 2 422 449 A2</text></patcit> relates to a communication system comprising an FM receiver for a hearing aid, wherein audio signals may be transmitted from a plurality of transmitters via an analog FM audio link.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">Usually the remote wireless microphone of a wireless hearing assistance system is a portable or hand-held device which may be used in multiple environments and conditions: (a) the remote microphone may be held by the hearing-impaired person and pointed towards the desired audio source, such as in a one-to-one conversation to the interlocutor; (b) the remote microphone may be worn around the neck; (c) the remote microphone may be put on a table in a conference or restaurant situation; (d) an external microphone may be connected to the system, which may be worn, for example, in the manner of a lapel microphone or a boom microphone; (e) an external audio source, such as a music player, may be connected to the system.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">Usually, the audio signal processing schemes implemented in such wireless systems are a compromise between all wearing modes and operation options. Typically, these signal processing schemes, in particular, the gain model, are fixed, apart from the user's possibility to manually choose between a few beam forming and noise canceling options, which are commonly referred to as different "zoom" positions.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">For hearing instruments it is known to perform an analysis of the present acoustic environment ("classifier") based on the audio signals captured by the internal microphone of the hearing instrument in order to select the most appropriate audio signal processing scheme, in particular with regard to the compression characteristics, for the audio signal processing<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> within the hearing instrument based on the result of the acoustic environment analysis. Examples of classifier approaches are found in <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="US20020090098A1"><text>US 2002/0090098 A1</text></patcit>, <patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="US20070140512A1"><text>US 2007/0140512 A1</text></patcit>, <patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="EP1326478A2"><text>EP 1 326 478 A2</text></patcit> and <patcit id="pcit0005" dnum="EP1691576A2"><text>EP 1 691 576 A2</text></patcit>.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">In <patcit id="pcit0006" dnum="EP1691574A2"><text>EP 1 691 574 A2</text></patcit> and <patcit id="pcit0007" dnum="EP1819195A2"><text>EP 1 819 195 A2</text></patcit> wireless hearing assistance systems are described, comprising a transmission unit including a beam former microphone arrangement and a hearing instrument, wherein a classifier for analyzing the acoustic environment is located in the transmission unit and wherein the result provided by the classifier is used to adjust the gain applied to the audio signals captured by the beam former microphone arrangement in the transmission unit and/or in the receiver unit/hearing instrument.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012"><patcit id="pcit0008" dnum="EP1083769A1"><text>EP 1 083 769 A1</text></patcit> relates to a hearing aid system comprising a sensor for capturing the movements of the user's body, such as an acceleration sensor, wherein the information provided by such sensor is used in a speech recognition process applied to audio signals captured by the microphone of the hearing aid.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013"><patcit id="pcit0009" dnum="EP0567535B1"><text>EP 0 567 535 B1</text></patcit> relates to a hearing aid comprising an accelerometer for capturing mechanical vibrations of the hearing aid housing in order to subtract the accelerometer signal from the audio signals captured by the internal microphone of the hearing aid.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014"><patcit id="pcit0010" dnum="US6330339B1"><text>US 6 330 339 B1</text></patcit> discloses a hearing aid comprising an acceleration sensor. A noise cancelling mode of the hearing aid is selected based on an output of the acceleration sensor and a level of baseline tonus.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015"><patcit id="pcit0011" dnum="WO2007082579A2"><text>WO 2007/082579 A2</text></patcit> relates to a hearing protection system comprising two earplugs, which each comprise a microphone and a loudspeaker connected by wires to a common central audio signal processing unit worn around at the user's body. A detector is provided for detecting whether external audio signals are provided to the central audio signal processing unit from an external communication device connected to the central audio signal processing unit. The output signal of the detector is used to select an audio signal processing mode of the central audio signal processing unit.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016"><patcit id="pcit0012" dnum="US20040136522A1"><text>US 2004/0136522 A1</text></patcit> relates to a hearing protection system comprising two hearing protection headphones which both comprise an active-noise-reduction unit. The headphones also comprise a loudspeaker for reproducing external audio signals supplied from external communication devices. The system also comprises a boom microphone. A device detector is provided for controlling the supply of power to the boom microphone depending on whether a external communication device is connected to the system.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017"><patcit id="pcit0013" dnum="US20020106094A1"><text>US 2002/0106094 A1</text></patcit> relates to a hearing aid comprising in internal and a wireless external microphone. A connection detection circuit is provided for activating the power supply of the<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --><!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> external microphone once the external microphone is electrically separated from the hearing aid.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018"><patcit id="pcit0014" dnum="DE102005017496B3"><text>DE 10 2005 017 496 B3</text></patcit> relates to a hearing assistance system according to the preamble of claim 10, comprising a wireless directional microphone arrangement comprising two microphones and a control unit including an orientation sensor fixed at the microphones and providing for an orientation signal which is used for controlling the microphones. The microphones may be turned off when the main sound reception direction is vertically downwardly, may be used in a directional mode when the main sound reception direction is horizontal and may be used in an omnidirectional mode when the main sound reception direction is vertically upwardly.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">It is an object of the invention to provide for a method for providing hearing assistance using a wireless microphone arrangement, wherein the listening comfort, such as the signal to noise ratio (SNR), should be optimized at any time. It is a further object of the invention to provide for a corresponding wireless hearing assistance system.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">According to the invention, these objects are obtained by a method as defined in claim 1 and by a system as defined in claim 10, respectively.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">The invention is beneficial in that, by measuring at least one mechanical parameter of the microphone arrangement, namely the acceleration, and/or the distance to a sound source, with the distance being measured by an ultrasonic and/or optical distance sensor, and by selecting the central signal processing scheme according to the present value of this at least one mechanical parameter, the processing of the audio signals captured by the microphone arrangement can be automatically adjusted to the present use situation of the system.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">Preferred embodiments of the invention are defined in the dependent claims.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">In the following, examples of the invention are described and illustrated by reference to the attached drawings, wherein:
<dl id="dl0001"><dt>Fig. 1</dt><dd>is a block diagram of one embodiment of a hearing assistance system according to the invention;</dd><dt>Fig. 2</dt><dd>is a block diagram showing in a schematic manner the internal structure of the central signal processing unit of the system of <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>;<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></dd><dt>Fig. 3</dt><dd>is an example of a default setting of the output signal level (top) and the corresponding gain (bottom) as a function of the input signal level;</dd><dt>Fig. 4</dt><dd>shows examples of deviations from the default setting of <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> for different use modes of a hearing assistance system according to the invention; and</dd><dt>Fig. 5</dt><dd>shows an example of the gain as a function of the audio signal frequency for a default setting and for specific use modes of a hearing assistance system according to the invention.</dd></dl><!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p><p id="p0024" num="0024"><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> shows a block diagram of an example of a wireless hearing assistance system comprising a transmission unit 10 and at least one ear unit 12 which is to be worn at or in one of the user's ears (an ear unit 12 may be provided only for one of the two ears of the user, or an ear unit 12 may be provided for each of the ears). According to <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> the ear unit 12 comprises a receiver unit 14, which may supply its output signal to a hearing instrument 16 which is mechanically and electrically connected to the receiver unit 14, for example, via a standardized interface 17 (such as a so-called "audio shoe"), or, according to a variant, to a loudspeaker 18, which is worn at least in part in the user's ear canal (for example, the loudspeaker itself may be located in the ear canal or a sound tube may extend from the loudspeaker located at the ear into the ear canal).</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">The hearing instrument 16 usually will be a hearing aid, such as of the BTE (Behind The Ear)-type, the ITE (In The Ear)-type or the CIC (Completely In the Canal)-type. Typically, the hearing instrument 16 comprises one or more microphones 20, a central unit 22 for performing audio signal processing and for controlling the hearing instrument 16, a power amplifier 24 and a loudspeaker 26.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">The transmission unit 10 comprises a transmitter 30 and an antenna 32 for transmitting audio signals processed in a central signal processing unit 28 via a wireless link 34 to the receiver unit 14, which comprises an antenna 36, a receiver 38 and a signal processing unit 40 for receiving the audio signals transmitted via the link 34 in order to supply them to the hearing instrument 16 or the speaker 18. The wireless audio link 34 preferably is an FM (frequency modulation) link.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">Rather than consisting of a receiver unit 14 connected to a hearing instrument 16 the ear unit 12, as an alternative, may consist of a hearing instrument 16' into which the functionality of the receiver unit 14, i.e. the antenna 36 and the receiver 38, is integrated. Such an alternative is also schematically shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">The transmission unit 10 comprises a microphone arrangement 42, which usually comprises at least two spaced-apart microphones M1 and M2, an audio input 44 for connecting an external audio source 46, e.g. a music player, or an external microphone 48 to the transmission unit 10, a distance sensor 50, an acceleration sensor 52 and an orientation sensor 54. In addition, the transmission unit 10 may comprise a second audio input 44', so that, for example, the external audio source 46 and the external microphone 48 my be connected at the same time to the transmission unit 10, and an auxiliary microphone 56 in close mechanical<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> and acoustical contact with the housing of the transmission unit 10 for capturing audio signals representative of body noise and/or housing noise. The external microphone 48 may comprise one or several capsules, the signals of which are further processed in the central signal processing unit 28. The transmission unit 10 also comprises a unit 66 which is capable of determining whether an external audio signal source 46 is connected to the audio input 44 and to estimate the type of a external microphone 48, when connected to the audio input 44, by sensing at least one electrical parameter, such as the impedance of the external microphone 48.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">The transmission unit 10 is designed as a portable unit which may serve several purposes: (a) it may be used in a "conference mode", in which it is placed stationary on a table; (b) it may be used in a "hand-held mode", in which it is held in the hand of the user of the ear unit 12; (c) it may be worn around a person's neck, usually a person speaking to the user of the ear unit 12, such as the teacher in a classroom teaching hearing-impaired persons, or a guide in a museum, etc. ("neck mode"); (d) it may be worn at the body of the user of the ear unit 12, with an external microphone 48 and/or an external audio source 46 being connected to the transmission unit 10 ("external audio mode"); the external audio source may be e.g. a TV set or any kind of audio player (e.g. MP3). The transmission unit 10 may in this case also be placed next to the audio equipment.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030"><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> is a block diagram showing in a schematic manner the internal structure of the central signal processing unit 28 of the transmission unit 10, which comprises a beam former 58, a classification unit 60 including a voice activity detector (VAD), an audio signal mixing/adding unit 62 and an audio signal processing unit 64. The audio signal processing unit 64 usually will include elements like a gain model, noise canceling algorithms and/or an equalizer, i.e. frequency-dependent gain control.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">The audio signals captured by the microphones M1, M2 of the microphone arrangement 42 are supplied as input to the beam former 58, and the output signal provided by the beam former 58 is supplied to the mixing/adding unit 62. In addition, the audio signals of at least one of the microphones M1, M2 are supplied to the classification unit 60; in addition, also the output of the beam former 58 may be supplied to the classification unit 60. The classification unit 60 serves to analyze the audio signals captured by the microphone arrangement 42 in order to determine a present auditory scene category from a plurality of auditory scene categories, i.e. the classification unit 60 serves to determine the present acoustic environment. The output of the classification unit 60 is supplied to the beam former 58, the mixing/adding<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> unit 62 and the audio signal processing unit 64 in order to control the audio signal processing in the central signal processing unit 28 by selecting the presently applied audio signal processing scheme according to the present acoustic environment as determined by the classification unit 60.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">Also the audio signals captured by the external microphone 48 may be supplied to the classification unit 60 in order to be taken into account in the auditory scene analysis.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">The output of the audio input monitoring unit 66 may be supplied to the classification unit 60, to the mixing/adding unit 62 and to the audio signal processing unit 64 in order to select an audio signal processing scheme according to the presence of an external audio source 46 or according to the type of external microphone 48. For example, the external microphone 48 may be a boom microphone, one or a plurality of omni-directional microphones or a beamforming microphone. Depending on the type of microphone, the audio input sensitivity and other parameters, such as the choice between an energy-based VAD or a more sophisticated VAD based on direction of arrival in the classification unit 60, may be adjusted automatically.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">The audio signals captured by the auxiliary microphone 56 are supplied to the mixing/adding unit 62 in order to be subtracted from the audio signals captured by the microphone arrangement 42, for example, by using a Wiener filter, in order to remove body noise and/or housing noise from the audio signals captured by the microphone arrangement 42.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">The audio signals received at the audio input 44, 44' are supplied to the mixing/adding unit 62.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">The output of the mixing/adding unit 62 is supplied to the audio signal processing unit 64.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">The distance sensor 50 comprises an ultrasonic and/or an optical, usually infrared, distance sensor in order to measure the distance between the sound source, usually a speaking person towards which the microphone arrangement 42 is directed, and the microphone arrangement 42. To this end, the distance sensor 50 is arranged in such a manner that it aims at the object to which the microphone arrangement 42 is directed. The output of the distance sensor 50 is taken into account in the gain model 64 in order to select an audio signal processing scheme according to the measured distance.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">The acceleration sensor 52 serves to measure the acceleration acting on the transmission unit 10 - and hence on the microphone arrangement 42 - in order to estimate in which mode the<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> transmission unit 10 is presently used. For example, if the measured acceleration is very low, it can be concluded that the transmission unit 10 is used in a stationary mode, i.e. in a conference mode.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">The orientation sensor 54 preferably is designed for measuring the spatial orientation of the transmission unit, and hence the microphone arrangement 42, so that it can be estimated whether the microphone arrangement 42 oriented essentially vertical or essentially horizontal. Such orientation information can be used for estimating the present use mode of the transmission unit 10. For example, an essentially vertical orientation is typical for a neck-worn / chest-worn mode.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">By combining the information provided by the acceleration sensor 52 and the orientation sensor 54 the best estimation of the present use mode is obtained. For example, an essentially horizontal position without significant acceleration is an indicator of a conference/restaurant mode, whereas an essentially horizontal position with acceleration of some extent is an indicator of a hand-held mode. In the hand-held mode, the distance measurement by the distance sensor 50 is most useful, since in the hand-held mode the user may hold the transmission unit 10 in such a manner that the microphone arrangement 52 points to a person speaking to the user. The orientation sensor 54 may comprise a gyroscope, a tilt sensor and/or a roll ball switch.</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">The output of the sensors 50, 52 and 54 is supplied to the audio signal processing unit 64 in order to select an audio signal processing scheme according to the measured values of the mechanical parameters of the microphone arrangement 42 monitored by the sensors 50, 52 and 54. In particular, as already mentioned above, the information provided by the sensors 50, 52 and 54 can be used to estimate the present use mode of the transmission unit 10 in order to automatically optimize the audio signal processing by selecting the audio signal processing scheme most appropriate for the present use mode.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">In the following, examples of such optimization of the audio signal processing are described by reference to <figref idrefs="f0003">Figs. 3 to 5</figref>.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">At the bottom in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> an example of the gain as a function of the input signal level (the corresponding dependency of the output signal level on the input signal level is shown above in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>) of a default gain model is shown. In the example of <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> the gain is essentially constant for medium input signal levels (from K1 to K2) while the gain is reduced for high<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> input signal levels with increasing input signal level ("compression") and the gain is also reduced for low input signal levels ("soft squelch" or "expansion").</p><p id="p0044" num="0044"><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 5</figref> shows an example of the gain as a function of frequency of a default gain model (curve A), which is relatively flat.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045">When the transmission unit 10 is hanging around the neck or is attached to the chest of a person speaking to the user of the ear unit 12 ("neck/chest mode", which is indicated by an essentially vertical position as measured by the orientation sensor 54), input levels exceeding 75 dB-SPL can typically be expected for the speech signal to be transmitted (this condition is indicated by the working point P1 in <figref idrefs="f0003">Figs. 3 and 4</figref>). The compression reduces the gain in this case. In the "neck/chest mode", input signals below a certain level, e.g. knee point K2, can be considered to be mostly surrounding noise and/or clothing noise and shall be compressed. Based on the information of the wearing mode, the release time of the compression algorithm can be increased to a few seconds, which avoids the background noise coming up in speech pauses.</p><p id="p0046" num="0046">A similar reduction of the overall gain may take place if the audio input monitoring unit 66 detects that a chest microphone or a boom microphone is connected to the transmission unit 10.</p><p id="p0047" num="0047">When the audio input monitoring unit 66 detects the presence of an external audio signal source 46, which typically is a music player, a "music mode" may be selected in which the dynamic range is increased, for example, by avoiding too strong compression in order to enhance the listening comfort (an example is indicated in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 4</figref> by the curve M).</p><p id="p0048" num="0048">When the transmission unit 10 is in a horizontal position with virtually no movement, which is an indicator for the conference/restaurant mode in which the transmission unit 10 is placed on a table, the beam former 58 should be switched to an omni-directional mode in which there is no beam forming, while the frequency-dependent gain should be optimized for speech understanding. According to <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 5</figref>, speech understanding may be enhanced by reducing the gain at frequencies below and above the speech frequency range, see curve C. Alternatively, the beam former 58 may be switched to a zoom mode in which the direction of the beamformer is automatically adjusted to the direction of the most intense sound source.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">As already mentioned above, an essentially horizontal position of the transmission unit 10 with relative movements of some extent indicates that the transmission unit 10 is carried in<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> the hand of the user of the ear unit 12. In this case, a beamforming algorithm with enhanced gain at lower input levels (as indicated by the arrow in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 4</figref>) would be the first choice. The gain applied at lower input levels may depend on the measured distance to the sound source, with a larger distance requiring higher gain. Such enhanced gain at lower input levels is indicated by the curves H1 and H2 in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 4</figref>. In addition, an enhanced roll-off at low and high frequencies, i.e. at frequencies outside the speech frequency range, may be applied in order to emphasize speech signals while keeping low frequency and high frequency noises at reduced gain levels, see curves B and C of <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 5</figref>.</p><p id="p0050" num="0050">The information obtained by the distance sensor 50 with regard to the distance of the microphone arrangement 42 to the sound source may be used to set the level-dependent and/or frequency-dependent gain and/or the aperture angle of the beam former 58 according to the measured distance.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56984606" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Verfahren zur Hörunterstützung eines Nutzers, wobei:
<claim-text>Audiosignale mittels einer Mikrofonanordnung (42) aufgefangen werden;</claim-text>
<claim-text>mindestens ein mechanischer Parameter gemessen wird, der aus der aus einer Beschleunigung der Mikrofonanordnung und einem Abstand der Mikrofonanordnung von einer Schallquelle bestehenden Gruppe ausgewählt ist, wobei der Abstand mittels eines Ultraschall-Abstandssensors und/oder optischen Abstandssensors gemessen wird;</claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Audiosignalverarbeitungsschema gemäß dem gemessenen mindestens einen mechanischen Parameter ausgewählt wird;</claim-text>
<claim-text>die aufgefangenen Audiosignale mittels einer zentralen Signalverarbeitungseinheit (28) gemäß dem ausgewählten Audiosignalverarbeitungsschema verarbeitet werden;</claim-text>
<claim-text>die verarbeiteten Audiosignale über eine drahtlose Audiostrecke (34) zu Stimulationsmitteln (18, 26) gesendet werden, die an oder in mindestens einem Ohr des Nutzers getragen werden; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>das Gehör des Nutzers mittels der Stimulationsmittel gemäß den verarbeiteten Audiosignalen stimuliert wird;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei die Mikrofonanordnung (42) Mittel (50, 52, 54) zum Messen des mindestens einen mechanischen Parameters, die zentrale Signalverarbeitungseinheit (28) und ein Sendeabschnitt (30, 32) für das Senden der verarbeiteten Audiosignale innerhalb einer tragbaren Einheit (10) integriert sind, welche stationär auf einem Tisch platziert wird, in der Hand des Nutzers gehalten wird, oder um den Nacken oder an der Brust einer Person getragen wird.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Verfahren gemäß Anspruch 1, wobei es sich bei der Audiosignalstrecke um eine FM-Strecke handelt, wobei das Verfahren ferner die folgenden Schritte beinhaltet: Zuführen der Audiosignale von einer externen Audiosignalquelle (46) zu der zentralen Signalverarbeitungseinheit (28), Bestimmen, ob die externe Audiosignalquelle mit der zentralen Signalverarbeitungseinheit verbunden ist, und Auswählen des Audiosignalverarbeitungsschemas gemäß der festgestellten Gegenwart eines externen Audiosignals, und wobei ein Audiosignalverarbeitungsschema ausgewählt wird, in welchem ein Dynamikbereich bezüglich eines Voreinstellungs-Signalverarbeitungsschemas vergrößert ist.<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Verfahren gemäß einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei ferner ein externes Mikrofon (48) mit der zentralen Signalverarbeitungseinheit (28) verbunden wird, die Art des externen Mikrofons abgeschätzt wird, indem mindestens ein elektrischer Parameter des externen Mikrofons erfasst wird, das Audiosignalverarbeitungsschema gemäß der abgeschätzten Art des externen Mikrofons ausgewählt wird und von dem externen Mikrofon aufgefangene Audiosignale der zentralen Signalverarbeitungseinheit zugeführt werden, wobei ein Audiosignalverarbeitungsschema ausgewählt wird, in welchem eine Audioeingangsempfindlichkeit gemäß der abgeschätzten Art des externen Mikrofons (48) eingestellt wird, wobei die Art eines Stimmaktivitätsdetektors gemäß der abgeschätzten Art des externen Mikrofons (48) ausgewählt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Verfahren gemäß einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei ferner die aufgefangenen Audiosignale mittels einer Klassifizierungseinheit (60) der zentralen Signalverarbeitungseinheit (28) analysiert werden, um eine vorliegende Hörumgebungskategorie aus einer Mehrzahl von Hörumgebungskategorien zu bestimmen, und das Audiosignalverarbeitungsschema gemäß der bestimmten gegenwärtigen Hörumgebungskategorie ausgewählt wird, wobei die Mikrofonanordnung (42) mindestens zwei in Abstand voneinander angeordnete Mikrofone (M1, M2) aufweist, die zu einer akustischen Strahlbündelung in der Lage sind, wobei die räumliche Anordnung der Mikrofonanordnung gemessen wird und wobei, falls eine im Wesentlichen stationäre horizontale Orientierung der Mikrofonanordnung (42) gemessen wird, das Audiosignalverarbeitungsschema gemäß einem Konferenzmodus in einer Weise ausgewählt wird, dass eine frequenzabhängige Verstärkung bezüglich eines Voreinstellungs-Audiosignalverarbeitungsschemas hinsichtlich Sprachverständlichkeit optimiert wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Verfahren gemäß Anspruch 4, wobei ein Audiosignalverarbeitungsschema ausgewählt wird, in welchem es keine Strahlbündelung gibt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Verfahren gemäß Anspruch 4, wobei ein Audiosignalverarbeitungsschema mit einem akustischen Zoommodus ausgewählt wird, in welchem die Richtung der Strahlbündelung automatisch an die Richtung der intensivsten Schallquelle angepasst wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Verfahren gemäß einem der Ansprüche 4 bis 6, wobei, falls eine im Wesentlichen horizontale nichtstationäre Orientierung der Mikrofonanordnung (42) gemessen wird, ein Audiosignalverarbeitungsschema gemäß einem Hand-Halte-Modus ausgewählt wird, in welchem eine Strahlbündelung stattfindet, und wobei die Verstärkung bei niedrigen Eingangspegeln bezüglich eines Voreinstellungs-Audiosignalverarbeitungsschemas erhöht wird, wobei die Erhöhung der Verstärkung bei niedrigen Eingangspegeln mit zunehmendem gemessenem Abstand der Mikrofonanordnung (42) von der Schallquelle ansteigt, und wobei<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> ein Audiosignalverarbeitungsschema ausgewählt wird, in welchem die Verstärkung bei Frequenzen unterhalb und oberhalb eines Sprachfrequenzbereichs bezüglich eines Voreinstellungs-Audiosignalverarbeitungsschemas verringert wird, um Sprachsignale zu betonen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Verfahren gemäß einem der Ansprüche 4 bis 7, wobei, falls eine im Wesentlichen vertikale Orientierung der Mikrofonanordnung (42) gemessen wird, ein Audiosignalverarbeitungsschema gemäß einem Nacken/Brustmodus ausgewählt wird, in welchem bezüglich eines Voreinstellungs-Audiosignalverarbeitungsschemas eine Gesamtverstärkung verringert und/oder eine Abfallzeit auf mehr als eine Sekunde erhöht wird, um Hintergrundstörschall zu verringern.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Verfahren gemäß einem der Ansprüche 4 bis 8, wobei ein Audiosignalverarbeitungsschema ausgewählt wird, in welchem eine pegelabhängige und/oder frequenzabhängige Verstärkung und/oder ein Öffnungswinkel der Strahlbündelung gemäß dem gemessenen Abstand der Mikrofonanordnung (42) von der Schallquelle ausgewählt werden.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>System zur Hörunterstützung eines Nutzers, mit:
<claim-text>einer Mikrofonanordnung (42) zum Auffangen von Audiosignalen;</claim-text>
<claim-text>einer zentralen Signalverarbeitungseinheit (28) zum Verarbeiten der aufgefangenen Audiosignale; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Mitteln (30, 32, 36, 38) zum Senden der verarbeiteten Audiosignale über eine drahtlose Audiostrecke (34) zu Mitteln (18, 26) zum Stimulieren des Gehörs des Nutzers gemäß der verarbeiteten Audiosignale, die an oder in mindestens einem Ohr des Nutzers getragen werden, wobei die Sendemittel einen Senderteil (30, 32) und einen Empfängerteil (36, 38) aufweisen,</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>gekennzeichnet durch</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>Mittel (50, 52, 54) zum Messen mindestens eines mechanischen Parameters, der aus einer aus einer Beschleunigung der Mikrofonanordnung und einem Abstand der Mikrofonanordnung von einer Schallquelle bestehenden Gruppe ausgewählt ist, wobei der Abstand mittels eines Ultraschall-Abstandssensors und/oder optischen Abstandssensors der Messmittel zu messen ist, wobei die zentrale Signalverarbeitungseinheit (28) zum Verarbeiten der aufgefangenen Audiosignale gemäß einem Audiosignalverarbeitungsschema ausgebildet ist, welches gemäß dem gemessenen mindestens einen mechanischen Parameter ausgewählt wird, wobei die Mikrofonanordnung (42), die Messmittel (50, 52, 54), die zentrale Signalverarbeitungseinheit (28) und der Senderteil (30, 32) innerhalb einer tragbaren Einheit (10) integriert sind, welche ausgebildet ist, um stationär auf einem Tisch platziert zu werden, in der Hand des Nutzers gehalten zu werden, oder um einen Hals einer Person oder an einer Brust einer Person getragen zu werden.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>System gemäß Anspruch 10, wobei die Sendemittel (30, 32, 36, 38) zum Aufbauen einer Radiofrequenzaudiostrecke ausgebildet sind, wobei die tragbare Einheit (10) einen Eingang (44, 44') zum Zuführen von Audiosignalen von einer externen Audiosignalquelle (46) zu der zentralen Signalverarbeitungseinheit (28) aufweist, wobei die tragbare Einheit (10) Mittel (66) zum Bestimmen aufweist, ob eine externe Audiosignalquelle (46) mit dem Eingang verbunden ist, und wobei die zentrale Signalverarbeitungseinheit (28) ausgebildet ist, um das Audiosignalverarbeitungsschema gemäß der bestimmten Gegenwart einer externen Audiosignalquelle auszuwählen, wobei die tragbare Einheit (10) einen Eingang (44, 44') zum Zuführen von mittels eines externen Mikrofons (48) aufgefangenen Audiosignalen zu der Audiosignalverarbeitungseinheit (28) aufweist, wobei die tragbare Einheit (10) Mittel (66) zum Abschätzen der Art des mit dem Eingang (44, 44') verbundenen externen Mikrofons mittels Erfassen mindestens eines elektrischen Parameters des externen Mikrofons aufweist, und wobei die zentrale Signalverarbeitungseinheit (28) ausgebildet ist, um das Audiosignalverarbeitungsschema gemäß der abgeschätzten Art des externen Mikrofons auszuwählen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>System gemäß einem der Ansprüche 10 und 11, wobei die Messmittel (50, 52, 54) einen akustischen Abstandssensor und/oder einen optischen Abstandssensor aufweisen, wobei die Messmittel (50, 52, 54) ein Gyroskop, einen Neigungssensor und/oder einen Rollkugelschalter aufweisen, und wobei die Messmittel (50, 52, 54) zum Messen der räumlichen Orientierung der Mikrofonanordnung (42) innerhalb einer senkrechten Ebene ausgebildet sind.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>System gemäß einem der Ansprüche 10 bis 12, wobei die zentrale Signalverarbeitungseinheit (28) eine Klassifizierungseinheit (60) zum Analysieren der Audiosignale zwecks Bestimmen einer vorliegenden Hörumgebungskategorie aus einer Mehrzahl von Hörumgebungskategorien aufweist, und wobei die zentrale Signalverarbeitungseinheit ausgebildet ist, um ein Audiosignalverarbeitungsschema gemäß der bestimmten vorliegenden Hörumgebungskategorie auszuwählen, wobei die Klassifizierungseinheit (60) einen Stimmaktivitätsdetektor aufweist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>System gemäß einem der Ansprüche 10 bis 13, wobei die Stimulationsmittel (26) Teil eines Hörgeräts (16, 16') sind, welches mindestens ein Mikrofon (20) aufweist, wobei der Empfängerteil (36, 38) in das Hörgerät (16, 16') integriert ist oder mit diesem verbunden ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>System gemäß einem der Ansprüche 10 bis 14, wobei die tragbare Einheit (10) ein Hilfsmikrofon (56) in engem mechanischem und akustischem Kontakt mit dem Gehäuse der tragbaren Einheit zwecks Auffangen von Audiosignalen aufweist, welche repräsentativ für Körperstörschall und/oder Gehäusestörschall sind, und wobei die zentrale<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> Signalverarbeitungseinheit (28) ausgebildet ist, um die von dem Hilfsmikrofon aufgefangenen Audiosignale zum Entfernen von Körperstörschall und/oder Gehäusestörschall aus den mittels der Mikrofonanordnung (42) aufgefangenen Audiosignalen zu verwenden, und wobei die zentrale Signalverarbeitungseinheit (28) ausgebildet ist, um einen Wienerfilter zu verwenden, um die von dem Hilfsmikrofon (56) aufgefangenen Audiosignale von den von der Mikrofonanordnung (42) aufgefangenen Audiosignalen abzuziehen.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56984607" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A method for providing hearing assistance to a user, comprising:
<claim-text>capturing audio signals by a microphone arrangement (42);</claim-text>
<claim-text>measuring at least one mechanical parameter selected from the group consisting of an acceleration of the microphone arrangement and a distance of the microphone arrangement to a sound source, wherein said distance is measured by an ultrasonic and/or optical distance sensor;</claim-text>
<claim-text>selecting an audio signal processing scheme according to the measured at least one mechanical parameter;</claim-text>
<claim-text>processing, by a central signal processing unit (28), the captured audio signals according to the selected audio signal processing scheme;</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting the processed audio signals to stimulating means (18, 26) worn at or in at least one of the user's ears via a wireless audio link (34); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>stimulating the user's hearing by said stimulating means according to the processed audio signals,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the microphone arrangement (42), means (50, 52, 54) for measuring said at least one mechanical parameter, the central signal processing unit (28) and a transmitter portion (30, 32) for said transmitting of the processed audio signals are integrated within a portable unit (10), which is placed stationary on a table, held in the hand of the user, or worn around a person's neck or on a person's chest.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The method of claim 1, wherein the wireless audio link is an FM link, the method further comprising supplying audio signals from an external audio signal source (46) to the central signal processing unit (28), determining whether the external audio signal source is connected to the central signal processing unit, and selecting said audio signal processing scheme according to the determined presence of an external audio signal, and wherein said audio signal processing scheme is selected in which a dynamic range is increased with regard to a default audio signal processing scheme.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The method of one of the preceding claims, further comprising connecting an external microphone (48) to the central signal processing unit (28), estimating the type of<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> external microphone by sensing at least one electrical parameter of the external microphone, selecting said audio signal processing scheme according to the estimated type of external microphone and supplying audio signals captured by the external microphone to the central signal processing unit, wherein said audio signal processing scheme is selected in which an audio input sensitivity is adjusted according to the estimated type of extenaal microphone (48), wherein a type of voice activity detector is selected according to the estimated type of external microphone (48).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The method of one of the preceding claims, further comprising analyzing, by a classification unit (60) of the central signal processing unit (28), the captured audio signals in order to determine a present auditory scene category from a plurality of auditory scene categories, and selecting said audio signal processing scheme according to the determined present auditory scene category, wherein the microphone arrangement (42) comprises at least two spaced-apart microphones (M1, M2) capable of acoustic beamforming, wherein the spatial orientation of the microphone arrangement is measured, and wherein, if an essentially stationary horizontal orientation of the microphone arrangement (42) is measured, said audio signal processing scheme is selected corresponding to a conference mode in manner that, with regard to a default audio signal processing scheme, a frequency-dependent gain is optimized for speech understanding.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The method of claim 4, wherein an audio signal processing scheme is selected in which there is no beamforming.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The method of claim 4, wherein an audio signal processing scheme including an acoustic zoom mode is selected in which the direction of the beamformer is automatically adjusted to the direction of the most intense sound source.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The method of one of claims 4 to 6, wherein, if an essentially horizontal non-stationary orientation of the microphone arrangement (42) is measured, an audio signal processing scheme according to a hand-held mode is selected in which beamforming takes place and wherein, with regard to a default audio signal processing scheme, the gain at low input levels is enhanced, wherein the enhancement of the gain at low input levels increases with increasing measured distance of the microphone arrangement (42) to the sound source, and wherein an audio signal processing scheme is selected in which, with<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> regard to a default audio signal processing scheme, the gain at frequencies below and above a speech frequency range is reduced in order to emphasize speech signals.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The method of one of claims 4 to 7, wherein, if an essentially vertical orientation of the microphone arrangement (42) is measured, an audio signal processing scheme according to a neck/chest mode is selected in which, with regard to a default audio signal processing scheme, an overall gain is reduced and/or a release time is increased to more than one second in order to reduce background noise.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The method of one of claims 4 to 8, wherein an audio signal processing scheme is selected, wherein a level-dependent and/or frequency dependent gain and/or an aperture angle of the beamformer is selected according to the measured distance of the microphone arrangement (42) to the sound source.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>A system for providing hearing assistance to a user, comprising:
<claim-text>a microphone arrangement (42) for capturing audio signals;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a central signal processing unit (28) for processing the captured audio signals; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>means (30, 32, 36, 38) for transmitting the processed audio signals via a wireless audio link (34) to means (18, 26) worn at or in at least one of the user's ears for stimulating the hearing of the user according to the processed audio signals, said transmitting means comprising a transmitter portion (30, 32) and a receiver portion (36, 38),</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>characterized by</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>means (50, 52, 54) for measuring at least one mechanical parameter selected from the group consisting of an acceleration of the microphone arrangement and a distance of the microphone arrangement to a sound source, wherein said distance is to be measured by an ultrasonic and/or optical distance sensor of said measuring means, wherein the central signal processing unit (28) is for processing the captured audio signals according to an audio signal processing scheme selected according to the measured at least one mechanical parameter, wherein the microphone arrangement (42), the measuring means (50, 52, 54), the central signal processing unit (28) and the transmitter portion (30, 32) are integrated within a portable unit (10), which is designed to be placed stationary on a table, to be held in the hand of the user, or to be worn around a person's neck or on a person's chest.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>The system of claim 10, wherein the transmitting means (30, 32, 36, 38) is adapted to establish a radio frequency audio link, wherein the portable unit (10) comprises an input (44, 44') for supplying audio signals from an external audio signal source (46) to the central signal processing unit (28), wherein the portable unit (10) comprises means (66) for determining whether an external audio signal source (46) is connected to the input, and wherein the central signal processing unit (28) is adapted to select said audio signal processing scheme according to the determined presence of an external audio signal, wherein the portable unit (10) comprises an input (44, 44') for supplying audio signals captured by an external microphone (48) to the audio signal processing unit (28), wherein the portable unit (10) comprises means (66) for estimating the type of external microphone (48) connected to the input (44, 44') by sensing at least one electrical parameter of the external microphone, and wherein the central signal processing unit (28) is adapted to select said audio signal processing scheme according to the estimated type of external microphone.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>The system of one of claims 10 and 11, wherein the measuring means (50, 52, 54) comprises an acoustic distance sensor and/or an optical distance sensor, wherein the measurement means (50, 52, 54) comprises at least one of a gyroscope, a tilt sensor and a roll ball switch, and wherein the measuring means (50, 52, 54) are for measuring the spatial orientation of the microphone arrangement (42) within a vertical plane.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>The system of one of claims 10 to 12, wherein the central signal processing unit (28) comprises a classification unit (60) for analyzing the audio signals in order to determine a present auditory scene category from a plurality of auditory scene categories, and wherein the central signal processing unit is adapted to select an audio signal processing scheme according to the determined present auditory scene category, wherein the classification unit (60) comprises a voice activity detector.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>The system of one of claims 10 to 13, wherein the stimulating means (26) is part of a hearing instrument (16, 16') comprising at least one microphone (20), wherein the receiver portion (36, 38) is integrated within or connected to the hearing instrument (16, 16').</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>The system of one of claims 10 to 14, wherein the portable unit (10) comprises an auxiliary microphone (56) in close mechanical and acoustical contact with the housing of the portable unit for capturing audio signals representative of body noise and/or<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> housing noise, and wherein the central signal processing unit (28) is adapted to use the audio signals captured by the auxiliary microphone for removing body noise and/or housing noise from the audio signals captured by the microphone arrangement (42), and wherein the central signal processing unit (28) is adapted to use a Wiener filter in order to subtract the audio signals captured by the auxiliary microphone (56) from the audio signals captured by the microphone arrangement (42).</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56984608" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Procédé pour fournir une assistance auditive à un utilisateur, comprenant :
<claim-text>la capture de signaux audio par un agencement de microphones (42) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>la mesure d'au moins un paramètre mécanique sélectionné dans le groupe consistant en une accélération de l'agencement de microphones et une distance entre l'agencement de microphones et une source sonore, dans lequel ladite distance est mesurée par un capteur de distance ultrasonore et/ou optique ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>la sélection d'une méthode de traitement de signaux audio conformément au dit au moins un paramètre mécanique mesuré ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>le traitement, par une unité centrale de traitement de signaux (28), des signaux audio capturés selon la méthode de traitement de signaux audio sélectionnée ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>la transmission des signaux audio traités à des moyens de stimulation (18, 26) portés au niveau d'au moins l'une des oreilles de l'utilisateur ou dans celle-ci par l'intermédiaire d'une liaison audio sans fil (34) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>la stimulation de l'audition de l'utilisateur par lesdits moyens de stimulation conformément aux signaux audio traités,</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel l'agencement de microphones (42), les moyens (50, 52, 54) pour mesurer ledit au moins un paramètre mécanique, l'unité centrale de traitement de signaux (28) et une partie d'émission (30, 32) pour ladite émission des signaux audio traités sont intégrés dans une unité portable (10), qui est placée fixement sur une table, tenue dans la main de l'utilisateur, ou portée autour du cou de la personne ou sur la poitrine de la personne.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, dans lequel la liaison audio sans fil est une liaison FM, le procédé comprenant en outre la fourniture de signaux audio d'une source de signaux audio externe (46) à l'unité centrale de<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --> traitement de signaux (28), la détermination si la source de signaux audio externe est connectée à l'unité centrale de traitement de signaux, et la sélection de ladite méthode de traitement de signaux audio en fonction de la présence déterminée d'un signal audio externe, et dans lequel ladite méthode de traitement de signaux audio dans laquelle une plage dynamique est augmentée en relation avec une méthode de traitement de signaux audio par défaut est sélectionnée.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une des revendications précédentes, comprenant en outre la connexion d'un microphone externe (48) a l'unité centrale de traitement de signaux (28), l'estimation du type de microphone externe en détectant au moins un paramètre électrique du microphone externe, la sélection de ladite méthode de traitement de signaux audio en fonction du type estimé de microphone externe et la fourniture des signaux audio capturés par le microphone externe à l'unité centrale de traitement de signaux, dans lequel ladite méthode de traitement de signaux audio dans laquelle une sensibilité d'entrée audio est ajustée en fonction du type estimé de microphone externe (48) est sélectionnée, dans lequel un type de détecteur d'activité vocale est sélectionné en fonction du type estimé de microphone externe (48).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une des revendications précédentes, comprenant en outre l'analyse, par une unité de classement (60) de l'unité centrale de traitement de signaux (28), des signaux audio capturés afin de déterminer une présente catégorie de scène auditive parmi une pluralité de catégories de scène auditive, et la sélection de ladite méthode de traitement de signaux audio conformément à la présente catégorie de scène auditive déterminée, dans lequel l'agencement de microphones (42) comprend au moins deux microphones (M1, M2) espacés capables d'effectuer une formation de faisceau acoustique, dans lequel l'orientation spatiale de l'agencement de microphones est mesuré, et dans lequel, si une orientation<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --> horizontale essentiellement fixe de l'agencement de microphones (42) est mesurée, ladite méthode de traitement de signaux audio est sélectionnée en correspondance avec un mode de conférence d'une manière telle, en relation avec une méthode de traitement de signaux audio par défaut, qu'un gain dépendant de la fréquence est optimisé pour la compréhension de la parole.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 4, dans lequel une méthode de traitement de signaux audio dans laquelle il n'y a pas de formation de faisceau est sélectionnée.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 4, dans lequel une méthode de traitement de signaux audio comprenant un mode de zoom acoustique dans laquelle la direction du dispositif de formation de faisceau est ajustée automatiquement dans la direction de la source sonore la plus intense est sélectionnée.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une des revendications 4 à 6, dans lequel, si une orientation non stationnaire essentiellement horizontale de l'agencement de microphones (42) est mesurée, une méthode de traitement de signaux audio selon un mode tenu en main dans laquelle une formation de faisceau a lieu est sélectionnée, et dans lequel, en relation avec une méthode de traitement de signaux audio par défaut, le gain à de faibles niveaux d'entrée est amélioré, dans lequel l'amélioration du gain à de faibles niveaux d'entrée augmente avec l'augmentation d'une distance mesurée entre l'agencement de microphones (42) et la source sonore, et dans lequel une méthode de traitement de signaux audio dans laquelle, en relation avec une méthode de traitement de signaux audio par défaut, le gain à des fréquences au-dessous et au-dessus d'une plage de fréquence vocale est réduit afin d'accentuer les signaux de parole est sélectionnée.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une des revendications 4 à 7, dans lequel, si une orientation essentiellement verticale de l'agencement de microphones (42) est mesurée, une méthode<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> de traitement de signaux audio selon un mode cou/poitrine dans laquelle, en relation avec une méthode de traitement de signaux audio par défaut, un gain global est réduit et/ou un temps de libération est augmenté à plusieurs secondes afin de réduire un bruit de fond est sélectionnée.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une des revendications 4 à 8, dans lequel une méthode de traitement de signaux audio, dans laquelle un gain dépendant du niveau et/ou dépendant de la fréquence et/ou un angle d'ouverture du dispositif de formation de faisceau sont sélectionnés en fonction de la distance mesurée entre l'agencement de microphones (42) et la source sonore est sélectionnée.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Système pour fournir une assistance auditive à un utilisateur, comprenant :
<claim-text>un agencement de microphones (42) pour capturer des signaux audio ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une unité centrale de traitement de signaux (28) pour traiter les signaux audio capturés ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>des moyens (30, 32, 36, 38) pour transmettre les signaux audio traités par l'intermédiaire d'une liaison audio sans fil (34) vers des moyens (18, 26) portés au niveau d'au moins l'une des oreilles de l'utilisateur ou dans celle-ci pour stimuler l'audition de l'utilisateur conformément aux signaux audio traités, lesdits moyens de transmission comprenant une partie d'émission (30, 32) et une partie de réception (36, 38),</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>caractérisé par</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>des moyens (50, 52, 54) pour mesurer au moins un paramètre mécanique sélectionné dans le groupe consistant en une accélération de l'agencement de microphones et une distance entre l'agencement de microphones et une source sonore, dans lequel ladite distance doit être mesurée par un capteur de distance ultrasonore et/ou optique desdits moyens de mesure, dans lequel a l'unité centrale de traitement de signaux (28) sert au traitement des signaux audio capturés selon une méthode de traitement de signaux<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --> audio sélectionnée conformément au dit au moins un paramètre mécanique mesuré, dans lequel l'agencement de microphones (42), les moyens de mesure (50, 52, 54), a l'unité centrale de traitement de signaux (28) et la partie d'émission (30, 32) sont intégrés dans une unité portable (10), qui est conçue pour être placée fixement sur une table, pour être tenue dans la main de l'utilisateur, ou pour être portée autour du col ou sur la poitrine de la personne.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Système selon la revendication 10, dans lequel les moyens de transmission (30, 32, 36, 38) sont conçus pour établir une liaison audio radiofréquence, dans lequel l'unité portable (10) comprend une entrée (44, 44') pour fournir des signaux audio d'une source de signaux audio externe (46) à a l'unité centrale de traitement de signaux (28), dans lequel l'unité portable (10) comprend des moyens (66) pour déterminer si une source de signaux audio externe (46) est connectée à l'entrée, et dans lequel l'unité centrale de traitement de signaux (28) est conçue pour sélectionner ladite méthode de traitement de signaux audio en fonction de la présence déterminée d'un signal audio externe, dans lequel a l'unité portable (10) comprend une entrée (44, 44') pour fournir les signaux audio capturés par un microphone externe (48) à l'unité de traitement de signaux audio (28), dans lequel l'unité portable (10) comprend des moyens (66) pour estimer le type de microphone externe (48) connecté à l'entrée (44, 44') en détectant au moins un paramètre électrique du microphone externe, et dans lequel l'unité centrale de traitement de signaux (28) est conçue pour sélectionner ladite méthode de traitement de signaux audio en fonction du type estimé de microphone externe.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Système selon l'une des revendications 10 et 11, dans lequel les moyens de mesure (50, 52, 54) comprennent un capteur de distance acoustique et/ou un capteur de distance optique, dans lequel les moyens de mesure (50, 52,<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --> 54) comprennent au moins l'un d'un gyroscope, d'un capteur d'inclinaison et d'un commutateur à bille roulante, et dans lequel les moyens de mesure (50, 52, 54) sont destinés à mesurer l'orientation spatiale de l'agencement de microphones (42) dans un plan vertical.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Système selon l'une des revendications 10 à 12, dans lequel l'unité centrale de traitement de signaux (28) comprend une unité de classement (60) pour analyser les signaux audio afin de déterminer une présente catégorie de scène auditive parmi une pluralité de catégories de scène auditive, et dans lequel l'unité centrale de traitement de signaux est conçue pour sélectionner une méthode de traitement de signaux audio en fonction de la présente catégorie de scène auditive déterminée, dans lequel l'unité de classement (60) comprend un détecteur d'activité vocale.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Système selon l'une des revendications 10 à 13, dans lequel les moyens de stimulation (26) font partie de l'instrument auditif (16, 16') comprenant au moins un microphone (20), dans lequel la partie de réception (36, 38) est intégrée dans l'instrument auditif (16, 16') ou connectée à celui-ci.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Système selon l'une des revendications 10 à 14, dans lequel l'unité portable (10) comprend un microphone auxiliaire (56) en contact mécanique et acoustique étroit avec le logement de l'unité portable pour capturer des signaux audio représentatifs d'un bruit corporel et/ou d'un bruit de logement, et dans lequel l'unité centrale de traitement de signaux (28) est conçue pour utiliser les signaux audio capturés par le microphone auxiliaire pour retirer le bruit corporel et/ou le bruit de logement des signaux audio capturés par l'agencement de microphones (42), et dans lequel a l'unité centrale de traitement de signaux (28) est conçue pour utiliser un filtre de Wiener afin de soustraire les signaux audio capturés par le microphone auxiliaire (56) des signaux audio capturés par l'agencement de microphones (42).</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16671908" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="165" he="218" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="162" he="169" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3,4,5"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="165" he="217" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
