<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2677915-A1" country="EP" doc-number="2677915" kind="A1" date="20140101" family-id="49627156" file-reference-id="315082" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146551722" ucid="EP-2677915-A1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2677915</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-12705666-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154825645" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12705666</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120222</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP220439809" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12705666.1</doc-number><date>20120222</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140451001" ucid="EP-12705666-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12705666</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120222</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140454043" ucid="EP-2011000844-W" linkage-type="A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>2011000844</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20110222</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140453176" ucid="EP-2012053027-W" linkage-type="W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>2012053027</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20120222</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988137142" load-source="docdb">A47L   9/16        20060101AFI20120913BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988107190" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A47L   9/1683      20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988110993" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A47L   9/1691      20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988114936" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A47L   9/327       20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988116297" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A47L   9/108       20130101 FI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988116912" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A47L   9/1608      20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132187650" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">STAUBSAUGER</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132187651" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">VACUUM CLEANER</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132187652" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">ASPIRATEUR</invention-title><citations><non-patent-citations><nplcit><text>See references of WO 2012113840A1</text><sources><source mxw-id="PNPL67455455" load-source="docdb" name="SEA"/></sources></nplcit></non-patent-citations></citations></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918160585" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>ELECTROLUX AB</last-name><address><country>SE</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918165121" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>AKTIEBOLAGET ELECTROLUX</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918994095" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Aktiebolaget Electrolux</last-name><iid>101135853</iid><address><street>S:t Göransgatan 143</street><city>105 45 Stockholm</city><country>SE</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918140488" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>MIEFALK HAAKAN</last-name><address><country>SE</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918145810" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>MIEFALK, HAAKAN</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918992401" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>MIEFALK, Håkan</last-name><address><street>AB Electrolux S:t Göransgatan 143</street><city>S-105 45 Stockholm</city><country>SE</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918989281" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Selin Wretblad, Eva</last-name><iid>101323551</iid><address><street>AB Electrolux S:t Göramsgatan 143</street><city>105 45 Stockholm</city><country>SE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="EP-2012053027-W"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2012053027</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20120222</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2012113840-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2012113840</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20120830</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548841435" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS548938226" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS548841436" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS548869436" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS548947673" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS548935875" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS548938227" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS548841437" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548935876" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS548935877" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS548924009" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS548869437" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS548869438" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548841438" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548935954" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS548841439" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS548938228" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS548947674" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS548935955" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS548869439" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS548935956" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS548939774" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS548938229" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS548939775" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS548939776" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS548818272" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS548818273" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS548938230" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS548841440" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS548935957" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS548939777" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS548938231" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS548939778" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS548935958" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS548939779" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS548841441" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS548935959" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS548818274" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA99625549" ref-ucid="WO-2012113840-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p num="0000">The invention is directed to vacuum cleaner (1) comprising a horizontal type cleaner body (2) with a front (5) and back side (6) and two lateral sides (7), at least one primary stage cyclone dust separator (8) having a dust outlet opening fluidly connected to a primary stage dust collecting chamber (9), and at least one secondary stage cyclone dust separating unit (12). The primary stage dust collecting chamber (9) and the at least one secondary stage cyclone dust separating unit (12) is mounted at the front side (5) in a lateral side by side arrangement in between the lateral sides (7).</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA99824068" ref-ucid="WO-2012113840-A1" lang="EN" source="national office" load-source="docdb"><p>The invention is directed to vacuum cleaner (1) comprising a horizontal type cleaner body (2) with a front (5) and back side (6) and two lateral sides (7), at least one primary stage cyclone dust separator (8) having a dust outlet opening fluidly connected to a primary stage dust collecting chamber (9), and at least one secondary stage cyclone dust separating unit (12). The primary stage dust collecting chamber (9) and the at least one secondary stage cyclone dust separating unit (12) is mounted at the front side (5) in a lateral side by side arrangement in between the lateral sides (7).</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA99625550" ref-ucid="WO-2012113840-A1" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><p num="0000">L'invention concerne un aspirateur (1) comprenant : un corps d'aspiration de type horizontal (2) avec un côté avant (5), un côté arrière (6) et deux côté latéraux (7) ; au moins un séparateur de décharge de poussière de type cyclone à étage primaire (8) dont l'ouverture d'admission d'air est en liaison fluidique avec une chambre de collecte de la poussière à étage primaire (9) ; et au moins une unité de séparation de la poussière de type cyclone à étage secondaire (12). La chambre de collecte de la poussière à étage primaire (9) et l'unité de séparation de la poussière de type cyclone à étage secondaire (12) sont montées côte-à-côte contre le côté avant (5) entre les côtés latéraux (7).</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA99824069" ref-ucid="WO-2012113840-A1" lang="FR" source="national office" load-source="docdb"><p>L'invention concerne un aspirateur (1) comprenant : un corps d'aspiration de type horizontal (2) avec un côté avant (5), un côté arrière (6) et deux côté latéraux (7) ; au moins un séparateur de décharge de poussière de type cyclone à étage primaire (8) dont l'ouverture d'admission d'air est en liaison fluidique avec une chambre de collecte de la poussière à étage primaire (9) ; et au moins une unité de séparation de la poussière de type cyclone à étage secondaire (12). La chambre de collecte de la poussière à étage primaire (9) et l'unité de séparation de la poussière de type cyclone à étage secondaire (12) sont montées côte-à-côte contre le côté avant (5) entre les côtés latéraux (7).</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES50931294" ref-ucid="WO-2012113840-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="3"/>--><p id="p0001" num="0001">Vacuum Cleaner </p><p id="p0002" num="0002">The present invention is directed to a vacuum cleaner. In more detail, the invention is directed to a cyclone type vacuum cleaner . </p><p id="p0003" num="0003">Cyclone type vacuum cleaners are widely known because of their benefit in bagless dust collection. Bagless or cyclone type vac- uum cleaners or respective cyclone dust separating units are known for example from documents EP 1 042 981 Al, EP 1774887 Al, EP 1 688 078 A2 , EP 1 952 745 A2 and WO 2011/058365. </p><p id="p0004" num="0004">Cyclone type vacuum cleaners, in particular mentioned in the state of technology documents listed before, are still compara<sup>¬</sup> tively large in size and provide comparatively complicated air guiding and dust collecting devices and units. </p><p id="p0005" num="0005">Therefore, it is one of the objects of the present invention to provide a cyclone type vacuum cleaner having a comparatively compact design. In particular it is an object to provide a mul<sup>¬</sup> tiple stage cyclonic vacuum cleaner of comparatively compact de<sup>¬</sup> sign. Further, the vacuum cleaner shall have enhanced usability and operability, in particular with respect to dust separation and dust collecting chambers. </p><p id="p0006" num="0006">These and further objects are solved by the features of claim 1. Embodiments and variants result from the dependent claims. According to claim 1, a vacuum cleaner is provided which comprises a horizontal type cleaner body having a front and back side and two lateral sides. </p><p id="p0007" num="0007">The term "horizontal type cleaner body" in particular shall re- fer to the orientation of the cleaner body in normal or intended 
<!-- EPO <DP n="4"/>-->
use. Such a horizontal type cleaner body may comprise, as al<sup>¬</sup> ready implemented with known devices, wheels attached thereto and provided for easily moving the vacuum cleaner over the floor underneath during vacuum-cleaning. </p><p id="p0008" num="0008">A horizontal type vacuum cleaner in the meaning of the present application is for example shown in EP 1 774 887 Al . Aside from the horizontal type vacuum cleaners there also exist vertical type constructions generally comprising a handle to which the cleaner body is mounted to and by which the cleaner body is moved in concert with vacuum-cleaning operations. One example of such a vertical type vacuum cleaner is shown in WO 2011/058365. </p><p id="p0009" num="0009">The vacuum cleaner comprises at least one primary stage cyclone dust separator which has a dust outlet opening fluidly connected to a primary stage dust collecting chamber. </p><p id="p0010" num="0010">The vacuum cleaner further comprises a secondary cyclonic separation step. In more detail, the vacuum cleaner comprises at least one secondary stage cyclone dust separating unit. The sec<sup>¬</sup> ondary stage cyclone dust separating unit is coupled and in<sup>¬</sup> stalled downstream the primary stage cyclone dust separator. Providing a secondary stage dust separation stage greatly enhances overall dust separation efficiency </p><p id="p0011" num="0011">With the proposed vacuum cleaner, the primary stage dust col<sup>¬</sup> lecting chamber and the at least one secondary stage cyclone dust separating unit is mounted at the front side in a lateral side by side arrangement in between the lateral sides. </p><p id="p0012" num="0012">The proposed arrangement of primary stage dust collecting cham<sup>¬</sup> ber and the at least one secondary stage cyclone dust separating unit enables space saving arrangements and in particular compact overall designs of the cleaner body and vacuum cleaner. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="5"/>-->
With the proposed vacuum cleaner construction, the lateral ex<sup>¬</sup> tension of the primary stage dust collecting chamber is less than the overall width of the cleaner body and vacuum cleaner. Space not occupied by the primary stage dust collecting chamber in lateral direction can be used as installation space for at least one of the at least one secondary stage cyclone dust sepa<sup>¬</sup> rating unit. </p><p id="p0013" num="0013">Providing the primary stage dust collecting chamber at the front side has, amongst others, the advantage that it is easily acces<sup>¬</sup> sible. Further if adequate front side fill level indicators, in particular inspection windows, are provided a user can quickly inspect the filling level of the primary stage dust collecting chamber. The term "front side fill level indicator" in particu- lar shall mean that the fill level indicator is accessible and visible at and from the front side of the vacuum cleaner. </p><p id="p0014" num="0014">The fill level indicator, in particular inspection window, in particular when arranged immediately at the front side, is ef- fective in presenting the filling level of the primary stage dust collecting chamber to a user, and will contribute to ade<sup>¬</sup> quate emptying intervals. This in turn secures optimal cleaning efficiency of the vacuum cleaner. Note that the inspection window may be implemented as a translucent or transparent wall sec- tion of the primary stage dust collecting chamber. </p><p id="p0015" num="0015">As will be described in more detail further below, arranging the at least one secondary stage cyclone dust separating unit at the front side, side to side with the primary stage dust collection chamber allows a space saving arrangement of secondary stage dust collecting chambers of respective secondary stage cyclone dust collecting units. </p><p id="p0016" num="0016">Note that the primary stage cyclone dust separator may be pro- vided and adapted to separate coarse dust, debris and other par- 
<!-- EPO <DP n="6"/>-->
ticulate matter from air. Secondary stage cyclone dust separat<sup>¬</sup> ing units may be adapted to separate fine dust from air, in par<sup>¬</sup> ticular dust that either could not be separated in the first stage or that is too fine or small to be separated in the first stage. Combining several dust separation stages in series great<sup>¬</sup> ly enhances the overall cleaning efficiency. </p><p id="p0017" num="0017">In a preferred embodiment, the vacuum cleaner comprises two sec<sup>¬</sup> ondary stage cyclone dust separating units. The two secondary stage cyclone dust separating units are mounted at opposite lat<sup>¬</sup> eral sides, side by side to the primary stage dust collecting chamber. The primary stage dust collecting chamber in this case is centered between the two secondary stage cyclone dust sepa<sup>¬</sup> rating units and lateral sides. In other words, the secondary stage cyclone dust separating units are respectively positioned laterally next to the primary stage dust collecting chamber which is centered with respect to the cleaner body. </p><p id="p0018" num="0018">In one further embodiment, each secondary stage cyclone dust separating unit comprises several conical cyclones arranged side to side in parallel to a respective lateral side. </p><p id="p0019" num="0019">Preferably, the diameters of the conical cyclones are smaller than that of the first stage cyclone dust separator. Note that the first stage cyclone dust separator preferably has a constant overall circular cross section, i. e. has essentially no conical sections. The smaller conical cyclones preferably are equally dimensioned. Providing smaller conical cyclones in the secondary stage cyclone dust separating units is effective in separating fine dust and dust particles too small to be effectively removed in the primary separation stage. </p><p id="p0020" num="0020">It shall be noted, that more than the above described two dust separation stages may be combined in series. This will enhance dust separation efficiency and allow blowing out comparatively 
<!-- EPO <DP n="7"/>-->
clean air to the environment again. As an example, one of the higher order dust separating steps, e. g. a tertiary dust separation step, may be a filter type separation, in particular adapted to retain residual dust particles. But also tertiary stage cyclone dust separators are conceivable. </p><p id="p0021" num="0021">In a yet further embodiment, conical cyclones of the at least one secondary stage cyclone dust separating unit are mounted and adapted such that their center axes are tilted or slanted from top front side to bottom back side. Such a tilted arrangement is of particular advantage, if a main airflow through the cyclones is also directed from top front to bottom back. In this case, a secondary stage dust collecting chamber fluidly connected to dust outlets of the cyclones can be arranged in a space saving way underneath and/or in front to back direction behind the respective secondary stage cyclone dust separating unit. </p><p id="p0022" num="0022">In a preferred variant, the center axes of the conical cyclones are tilted vis-a-vis the horizontal direction of ordinary use, in more detail vis-a-vis the front to back direction, by an an<sup>¬</sup> gle of 10 to 50 degrees, preferably 30 degrees. Such tilt angles are adequate for compact design, yet allowing sufficient separa<sup>¬</sup> tion efficiency. In a further embodiment, and as already indicated further above, each secondary stage cyclone dust separating unit comprises a secondary stage dust collecting chamber downstream of and fluidly connected with dust outlet openings of respective secondary stage cyclones. </p><p id="p0023" num="0023">The secondary stage dust collecting chambers in particular may be oriented and mounted as already indicated further above. In particular, the secondary stage dust collecting chambers may be located and positioned at respective lateral sides. With regard to front to back direction, the secondary stage dust collecting 
<!-- EPO <DP n="8"/>-->
chambers are preferably arranged behind, i. e. downstream, and flush with respective secondary stage conical cyclones. The pro<sup>¬</sup> posed arrangement of the secondary stage dust collecting chamber may lead to optimal utilization of space, and therefore compact design. </p><p id="p0024" num="0024">In another embodiment, with regard to planes running essentially parallel to a respective lateral side, the secondary stage dust collecting chamber has a triangular shaped cross section. Trian- gular shaped cross sections may provide optimal utilization of space. In particular due to the fact that a triangular shaped space may be available downstream and underneath a dust outlet face or plane of conical cyclones of a secondary stage cyclone dust separating unit. The dust outlet plane shall be understood to be defined by respective dust outlet openings of conical cy<sup>¬</sup> clones . </p><p id="p0025" num="0025">In a yet further embodiment, a tertiary stage dust separator, which may be a fine and/or main filter, is provided. The ter- tiary stage dust separator is, with regard to front to back di<sup>¬</sup> rection, mounted behind the primary dust collecting chamber and laterally adjacent to the at least one secondary stage dust col<sup>¬</sup> lecting chamber. If secondary stage dust collecting chambers are provided at opposite lateral sides, the tertiary stage dust sep- arator may be centered in lateral direction between the second<sup>¬</sup> ary stage dust collecting chambers. </p><p id="p0026" num="0026">In a further embodiment, the vacuum cleaner comprises air channels connecting an air outlet of the primary stage cyclone dust separator to the at least one secondary stage cyclone dust sepa<sup>¬</sup> rating unit, in particular to an air inlet opening of the at least one secondary stage cyclone dust separating unit. Further, the air channels are guided at a top side of the cleaner body. This is favorable with regard to utilization of space. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="9"/>-->
Such air channels are of particular advantage if a longitudinal main axis of the primary stage cyclone dust separator is orient<sup>¬</sup> ed essentially parallel to the front to back direction, and an air outlet of the primary stage cyclone dust separator is locat- ed at or placed towards the back side. </p><p id="p0027" num="0027">Each air channel guides at least partially cleaned air from the primary stage cyclone dust separator to an air inlet, in partic<sup>¬</sup> ular air inlet chamber, of a respective secondary stage cyclone dust separating unit. The inlet chamber communicates with air inlet openings of all conical cyclones of a respective secondary stage cyclone dust separating unit. The inlet chamber is de<sup>¬</sup> signed and adapted such that air is guided optimally, preferably equally, to and into all conical cyclones of a secondary stage cyclone dust separating unit. </p><p id="p0028" num="0028">In a further embodiment, the primary stage cyclone dust separa<sup>¬</sup> tor is, with regard to front to back direction, mounted behind the dust collecting chamber. In this case, it is advantageous that the primary stage cyclone dust separator is a horizontal type dust separator. In this connection, a horizontal type dust separator shall be understood in particular as indicated further above, i. e. that a longitudinal main axis of the primary stage cyclone dust collector is parallel to the front to back direc- tion. This in particular means that a main airflow through the primary stage cyclone dust separator is parallel and/or anti- parallel to the front to back direction. Placing and orienting the primary stage cyclone dust separator as proposed beforehand is effective in obtaining comparatively small bottom to top di- mensions. </p><p id="p0029" num="0029">Exemplary embodiments will now be described in connection with the annexed figures, in which: Fig. 1 shows a perspective view of a vacuum cleaner; 
<!-- EPO <DP n="10"/>-->
Fig. 2 shows a lateral side view of the vacuum cleaner; and </p><p id="p0030" num="0030">Fig. 3 shows vertical cross sectional view of the vacuum cleaner . </p><p id="p0031" num="0031">Fig. 1 shows a perspective view of a vacuum cleaner 1. The vacu- um cleaner 1 comprises a horizontal type cleaner body 2 with a bottom 3, top 4, front 5 and back side 6 and two lateral sides</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">7. </p><p id="p0033" num="0033">The term horizontal type shall mean that in the ordinary and in- tended position of use, the cleaner body 2 is positioned essen<sup>¬</sup> tially horizontally. In the context of the present invention and in more general terms this in particular shall mean that, the cleaner body 2 during normal operation and with regard to front to back direction is positioned essentially parallel to the ground underneath. Note that in the figures, the vacuum cleaner is shown in its ordinary horizontal use position. </p><p id="p0034" num="0034">The vacuum cleaner 1 comprises a primary stage cyclone dust sep<sup>¬</sup> arator 8. The primary stage cyclone dust separator 8 is coupled to a primary stage dust collecting chamber 9. A dust outlet opening 10 (Fig. 3) of the primary stage cyclone dust separator</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">8 is fluidly connected to the primary stage dust collecting chamber 9. The primary stage dust collecting chamber 8, which may also be designated as a dust collecting container, is positioned and ar<sup>¬</sup> ranged at the front side 5 of the cleaner body 2. </p><p id="p0036" num="0036">In a front side section, the primary stage dust collecting cham- ber 9 has a fill level indicator, which in the present case is 
<!-- EPO <DP n="11"/>-->
implemented as a transparent wall section arranged and visible from the front. In one implementation, essentially the whole primary stage dust collecting chamber 9, at least walls at the front side, are made from a transparent material. Here, a user can easily observe the fill level of the primary stage dust col<sup>¬</sup> lecting chamber 9, recognize inadequately high filling levels and, as a consequence, will timely empty the primary stage dust collecting chamber 9. The vacuum cleaner 1 comprises wheels 10 arranged at/in or on the lateral sides 7 and bottom side 3 of the cleaner body 2, re<sup>¬</sup> spectively. The wheels 10 are arranged and adapted such that the vacuum cleaner 1 during normal and ordinary operation can be easily moved on the surface underneath. The vacuum cleaner 1 may comprise other functional elements, such as handles and the like, which will not be described in further detail. </p><p id="p0037" num="0037">At the front side 5 of the vacuum cleaner 1, an interface 11 is provided which is adapted and configured to connect a flexible suction hose (not shown) . </p><p id="p0038" num="0038">The vacuum cleaner 1 further comprises two secondary stage cyclone dust separating units 12. The secondary stage cyclone dust separating units 12 are positioned and mounted at the front side 5. </p><p id="p0039" num="0039">As can in particular be seen from Fig. 1, the primary stage dust collecting chamber 9 and the secondary stage cyclone dust sepa<sup>¬</sup> rating units 12 are mounted in between the lateral sides 7. </p><p id="p0040" num="0040">Further, it can be seen from Fig. 1 that the primary stage dust collecting chamber 9 and the secondary stage cyclone dust sepa<sup>¬</sup> rating units 12 are, with respect to the lateral extension, ar<sup>¬</sup> ranged in a side by side arrangement, wherein the primary stage dust collecting chamber 9 is placed, in particular centered, be- 
<!-- EPO <DP n="12"/>-->
tween the secondary stage cyclone dust separating units 12. In other words, at each lateral side of the primary stage dust col<sup>¬</sup> lecting chamber 9 there is provided one of the secondary stage cyclone dust separating units 12. </p><p id="p0041" num="0041">From Fig. 1 it can be readily seen that the proposed arrange<sup>¬</sup> ment, in particular the arrangement of primary stage dust col<sup>¬</sup> lecting chamber 9 and the secondary stage cyclone dust separat<sup>¬</sup> ing units 12, allows a compact and space saving design. Further, a functional arrangement combined with good operability of com<sup>¬</sup> ponents of the vacuum cleaner 1 can be obtained. </p><p id="p0042" num="0042">Further details of the vacuum cleaner will become apparent in connection with Figures 2 and 3. </p><p id="p0043" num="0043">As can be seen in more detail from Fig. 2, representing a partially broken up side view of the vacuum cleaner 1, each secondary stage cyclone dust separating unit 12 comprises several con<sup>¬</sup> ical cyclones 13. The conical cyclones 13 have equal size, i. e. dimensions, and are arranged side to side in parallel to a re<sup>¬</sup> spective lateral side 7. </p><p id="p0044" num="0044">Air channels 14 running at the top side 4 of the cleaner body 2 fluidly connect an air outlet of the primary stage cyclone dust separator 8 to respective air inlets of the secondary stage cy<sup>¬</sup> clone dust separating units 12. With the present design, the air outlet of the primary stage cyclone dust separator 8 is located towards the back side 6 and centered with respect to the lateral sides 7. The air channels 14 are guided from a centered back side location in a curved section towards respective lateral sides 7 and then are guided along the lateral sides 7 of the cleaner body 2 to the secondary stage cyclone dust separating units 12. As can be seen, the air channels 14 can be integrated without increasing the overall lateral and bottom to top exten- sion of the cleaner body 2. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="13"/>-->
The air channels 14 open into the secondary stage cyclone dust separating units 12. Air guided into the secondary stage cyclone dust separating units 12 preferably is equally distributed to the conical cyclones 13. Here, an air distribution chamber flu- idly connected to air inlets of the conical cyclones 13 and adapted to equally distribute incoming air may be used. If re<sup>¬</sup> quired, air guiding elements may be provided in the air distri<sup>¬</sup> bution chamber. </p><p id="p0045" num="0045">With regard to the airflow within the vacuum cleaner 1, the secondary stage cyclone dust separating units 12 are provided down<sup>¬</sup> stream the primary stage cyclone dust separator 8. This means, that the primary stage cyclone dust separator 8 and secondary stage cyclone dust separating units 12 are connected in series. In particular with reference to Fig. 2 it can be seen that the conical cyclones 13 of a respective secondary stage cyclone dust separating unit 12 are connected in parallel. With further reference to Fig. 2, the conical cyclones 13 are mounted and aligned such that their center axes are tilted from top front to bottom back, which is indicated for one of the con<sup>¬</sup> ical cyclones by a dotted arrow (v2) . In a direction perpendicu<sup>¬</sup> lar to the center axes, the conical cyclones 13 are positioned in a line, without axial displacement. This in particular means that air inlets and dust outlets of the conical cyclones of a secondary stage cyclone dust separating unit 12 respectively lie in common planes. As the conical cyclones 13 are of equal de<sup>¬</sup> sign, the air inlet planes and dust outlet planes are essential- ly parallel to each other. </p><p id="p0046" num="0046">Coming back to the tilt or declination of the center axes of the conical cyclones 13, it has been proven advantageous that a tilt angle a is in the range of 10 to 50 degrees. A preferred tilt angle is 30 degrees. Note that the tilt angle shall be under- 
<!-- EPO <DP n="14"/>-->
stood to be defined between a vector vl parallel to the front to back direction and a vector v2 parallel to a center axis of a respective conical cyclone 13 and running in a direction top front to bottom back. Note that the direction top front to bot- torn back corresponds to the main air flow direction in respective conical cyclones 13. </p><p id="p0047" num="0047">With further reference to Fig. 2, each secondary stage cyclone dust separating unit 12 comprises a secondary stage dust col- lecting chamber 15 downstream of and fluidly connected to dust outlet openings 16 of respective conical cyclones 13. In Fig. 2 only one of the secondary stage dust collecting chambers 15 is visible . On a side of a respective secondary step dust collecting chamber 15 facing the dust outlet openings 16 of the conical cyclones 13, the secondary step dust collecting chamber 15 has corresponding dust inlet openings. The dust inlet openings and dust outlet openings 16 are adapted such that a tight, in particular fluid and dust tight, connection between secondary step dust collecting chamber 15 and respective conical cyclones 13 is ob<sup>¬</sup> tained . </p><p id="p0048" num="0048">The secondary step dust collecting chamber 15 may be detachably coupled to a section of the secondary stage cyclone dust sepa<sup>¬</sup> rating unit 12, such that it can be easily removed for discharging dust collected therein, and such that the conical cyclones 13 can easily be cleaned. It shall however be noted, that the secondary step dust collecting chamber 15 may alternatively be a non-detachable integrated part of the secondary stage cyclone dust separating unit 12. In this case it may be that the second<sup>¬</sup> ary stage cyclone dust separating unit 12 as a whole is detacha<sup>¬</sup> bly mounted to the cleaner body 2. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="15"/>-->
From Fig. 2 it can further be seen, that with regard to front to back direction each secondary stage dust collecting chamber 15 is positioned and mounted behind respective secondary stage cy<sup>¬</sup> clones 13. From Fig. 1 it can be seen that with regard to front to back direction the secondary stage dust collecting chambers 15 are arranged flush with respective secondary stage cyclones 13 and respective cyclone units. Optimal and favorable utiliza<sup>¬</sup> tion of space can in particular be obtained if the secondary stage dust collecting chambers 15, as shown in Fig. 2, have tri- angular shaped cross sections in planes running parallel to the lateral sides 7. </p><p id="p0049" num="0049">The arrangement as described before is advantageous for obtain<sup>¬</sup> ing compact overall designs. In addition, the proposed arrange- ment allows favorable usability and handling of components of the vacuum cleaner 1, and of the vacuum cleaner 1 as a whole. </p><p id="p0050" num="0050">With reference to Fig. 3, the vacuum cleaner may comprise a tertiary stage dust separator 17. Note that even higher order dust separating stages may be provided. The tertiary stage dust sepa<sup>¬</sup> rator 17 is mounted, with regard to front to back direction, be<sup>¬</sup> hind the primary stage dust collecting chamber 9 and with regard to bottom to top direction below the primary stage cyclone dust separator 8. In combination with Fig. 2 it becomes clear, that the tertiary stage dust separator 17 is centered between the secondary stage dust collecting chambers 15. By this, optimal utilization of space and compact designs can be obtained. </p><p id="p0051" num="0051">The tertiary stage dust separator 17 may be a fine filter, in particular a main filter, of the vacuum cleaner, and be arranged immediately upstream an air exhaust of the vacuum cleaner. </p><p id="p0052" num="0052">In all, it can be seen, that the proposed vacuum cleaner pro<sup>¬</sup> vides a compact design, enhanced usability and satisfactory cleaning efficiency. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="16"/>-->
List of reference numerals </p><p id="p0053" num="0053">1 vacuum cleaner </p><p id="p0054" num="0054"> 2 cleaner body </p><p id="p0055" num="0055"> 3 bottom side </p><p id="p0056" num="0056"> 4 top side </p><p id="p0057" num="0057"> 5 front side </p><p id="p0058" num="0058"> 6 back side </p><p id="p0059" num="0059"> 7 lateral side </p><p id="p0060" num="0060"> 8 primary stage cyclone dust separator </p><p id="p0061" num="0061"> 9 primary stage dust collecting chamber </p><p id="p0062" num="0062"> 10 wheel </p><p id="p0063" num="0063"> 11 interface </p><p id="p0064" num="0064"> 12 secondary stage cyclone dust separating unit</p><p id="p0065" num="0065">13 conical cyclone </p><p id="p0066" num="0066"> 14 air channel </p><p id="p0067" num="0067"> 15 secondary stage dust collecting chamber</p><p id="p0068" num="0068">16 dust outlet opening </p><p id="p0069" num="0069"> 17 tertiary stage dust separator a tilt angle </p><p id="p0070" num="0070">vl, v2 vectors 
</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM44727248" ref-ucid="WO-2012113840-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><claim-statement><!-- EPO <DP n="17"/>-->Claims </claim-statement><claim id="clm-0001" num="1"><claim-text>1. Vacuum cleaner (1) comprising a horizontal type cleaner body (2) with a front (5) and back side (6) and two lateral sides (7), at least one primary stage cyclone dust separator (8) having a dust outlet opening fluidly connected to a primary stage dust collecting chamber (9), and at least one secondary stage cyclone dust separating unit (12), wherein the primary stage dust collecting chamber (9) and the at least one sec<sup>¬</sup> ondary stage cyclone dust separating unit (12) are mounted at the front side (5) in a lateral side by side arrangement in between the lateral sides (7) . </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0002" num="2"><claim-text>2. Vacuum cleaner (1) according to claim 1, comprising two secondary stage cyclone dust separating units (12) mounted at opposite lateral sides (7) and side by side with the primary stage dust collecting chamber (9) which is centered between the two secondary stage cyclone dust separating units (12) and lateral sides (7) . </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0003" num="3"><claim-text>3. Vacuum cleaner (1) according to any of the preceding claims, wherein each secondary stage cyclone dust separating unit (12) comprises several conical cyclones (13) arranged side to side in parallel to a respective lateral side (7) . </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0004" num="4"><claim-text>4. Vacuum cleaner (1) according to at least one of the preceding claims, wherein conical cyclones (13) of the at least one secondary stage cyclone dust separating unit (12) are mounted and adapted such that their center axes are tilted from top front to bottom back. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0005" num="5"><claim-text>5. Vacuum cleaner (1) according to claim 4, wherein the center axes of the conical cyclones (13) are tilted vis-a-vis the front to back direction by an angle (a) of 10 to 50 degrees, preferably 30 degrees. <!-- EPO <DP n="18"/>--> </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0006" num="6"><claim-text>6. Vacuum cleaner (1) according to any of claims 4 and 5, wherein each secondary stage cyclone dust separating unit (12) comprises a secondary stage dust collecting chamber (15) downstream of and fluidly connected to dust outlet openings (16) of respective secondary stage conical cyclones (13) . </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0007" num="7"><claim-text>7. Vacuum cleaner (1) according to claim 6, wherein with regard to front to back direction, each secondary stage dust col<sup>¬</sup> lecting chamber (15) is positioned and mounted behind and flush with respective secondary stage conical cyclones (13) . </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0008" num="8"><claim-text>8. Vacuum cleaner (1) according to any of claims 6 and 7, wherein with regard to planes running essentially parallel to a respective lateral side (7) the secondary stage dust collect<sup>¬</sup> ing chamber (15) has a triangular shaped cross section. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0009" num="9"><claim-text>9. Vacuum cleaner (1) according to any of claims 6 to 8, comprising a tertiary stage dust separator (17) which is, in front to back direction, mounted behind the primary stage dust collecting chamber (9) and laterally adjacent to the at least one secondary stage dust collecting chamber (15) . </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0010" num="10"><claim-text>10. Vacuum cleaner (1) according to at least one of the preceding claims, further comprising air channels (14) connecting an air outlet of the primary stage cyclone dust separator (8) to the at least one secondary stage cyclone dust separating unit (12), wherein the air channels (14) are guided at a top side (4) of the cleaner body (2) . </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0011" num="11"><claim-text>11. Vacuum cleaner (1) according to at least one of the preceding claims, wherein the primary stage cyclone dust separator (8) is, in front to back direction, mounted behind the primary stage dust collecting chamber (9), and wherein the primary <!-- EPO <DP n="19"/>--> stage cyclone dust separator (8) preferably is a horizontal type dust separator. </claim-text></claim></claims><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
