<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2499453-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2499453" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="41395224" file-reference-id="315058" date-produced="20180825" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146587844" ucid="EP-2499453-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2499453</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-10795028-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154850036" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>10795028</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20101104</date><lang>FI</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP181443941" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>10795028.9</doc-number><date>20101104</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140552031" ucid="FI-20096175-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>FI</country><doc-number>20096175</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20091111</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140552411" ucid="FI-2010050891-W" linkage-type="W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>FI</country><doc-number>2010050891</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20101104</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130715</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989324060" load-source="docdb">F27B   7/42        20060101ALI20110601BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989324061" load-source="docdb">G01B   7/28        20060101ALI20110601BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989324062" load-source="docdb">G01B  21/20        20060101ALI20110601BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989324063" load-source="docdb">G01B  21/24        20060101AFI20110601BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1839999059" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G01B   7/281       20130101 LI20170307BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1839999060" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F27B   7/26        20130101 FI20170307BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2029353354" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F27B   7/42        20130101 LI20150817BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2029355445" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F27D  21/04        20130101 LI20150817BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2029355625" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F27D  19/00        20130101 LI20150817BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2029356207" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F27D  21/00        20130101 LI20150817BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2029358502" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G01B  21/20        20130101 LI20150817BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132368165" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">VERFAHREN ZUR MESSUNG UND AUSRICHTUNG EINES ZYLINDERFÖRMIGEN ROTATIONSGERÄTS</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132368166" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">METHOD FOR MEASURING AND ALIGNING A ROTARY CYLINDRICAL APPARATUS</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132368167" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">PROCEDE DE MESURE ET D'ALIGNEMENT D'UN APPAREIL CYLINDRIQUE ROTATIF</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919516878" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>ANDRITZ OY</last-name><address><country>FI</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919522620" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>ANDRITZ OY</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919520367" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>HAEKKINEN TEEMU</last-name><address><country>FI</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919505680" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>HAEKKINEN, TEEMU</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919020315" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>HÄKKINEN, Teemu</last-name><address><street>Mustalammenkuja 10 C 28</street><city>FI-57170 Savonlinna</city><country>FI</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919541455" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>IIVARINEN HEIKKI</last-name><address><country>FI</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919540892" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>IIVARINEN, HEIKKI</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919020311" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>IIVARINEN, HEIKKI</last-name><address><street>Urpurinne 9</street><city>FI-57230 Savonlinna</city><country>FI</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919518666" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>KAIKKONEN PERTTI</last-name><address><country>FI</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919521982" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>KAIKKONEN, PERTTI</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919020312" load-source="patent-office" sequence="3" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>KAIKKONEN, PERTTI</last-name><address><street>Ritalanmäentie 71</street><city>FI-57600 Savonlinna</city><country>FI</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919517401" load-source="docdb" sequence="4" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>LINTUNEN TUOMO</last-name><address><country>FI</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919519782" load-source="docdb" sequence="4" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>LINTUNEN, TUOMO</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919020310" load-source="patent-office" sequence="4" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>LINTUNEN, TUOMO</last-name><address><street>Pietari Kylliäisentie 31</street><city>FI-57710 Savonlinna</city><country>FI</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919020314" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Andritz Oy</last-name><iid>100076803</iid><address><street>Tammasaarenkatu 1</street><city>00180 Helsinki</city><country>FI</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919020313" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>HOFFMANN EITLE</last-name><iid>100061036</iid><address><street>Patent- und Rechtsanwälte Arabellastrasse 4</street><city>81925 München</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="FI-2010050891-W"><document-id><country>FI</country><doc-number>2010050891</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20101104</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2011058221-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2011058221</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20110519</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549921511" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS549866680" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549778625" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549794272" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549885934" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549778626" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549779017" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549921512" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549778627" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549778628" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549862566" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549794281" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549794282" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549921513" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549778637" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549921514" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549779018" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549885935" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549778638" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549794283" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549778639" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549794284" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549866681" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549794293" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549794294" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549866686" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS549866687" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549862567" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549864409" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549862568" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549866688" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549885936" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549866689" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS549862569" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549779019" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549864418" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549864419" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS549794295" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63960278" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to a method of measuring and aligning a rotary cylindrical or other rotationally symmetrical apparatus, e.g. in the form of a truncated cone. The rotationally symmetrical apparatus can be e.g. a kiln, such as a lime kiln or a cement kiln, or a drum, used in the chemical pulp industry.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002">Aligning a rotary cylindrical apparatus, such as a kiln or a drum, refers in this connection to straightening of the shell thereof, e.g. in order to keep the bricks in place in the kiln and for ensuring the desired functioning. In practice this means transferring the center points of the shell of a rotary object to a common straight line at the location of its supporting points. Adjustment of a rotary apparatus, in its turn, commonly refers to changing the declination angles of the support rollers of the rotary apparatus in respect of the center line of the apparatus. The adjustment aims at decreasing the wearing of mechanical parts and at desired functioning of the apparatus.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">It is known from the state of art to align a rotary apparatus using e.g. the arrangement of FI utility model 8330 comprising orientation points fixed around the apparatus, measurement points fixed in connection with the support rings, measurement points fixed in connection with support rollers meant for supporting the support rings and at least two station points for setting the measuring device to said station point, and further apparatuses. Thus, the solution according to said publication utilizes, in addition to a measuring device, also a measurement point physically fixed in the object of measurement. The measurement point can be e.g. a target, an adhesive, a prism or a bar. In the solution according to said publication the object is measured when it is cold.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US5491553A"><text>US-publication 5 491 553</text></patcit>, in turn, presents an arrangement for measuring a kiln where the measuring device is fixed on a base that is located under the kiln for<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> the measurement. The measuring device in the publication comprise three semiconductor lasers.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">In the prior art solutions, such as e.g. in publication FI 8330, a drum-like object is measured stationary, i.e. cold. However, measuring of a cold kiln or drum does not give a right result, but the geometry of the kiln or drum changes during operation due to e.g. thermal expansion. In prior art, the thermal expansion is not always taken into account at all, but aligning is performed in accordance with the geometry of a cold kiln or drum. Then the alignment may differ even remarkably from the correct alignment. Further, taking thermal expansion into account during aligning is very troublesome and it is usually impossible to perform it exactly. And, a problem that arises in measuring a cold kiln or drum is that during the measurement and aligning the kiln or drum has to be kept out of operation. In practice this means that the measurement and aligning are to be performed during shutdown, when many repair and maintenance operations are performed at the mill. Scheduling the measurement and aligning with the other operations can be very difficult.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">Another problem in the known solutions is caused by the aim to align the shell of the apparatus in a so-called indirect way, e.g. by measuring for instance the diameters of the support rollers, the distance between the support rollers, the diameter of the support rings, relative differences in altitude of the bases of the support rollers, the clearances of the casing and support ring etc. Such an indirect cold measuring is clearly more unreliable than measuring during the operation of the kiln, because the temperatures vary at different piers. For this reason, the clearance between the shell and the ring does not remain the same, but the center line of the kiln changes. According to prior art, the clearance is measured through backward slip, but the measurement is not totally reliable, as the slip changes a bit due to e.g. rotational speed.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">In the solution according to said US-publication, locating the measuring device below the object to be measured is troublesome and time consuming.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p><p id="p0008" num="0008">Additionally, the equipment that is needed is weighty. For these reasons, the measurement is carried out on one side of the support ring only. Further, the measurement is carried out below the shell on one side only, whereby it is not even possible to effect the measurement in close vicinity of the support ring because of the support rollers located below the support ring. An additional problem in the technique according to said US-publication is the narrowness of the sector on which the measurement points can be measured. A narrow measuring sector gives an unreliable result. Further, the shape of the shell changes the least on the bottom side, which further increases the unreliability of the measuring result.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009"><patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="EP0420663A"><text>EP 0 420 663</text></patcit> discloses aligning a hot kiln, whereby measurements are performed in proximity to the support rings, a center line corresponding to the measurements positions is calculated, and each support ring is then moved by the corresponding amount in order to align the kiln.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010"><patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="JP6159942B"><text>JP 6159942</text></patcit> discloses aligning a kiln, whereby measurements are performed on either sides of each support ring. Deviations with respect to a datum line are found, and the kiln is then aligned accordingly.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011"><patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="US7110910B"><text>US 7,110,910</text></patcit> describes measuring points on a rotationally symmetric apparatus. Centroids are calculated, and a line is fitted to these.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012"><patcit id="pcit0005" dnum="CA2028505"><text>CA 2028505</text></patcit> discloses measuring deflections in the shell of a kiln.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">The present invention provides a solution for the above problems. According to the present invention, a novel solution has been developed for measuring and aligning a rotary cylindrical apparatus.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">The invention is defined in the appended claims.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">According to the present invention, the geometry of a rotary object is measured during operation. The measurement results allow aligning the object and thereafter checking the alignment by re-measurement. To be more exact, an object of the invention is to determine the geometry of the object during operation by forming a three-dimensional model of the measurement points, by means of which it is possible e.g. to determine the shell's center points<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> at the supporting points with respect to each other.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">The measurement requires an equipment, by means of which it is possible to create a model of the object in a three-dimensional coordinate system by means of the measurement points. According to the invention, the measurement uses an apparatus that is capable of measuring the measurement point directly from the surface of the object being measured without any target, such as an adhesive, a prism or a bar. In practice, the measurement can be carried out with either an electronic tacheometer or a 3D-scanner. In addition, a software is needed in the measuring and the subsequent alignment of the kiln or drum, by means of which a 3-dimensional model of the object of measurement can be created based on the measurement points. For the measurement, an orientation point network is created around the kiln, which allows orientating the measuring device in a free or known station point in a desired coordinate system. Thus, the measuring device can be located in an easily accessible location, e.g. at a very stabile location in the surroundings of the object to be measured, and there is no need to locate it in a tight or otherwise inconvenient place, e.g. below the object to be measured.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">Usually, when a rotary object is measured, a free station point is used. The orientation points are to be located in the surroundings of the object so that at least two orientation points are observable from each planned free station point. All orientation points can be determined in a desired system of coordinates from one point, in order to be able to later determine the free station point with maximum accuracy.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">The aim of the measurement is to measure the center point of a rotating object at the support rings and the direction of the axes of the support rollers in relation to the calculated center line of the shell. An adequate number of measurement points are measured on the shell of the rotating object from upper and from lower side, i.e. in the axial direction on both sides at equal distances on the same line and at the same distance from the support ring so that the measurement points cover an adequate sector of the shell on both sides of each support ring. An adequate number of measurement points for reaching the required accuracy of measurement is case-dependent. According to the invention, the number of measurement points is at least three. Good results are reached with e.g. approximately ten measurement points. Naturally, the accuracy increases along increasing number<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> of measurement points. When scanning the shell of the object being measured and aligned, the measurement points occur at even intervals and their number is preferably approximately 20-60. The upper side here refers to the side of the support ring, from where the material to be treated is fed into the kiln or drum and the lower side refers to the side from where the material is discharged from the kiln or the drum. In other words, the product moves inside the kiln or drum from above downwards. A rotating object is measured from one side of the shell at minimum. According to the invention, the measurement is effected on the shell of the rotating object preferably on at least two sides.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">In accordance with the invention, the object rotates during the measurement at least once, whereby the measurement points cover all possible positions of motion of the shell of the kiln or drum. The measuring lines are located as close to the support ring as possible and at equal distances from the ring on both sides thereof as shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>. Measuring lines are created on the support rollers both on the upper and the lower side on the surface of the roller and from them an adequate number of points, e.g. approximately 60 points, are measured at even spacing. The axial thrust rollers can be measured using one measuring line only, because it is necessary to determine the center points of the axial thrust rollers in relation to the center line of the kiln. The measured measurement points are transmitted to a computer, where the actual analysis and calculation of the results is performed. By means of the program, circular regression, i.e. best fit circle for all the measuring points is calculated from the points measured on the measuring lines. Coordinates are determined for the center points of the calculated circles in a three-dimensional system of coordinates. After this, a line segment is determined between the center points of the circles calculated on both sides of the support rings of each pier and coordinates are determined for the center point of this line segment. In this way, the coordinates of the shell's center point can be determined from the center of the support ring highly accurately. The corresponding calculations are carried out for the support rollers. That is, first the best fit circles are calculated from the measurement points and center point coordinates determined for them, after which a straight line is determined between the center points. When the center point coordinates of the shell have been determined from the center of the support rings as mentioned in the above, a reference straight line can be calculated for the shell's center line. The reference<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> straight line can be determined as a regression straight line either by taking into account the coordinates of the center points of all piers or by fixing the coordinates of the center point of one pier onto the straight line. The reference straight line can also be determined by fixing the center points of two piers as a straight line. After this it is possible to calculate the vertical and horizontal distances of the shell's center points to the determined reference straight line. Additionally, based on the reference straight line the declination angle of the object is known and can be compared to the designed declination angle. As to the support rollers, the vertical and horizontal declination angles thereof can be determined with respect to the calculated reference straight line of the object's shell, as well as the center points of the rollers' axes. By means of the calculated values the shell of the object can be aligned straight by transferring the center points of the line segments located between the center points of the calculated circular regressions to the calculated reference line. These center points for the line segments are the same as the center points of rotation of the shell. The calculation can be effected utilizing the determined center points of the support rollers' axes, or alternatively it is also possible to measure the diameters of the support rollers and the support rings, the distance between the support rollers and the clearance between the shell and the support roller, based on which the geometry required for the alignment can be solved mathematically. Additionally, the vertical declination angles of the support rollers can be adjusted to correspond to the declination angle of the shell, if needed. When the required transfers have been made, a control measurement can be effected.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">Additional advantages of the invention include the following:
<ul><li>the measurement is done easily and quickly during operation,</li><li>the equipment required for the measurement is light-weighted and easily supported by one person,<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></li><li>very exact measuring result, which provides good alignment and better operability of the kiln or drum,</li><li>the measuring result can be verified by means of a re-measurement,</li><li>the measuring and the aligning can be perforemd during operation, whereby there is no need for a shut-down,</li><li>adjustments can be anticipated and problem situations avoided, and</li><li>the described measuring method eliminates risk factors in the measurements compared to old methods of measuring the support roller basis levels. These risk factors, especially with regard to journal bearings, include e.g. uneven wear of journal bearing halves and dimension differences between journal boxes.</li></ul></p><p id="p0021" num="0021">In the following, the invention is disclosed in more detail with reference to the appended drawings, of which
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> illustrates a solution according to the invention for measuring the shell of a rotating cylindrical object,</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref> illustrates the actual profile of the shell, and</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3</figref> illustrates the apparatus according to the invention as a schematic drawing and an example of locating the orientation points and the free station point in the surroundings of the apparatus.</li></ul></p><p id="p0022" num="0022"><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> illustrates a solution according to a preferred embodiment of the invention, showing a part of a shell 10 of a drum or kiln being aligned, a support ring 20, support rollers 30, a measuring device 40, upper side 70 and lower side 80 of the support ring and the left side 90 and the right side 100 of the shell. On both sides of the support ring measuring lines 50 are determined, from which the measurement points are measured. The measured measurement points are transmitted from the measuring device via a data transfer line to a computer 190, e.g. a PC-based apparatus, which produces a three-dimensional<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> model of the apparatus and performs the actual analyzing and calculation of the results that is required for the alignment. By means of the program, circular regressions are calculated from the measured points. Coordinates are determined for the center points of the calculated circles in a 3-dimensional system of coordinates. After this, a line segment 110 is determined between the center points of the circles calculated on both sides of the support rings 20 of each pier and coordinates are determined for the center point 60 of this line segment. In this way, the coordinates of the shell's 10 center point of rotation 60 can be determined from the center of the support ring 20 highly accurately. The corresponding calculations are carried out for the support rollers 30. That is, first the best fit circles are calculated from the measurement points and center point coordinates determined for them, after which a line segment is determined between the center points and a center point 120 for said line segment.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023"><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref> illustrates the actual profile of the shell in the measuring line and the center point 170 of rotation. Continuous lines 130 illustrate the shape of the shell during rotation. The center point 170 of the circle 180 calculated in accordance with the invention, as described in the above, illustrates the center point of rotation of the shell, not the geometric center point 140. The rotation center point 170 is determined by forming a circular regression 180 from an adequate number of measurement points 160 measured from the measuring line 50 along a sector 150 of adequate size, the center point of which circular regression illustrates the average center point of rotation of the shell. As a shell of a kiln or drum, especially when hot, has a known tendency to dent at the support rollers as well as from above during rotation, the actual shape of the shell is not circular, but predominantly oval. Further, the shell can move slightly radially during rotation, so that by measuring the shell during rotation, the average rotation center point 170 of the shell is<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> obtained in accordance with <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref>.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024"><figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3</figref> illustrates an example of the location of the orientation points and a free station point in the surroundings of the object. The <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3</figref> shows a rotating cylindrical apparatus, e.g. a kiln or a drum 300. It is carried by support rings 20 supported upon support rollers 30, the middlemost of which support rings is surrounded by shown axial thrust rollers 220. The axial thrust rollers can also be measured and aligned. According to the invention, at least one axial thrust roller 220 is measured by creating a measurement line on the surface of each roller and measuring measurement points on at least one side. Circular regressions are calculated from these measurement points and center points are defined for the circular regressions that illustrate the center point of the axial thrust rollers. The axial thrust rollers are aligned to the same straight line with the shell of the kiln by transferring the center point of the circular regression calculated from the axial thrust roller as seen from above to the regression straight line illustrating the shell.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">Additionally <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3</figref> illustrates a line 210 that in a simplified way illustrates the actual measured center line of the kiln, and a reference straight line 200. The reference straight line 200 can be determined as a regression straight line either by taking into account the coordinates 60 the center points of all piers or by fixing the coordinates of the center point of one pier onto the straight line. The figure also illustrates a number of orientation points 240, which have allowed determining the free station points 230 and the measured center lines 250 of the support rollers' axes.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">Although the above description relates to an embodiment of the invention that is in the light of present knowledge considered the most preferable, it is obvious to a person skilled in the art that the invention can be modified in many different ways within the scope defined by the appended claims.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56983571" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Verfahren zum Messen und Ausrichten einer Rotationszylinder- oder anderen rotationssymmetrischen Vorrichtung (300), wie zum Beispiel eines Ofens oder einer Trommel, wobei die Vorrichtung eine Hülse (10) und zumindest einen Lagerring (20) aufweist, wobei die Hülse und der Lagerring jeweils einen Satz Lagerrollen (30) aufweisen, mittels eines Messgeräts (40), wobei während Rotation der Rotationsvorrichtung (300) unter den Arbeitsbedingungen die folgenden Schritte durchgeführt werden:
<claim-text>Messpunkte (160) werden an der Hülse (10) der Rotationsvorrichtung (300) direkt von der Oberfläche davon in die axiale Richtung auf beiden Seiten jedes Lagerrings (20) entlang derselben kreisförmigen Messlinie (50) im Wesentlichen an gleichen Abständen von dem Lagerring (20) gemessen,</claim-text>
<claim-text>kreisförmige Regressionen (180) werden von den gemessenen Messpunkten (160) berechnet,</claim-text>
<claim-text>Mittelpunkte (170) werden für die berechneten kreisförmigen Regressionen (180) bestimmt,</claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Liniensegment (110) wird zwischen den Mittelpunkten (170) der kreisförmigen Regressionen (180) bestimmt, die auf beiden Seiten des Lagerrings (20) berechnet sind, und Koordinaten werden für den Mittelpunkt (60) dieses Liniensegments berechnet, der gleichzeitig der Mittelpunkt der Rotation der Hülse (10) ist,</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine gerade Bezugslinie (200) wird für die Mittellinie der Hülse (10) als eine gerade Regressionslinie berechnet,</claim-text>
<claim-text>die Abstände der Mittelpunkte (60) der Liniensegmente zwischen den Mittelpunkten (170) der kreisförmigen Regressionen (180) zu der definierten geraden Bezugslinie (200) werden berechnet und</claim-text>
<claim-text>die Hülse (10) der Rotationsvorrichtung (300) wird durch Übertragen der Mittelpunkte der Rotationen der Hülse (10),<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> die die gleichen wie die bestimmten Mittelpunkte (60) der Liniensegmente zwischen den kreisförmigen Regressionen (180) sind, zu der berechneten Bezugslinie (200) gerade ausgerichtet.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die Lagerrollen (30) durch Erzeugen kreisförmiger Messlinien (50) um die Oberfläche jeder Lagerrolle (30) sowohl auf der oberen als auch der unteren Seite, wobei die obere Seite die Seite ist, von der das zu behandelnde Material in die Rotationsvorrichtung (300) zugeführt wird, und die untere Seite die Seite ist, von der Material von der Rotationsvorrichtung (300) abgegeben wird, und durch Messen von Messpunkten gemessen werden,<br/>
kreisförmige Regressionen von den Messpunkten berechnet werden,<br/>
Mittelpunkt-Koordinaten zu den kreisförmigen Regressionen bestimmt werden und<br/>
ein Liniensegment zwischen den Mittelpunkten bestimmt wird und ein Mittelpunkt (120) für das Liniensegment definiert wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1 oder 2, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> ein vertikaler Neigungswinkel der Rotationsachse jeder der Lagerrollen (30) gemessen und mit dem Neigungswinkel der Hülse (10) verglichen wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> nach den Ausrichtungsübertragungen eine Steuermessung durchgeführt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> der Neigungswinkel der Mittellinie der Rotationsvorrichtung (300), der aus der Bezugslinie (200) erhalten wird, mit dem vorgesehenen<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> Neigungswinkel der Rotationsvorrichtung (300) verglichen wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> das Messen unter Verwendung eines Geräts (40) durchgeführt wird, das im Stande ist, den Messpunkt (160) direkt von der Oberfläche der zu messenden Rotationsvorrichtung (300) zu messen, und zwar ohne ein Zielzeichen, wie beispielsweise ein Klebeziel, ein Prisma oder einen Stab.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die Messpunkte an der Hülse (10) von zumindest einer Seite der Hülse gemessen werden.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 7, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die Messpunkte an der Hülse (10) der Rotationsvorrichtung (300) von zumindest zwei Seiten der Hülse (10) gemessen werden.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> ferner zumindest eine Axialdruckrolle (220) durch Erzeugen einer kreisförmigen Messlinie um die Oberfläche jeder Axialdruckrolle (220) und durch Messen von Messpunkten gemessen wird, kreisförmige Regressionen aus den Messpunkten berechnet werden, Mittelpunkte, die den Mittelpunkt der Axialdruckrollen darstellen, für die kreisförmigen Regressionen definiert werden und die Axialdruckrollen (220) zu derselben geraden Linie mit der Hülse (10) der Rotationsvorrichtung (300) durch Übertragen des Mittelpunkts der Rotation der Axialdruckrolle (220), der aus den kreisförmigen Regressionen berechnet ist, wie von oben betrachtet, auf die gerade Regressionslinie ausgerichtet werden, die die Hülse darstellt.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56983572" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A method of measuring and aligning a rotary cylindrical or other rotationally symmetrical apparatus (300), such as e.g. a kiln or a drum, said apparatus having a shell (10) and at least one support ring (20), each of which has a set of support rollers (30), by means of a measuring device (40), wherein during rotation of the rotary apparatus (300) under process conditions the following steps are performed:
<claim-text>measurement points (160) are measured on the shell (10) of the rotary apparatus (300), directly from the surface thereof, in the axial direction on both sides of each support ring (20) along the same circular measuring line (50) essentially at equal distances from the support ring (20),</claim-text>
<claim-text>circular regressions (180) are calculated from the measured measurement points (160),</claim-text>
<claim-text>center points (170) are determined for the calculated circular regressions (180),</claim-text>
<claim-text>a line segment (110) is determined between the center points (170) of the circular regressions (180) calculated on both sides of the support ring (20) and coordinates are determined for the center point (60) of this line segment, which center point (60) simultaneously is the center point of rotation of the shell (10),</claim-text>
<claim-text>a reference straight line (200) is calculated for the center line of the shell (10) as a regression straight line</claim-text>
<claim-text>the distances of the center points (60) of the line segments between the center points (170) of the circular regressions (180) to the defined reference straight line (200) are calculated, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the shell (10) of the rotary apparatus (300) is aligned straight by transferring the center points of rotations of the shell (10), which are the same as the determined center points (60) of the line segments between the circular regressions (180) to the calculated reference line (200).</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>A method according to claim 1 , <b>characterized in that</b> the support rollers (30) are measured by creating circular measuring lines (50) around the surface of each support roller (30) both on the upper and the lower side, the upper side being the side from which material to be treated is fed into the rotary apparatus (300) and the lower side being the side from which material is discharged from the rotary apparatus (300), and measuring measurement points,<br/>
circular regressions are calculated from the measurement points,<br/>
center point coordinates are determined to the circular regressions, and<br/>
a line segment is defined between the center points and a center point (120) is defined for the line segment.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>A method according to claim 1 or 2, <b>characterized in that</b> a vertical declination angle of the axis of rotation of each of the support rollers (30) is measured and compared to the declination angle of the shell (10).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>A method according to any one of the preceding claims, <b>characterized in that</b> after the aligning transfers a control measurement is performed.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>A method according to any one of the preceding claims, <b>characterized in that</b> the declination angle of the center line of the rotary apparatus (300) obtained from the reference line (200) is compared to the designed declination angle of the rotary apparatus (300).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>A method according to any one of the preceding claims, <b>characterized in that</b> the measuring is carried out using a device (40) that is capable of measuring the measurement point (160) directly from the surface of the rotary apparatus (300) being measured, without any target sign, such as an adhesive target, a prism or a bar.<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>A method according to any one of the preceding claims, <b>characterized in that</b> the measurement points are measured on the shell (10) from at least one side of the shell.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>A method according to any one of claims 1-7, <b>characterized in that</b> the measurement points are measured on the shell (10) of the rotary apparatus (300) from at least two sides of the shell (10).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>A method according to any one of the preceding claims, <b>characterized in that</b> further at least one axial thrust roller (220) is measured by creating a circular measuring line around the surface of each axial thrust roller (220) and measuring measurement points, circular regressions are calculated from the measurement points, center points are defined for the circular regressions, which center points illustrate the center point of the axial thrust rollers, and the axial thrust rollers (220) are aligned to the same straight line with the shell (10) of the rotary apparatus (300) by transferring the center point of rotation of the axial thrust roller (220), which is calculated from the circular regressions, as seen from above to the regression straight line illustrating the shell.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56983573" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Procédé de mesure et d'alignement d'un appareil cylindrique rotatif ou d'un autre appareil à symétrie de révolution (300), tel que, par exemple, un four ou un tambour, ledit appareil comportant une coque (10) et au moins un anneau de support (20) dont chacun possède un ensemble de galets de support (30), au moyen d'un dispositif de mesure (40), dans lequel, pendant la rotation de l'appareil rotatif (300), dans les conditions du processus, les étapes suivantes sont exécutées :
<claim-text>des points de mesure (160) sont mesurés sur la coque (10) de l'appareil rotatif (300) directement à partir de sa surface, dans la direction axiale sur les deux côtés de chaque anneau de support (20) le long de la même ligne de mesure circulaire (50) essentiellement à égales distances de l'anneau de support (20),</claim-text>
<claim-text>des régressions circulaires (180) sont calculées à partir des points de mesure mesurés (160),</claim-text>
<claim-text>des points centraux (170) sont déterminés pour les régressions circulaires calculées (180),</claim-text>
<claim-text>un segment de ligne (110) est déterminé entre les points centraux (170) des régressions circulaires (180) calculées sur les deux côtés de l'anneau de support (20) et des coordonnées sont déterminées pour le point central (60) de ce segment de ligne, lequel point central (60) est en même temps le point central de rotation de la coque (10),</claim-text>
<claim-text>une ligne droite de référence (200) est calculée pour la ligne centrale de la coque (10) en tant que ligne droite de régression</claim-text>
<claim-text>les distances des points centraux (60) des segments de ligne entre les points centraux (170) des régressions<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> circulaires (180) à la ligne droite de référence définie (200) sont calculées, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>la coque (10) de l'appareil rotatif (300) est mise en alignement rectiligne en transférant les points centraux des rotations de la coque (10), lesquels sont les mêmes que les points centraux déterminés (60) des segments de ligne entre les régressions circulaire (180), à la ligne de référence calculée (200).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> les galets de support (30) sont mesurés en créant des lignes de mesure circulaires (50) autour de la surface de chaque galet de support (30) à la fois sur le côté supérieur et le côté inférieur, le côté supérieur étant le côté à partir duquel le matériau à traiter est fourni dans l'appareil rotatif (300) et le côté inférieur étant le côté à partir duquel le matériau est déchargé hors de l'appareil rotatif (300), et en mesurant des points de mesure,<br/>
des régressions circulaires sont calculées à partir des points de mesure,<br/>
des coordonnées de points centraux sont déterminées par rapport aux régressions circulaires, et<br/>
un segment de ligne est défini entre les points centraux et un point central (120) est défini pour le segment de ligne.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1 ou 2, <b>caractérisé en ce qu'</b>un angle de déclinaison verticale de l'axe de rotation de chacun des galets de support (30) est mesuré et comparé à l'angle de déclinaison de la coque (10).<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, <b>caractérisé en ce qu'</b>après les transferts d'alignement une mesure de contrôle est effectuée.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> l'angle de déclinaison de la ligne centrale de l'appareil rotatif (300) obtenu à partir de la ligne de référence (200) est comparé à l'angle de déclinaison de conception de l'appareil rotatif (300).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> la mesure est réalisée en utilisant un dispositif (40) qui est capable de mesurer le point de mesure (160) directement à partir de la surface de l'appareil rotatif (300) en cours de mesure, sans un quelconque signe de cible tel qu'une cible adhésive , un prisme ou une barre.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> les points de mesure sont mesurés sur la coque (10) à partir d'au moins un côté de la coque.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> les points de mesure sont mesurés sur la coque (10) de l'appareil rotatif (300) à partir d'au moins deux côtés de la coque (10).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b>, de plus, au moins un galet de pression axiale (220) est mesuré en créant une ligne de mesure circulaire autour de la surface de chaque<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> galet de pression axiale (220) et en mesurant des points de mesure, des régressions circulaires sont calculées à partir des points de mesure, des points centraux sont définis pour les régressions circulaires, lesquels points centraux illustrent le point central des galets de pression axiale, et les galets de pression axiale (220) sont alignés sur la même ligne droite avec la coque (10) de l'appareil rotatif (300) en transférant le point central de rotation du galet de pression axiale (220), lequel est calculé à partir des régressions circulaires, comme observé ci-dessus à la ligne droite de régression illustrant la coque.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16671590" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="144" he="147" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="144" he="132" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="138" he="208" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
