<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2960112-A1" country="EP" doc-number="2960112" kind="A1" date="20151230" family-id="51410151" file-reference-id="315111" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="160452033" ucid="EP-2960112-A1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2960112</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20151230</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-15171860-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP193867034" load-source="patent-office" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>15171860.8</doc-number><date>20150612</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP193867035" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>15171860</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20150612</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC162032233" ucid="GB-201411356-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>GB</country><doc-number>201411356</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20140626</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1988520402" load-source="docdb">B60R  11/06        20060101ALI20151030BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1988526987" load-source="docdb">A47B  81/00        20060101ALI20151030BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1988527637" load-source="docdb">B60R   7/02        20060101AFI20151030BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1976517515" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A47B  81/00        20130101 LI20160201BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1987770250" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B60R   7/02        20130101 FI20151028BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1987795900" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B60R  11/06        20130101 LI20151028BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT165547565" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">SPEICHERANORDNUNG</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT165547566" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">STORAGE ASSEMBLY</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT165547567" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">ENSEMBLE DE STOCKAGE</invention-title><citations><patent-citations><patcit mxw-id="PCIT335742491" load-source="docdb" ucid="CN-202980984-U"><document-id format="epo"><country>CN</country><doc-number>202980984</doc-number><kind>U</kind><date>20130612</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="X" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT335741100" load-source="docdb" ucid="US-20050225108-A1"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>20050225108</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20051013</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="X" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT335739707" load-source="docdb" ucid="US-20120126575-A1"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>20120126575</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20120524</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="A" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT335745905" load-source="docdb" ucid="US-20130134733-A1"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>20130134733</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20130530</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="A" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit></patent-citations></citations></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR1103340809" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>BRI STOR SYSTEMS LTD</last-name><address><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR1103339130" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>BRI-STOR SYSTEMS LTD.</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR1101640271" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Bri-Stor Systems Ltd.</last-name><iid>101530080</iid><address><street>Church Lane Hixon</street><city>Stafford ST18 0PS</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1103314656" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>HUMPHREY ANDREW PAUL</last-name><address><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1103343761" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>Humphrey, Andrew Paul</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1101639533" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Humphrey, Andrew Paul</last-name><address><street>Bri-Stor Systems Ltd Church Lane Hixon</street><city>Stafford, GB ST18 0PS</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR1101645249" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Sales, Robert Reginald</last-name><suffix>et al</suffix><iid>100032975</iid><address><street>Swindell &amp; Pearson Limited 48 Friar Gate</street><city>Derby DE1 1GY</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS660786264" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS660618150" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS660786266" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS660695883" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS660709163" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS660615597" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS660618155" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS660698388" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS660615598" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS660615611" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS660694813" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS660695884" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS660695885" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS660786267" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS660786268" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS660786269" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS660618156" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS660709164" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS660786270" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS660695886" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS660615612" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS660698389" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS660618157" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS660698390" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS660698395" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS660618476" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS660618477" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS660618158" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS660694814" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS660618167" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS660698397" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS660618168" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS660698398" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS660618169" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS660698411" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS660709165" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS660709166" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS660618478" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states><ep-extended-states><ep-extended-state-data><country>BA</country></ep-extended-state-data><ep-extended-state-data><country>ME</country></ep-extended-state-data></ep-extended-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA166480403" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p id="pa01" num="0001">A storage assembly 10 mountable in a van 12. The assembly 10 is substantially trapezoidal in plan view and provides a face against which sheets of material may lean. The assembly 10 also includes an elongate holder 56 extending across a lower part thereof to receive elongate items such as piping.
<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="157" he="124" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA166760215" lang="EN" source="EPO" load-source="docdb"><p>A storage assembly 10 mountable in a van 12. The assembly 10 is substantially trapezoidal in plan view and provides a face against which sheets of material may lean. The assembly 10 also includes an elongate holder 56 extending across a lower part thereof to receive elongate items such as piping.</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES98405104" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><p id="p0001" num="0001">This invention concerns a storage assembly, particularly but not exclusively a storage assembly for a van, and also a van incorporating such a storage assembly.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002">Vans are used in a very wide range of applications. For instance many builders, workmen, tradesmen and technicians require vans to store and accessibly carry a range of items.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">Traditionally many items and materials have been carried on the outside of vans and particularly on roof racks. This can however lead to materials potentially becoming wet and/or dirty.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">With some materials such as for instance copper pipe, due to the increase in metal prices, such materials have become prey to theft when left on the outside of vans. Lengths of copper pipe and other elongate products are often supplied for instance in three metre lengths which can prove problematic to carry inside many vans.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">According to a first aspect of the invention there is provided a storage assembly mountable in a vehicle, the assembly having a profile in plan view which in use tapers towards the rear of the vehicle.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">The storage assembly may have a trapezoidal shape in plan view, with the front and rear ends in use substantially parallel to each other.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">The storage assembly may be mountable in the load area of a van so as to extend rearwardly from substantially adjacent the bulkhead of the van. The storage assembly may in use extend for at least substantially the majority of the length of the load area of the van.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p><p id="p0008" num="0008">The storage assembly may include a first side which in use extends adjacent to and parallel to a side wall of the van, and a second side wall which converges rearwardly towards the first side wall.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">The storage assembly may include a plurality of shelf arrangements. The storage assembly may include a plurality of spaced uprights mountable to the floor of the van. Respective pairs of spaced uprights may be provided at the front end and rear ends in use of the storage assembly. One or more pairs of spaced uprights may also be provided intermediate of the front and rear ends of the assembly.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">The shelf arrangements may selectively mount a plurality of storage boxes, and may include dividers to securely locate storage boxes.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">The shelf arrangements may mount one or more drawer assemblies.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">The shelf assembly may be mountable in a van with the first side adjacent the offside of the van. The shelf assembly may be arranged such that a part of the storage assembly can be accessed through a door in the offside of the van.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">An end panel may be provided on the rear end in use of the storage assembly, and storage components may be mountable on the end panel.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">The second side of the storage assembly may provide a face against which sheets of material may lean, and securing means may be provided for retaining the sheets against the second side.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">The storage assembly may include an elongate holder defining an elongate space for receiving elongate items. The elongate holder may in use extend diagonally across the load area of a van. The elongate holder may be provided at a lower part of the storage assembly. The elongate holder may<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> extend through the van bulkhead and may extend at least partially beneath the passenger seat or seats of the van.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">The elongate holder may extend in use from adjacent the rear offside corner of the van, and the elongate holder may extend through the storage assembly end panel. A selectively openable closure may be provided on the rear end of the elongate holder to retain elongate items therein. A window may be provided part way along the elongate holder to enable any items held therein to be viewed.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">The elongate holder may extend substantially parallel to the second side of the storage assembly.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">According to a second aspect of the invention there is provided a van incorporating a storage assembly according to any of the preceding thirteen paragraphs.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">The van may include a nearside door opening into the load area thereof.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">The van may include an offside door opening into the load area thereof.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">Embodiments of the present invention will now be described by way of example only and with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which:-
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is a diagrammatic plan view of a first storage assembly according to the invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2</figref> is a diagrammatic rear perspective view of the assembly of <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>;<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 3</figref> is a diagrammatic first side view of the assembly of <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 4</figref> is a diagrammatic rear view of the assembly of <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 5</figref> is a diagrammatic part cut away plan view of the assembly of <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> fitted in a van;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 6</figref> is a diagrammatic part cut away rear perspective view of the assembly of <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> fitted in a van;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 7</figref> is a diagrammatic part cut away first side view of the assembly of <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> fitted in a van;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 8</figref> is a diagrammatic part cut away rear view of the assembly of <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> fitted in a van;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 9</figref> is a similar view to <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 6</figref> but incorporating additional elements;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 10</figref> is a diagrammatic partially cut away second side view of the arrangement shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 9</figref>; and</li><li><figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 11</figref> is a similar view to <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 6</figref> but of a second arrangement.</li></ul></p><p id="p0022" num="0022"><figref idrefs="f0001 f0002 f0003 f0004 f0005">Figs. 1 to 10</figref> show a first storage assembly 10 mountable in a van 12 part only of which has been shown for clarity in <figref idrefs="f0003 f0004 f0005">Figs. 5 to 10</figref>. The assembly 10 has a main part 14 which is substantially trapezoidal in plan view and comprises a front end 16 with a spaced pair of uprights 18 interconnected by a top crossbar 20 and one or more further crossbars which are not visible in the drawings.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">The assembly 10 has a rear end 22 with a pair of spaced uprights 24 with a plate 26 extending therebetween. The rear end 22 is significantly<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> narrower than the front end 16, but extends parallel thereto, thereby defining the trapezoidal shape. An intermediate pair of uprights 28 are provided midway between the front and rear ends 16, 22, and one or more crossbars (not shown) may be provided between the intermediate uprights 28 as required.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">Three sets of shelves 30, 32, 34 one above each other are provided respectively between the front end 16 and the intermediate uprights 28 one above each other. Three further shelves 36, 38, 40 are provided extending between the intermediate uprights 28 and the rear end 22, again one above each other. All of the shelves 30 - 40 are trapezoidal in plan view to maintain the overall trapezoidal shape of the assembly 10.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">The uppermost two shelves 32, 34 between the front end 16 and the intermediate uprights 28 have a divider 42 parallel to their first side 44 on the offside of the van which defines a rectangular space 46 which can receive a number of storage bins 48 as shown for example in <figref idrefs="f0005">Figs. 9 and 10</figref>. Further storage bins 50 may be mounted on the rear end plate 26 as shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">Figs. 9 and 10</figref>.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">All of the uprights 18, 24, 28 have a plurality of mounting holes 52 along their length such that the shelves 30 - 40 can be mounted at different heights as required for storage of different sized items.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 10</figref> a set of drawers 54 may be mounted between the lower shelve 30 and the van floor, and these could be accessed through an offside side door of the van 10, as could the shelves 30, 32, 34 thereabove.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">An elongate holder 56 is also provided. The holder 56 comprises a square section extension 58 coming out of the rear end plate 26 with a closable flap 60. This extends into a box section 62 which extends below the lower shelves 30, 36 and parallel to the second side 64 of the assembly 10<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> away from the offside of the van. The box section 62 extends into a further length of L-shape section 66 which extends through the van bulkhead 68 to locate beneath the passenger seat or seats of the van.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">The storage assembly 10 can be mounted to the floor of the van 12 by any appropriate means, and particular brackets may be provided so that the assembly can be mounted to standard fixing points on the van 12. Fixings may be provided at the upper ends of the uprights 18, 24, 28 which connect to the van roof.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">The storage assembly 10 provides ready access through a nearside opening 70 which would be provided with a door conventionally in a van. Where an offside door is provided this can also provide ready access to the assembly 10 as described above, and particularly in relation to <figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 10</figref>. The trapezoidal shape permits ready access to all of the storage assembly 10 either through a nearside door or the rear door or doors of the van.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">The elongate holder 54 allows elongate items such as lengths of copper pipe to readily be carried and stored clear of other items. A window 72 is provided part way along the box section 62 to enable a clear indication to be provided as to whether anything is located in the elongate holder 56. The storage assembly 10 is also very suited to carry sheets of material such as plasterboard or plywood which typically would come in sheets with a dimension along the lines of 1.2 x 2.4 metres. Restraining arrangements such as straps or brackets may be provided on the uprights 18, 24 and/or 28 particularly at their upper ends to retain such sheets in position.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032"><figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 11</figref> shows a second storage assembly 100 which is similar in most respects to the storage assembly 10, and only the differences will be highighted. In this instance only two shelves 102, 104 are provided, again mounted between respective pairs of uprights 106. A rear plate 108 is provided. In this instance an opening 110 is provided at a lower end of the<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> rear plate 108, and elongate members can simply extend therethrough for their forward ends to lie on the floor, or potentially to extend through a hole in the bulkhead.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">There are thus described storage assemblies which make for very efficient and accessible use of the load area of a van. The assemblies can be inexpensively and robustly manufactured, and can be produced in a wide range of variations and/or adjustments for use in a wide range of applications and to hold and store a range of different items.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">Different storage containers or otherwise can be held or mounted on the storage assembly if required. A different number and/or type of shelves may be provided.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">Whilst endeavouring in the foregoing specification to draw attention to those features of the invention believed to be of particular importance it should be understood that the Applicant claims protection in respect of any patentable feature or combination of features hereinbefore referred to and/or shown in the drawings whether or not particular emphasis has been placed thereon.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM90460060" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --><claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A storage assembly mountable in a vehicle, the assembly having a profile in plan view which in use tapers towards the rear of the vehicle.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>An assembly according to claim 1, in which the storage assembly has a trapezoidal shape in plan view, with the front and rear ends in use substantially parallel to each other.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>An assembly according to claims 1 or 2, in which the storage assembly is mountable in the load area of a van so as to extend rearwardly from substantially adjacent the bulkhead of the van, and the storage assembly may extend for at least substantially the majority of the length of the load area of the van.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>An assembly according to claim 3, in which the storage assembly includes a first side which in use extends adjacent to and parallel to a side wall of the van, and a second side wall which converges rearwardly towards the first side wall, in which the storage assembly is mountable in a van with the first side adjacent the offside of the van, and in which the storage assembly is arranged such that a part of the storage assembly can be accessed through a door in the offside of the van.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>An assembly according to claim 4, in which the second side of the storage assembly provides a face against which sheets of material may lean, and securing means may be provided for retaining the sheets against the second side of the storage assembly.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>An assembly according to any of the preceding claims, in which the storage assembly includes a plurality of spaced uprights mountable to the floor of a van, in which respective pairs of spaced uprights are provided at the front end and rear ends in use of the storage assembly, and in which one or<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> more pairs of spaced uprights are provided intermediate of the front and rear ends of the assembly.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>An assembly according to any of the preceding claims, in which the storage assembly includes a plurality of shelf arrangements, in which the shelf arrangements may selectively mount a plurality of storage boxes, in which the shelf arrangements may include dividers to securely locate storage boxes, and in which the shelf arrangements may mount one or more drawer assemblies.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>An assembly according to any of the preceding claims, in which an end panel is provided on the rear end in use of the storage assembly, and in which storage components may be mountable on the end panel.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>An assembly according to any of the preceding claims, in which the storage assembly includes an elongate holder defining an elongate space for receiving elongate items, and in which the elongate holder extends substantially parallel to a second side of the storage assembly which converges rearwardly towards a first side wall of the storage assembly.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>An assembly according to claim 9, in which the elongate holder in use extends diagonally across the load area of a van.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>An assembly according to claims 9 or 10, in which the elongate holder is provided at a lower part of the storage assembly, in which the elongate holder may extend through the van bulkhead, in which the elongate holder may extend at least partially beneath the passenger seat or seats of the van, and in which the elongate holder may extend in use from adjacent the rear offside corner of the van.<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>An assembly according to any of claims 9 to 11, when dependent on claim 8, in which the elongate holder extends through the storage assembly end panel.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>An assembly according to any of claims 9 to 12, in which a selectively openable closure is provided on the rear end of the elongate holder to retain elongate items therein.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>An assembly according to any of claims 9 to 13, in which a window is provided part way along the elongate holder to enable any items held therein to be viewed.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>A van incorporating a storage assembly according to any of the preceding claims, in which the van may include a nearside door opening into the load area thereof, and in which the van may include an offside door opening into the load area thereof.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW20422744" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1,2"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="165" he="231" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --><figure id="f0002" num="3,4"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="165" he="231" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --><figure id="f0003" num="5,6"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="165" he="227" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --><figure id="f0004" num="7,8"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="165" he="227" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --><figure id="f0005" num="9,10"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="165" he="227" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --><figure id="f0006" num="11"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="165" he="125" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><search-report-data><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="160" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="160" he="233" type="tif"/></search-report-data><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
