<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2581146-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2581146" kind="B1" date="20140101" family-id="46968003" file-reference-id="315091" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146553392" ucid="EP-2581146-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2581146</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-12185032-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154827315" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12185032</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120919</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP182062558" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12185032.5</doc-number><date>20120919</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140449378" ucid="US-201161547136-P" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>201161547136</doc-number><kind>P</kind><date>20111014</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140450757" ucid="US-201213596257-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>201213596257</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120828</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20131021</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988099069" load-source="docdb">B21D  35/00        20060101ALI20130516BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988115816" load-source="docdb">B21H   7/16        20060101ALI20130516BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988129422" load-source="docdb">B21D  53/78        20060101AFI20130516BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988135667" load-source="docdb">B23P  15/02        20060101ALI20130516BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2025733717" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B21D  35/002       20130101 LI20150904BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2025733903" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B21D  11/08        20130101 LA20150903BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2025734101" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B23P  15/04        20130101 LI20150904BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2025739243" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B64C  27/473       20130101 LA20150904BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2025739514" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B21D  53/78        20130101 FI20150904BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2025740181" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B64C  11/205       20130101 LA20150904BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2025740459" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B21H   7/16        20130101 LI20130207BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2025741609" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B23P  15/02        20130101 LI20130207BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132192660" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">System und Verfahren zum Herstellen einer Struktur</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132192661" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">System and method of manufacturing a structure</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132192662" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Système et procédé de fabrication d'une structure</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918173318" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>BELL HELICOPTER TEXTRON INC</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918159274" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>BELL HELICOPTER TEXTRON INC.</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918146598" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>BISHOP STEPHEN K</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918135069" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>BISHOP, STEPHEN K.</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918996827" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>BISHOP, STEPHEN K.</last-name><address><street>7491 Walling Lane</street><city>Dallas, TX Texas 75231</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918142010" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>SWENSON STEPHEN S</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918137162" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>Swenson, Stephen S.</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918996831" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Swenson, Stephen S.</last-name><address><street>131 Garnet</street><city>Weatherford, TX Texas 76087</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918145906" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>WILSON CRYSTAL L</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918145176" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>Wilson, Crystal L.</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918996832" load-source="patent-office" sequence="3" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Wilson, Crystal L.</last-name><address><street>14001 Mallard Springs</street><city>Haslet, TX Texas 76052</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918134373" load-source="docdb" sequence="4" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>LEMOND PAULETTE D</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918156735" load-source="docdb" sequence="4" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>Lemond, Paulette D.</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918996830" load-source="patent-office" sequence="4" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Lemond, Paulette D.</last-name><address><street>9717 Links Fairway Drive</street><city>Rowlett, TX Texas 75089</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918996829" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Bell Helicopter Textron Inc.</last-name><iid>100085435</iid><address><street>P.O. Box 482</street><city>Fort Worth, TX 76101</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918996828" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Lawrence, John</last-name><iid>100029147</iid><address><street>Barker Brettell LLP 100 Hagley Road</street><city>Edgbaston Birmingham B16 8QQ</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548860281" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS548883253" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS548860282" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS548977318" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS548972944" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS548983664" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS548883254" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS548860283" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548983665" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS548983666" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS548975835" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS548977319" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS548972945" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548860284" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548983667" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS548860285" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS548883255" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS548975836" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS548983668" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS548973046" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS548983669" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS548977320" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS548828456" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS548977321" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS548977322" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS548828457" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS548828458" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS548983670" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS548860286" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS548983671" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS548977323" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS548883256" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS548977324" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS548983672" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS548973047" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS548860287" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS548860288" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS548828459" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA129848813" lang="EN" source="EPO" load-source="docdb"><p>The system and method of the present application can include machining complex part features in a flat metal sheet (401), and subsequently forming the machined flat metal sheet to have the desired shape and contours. Prior to the step (303) of machining the complex part features, the method can include (311) calculating a scaled location of the complex part features so that the subsequent forming step (305) acts to translate and deform the complex part features into a desired location.</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES63957199" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001"><b>BACKGROUND</b></heading><heading id="h0002"><b>Technical Field:</b></heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present application relates to a method and system of manufacturing an article, according to the preamble of claims 1 and 13 respectively. The system and method of the present application is particularly useful for manufacturing an aerodynamic structure for a rotor blade of an aircraft.</p><heading id="h0003"><b>Description of Related Art:</b></heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">In general, certain aircraft structures may require a high level of precision, as well as a plurality of complex manufacturing steps configured to achieve the requisite high level of precision. For example, it is well known that chemical milling is a manufacturing process commonly used to manufacture parts having complex contours and tapered surfaces. However, chemically milling has shortcomings, such as surfaces pitting, tolerance variation, labor intensive masking, material limitations, and toxic material risks, to name a few.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">Hence, there is a need for an improved manufacturing system and method that improves structure quality and accuracy, while also decreasing labor hours and part rework. <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="WO2010084941A"><text>WO2010/084941</text></patcit> discloses a method of manufacturing a member for reinforcing the front edge of a fan blade, in which plate material is superplastically formed in a mold by pressurizing the inside of the plate material.</p><heading id="h0004"><b>Description of the Drawings</b></heading><p id="p0004" num="0004">The method and the system of the present application are set forth in the independent claims 1 and 13. However, the system and method themselves, as well as a preferred mode of use, and further objectives and advantages thereof, will best be understood by reference to the following detailed description when read in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, wherein:
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001"><b>Figure 1</b></figref> is a perspective view of an aircraft;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002"><b>Figure 2</b></figref> is a cross-sectional view of a rotor blade, taken at section lines II-II in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>, which can be manufactured by the method and the system according to the present invention;<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></li><li><figref idrefs="f0003"><b>Figure 3</b></figref> is a schematic view of a method of manufacturing, according to the illustrative embodiment of the present invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004"><b>Figure 4</b></figref> is a perspective view of a metal sheet;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004"><b>Figure 5</b></figref> is a top view of a machined metal sheet;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005"><b>Figure 6</b></figref> is a cross-sectional view of the machined metal sheet, taken at section lines VI-VI in <figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 5</figref>;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002"><b>Figure 7</b></figref> is a cross-sectional view of a finished abrasion strip member, manufactured by the method of the present application; and</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005"><b>Figure 8</b></figref> is a schematic block diagram of a system, according to an illustrative embodiment of the present invention.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0005"><b>Description of the Preferred Embodiment</b></heading><p id="p0005" num="0005">Illustrative embodiments of the system and method are described below.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p><p id="p0006" num="0006">The present application includes a system and method for efficiently manufacturing structures having a complex surfaces and precision located features. For example, the system and method of the present application is particularly well suited for manufacturing a leading edge abrasion strip member of a rotor blade, the abrasion strip member having an exterior airfoil surface and an interior portion, each having precision located features. However, it should be fully appreciated that the system and method may be used to manufacture any variety of structures; for example, wing members, nose cones, tip-caps, and tail rotor blades, are examples of other structures that may be manufactured using the method and system of the present application.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>, an aircraft 101 is illustrated. Aircraft 101 is a tilt-rotor aircraft having a nacelle 103 on each of end of a wing 107. Each nacelle 103 includes a rotor hub with a plurality of rotor blades 105. Aircraft 101 further includes a fuselage 109 and a tail member 111. Aircraft 101 is illustrated as a tilt-rotor aircraft for exemplary purposes only. It should be appreciated that the method and system of the present application may be used to manufacture structures on aircraft other than a tilt-rotor aircraft. Further, the method and system of the present application may be used to manufacture structures on non-aircraft vehicles and implementations.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">Referring now also to <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref>, each rotor blade 105 includes an abrasion strip member 113 located on a leading edge portion of rotor blade 105. Rotor blade 105 further includes a body portion 115 and a skin member 117. As known in the art, body portion 115 can include any variety of structures, such as a spar, a composite core, a rib, to name a few. In the exemplary embodiment, abrasion strip member 113 includes dimensions that are critical to the structural integrity and performance of rotor blade 105. For example, the exterior airfoil shape and contour of abrasion strip<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> member 113 is critical to the performance of rotor blade 105. Further, the inner shape and dimensions of abrasion strip member 113 can be critical for mating with body portion 115. For example, a location of a lip portion 119 can be critical for the proper structural mating with a spar in body portion 115.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">Referring now to <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3</figref>, a method 301 of manufacturing a structure is schematically illustrated. For example purposes, method 301 is illustrated with regard to manufacturing abrasion strip member 105. Method 301 includes a step 303 which involves machining scaled features with a size and location that compensates for feature movement during a subsequent forming step. Method 301 further includes a forming step 305 and a post processing step 307.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">Step 303 includes a step 311 for calculating the scaled location of the machined features. In step 305, the part is formed through in a stretch forming and/or brake forming procedure that deforms and moves features of the part. As such, step 311 involves calculating the scaled size and location of the features so that the features will be in the proper location subsequent to forming step 305. In the preferred embodiment, step 311 is performed by first machining the features in the part, then brake forming and stretch forming the part, then measuring the dimension dislocation and distortion of the machined features. Data pertaining to the measured dimension dislocation and distortion of the machined features can be statistically evaluated to confirm relative uniformity of feature movement within context of allowable tolerances for both measurement capability and final part assembly. In an alternative embodiment, the calculation of the scaled size and location of the machined features is performed analytically, such that the scaled size and location of the machined features is determined by analytically predicting the dislocation and distortion of the machined features in the forming step 305.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">Step 309 includes programming the machining tool with the data developed in step 311. It is well known in the art that machining tools, such as a CNC machining tool, are typically programmable with a set of instructions for machining the part. As such, step 309 includes programming the machining tool to machine the desired part features in accordance with the scaled feature size and location determined in step 311.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></p><p id="p0012" num="0012">Referring now also to <figref idrefs="f0004 f0005">Figures 4-6</figref>, the machining of abrasion strip member 113 is illustrated as an example of a machining operation in step 303. At least some of the machined features in step 303 are located and sized so that a subsequent forming step functions to move and distort the features into the desired final location. As such, at least some of the features as machined in step 303 are not of the final size and location until after a subsequent forming operation in step 305. In the illustrated embodiment, step 303 includes machining the scaled features onto a flat blank sheet 401. Blank sheet 401 is illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 4</figref>. The size and material of sheet 401 is implementation specific. In one embodiment, sheet 401 is stainless steel (301 SS) and approximately 1.9mm (.075 inches) thick, 1.83 metres (6 feet) long, and 35.6cm (14 inches) wide. However, it should be fully appreciated that other materials and sizes of sheet 401 may be used.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0004">Figures 5</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0005">6</figref>, example machined article 501 is illustrated. The scaled sizes and locations of the features are machined into machined article 501 while sheet 401 is in the flat state. In the illustrated embodiment, a frame 503 having a uniform thickness is preserved in sheet 401. Further, tooling holes 505 can be located in the frame 503. Frame 503 and tooling holes 505 are configured to facilitate brake forming and stretch forming in the forming step 305, as discussed further herein. One example feature that is machined in a scaled location is a profile feature 507. Feature 507 includes a periphery and thickness profile that is machined in a scaled location and thickness so that the scaled features move and distort into the desired position in the subsequent forming step 305. The periphery of feature 507 is contoured in relation to a centerline of the part because of a built-in twist of abrasion strip member 113. Alternative embodiments of abrasion strip member 113 may have zero twist, such that feature 507 is approximately centered and symmetric on a lengthwise centerline.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">Referring again to <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3</figref>, method 301 further includes a forming step 305. In the preferred embodiment, step 305 includes a brake forming step 313 and a subsequent stretch forming step 315. Brake forming step 313 includes using a brake die, the leading edge of the brake die being properly aligned with the machined article 501 with use of tooling pins inserted into tooling holes 505. The brake forming in step 305 bends<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> machined article 501 around a brake die so as to establish the radius of abrasion strip member 113.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">Next, stretch forming step 315 is performed with precision to reproducibly distort the part. The stretch forming is performed in a controlled manner so as to control the strain-rate applied to the metal. Lubrication can be used to prevent any sudden slippage or jerking that might otherwise happen if the part were to bind with the stretch forming tool. Further, tooling pins may be located in tooling holes 505 to assure positive location of the part during stretch forming. Preferably, the jaws of the stretch forming tool are attached to the previously braked formed machine article 501 at the frame 503 that is intentional produced in the machining step 303. Preferably, frame 503 has a constant thickness and sufficient width to provide grip on the entire jaw-plate of the stretch form grips (jaws). Strain rate is controlled and consistent during the stretch forming so as to prevent the part from distorting in an undesired manner. Further, the over-press part of the stretch forming tool should also being controlled to form the part.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">Method 301 can further include a post processing step 307 for upgrading and trimming the part. For example, step 307 can include trimming off frame 503 and touching up any surface finish blemishes. Step 307 can also include a dye-penetrant check to confirm the absence of cracks and pits in the part. Referring now also to <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 7</figref>, abrasion strip member 113 is illustrated after frame 503 is trimmed off.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">Referring now to <figref idrefs="f0005">Figure 8</figref>, a computer system 801 is schematically illustrated. System 801 is configured for performing one or more functions with regard to method 301, as well as other methods or processes described herein.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">The system 801 can include an input/output (I/O) interface 803, an analysis engine 805, and a database 807. Alternative embodiments can combine or distribute the input/output (I/O) interface 803, analysis engine 805, and database 807, as desired. Embodiments of the system 801 can include one or more computers that include one or more processors and memories configured for performing tasks described herein. This can include, for example, a computer having a central processing unit (CPU) and non-volatile memory that stores software instructions for instructing the CPU to perform at least some of the tasks described herein. This can also include, for<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> example, two or more computers that are in communication via a computer network, where one or more of the computers include a CPU and non-volatile memory, and one or more of the computer's non-volatile memory stores software instructions for instructing any of the CPU(s) to perform any of the tasks described herein. Thus, while the exemplary embodiment is described in terms of a discrete machine, it should be appreciated that this description is non-limiting, and that the present description applies equally to numerous other arrangements involving one or more machines performing tasks distributed in any way among the one or more machines. It should also be appreciated that such machines need not be dedicated to performing tasks described herein, but instead can be multi-purpose machines, for example computer workstations, that are suitable for also performing other tasks.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">The I/O interface 803 provides a communication link between external users, systems, and data sources and components of the system 801. The I/O interface 803 can be configured for allowing one or more users to input information to the system 801 via any known input device. Examples can include a keyboard, mouse, touch screen, and/or any other desired input device. The I/O interface 803 can be configured for allowing one or more users to receive information output from the system 801 via any known output device. Examples can include a display monitor, a printer, and/or any other desired output device. The I/O interface 803 can be configured for allowing other systems to communicate with the system 801. For example, the I/O interface 803 can allow one or more remote computer(s) to access information, input information, and/or remotely instruct the system 801 to perform one or more of the tasks described herein. The I/O interface 803 can be configured for allowing communication with one or more remote data sources. For example, the I/O interface 803 can allow one or more remote data source(s) to access information, input information, and/or remotely instruct the system 801 to perform one or more of the tasks described herein.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">The database 807 provides persistent data storage for system 801. While the term "database" is primarily used, a memory or other suitable data storage arrangement may provide the functionality of the database 807. In alternative embodiments, the database 807 can be integral to or separate from the system 801 and can operate on one or more computers. The database 807 preferably provides non-volatile data<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> storage for any information suitable to support the operation of the system 801, including various types of data discussed further herein.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">The analysis engine 805 can be configured for calculating and predicting the scaled location of machined features in step 311, programming the scaled machining operation in step 309, as well as other concepts disclosed herein. For example, the analysis engine 805 can be configured to analytically predict the dimension dislocation and distortion of the machined features during the forming procedures, thereby analytically calculating the scaled location of the features for machining. The analysis engine 805 can include various combinations of one or more processors, memories, and software components.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">The system and method of the present application provide significant advantages, including: 1) creating the critical and complex surface features prior to brake forming and stretch forming; 2) calculating the scaled location of the machined features so that a subsequent forming step translates and deforms the machined features into the desired location; and 3) providing a manufacturing method which does not require the chemical milling.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">Another advantageous feature of the system and method is the placement of tooling holes 505 in the same machining operation in step 303 for machining the scaled features, so as to reduce tolerance stack-up as compared to separately drilling tooling holes 505 in a separate step. Tooling holes 505 are configured for use with tooling pins in the brake form die so as to maintain alignment of the features about a leading edge reference datum.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">Another advantageous feature of the system and method is integrating frame 303 into machined article 501 so that tooling used for forming can utilize the uniform thickness of frame 303 to prevent part slippage and non-uniform stress concentration in the machine article 501 during a forming step, such as stretch forming step 315.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56979086" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Ein Verfahren zur Herstellung eines Artikels (113) aus einem Metallblech (401), wobei das Verfahren aus Folgenden besteht:
<claim-text>maschinelle Einarbeitung eines skalierten Merkmals in das Metallblech (401);</claim-text>
<claim-text>Formen des Metallblechs (401) auf eine Art, dass das skalierte Merkmal verformt wird, um in eine gewünschte Position überzugehen;</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> der Schritt des Formens des Metallblechs (401) eine Abkantoperation und/oder Streckziehoperation mit einbezieht.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Das Verfahren entsprechend Anspruch 1, wobei der Artikel (113) ein Scheuerschutzband (113) für ein Rotorblatt (105) umfasst und wobei zur Herstellung das maschinelle Einarbeiten eines skalierten Merkmals in einen internen Abschnitt des Metallblechs (401) gehört.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Das Verfahren entsprechend Anspruch 1 oder Anspruch 2, zu dem weiterhin Folgendes gehört:
<claim-text>Errechnen einer skalierten Position des skalierten Merkmals vor dem Schritt des maschinellen Einarbeitens des skalierten Merkmals in das Metallblech (401).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Das Verfahren entsprechend Anspruch 3, wobei zum Schritt des Errechnens der skalierten Position des skalierten Merkmals eine analytische Vorhersage einer Bewegung des skalierten Merkmals gehört, die während des Schritts des Formens des Metallblechs (401) auftritt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Das Verfahren entsprechend Anspruch 3 oder Anspruch 4, wobei
<claim-text>(i) zum Schritt des Errechnens der skalierten Position des skalierten Merkmals die maschinell Einarbeitung eines Testmerkmals in ein Teststück gehört, wonach das Teststück geformt wird, wonach eine Verformung des Testmerkmals gemessen wird; oder</claim-text>
<claim-text>(ii) zum Schritt des Schritts des Errechnens der skalierten Position des skalierten Merkmals die maschinelle Einarbeitung einer Reihe von Testmerkmalen in ein Teststück gehört, wonach das Teststück geformt wird, wonach eine Verformung des jedes Testmerkmals gemessen wird.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Das Verfahren entsprechend Anspruch 4 oder Anspruch 5, zu dem weiterhin Folgendes gehört:
<claim-text>Einprogrammieren der skalierten Position des skalierten Merkmals in eine Werkzeugmaschine.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Das Verfahren entsprechend einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei zum Schritt des Formens des Metallblechs eine Streckziehoperation gehört</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Das Verfahren entsprechend einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei zum Schritt des maschinellen Einarbeitens des skalierten Merkmals in ein Metallblech auch das Beibehalten eines Rahmenteils (503) von ungefähr einheitlicher Dicke um ein Kantenteil des Metallblechs (401) gehört; oder wobei zum Schritt des maschinellen Einarbeitens des skalierten Merkmals in ein Metallblech (401) auch gehört, dass ein Rahmenteil (503) von ungefähr einheitlicher Dicke um den Rand des Metallblechs entsteht.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Das Verfahren entsprechend einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei zum Schritt des maschinellen Einarbeitens des skalierten Merkmals das Metallblech (401) auch das Bohren einer Reihe von Aufnahmelöchern (505) in einen Rahmenteil (503) des Metallblechs (401) gehört.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Das Verfahren entsprechend einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei das skalierte Merkmal ein Ansatz ist, der so konfiguriert ist, dass er in ein Rumpfteil des Rotorblatts (105) passt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Das Verfahren entsprechend einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, der sich direkt oder indirekt von Anspruch 2 oder Anspruch 3 ableitet, wobei:
<claim-text>(i) zum Schritt des Formens des Metallblechs (401) eine Abkantoperation gehört, die den Radius des Scheuerschutzteils (113) bestimmt; und/oder</claim-text>
<claim-text>(ii) zum Schritt des Formens des Metallblechs (401) eine Streckziehoperation gehört, welche die endgültige Kontur des Scheuerschutzes (411) liefert.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Das Verfahren entsprechend einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, der sich direkt oder indirekt von Anspruch 2 oder Anspruch 3 ableitet, zudem auch Folgendes gehört:
<claim-text>Abschneiden eines Rahmenteils (403) vom Scheuerschutzband (113).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Ein System (801) zur Durchführung von einem oder mehreren Schritten zur Herstellung eines Artikels (113) aus einem Metallblech (401), wobei das System (801) eine oder mehrere Bearbeitungseinheiten und Speichern von computerlesbaren Anweisungen in einem nichtflüchtigen Speicher umfasst, um:
<claim-text>die Position eines skalierten Merkmals vor nachfolgender Bearbeitung des skalierten Merkmals zu bestimmen;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Maschinenoperation zu steuern, damit an der zuvor bestimmten Position ein skaliertes Merkmal in ein Metallblech (401) eingearbeitet wird; <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b><!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Formwerkzeug gesteuert wird, welches das Metallblech (401) durch eine Abkantoperation und/oder Streckziehoperation so formt, dass das skalierte Merkmal verformt wird, damit das skalierte Merkmal in eine gewünschte Position gebracht wird.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56979087" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A method of manufacturing an article (113) from a metal sheet (401), the method comprising:
<claim-text>machining a scaled feature into the metal sheet (401);</claim-text>
<claim-text>forming the metal sheet (401) such that the scaled feature is distorted to move into a desired location;</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>characterized in that</b> the step of forming the metal sheet (401) includes a brake forming operation and/or stretch forming operation.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The method of claim 1 wherein the article (113) comprises an abrasion strip (113) for a rotor blade (105), and wherein the manufacturing comprises machining a scaled feature into an interior portion of the metal sheet (401).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The method according to claim 1 or claim 2, further comprising:
<claim-text>calculating a scaled location of the scaled feature prior to the step machining the scaled feature into the metal sheet (401).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The method according to claim 3, wherein the step of calculating the scaled location of the scaled feature includes analytically predicting a movement of the scaled feature that occurs during the step of forming the metal sheet (401).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The method according to claim 3 or claim 4 wherein
<claim-text>(i) the step of calculating the scaled location of the scaled feature includes machining a test feature in a test specimen, then forming the test specimen, then measuring a distortion of the test feature; or</claim-text>
<claim-text>(ii) the step of the step of calculating the scaled location of the scaled feature includes machining a plurality of test features in a test specimen, subsequently forming the test specimen, and then measuring a distortion of each test feature.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The method according to claim 4 or of claim 5, further comprising: programming the scaled location of the scaled feature into a machining tool.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The method according to any preceding claim, wherein the step of forming the metal sheet includes a stretch forming operation.<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The method according to any preceding claim, wherein the step of machining the scaled feature into a metal sheet also includes retaining a frame portion (503) of approximately uniform thickness around an edge portion of the metal sheet (401); or wherein the step of machining the scaled feature into the metal sheet (401) also includes causing a frame portion (503) of approximately uniform thickness around a perimeter of the metal sheet to result.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The method according to any preceding claim, wherein the step of machining the scaled feature into the metal sheet (401) also includes drilling a plurality of tooling holes (505) in a frame portion (503) of the metal sheet (401).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The method according to any preceding claim, wherein the scaled feature is a lip portion that is configured for mating to a body portion of the rotor blade (105).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>The method according to any preceding claim dependent directly or indirectly from claim 2 or claim 3, wherein:-
<claim-text>(i) the step of forming the metal sheet (401) includes a brake forming operation that establishes a radius of the abrasion strip member (113); and/or</claim-text>
<claim-text>(ii) the step of forming the metal sheet (401) includes a stretch forming operation that produces the final contour of the abrasion strip member (411).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>The method according to any claim dependent directly or indirectly from claim 2, further comprising:
<claim-text>trimming a frame portion (403) off of the abrasion strip member (113).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>A system (801) for performing one or more steps of manufacturing an article (113) from a metal sheet (401), the system (801) comprising one or more processing units and non-volatile memory storing computer-readable instructions for:
<claim-text>determining a location of the scaled feature prior to a subsequent machining of the scaled feature;</claim-text>
<claim-text>controlling a machining operation so as to machine a scaled feature into the metal sheet (401) at the location previously determined; <b>characterized by</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>controlling a forming tool that forms the metal sheet (401) by a brake forming operation and/or stretch forming operation such that the scaled feature is distorted so as to move the scaled feature into a desired location.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56979088" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Un procédé de fabrication d'un article (113) à partir d'une feuille de métal (401), le procédé comprenant:
<claim-text>l'usinage d'une caractéristique mise à l'échelle dans la feuille de métal (401),</claim-text>
<claim-text>le formage de la feuille de métal (401) de sorte que la caractéristique mise à l'échelle soit déformée de façon à se déplacer vers un emplacement souhaité,</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>caractérisé en ce que</b> l'opération de formage de la feuille de métal (401) comprend une opération de formage à la presse-plieuse et/ou une opération de formage par étirage.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Le procédé selon la Revendication 1 où l'article (113) comprend une bande d'abrasion (113) pour une pale de rotor (105), et où la fabrication comprend l'usinage d'une caractéristique mise à l'échelle dans une partie intérieure de la feuille de métal (401).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Le procédé selon la Revendication 1 ou 2, comprenant en outre :
<claim-text>le calcul d'un emplacement mis à l'échelle de la caractéristique mise à l'échelle avant l'opération d'usinage de la caractéristique mise à l'échelle dans la feuille de métal (401).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Le procédé selon la Revendication 3, où l'opération de calcul de l'emplacement mis à l'échelle de la caractéristique mise à l'échelle comprend la prédiction analytique d'un déplacement de la caractéristique mise à l'échelle qui a lieu au cours de l'opération de formage de la feuille de métal (401).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Le procédé selon la Revendication 3 ou 4 où
<claim-text>(i) l'opération de calcul de l'emplacement mis à l'échelle de la caractéristique mise à l'échelle comprend l'usinage d'une caractéristique de test dans un spécimen de test, puis le formage du spécimen de test, puis la mesure d'une déformation de la caractéristique de test, ou</claim-text>
<claim-text>(ii) l'opération de calcul de l'emplacement mis à l'échelle de la caractéristique mise à l'échelle comprend l'usinage d'une pluralité de caractéristiques de test dans un spécimen de test, subséquemment le formage du spécimen de test et ensuite la mesure d'une déformation de chaque caractéristique de test.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Le procédé selon la Revendication 4 ou 5, comprenant en outre :
<claim-text>la programmation de l'emplacement mis à l'échelle de la caractéristique mise à l'échelle dans un outil d'usinage.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Le procédé selon l'une quelconque des Revendications précédentes, où l'opération de formage de la feuille de métal comprend une opération de formage par étirage.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Le procédé selon l'une quelconque des Revendications précédentes, où l'opération d'usinage de la caractéristique mise à l'échelle dans une feuille de métal comprend également la conservation d'une partie cadre (503) d'une épaisseur approximativement uniforme autour d'une partie bordure de la feuille de métal (401), ou où l'opération d'usinage de la caractéristique mise à l'échelle dans la feuille de métal (401) comprend également la création d'une partie cadre (503) d'une épaisseur approximativement uniforme autour d'un périmètre de la feuille de métal.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Le procédé selon l'une quelconque des Revendications précédentes, où l'opération d'usinage de la caractéristique mise à l'échelle dans la feuille de métal (401) comprend également le perçage d'une pluralité de trous de repère (505) dans une partie cadre (503) de la feuille de métal (401).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Le procédé selon l'une quelconque des Revendications précédentes, où la caractéristique mise à l'échelle est une partie lèvre qui est configurée de façon à s'accoupler à une partie corps de la pale de rotor (105).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Le procédé selon l'une quelconque des Revendications précédentes dépendant directement ou indirectement de la Revendication 2 ou 3, où
<claim-text>(i) l'opération de formage de la feuille de métal (401) comprend une opération de formage à la presse-plieuse qui établit un rayon de l'élément de bande d'abrasion (113), et/ou</claim-text>
<claim-text>(ii) l'opération de formage de la feuille de métal (401) comprend une opération de formage par étirage qui produit le contour final de l'élément de bande d'abrasion (411).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Le procédé selon l'une quelconque des Revendications dépendant directement ou indirectement de la Revendication 2, comprenant en outre :
<claim-text>l'ébarbage d'une partie cadre (403) de l'élément de bande d'abrasion (113).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Un système (801) d'exécution d'une ou de plusieurs opérations de fabrication d'un article (113) à partir d'une feuille de métal (401), le système (801) comprenant une ou plusieurs unités de traitement et une mémoire non volatile conservant en mémoire des instructions lisibles par ordinateur destinées à :
<claim-text>la détermination d'un emplacement de la caractéristique mise à l'échelle avant un usinage subséquent de la caractéristique mise à l'échelle,<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>la commande d'une opération d'usinage de façon à usiner une caractéristique mise à l'échelle dans la feuille de métal (401) à l'emplacement déterminé antérieurement, <b>caractérisé par</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>la commande d'un outil de formage qui façonne la feuille de métal (401) par une opération de formage à la presse-plieuse et/ou une opération de formage par étirage de sorte que la caractéristique mise à l'échelle soit déformée de façon à déplacer la caractéristique mise à l'échelle vers un emplacement souhaité.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16668763" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="165" he="224" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2,7"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="165" he="193" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="165" he="124" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --><figure id="f0004" num="4,5"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="165" he="209" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --><figure id="f0005" num="6,8"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="165" he="201" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
