<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-1851892-B1" country="EP" doc-number="1851892" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="36793730" file-reference-id="270049" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146588862" ucid="EP-1851892-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>1851892</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-06734681-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154851054" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>06734681</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20060209</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140547655" ucid="US-2006004623-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>2006004623</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20060209</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140548825" ucid="US-34573206-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>34573206</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20060202</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140549470" ucid="US-65172805-P" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>65172805</doc-number><kind>P</kind><date>20050210</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130828</date></intention-to-grant-date><search-report-dispatch-date><date>20121221</date></search-report-dispatch-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989326863" load-source="ipcr">H04B   7/06        20060101ALI20130802BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989326864" load-source="ipcr">H04L   1/02        20060101AFI20130802BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989326865" load-source="ipcr">H04L  27/04        20060101ALI20130802BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989621544" load-source="ipcr">H04J  99/00        20090101AFI20081227RMEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989626805" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04B   7/061       20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989632885" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04L   1/02        20130101 FI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132371219" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">DATEN ZUR MODULIERUNG/DEMODULIERUNG EINES KOMMUNIKATIONSSYSTEMS MIT ANTENNENMUSTER UND ENTSPRECHENDE VERFAHREN</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132371220" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">COMMUNICATION SYSTEM MODULATING/DEMODULATING DATA USING ANTENNA PATTERNS AND ASSOCIATED METHODS</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132371221" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">SYSTEME DE COMMUNICATION A FONCTION DE MODULATION-DEMODULATION DE DONNEES DANS LEQUEL SONT UTILISES DES DIAGRAMMES D'ANTENNE, ET PROCEDES ASSOCIES</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919523430" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>INTERDIGITAL TECH CORP</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919537537" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>INTERDIGITAL TECHNOLOGY CORPORATION</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919529775" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>LI YINGXUE</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919508451" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>LI, YINGXUE</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919025143" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>LI, YINGXUE</last-name><address><street>45 Granville Way</street><city>Exton, PA 19341</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919025145" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>InterDigital Technology Corporation</last-name><iid>101366613</iid><address><street>200 Bellevue Parkway Suite 300</street><city>Wilmington, DE 19809</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919025144" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Engdahl, Stefan</last-name><iid>100755782</iid><address><street>Awapatent AB P.O. Box 45086</street><city>104 30 Stockholm</city><country>SE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="US-2006004623-W"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2006004623</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20060209</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2006086576-A2"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2006086576</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20060817</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549880836" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549886184" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549805984" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549789040" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549897578" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549880837" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549925603" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549897579" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549897580" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549790839" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549805985" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549805986" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549886185" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549897585" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549880842" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549789045" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549888190" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549805987" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549897586" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549925604" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549880843" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549925605" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549925606" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549790840" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549790853" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549897587" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549790854" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549790855" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549897588" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549873896" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549789046" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63961280" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001"><b><u>Field of the Invention</u></b></heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to the field of wireless communication systems, and more particularly, to modulation and demodulation techniques for a wireless data communication system.</p><heading id="h0002"><b><u>Background of the Invention</u></b></heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">In wireless data communication systems, information bits are modulated before transmission. Traditional modulation methods include amplitude modulation (AM), frequency modulation (FM) and phase keying modulation (PSK).</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">In these modulation schemes, a sequence of information bits is mapped to a signal with a unique amplitude, phase and/or frequency. Accordingly, the receiver will perform demodulation to convert received signals back to the information bits.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">An example transmitter <b>10</b> is illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>. A channel encoder <b>12</b> provides information bits <b>14</b> to a serial-to-parallel converter <b>16.</b> The output of the serial-to-parallel converter <b>16</b> provides 5 channel bits <b>18(1)-18(5)</b> to a signal mapper <b>20.</b> The signal mapper <b>20</b> maps the 5 channel bits <b>18(1)-18(5)</b> to a channel symbol <b>22.</b> Based upon the modulation performed by the signal mapper <b>20,</b> the modulated channel symbol<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> <b>22</b> is then transmitted over the air by a transmit antenna <b>24.</b></p><p id="p0005" num="0005">Each modulation scheme has a bit error rate, and this bit error rate is asymptotically determined by the minimum Euclidean distance between two distinct modulated symbols. To achieve high data rates in evolving wireless standards, high-order modulation schemes such as 16 QAM and 64 QAM are used.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">However, these high-order modulation schemes require a higher signal-to-noise (SNR) ratio to achieve certain bit error rates (BER). Modulation schemes that require high SNR to achieve certain bit error rates are adversely affected in multipath fading environments, thus causing the wireless links to be unreliable.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US20040264592A"><text>US2004/0264592</text></patcit> relates to the fields of multiplexing and modulation. A communication system comprises a transmitter that modulates a radio signal transmitted from two differently polarized antennas during a state time in which a wave state of the radio signal conveys information and is based on one or more polarization states selected from a constellation of polarization states comprising at least three polarization states. The communication system includes a receiver that intercepts the radio signal by two differently polarized antennas during the state time, and demodulates the signal.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008"><patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="WO03049397A"><text>WO03/049397</text></patcit> relates to iterative detection and decoding of data transmitted in a wireless communication system. The iterative detection and decoding is performed by iteratively passing soft "a priori" information between a detector and a decoder. The detector receives modulation symbols, performs a detection function that is complementary to the symbol mapping performed at the transmitter, and provides soft-decision symbols for transmitted coded bits.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p><heading id="h0003"><b><u>Summary of the Invention</u></b></heading><p id="p0009" num="0009">In view of the foregoing background, it is therefore an object of the present invention to provide a modulation/demodulation scheme that achieves desired bit error rates with reduced signal-to-noise ratios.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">This and other objects, features, and advantages in accordance with the present invention are provided by a wireless communication system comprising a transmitter comprising a serial-to-parallel converter for converting serial data bits to a parallel bit stream, a signal mapper coupled to the serial-to-parallel converter and an antenna selector coupled to the serial-to-parallel converter. The signal mapper receives as input a first group of bits from the parallel bit stream, and maps the first group of bits to a channel symbol. The antenna selector receives as input a second group of bits from the parallel bit <b>stream with the second group of bits being separate from the first group of bits.</b><!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p><p id="p0011" num="0011">The transmitter further comprises a transmit antenna array coupled to the antenna selector and to the signal mapper. The transmit antenna array generate a plurality of transmit antenna patterns with one of the transmit antenna patterns being selected for transmitting the channel symbol based upon the second group of bits from the antenna selector.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">Since information bits are modulated by an antenna pattern, different bit sequences may be transmitted by different antenna patterns. Due to unique RF characteristics associated with each transmit antenna pattern, a receiver is able to demodulate the transmitted bits. The antenna pattern modulation is also combined with traditional modulation techniques. This combination effectively uses a smaller signal constellation as compared to traditional modulation techniques while achieving the same data transfer rate. Consequently, less transmission power may be used to achieve the same BER.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">The plurality of transmit antenna patterns generated by the transmit antenna array may comprise a plurality of omni-directional or directional antenna patterns. The transmit antenna array may comprise a plurality of active antenna elements for forming a phased array. Alternatively, the transmit array may comprise at least one active antenna element and a plurality of passive antenna elements for forming a switched beam antenna.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">The transmitter periodically transmits reference signals from each transmit antenna pattern generated by the transmit antenna array. The wireless communication system further comprises a receive antenna array, and a receiver coupled to the receive<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> antenna array. The receiver may comprise a channel estimator for receiving the periodically transmitted reference signals from each transmit antenna pattern, and estimates radio frequency (RF) characteristics between each respective transmit antenna pattern and the receive antenna.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">The receiver further comprises a demodulator coupled to the channel estimator for receiving the transmitted channel symbol, for determining which channel symbol was transmitted and which transmit antenna pattern was used to transmit the channel symbol. The demodulator determines which channel symbol was transmitted and which transmit antenna pattern transmitted the channel symbol by comparing the channel symbol to the estimated channel symbols transmitted from each transmit antenna pattern.</p><heading id="h0004"><b><u>Brief Description of the Drawings</u></b></heading><p id="p0016" num="0016"><ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a block diagram of a transmitter in accordance with the prior art.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 2</figref> is a block diagram of a transmitter in accordance with the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 3</figref> is a block diagram of a receiver in accordance with the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 4</figref> is a mapping of superimposed QPSK signal constellations in accordance with the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 5a</figref> is a mapping of bits for an 8PSK signal constellation in accordance with the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 5b</figref> is a mapping of bits for a QPSK signal constellation in accordance with the present invention.<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 6</figref> is a performance comparison between prior art communication systems versus communication systems in accordance with the present invention.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0005"><b><u>Detailed Description of the Preferred Embodiments</u></b></heading><p id="p0017" num="0017">The present invention will now be described more fully hereinafter with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which preferred embodiments of the invention are shown. This invention may, however, be embodied in many different forms and should not be construed as limited to the embodiments set forth herein. Rather, these embodiments are provided so that this disclosure will be thorough and complete, and will fully convey the scope of the invention to those skilled in the art. Like numbers refer to like elements throughout.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">A wireless data communications system in accordance with the present invention combines antenna pattern modulation with traditional modulation techniques. This combination effectively uses a smaller signal constellation as compared to using only traditional modulation techniques to achieve the same data transfer rate. Moreover, this combination requires less transmission power to achieve the same bit error rate (BER).</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">Referring now to <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 2</figref>, the illustrated transmitter <b>50</b> includes a channel encoder <b>52</b> providing information bits <b>54</b> to a serial-to-parallel converter <b>56.</b> The output of the serial-to-parallel converter <b>56</b> is divided into two groups.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">For comparison purposes, the serial-to-parallel converter <b>56</b> outputs the same number of bits <b>58(1)-58(5)</b> as the serial-to-parallel converter <b>16</b> in<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>. The 5 information bits are only an example, with the actual number of bits varying based upon the intended application, as readily appreciated by those skilled in the art.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">The 5 information bits <b>58(1)-58(5)</b> output by the serial-to-parallel converter <b>56</b> in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 2</figref> are separated into first and second groups. The first group includes 3 channel bits <b>58(3), 58(4)</b> and <b>58(5)</b> that are input to a signal mapper <b>60.</b> The second group includes 2 antenna selection bits <b>58(1)</b> and <b>58(2)</b> which are input to an antenna selector <b>64.</b></p><p id="p0022" num="0022">The signal mapper <b>60</b> modulates the 3 channel bits <b>58(3)-58(5)</b> for generating a channel symbol <b>62.</b> Since there are 3 information bits, the modulation may be 8PSK. In contrast, the signal mapper <b>20</b> in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is 32QAM since each symbol is made up of 5 information bits.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">As readily understood by those skilled in the art, the signal mapper <b>20</b> in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> generates a signal constellation with 32 possible symbol points on an x-y plane, whereas the signal mapper <b>60</b> in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 2</figref> only generates a signal constellation with 8 possible symbol points on the x-y plane.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">For the transmitter <b>50</b> to generate an equivalent 32 symbol points in the x-y plane, antenna pattern modulation is used. The antenna <b>selector 64</b> selects one of 4 antenna elements <b>81, 82, 83, 84</b> to transmit the channel symbol <b>62.</b> The 4 antenna elements <b>81-84</b> are uncorrelated so that 4 different antenna patterns are generated. Since each of the 8 possible symbol points can be transmitted using a different antenna pattern, 32 possible symbols can be detected by a receiver <b>90.</b><!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></p><p id="p0025" num="0025">The antenna modulation is not limited to the illustrated embodiment. As an alternative, an antenna array with two elements may be used for generating more than two antenna patterns by applying different weights to each element of the antenna array. Consequently, the antenna array may be a phased array antenna or a switched beam antenna, for example.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">The applicable antenna patterns for the antenna array may be directional or omni-directional. When there is more than one omni-directional antenna, each omni-directional antenna will still be seen differently by the receiver due to multipath fading.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">An advantage in using the signal mapper <b>60</b> in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 2</figref> is that is has a smaller signal constellation as compared to the signal mapper <b>20</b> in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>. The signal constellation for the 8PSK modulation used by the signal mapper <b>60</b> is significantly less than the signal constellation for the 32QAM modulation used by the signal mapper <b>20.</b> Therefore, for the same transmission power, the minimum distance between two distinct signal points of 8PSK constellation is much greater than the minimum distance between two distinct signal points of 32QAM constellation. Consequently, to achieve the same BER, it will require less transmission power when 8PSK modulation is used as opposed to when 32QAM modulation is used.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">In this specific example, the signal constellation size for the signal mapper <b>60</b> is one-quarter the size of the signal constellation for the signal mapper <b>20.</b> Nonetheless, the data rate for the data being transmitted from each transmitter <b>10, 50</b> is the same. Under certain circumstances, the transmitter <b>50</b> in accordance with the present invention requires<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> less transmission power to achieve the same quality of service or cover a wider range with the same quality of service.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">For a receiver <b>90</b> to measure the RF characteristics of each antenna <b>81-84,</b> known reference bits are periodically transmitted by the transmitter <b>50.</b> These reference bits are referred to as pilot bits, for example.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">A block diagram of the receiver <b>90</b> for receiving the antenna modulated channel symbols is provided in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 3</figref>. A receive antenna array <b>92</b> receives a signal that includes the antenna modulated channel symbols. The receive antenna array <b>92</b> may comprise one or more antenna elements for generating one or more receive antenna patterns.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">The received signal is applied as input to a demodulator <b>94</b> and to a channel estimator <b>96.</b> The channel estimator <b>96</b> extracts known reference bits from the received signal. These reference bits, which may be pilot bits, for example, are used to estimate the radio frequency (RF) characteristics of the received signal associated with each transmit and receive antenna pair. The channel estimator <b>96</b> estimates the RF characteristics.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">The RF characteristics of the received signal associated with each transmit and receive antenna pair may include attributes such as amplitude, phase, delay spread and frequency response. The estimated RF characteristics for each transmit and receive antenna pair are then sent to the demodulator <b>94.</b></p><p id="p0033" num="0033">The demodulator <b>94</b> computes the Euclidean distance (ED) between the received signal and the estimated signals associated with each transmit and<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> receive antenna pair. The demodulator <b>94</b> chooses the bits associated with the smallest Euclidean distance as the final output.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">The demodulator <b>94</b> will now be described in greater detail while referring to the superimposed constellation as shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 4</figref>. Assume QPSK modulation is used for the channel symbols. The receiver would then see a superimposed constellation consisting of two subsets of QPSK constellation. The outer ring constellation is indicated by reference numeral <b>120,</b> and the inner ring constellation is represented by <b>122.</b></p><p id="p0035" num="0035">The inner ring <b>122</b> represents possible received signals if the channel symbol was transmitted over one antenna (say, antenna 0). The outer ring <b>120</b> represents four possible received signals if the channel symbol was transmitted over another antenna (say, antenna 1). When the receiver receives a signal <b>124,</b> the demodulator <b>94</b> calculates the distance between the received signal and each of eight candidates (four on the inner ring <b>122</b> assuming antenna 0 was used, and four on the outer ring <b>120</b> assuming antenna 1 was used. The demodulator <b>94</b> then selects the point which is nearest to the received signal <b>124.</b> In this example, the dot <b>126</b> corresponding to channel bits 00 would be selected. Once the signal point is selected, the receiver then knows that the channel bits are 00 and the antenna selection bit is 1 since the selected point is on the outer ring <b>120.</b></p><p id="p0036" num="0036">The calculation of the Euclidean distance may depend on the RF characteristics. An example is given below to demonstrate how the Euclidean distance is calculated, and how this provides better performance.<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --></p><p id="p0037" num="0037">In this example, a narrow band system is considered, where RF characteristics between each transmit and receive antenna pair is represented by a complex channel gain. An uncorrelated Rayleigh channel model is also assumed in this example, which means each channel gain is a zero mean complex Gaussian random variable with a variance of 0.5 per dimension. Channel gains of two distinct transmit/receive antenna pairs are uncorrelated. Multiple receive antennas are considered in this example.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">Mapping of the corresponding bits to the 8PSK and QPSK channel symbols is provided in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIGS. 5a and 5b</figref>. Assuming unity energy per information bit, the minimum squared Euclidean distance for the 8PSK signal constellation is: <maths id="math0001" num=""><math display="block"><msubsup><mi>d</mi><mn>8</mn><mn>2</mn></msubsup><mo>=</mo><mn>3</mn><mo>⁢</mo><mfenced separators=""><mn>2</mn><mo>-</mo><msqrt><mn>2</mn></msqrt></mfenced><mo>≈</mo><mn>1.76</mn></math><img id="ib0001" file="imgb0001.tif" wi="46" he="14" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0039" num="0039">The minimum squared Euclidean distance for the QPSK signal constellation is: <maths id="math0002" num=""><math display="block"><msubsup><mi>d</mi><mi>Q</mi><mn mathvariant="italic">2</mn></msubsup><mo>=</mo><mn>6</mn></math><img id="ib0002" file="imgb0002.tif" wi="19" he="13" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0040" num="0040">The signal separation for the QPSK signal constellation is 6, whereas the signal separation for the 8PSK signal constellation is about 1.76. As will be explained in greater detail below, the larger the signal separation between two distinct channel symbols, the easier it is to locate the desired points for demodulation.</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">A system with M receive antennas will now be considered, where a channel gain between an nth<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> transmit and an mth receiver antenna is α<i><sub>nm</sub>.</i> In a conventional transmitter, we assume antenna 0 is used. The receiver is a maximum likelihood (ML) receiver that calculates the Euclidean distance between the received signal and each possible channel symbol. The possible channel symbols are calculated between all of the possible transmit and receive antenna pairs using a know reference signal. A decision is made based upon the calculated Euclidean distance. The performance of such a maximum likelihood receiver depends on the minimum squared Euclidean distance between two distinct channel symbols received by the receiver <b>90.</b></p><p id="p0042" num="0042">If bit sequence S0 results in channel symbol x0 and antenna selection command p, and bit sequence S1 results in channel symbol x1 and antenna selection command q, then the squared Euclidean distance d<sup>2</sup> between two received channel symbols is calculated as: <maths id="math0003" num=""><math display="block"><msup><mi>d</mi><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>=</mo><mstyle displaystyle="true"><munderover><mo>∑</mo><mrow><mi>m</mi><mo>=</mo><mn>0</mn></mrow><mrow><mi>M</mi><mo>-</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></munderover></mstyle><msup><mfenced open="|" close="|" separators=""><msub><mi>α</mi><mi mathvariant="italic">pm</mi></msub><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi>x</mi><mn>0</mn></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>α</mi><mi mathvariant="italic">qm</mi></msub><mo>⁢</mo><msub><mi>x</mi><mn>1</mn></msub></mfenced><mn>2</mn></msup></math><img id="ib0003" file="imgb0003.tif" wi="49" he="17" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0043" num="0043">For the conventional method, the minimum squared Euclidean distance between two distinct channel symbols becomes: <maths id="math0004" num="Equation 1"><math display="block"><msubsup><mi>d</mi><mi>C</mi><mn>2</mn></msubsup><mo>=</mo><msubsup><mi>d</mi><mn>8</mn><mn>2</mn></msubsup><mstyle displaystyle="true"><munderover><mo>∑</mo><mrow><mi>m</mi><mo>=</mo><mn>0</mn></mrow><mrow><mi>M</mi><mo>-</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></munderover></mstyle><msup><mfenced open="|" close="|"><msub><mi>α</mi><mrow><mn>0</mn><mo>⁢</mo><mi mathvariant="italic">m</mi></mrow></msub></mfenced><mn>2</mn></msup></math><img id="ib0004" file="imgb0004.tif" wi="107" he="18" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0044" num="0044">For the modified transmitter <b>50,</b> the minimum squared Euclidean distance is:<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> <maths id="math0005" num="Equation 2"><math display="block"><msubsup><mi>d</mi><mi>I</mi><mn>2</mn></msubsup><mo>=</mo><mi>min</mi><mo>⁢</mo><mfenced separators=""><msubsup><mi>d</mi><mn>4</mn><mn>2</mn></msubsup><mstyle displaystyle="true"><munderover><mo>∑</mo><mrow><mi>m</mi><mo>=</mo><mn>0</mn></mrow><mrow><mi>M</mi><mo>-</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></munderover></mstyle><msup><mfenced open="|" close="|"><msub><mi>α</mi><mi mathvariant="italic">nm</mi></msub></mfenced><mn>2</mn></msup><mo>,</mo><munderover><mi>min</mi><mrow><mi>k</mi><mo>=</mo><mn>0</mn></mrow><mn>3</mn></munderover><mfenced separators=""><mn>3</mn><mo>⋅</mo><mstyle displaystyle="true"><munderover><mo>∑</mo><mrow><mi>m</mi><mo>=</mo><mn>0</mn></mrow><mrow><mi>M</mi><mo>-</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></munderover></mstyle><msup><mfenced open="|" close="|" separators=""><msub><mi>α</mi><mrow><mn>0</mn><mo>⁢</mo><mi mathvariant="italic">m</mi></mrow></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>α</mi><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>⁢</mo><mi mathvariant="italic">m</mi></mrow></msub><mo>⁢</mo><msup><mi>e</mi><mrow><mi mathvariant="italic">jkπ</mi><mo>/</mo><mn>2</mn></mrow></msup></mfenced><mn>2</mn></msup></mfenced></mfenced></math><img id="ib0005" file="imgb0005.tif" wi="134" he="20" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0045" num="0045">The first term in the outer parentheses corresponds to the case where two channel symbols are transmitted from the same antenna. The subscript n can be either 0 or 1. The second term corresponds to the case where the two channel symbols are transmitted from different antennas.</p><p id="p0046" num="0046">When the number of receive antennas M become large, we intuitively have: <maths id="math0006" num="Equation 3"><math display="block"><munderover><mi>min</mi><mrow><mi>k</mi><mo>=</mo><mn>0</mn></mrow><mn>3</mn></munderover><mfenced separators=""><mn>3</mn><mo>⋅</mo><mstyle displaystyle="true"><munderover><mo>∑</mo><mrow><mi>m</mi><mo>=</mo><mn>0</mn></mrow><mrow><mi>M</mi><mo>-</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></munderover></mstyle><msup><mfenced open="|" close="|" separators=""><msub><mi>α</mi><mrow><mn>0</mn><mo>⁢</mo><mi mathvariant="italic">m</mi></mrow></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>α</mi><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>⁢</mo><mi mathvariant="italic">m</mi></mrow></msub><mo>⁢</mo><msup><mi>e</mi><mrow><mi mathvariant="italic">jkπ</mi><mo>/</mo><mn>2</mn></mrow></msup></mfenced><mn>2</mn></msup></mfenced><mo>≈</mo><mn>3</mn><mo>⋅</mo><mstyle displaystyle="true"><munderover><mo>∑</mo><mrow><mi>m</mi><mo>=</mo><mn>0</mn></mrow><mrow><mi>M</mi><mo>-</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow></munderover></mstyle><msup><mfenced open="|" close="|" separators=""><msub><mi>α</mi><mrow><mn>0</mn><mo>⁢</mo><mi mathvariant="italic">m</mi></mrow></msub><mo>-</mo><msub><mi>α</mi><mrow><mn>1</mn><mo>⁢</mo><mi>m</mi></mrow></msub></mfenced><mn>2</mn></msup></math><img id="ib0006" file="imgb0006.tif" wi="116" he="21" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0047" num="0047">Using Equation 3 and averaging Equation 1 and 2 with respect to complex channel fading, we have the average minimum squared Euclidean distance for the conventional transmitter and the modified transmitter <b>50</b> as follows: <maths id="math0007" num=""><math display="block"><msubsup><mi>d</mi><mrow><mi>C</mi><mo>,</mo><mi mathvariant="italic">avg</mi></mrow><mn>2</mn></msubsup><mo>=</mo><msubsup><mi>d</mi><mn>8</mn><mn>2</mn></msubsup><mo>⁢</mo><mi>M</mi><mo>≈</mo><mn>1.76</mn><mo>⁢</mo><mi>M</mi></math><img id="ib0007" file="imgb0007.tif" wi="46" he="13" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> <maths id="math0008" num=""><math display="block"><msubsup><mi>d</mi><mrow><mi>I</mi><mo>,</mo><mi mathvariant="italic">avg</mi></mrow><mn>2</mn></msubsup><mo>≈</mo><msubsup><mi>d</mi><mi>Q</mi><mn>2</mn></msubsup><mo>⁢</mo><mi>M</mi><mo>=</mo><mn>6</mn><mo>⁢</mo><mi>M</mi></math><img id="ib0008" file="imgb0008.tif" wi="40" he="13" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0048" num="0048">The modified transmitter <b>50</b> clearly provides a larger separation between two distinct channel symbols as compared to the conventional method. The improvement corresponds to about 5 dB gain when the number of receive antennas M is large.<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></p><p id="p0049" num="0049">A graph illustrating simulation results comparing the conventional or prior art method with the modified method in accordance with the invention is provided in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 6</figref> when the number of receive antenna elements M respectively equals 2, 3 and 4. When the number of receive antennas increases, performance of both the conventional and the modified methods improve.</p><p id="p0050" num="0050">Line <b>130</b> corresponds to M = 2 for a conventional transmitter without antenna pattern modulation, and line <b>132</b> also corresponds to M = 2 but with antenna pattern modulation. For the same signal-to-noise ratio (SNR), the BER is lower with the antenna pattern modulation. To achieve the same BER, it requires less SNR with antenna modulation than without. For instance, to achieve 0.1% BER, the conventional approach without antenna modulation would require 14dB SNR, while 12dB is adequate to achieve the same BER for the invention. There is a 2dB advantage for the present invention.</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">Similarly, line <b>134</b> corresponds to M = 3 for a conventional transmitter without antenna pattern modulation, and line <b>136</b> also corresponds to M = 3 but with antenna pattern modulation. Yet again, Line <b>137</b> corresponds to M = 4 for a conventional transmitter without antenna pattern modulation, and line <b>139</b> also corresponds to M = 4 but with antenna pattern modulation.</p><p id="p0052" num="0052">As shown in the figure, the performance of the modified method improves faster than the conventional method. The gap between the modified and conventional methods increases as M increases.</p><p id="p0053" num="0053">Many modifications and other embodiments of the invention will come to the mind of one skilled in<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> the art having the benefit of the teachings presented in the foregoing descriptions and the associated drawings. Therefore, it is understood that the invention is not to be limited to the specific embodiments disclosed, and that modifications and embodiments are intended to be included within the scope of the appended claims.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56986580" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Drahtloskommunikationssystem, das Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>einen Sender (50), der Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>einen Seriell-Parallel-Wandler (56) zum Umwandeln serieller Datenbits zu einem parallelen Bitstrom,</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Signalmapper (60), der als Eingang eine erste Gruppe von Bits (58 (3)), (58 (4)), (58(5)) aus dem parallelen Bitstrom empfängt und die erste Gruppe von Bits (58 (3)), (58 (4)), (58(5)) auf ein Kanalsymbol (62) abbildet,</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Antennenselektor (64), der als Eingang eine zweite Gruppe von Bits (58 (1)), (58 (2)) aus dem parallelen Bitstrom empfängt, wobei die zweite Gruppe von Bits (58 (1)), (58 (2)) von der ersten Gruppe von Bits (58 (3)), (58 (4)), (58(5)) getrennt ist;</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Sendeantennen-Array (81-84), das mit dem Antennenselektor (64) und dem Signalmapper (60) gekoppelt ist, wobei das Sendeantennen-Array (81-84) zum Generieren mehrerer Sendeantennenmuster dient, wobei eines der Sendeantennenmuster zum Senden des Kanalsymbols (62) auf der Grundlage der zweiten Gruppe von Bits (58(1)), (58(2)) aus dem Antennenselektor (64) ausgewählt wird.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Drahtloskommunikationssystem nach Anspruch 1, wobei die mehreren Sendeantennenmuster mehrere Richtungsantennenmuster umfassen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Drahtloskommunikationssystem nach Anspruch 1, wobei die mehreren Sendeantennenmuster mehrere Rundstrahlantennenmuster umfassen.<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Drahtloskommunikationssystem nach Anspruch 1, wobei der Sender (50) periodisch Referenzsignale von jedem Sendeantennenmuster sendet.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Drahtloskommunikationssystem nach Anspruch 4, das des Weiteren Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>ein Empfangsantennen-Array; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Empfänger, der mit dem Empfangsantennen-Array gekoppelt ist und einen Kanalschätzer zum Empfangen der periodisch übertragenen Referenzsignale von jedem Sendeantennenmuster und Schätzen der Hochfrequenz (HF)-Eigenschaften zwischen jedem jeweiligen Sendeantennenmuster und der Empfangsantenne umfasst.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Drahtloskommunikationssystem nach Anspruch 5, das des Weiteren einen Demodulator umfasst, der mit dem Kanalschätzer gekoppelt ist, zum Empfangen des gesendeten Kanalsymbols (62) und zum Bestimmen, welches Kanalsymbol (62) gesendet wurde und welches Sendeantennenmuster zum Senden des Kanalsymbols (62) verwendet wurde.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Drahtloskommunikationssystem nach Anspruch 6, wobei der Demodulator durch Vergleichen des Kanalsymbols (62) mit den geschätzten Kanalsymbolen, die von jedem Sendeantennenmuster gesendet wurden, bestimmt, welches Kanalsymbol (62) gesendet wurde und welches Sendeantennenmuster das Kanalsymbol (62) sendete.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Drahtloskommunikationssystem nach Anspruch 1, das des Weiteren einen Kanalcodierer zum Übermitteln der seriellen Datenbits zu dem Seriell-Parallel-Wandler (56) umfasst.<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Drahtloskommunikationssystem nach Anspruch 1, wobei das Sendeantennen-Array mehrere aktive Antennenelemente zum Bilden eines Phased-Array umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Drahtloskommunikationssystem nach Anspruch 1, wobei das Sende-Array mindestens ein aktives Antennenelement und mehrere passive Antennenelemente zum Bilden einer Switched Beam-Antenne umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Drahtloskommunikationssystem nach Anspruch 4, wobei das Empfangsarray ein oder mehrere Antennenelemente zum Generieren eines oder mehrerer Empfangsantennenmuster umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Verfahren zum Kommunizieren zwischen einem Sender (50) und einem Empfänger (90) in einem Drahtloskommunikationssystem, wobei das Verfahren Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>Umwandeln serieller Datenbits in einen parallelen Bitstrom in dem Sender (50);</claim-text>
<claim-text>Unterteilen des parallelen Bitstroms in eine erste Gruppe von Bits (58 (3)), (58 (4)), (58(5)) und in eine zweite Gruppe von Bits (58(1)), (58(2)) in dem Sender (50), wobei die zweite Gruppe von Bits (58 (1)), (58 (2)) von der ersten Gruppe von Bits (58 (3)), (58 (4)), (58(5)) getrennt ist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Übermitteln der ersten Gruppe von Bits (58 (3)), (58 (4)), (58(5)) an einen Signalmapper (60) zum Abbilden der erste Gruppe von Bits (58 (3)), (58 (4)), (58(5)) auf ein Kanalsymbol (62) in dem Sender (50),</claim-text>
<claim-text>Übermitteln der zweiten Gruppe von Bits (58 (1)), (58 (2)) an einen Sendeantennenselektor (64), wobei der Sendeantennenselektor (64) mit einem Sendeantennen-Array (81-84) zum Generieren mehrerer Sendeantennenmuster gekoppelt ist; und<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>Auswählen eines der Sendeantennenmuster zum Senden des Kanalsymbols (62) auf der Grundlage der zweiten Gruppe von Bits (58(1)), (58(2)) aus dem Sendeantennenselektor (64).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 12, wobei die mehreren Sendeantennenmuster mehrere Richtungsantennenmuster umfassen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 12, wobei die mehreren Sendeantennenmuster mehrere Rundstrahlantennenmuster umfassen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 12, das des Weiteren das periodische Senden von Referenzsignalen von jedem Sendeantennenmuster umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0016" num="0016"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 15, das des Weiteren Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>Empfangen □ an einem Empfangsantennen-Array, das mit dem Empfänger gekoppelt ist □ der periodisch gesendeten Referenzsignale von jedem Sendeantennenmuster; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Schätzen □ in dem Empfänger □ von Hochfrequenz (HF)-Eigenschaften zwischen jedem jeweiligen Sendeantennenmuster und der Empfangsantenne.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0017" num="0017"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 16, das des Weiteren umfasst zu bestimmen, welches Kanalsymbol (62) gesendet wurde und welches Sendeantennenmuster zum Senden des Kanalsymbols (62) verwendet wurde.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0018" num="0018"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 17, wobei das Bestimmen, welches Kanalsymbol (62) gesendet wurde und welches Antennenmuster das Kanalsymbol (62) sendete, das Vergleichen des Kanalsymbols (62) mit den geschätzten Kanalsymbolen, die von jedem Sendeantennenmuster gesendet wurden, umfasst.<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0019" num="0019"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 12, das des Weiteren das Codieren der seriellen Datenbits umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0020" num="0020"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 12, wobei das Sendeantennen-Array mehrere aktive Antennenelemente zum Bilden eines Phased-Array umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0021" num="0021"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 12, wobei das Sende-Array mindestens ein aktives Antennenelement und mehrere passive Antennenelemente zum Bilden einer Switched Beam-Antenne umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0022" num="0022"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 16, wobei das Empfangsarray ein oder mehrere Antennenelemente zum Generieren eines oder mehrerer Empfangsantennenmuster umfasst.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56986581" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A wireless communication system comprising:
<claim-text>a transmitter (50) comprising<br/>
a serial-to-parallel converter (56) for converting serial data bits to a parallel bit stream,<br/>
a signal mapper (60) receiving as input a first group of bits (58(3)), (58(4)), (58(5)) from the parallel bit stream, and mapping the first group of bits (58(3)), (58(4)), (58(5)) to a channel symbol (62),<br/>
an antenna selector (64) receiving as input a second group of bits (58(1)), (58(2)) from the parallel bit stream, with the second group of bits (58(1)), (58(2)) being separate from the first group of bits (58(3)), (58(4)), (58(5)) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a transmit antenna array (81-84) coupled to said antenna selector (64) and to said signal mapper (60), said transmit antenna array (81-84) for generating a plurality of transmit antenna patterns with one of the transmit antenna patterns being selected for transmitting the channel symbol (62) based upon the second group of bits (58(1)), (58(2)) from said antenna selector (64).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>A wireless communication system according to Claim 1 wherein the plurality of transmit antenna patterns comprises a plurality of directional antenna patterns.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>A wireless communication system according to Claim 1 wherein the plurality of transmit antenna patterns comprises a plurality of omni-directional antenna patterns.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>A wireless communication system according to<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> Claim 1 wherein said transmitter (50) periodically transmits reference signals from each transmit antenna pattern.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>A wireless communication system according to Claim 4 further comprising:
<claim-text>a receive antenna array; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a receiver coupled to said receive antenna array and comprising a channel estimator for receiving the periodically transmitted reference signals from each transmit antenna pattern, and estimating radio frequency, RF, characteristics between each respective transmit antenna pattern and said receive antenna</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>A wireless communication system according to Claim 5 further comprising a demodulator coupled to said channel estimator for receiving the transmitted channel symbol (62), for determining which channel symbol (62) was transmitted and which transmit antenna pattern was used to transmit the channel symbol (62).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>A wireless communication system according to Claim 6 wherein said demodulator determines which channel symbol (62) was transmitted and which transmit antenna pattern transmitted the channel symbol (62) by comparing the channel symbol (62) to the estimated channel symbols transmitted from each transmit antenna pattern.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>A wireless communication system according to Claim 1 further comprising a channel encoder for providing the serial data bits to said serial-to-parallel converter (56).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>A wireless communication system according to Claim 1 wherein said transmit antenna array comprises a plurality of active antenna elements for forming a phased<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> array.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>A wireless communication system according to Claim 1 wherein said transmit array comprises at least one active antenna element and a plurality of passive antenna elements for forming a switched beam antenna.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>A wireless communication system according to Claim 4 wherein said receive array comprises one or more antenna elements for generating one or more receive antenna patterns.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>A method for communicating between a transmitter (50) and a receiver (90) in a wireless communication system, the method comprising:
<claim-text>converting serial data bits to a parallel bit stream in the transmitter (50);</claim-text>
<claim-text>dividing the parallel bit stream into a first group of bits (58(3)), (58(4)), (58(5)) and into a second group of bits (58(1)),(58(2)) in the transmitter (50), with the second group of bits (58(1)),(58(2)) being separate from the first group of bits (58(3)), (58(4)), (58(5)) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing the frist group of bits (58(3)), (58(4)), (58(5)) to a signal mapper (60) for mapping the first group of bits (58(3)), (58(4)), (58(5)) to a channel symbol (62) in the transmitter (50),</claim-text>
<claim-text>providing the second group of bits (58(1)), (58(2)) to a transmit antenna selector (64), the transmit antenna selector (64) being coupled to a transmit antenna array (81-84) for generating a plurality of transmit antenna patterns; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>selecting one of the transmit antenna patterns for transmitting the channel symbol (62) based upon the second group of bits (58(1)),(58(2)) from the transmit antenna selector (64).</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>A method according to Claim 12 wherein the plurality of transmit antenna patterns comprises a plurality of directional antenna patterns.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>A method according to Claim 12 wherein the plurality of transmit antenna patterns comprises a plurality of omni-directional antenna patterns.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>A method according to Claim 12 further comprising periodically transmitting reference signals from each transmit antenna pattern.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0016" num="0016"><claim-text>A method according to Claim 15 further comprising:
<claim-text>receiving at a receive antenna array coupled to the receiver the periodically transmitted reference signals from each transmit antenna pattern; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>estimating in the receiver radio frequency, RF, characteristics between each respective transmit antenna pattern and the receive antenna.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0017" num="0017"><claim-text>A method according to Claim 16 further comprising determining which channel symbol (62) was transmitted and which transmit antenna pattern was used to transmit the channel symbol (62).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0018" num="0018"><claim-text>A method according to Claim 17 wherein determining which channel symbol (62) was transmitted and which antenna pattern transmitted the channel symbol (62) comprises comparing the channel symbol (62) to the estimated channel symbols transmitted from each transmit antenna pattern.<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0019" num="0019"><claim-text>A method according to Claim 12 further comprising encoding the serial data bits.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0020" num="0020"><claim-text>A method according to Claim 12 wherein the transmit antenna array comprises a plurality of active antenna elements for forming a phased array.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0021" num="0021"><claim-text>A method according to Claim 12 wherein the transmit array comprises at least one active antenna element and a plurality of passive antenna elements for forming a switched beam antenna.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0022" num="0022"><claim-text>A method according to Claim 16 wherein the receive array comprises one or more antenna elements for generating one or more receive antenna patterns.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56986582" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Système de communication sans fil comprenant:
<claim-text>un émetteur (50) comprenant<br/>
un convertisseur série-parallèle (56) pour convertir des bits de données en série en un flux de bits parallèles,<br/>
un mappeur de signal (60) recevant comme entrée un premier groupe de bits (58(3)), (58(4)), (58(5)) à partir du flux de bits parallèles, et mappant le premier groupe de bits (58(3)), (58(4)), (58(5)) sur un symbole de canal (62),<br/>
un sélecteur d'antenne (64) recevant comme entrée un deuxième groupe de bits (58(1)), (58(2)) à partir du flux de bits parallèles, le deuxième groupe de bits (58(1)), (58(2)) étant distinct du premier groupe de bits (58(3)), (58(4)), (58(5));</claim-text>
<claim-text>un réseau d'antennes d'émission (81-84) couplé au dit sélecteur d'antenne (64) et au dit mappeur de signal (60), ledit réseau d'antennes d'émission (81-84) étant destiné à générer une pluralité de motifs d'antennes d'émission, l'un des motifs d'antennes d'émission étant sélectionné pour émettre le symbole de canal (62) sur la base du deuxième groupe de bits (58(1)), (58(2)) à partir dudit sélecteur d'antenne (64).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Système de communication sans fil selon la revendication 1, dans lequel la pluralité de motifs d'antennes d'émission comprend une pluralité de motifs d'antennes directionnelles.<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Système de communication sans fil selon la revendication 1, dans lequel la pluralité de motifs d'antennes d'émission comprend une pluralité de motifs d'antennes omnidirectionnelles.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Système de communication sans fil selon la revendication 1, dans lequel ledit émetteur (50) émet périodiquement des signaux de référence à partir de chaque motif d'antennes d'émission.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Système de communication sans fil selon la revendication 4, comprenant en outre:
<claim-text>un réseau d'antennes de réception; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un récepteur couplé au dit réseau d'antennes de réception et comprenant un estimateur de canal pour la réception des signaux de référence émis périodiquement à partir de chaque motif d'antennes d'émission, et l'estimation de caractéristiques de radiofréquences, RF, entre chaque motif d'antennes d'émission respectif et ladite antenne de réception.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Système de communication sans fil selon la revendication 5, comprenant en outre un démodulateur couplé au dit estimateur de canal pour la réception du symbole de canal émis (62), pour déterminer quel symbole de canal (62) a été émis et quel motif d'antennes d'émission a été utilisé pour émettre le symbole de canal (62).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Système de communication sans fil selon la revendication 6, dans lequel ledit démodulateur détermine quel symbole de canal (62) a été émis et quel motif d'antennes d'émission a émis le symbole de canal (62) en comparant le symbole de canal (62) aux symboles de canal estimés émis à partir de chaque motif d'antennes d'émission.<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Système de communication sans fil selon la revendication 1, comprenant en outre un codeur de canal pour fournir les bits de données en série au dit convertisseur série-parallèle (56).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Système de communication sans fil selon la revendication 1, dans lequel ledit réseau d'antennes d'émission comprend une pluralité d'éléments d'antennes actifs pour former un réseau en phase.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Système de communication sans fil selon la revendication 1, dans lequel ledit réseau d'antennes d'émission comprend au moins un élément d'antenne actif et une pluralité d'éléments d'antennes passifs pour former une antenne de faisceau commuté.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Système de communication sans fil selon la revendication 4, dans lequel ledit réseau d'antennes de réception comprend un ou plusieurs éléments d'antennes pour générer un ou plusieurs motifs d'antennes de réception.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Procédé de communication entre un émetteur (50) et un récepteur (90) dans un système de communication sans fil, le procédé comprenant:
<claim-text>la conversion de bits de données en série en un flux de bits parallèles dans l'émetteur (50);</claim-text>
<claim-text>la division du flux de bits parallèles en un premier groupe de bits (58(3)), (58(4)), (58(5)) et en un deuxième groupe de bits (58(1)), (58(2)) dans l'émetteur (50), le deuxième groupe de bits (58(1)), (58(2)) étant distinct du premier groupe de bits (58(3)), (58(4)), (58(5));</claim-text>
<claim-text>la fourniture du premier groupe de bits (58(3)), (58(4)), (58(5)) à un mappeur de signal (60) pour mapper le premier groupe de bits (58(3)), (58(4)), (58(5)) sur un symbole de canal (62) dans l'émetteur (50);<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>la fourniture du deuxième groupe de bits (58(1)), (58(2)) à un sélecteur d'antennes d'émission (64), le sélecteur d'antennes d'émission (64) étant couplé à un réseau d'antennes d'émission (81-84) pour générer une pluralité de motifs d'antennes d'émission; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>la sélection de l'un des motifs d'antennes d'émission pour émettre le symbole de canal (62) sur la base du deuxième groupe de bits (58(1)), (58(2)) à partir dudit sélecteur d'antenne d'émission (64).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 12, dans lequel la pluralité de motifs d'antennes d'émission comprend une pluralité de motifs d'antennes directionnelles.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 12, dans lequel la pluralité de motifs d'antennes d'émission comprend une pluralité de motifs d'antennes omnidirectionnelles.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 12, comprenant en outre l'émission périodique de signaux de référence à partir de chaque motif d'antennes d'émission.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0016" num="0016"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 15, comprenant en outre:
<claim-text>la réception, à un réseau d'antennes de réception couplé au récepteur, des signaux de référence émis périodiquement à partir de chaque motif d'antennes d'émission; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'estimation, dans le récepteur, de caractéristiques de radiofréquences, RF, entre chaque motif d'antennes d'émission respectif et l'antenne de réception.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0017" num="0017"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 16, comprenant en outre la détermination du symbole de canal (62) qui a été émis et du motif<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --> d'antennes d'émission qui a été utilisé pour émettre le symbole de canal (62).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0018" num="0018"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 17, dans lequel la détermination du symbole de canal (62) qui a été émis et du motif d'antennes d'émission qui a émis le symbole de canal (62) comprend la comparaison du symbole de canal (62) aux symboles de canal estimés émis à partir de chaque motif d'antennes d'émission.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0019" num="0019"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 12, comprenant en outre le codage des bits de données en série.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0020" num="0020"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 12, dans lequel ledit réseau d'antennes d'émission comprend une pluralité d'éléments d'antennes actifs pour former un réseau en phase.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0021" num="0021"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 12, dans lequel ledit réseau d'antennes d'émission comprend au moins un élément d'antenne actif et une pluralité d'éléments d'antennes passifs pour former une antenne de faisceau commuté.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0022" num="0022"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 16, dans lequel ledit réseau d'antennes de réception comprend un ou plusieurs éléments d'antennes pour générer un ou plusieurs motifs d'antennes de réception.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16672491" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1,2"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="165" he="215" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --><figure id="f0002" num="3,4,5a,5b"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="127" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --><figure id="f0003" num="6"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="165" he="139" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
