<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-1978142-B1" country="EP" doc-number="1978142" kind="B1" date="20140101" family-id="39495980" file-reference-id="311125" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146553512" ucid="EP-1978142-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>1978142</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-08153277-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154827435" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>08153277</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20080326</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140451832" ucid="KR-20070034424-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>KR</country><doc-number>20070034424</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20070406</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130711</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988125389" load-source="ipcr">D06F  35/00        20060101AFI20080627BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988106571" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">D06F  35/003       20130101 FI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132193020" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Waschmaschine und Verfahren hierfür</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132193021" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Washing machine and method</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132193022" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Appareil et procédé de lavage</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918163237" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>SAMSUNG ELECTRONICS CO LTD</last-name><address><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918148024" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>SAMSUNG ELECTRONICS CO., LTD.</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918143044" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>LIM JUNG SOO</last-name><address><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918154868" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>LIM, JUNG SOO</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918997060" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>LIM, JUNG SOO</last-name><address><street>No.103-1202, Doosan-weve Apt., Banweol-dong,</street><city>Hwaseong-si Gyeonggi-do</city><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918158190" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>CHANG PHIL SOO</last-name><address><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918144474" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>CHANG, PHIL SOO</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918997066" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>CHANG, PHIL SOO</last-name><address><street>No.127-704, Park-town-lotte Apt., Sunae-dong,</street><city>Bundang-gu, Seongnam-si Gyeonggi-do</city><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918167290" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>YANG HYE SOON</last-name><address><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918139421" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>YANG, HYE SOON</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918997065" load-source="patent-office" sequence="3" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>YANG, HYE SOON</last-name><address><street>No.703-202, Samsung-ramian-7th Apt.,</street><city>Pungdukcheon-dong, Yongin-si Gyeonggi-do</city><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918142351" load-source="docdb" sequence="4" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>KANG YOUNG HOON</last-name><address><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918149799" load-source="docdb" sequence="4" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>KANG, YOUNG HOON</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918997063" load-source="patent-office" sequence="4" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>KANG, YOUNG HOON</last-name><address><street>No.248-401, Hwanggolmaeul-2nd Apt.,</street><city>Yeongtong-dong, Yeongtong-gu, Suwon-si Gyeonggi-do</city><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918148668" load-source="docdb" sequence="5" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>YANG BYOUNG YULL</last-name><address><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918171846" load-source="docdb" sequence="5" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>YANG, BYOUNG YULL</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918997064" load-source="patent-office" sequence="5" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>YANG, BYOUNG YULL</last-name><address><street>No.438-2203, Solbitmaeul-sindo-braenew Apt.</street><city>Bansong-dong, Hwaseong-si Gyeonggi-do</city><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918161930" load-source="docdb" sequence="6" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>KIM TAI EUN</last-name><address><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918139815" load-source="docdb" sequence="6" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>KIM, TAI EUN</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918997061" load-source="patent-office" sequence="6" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>KIM, TAI EUN</last-name><address><street>No.506-602, Greenvill-5th Apt, Maetan-3-dong,</street><city>Paldal-gu, Suwon-si Gyeonggi-do</city><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918164522" load-source="docdb" sequence="7" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>JIN HEE WON</last-name><address><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918173624" load-source="docdb" sequence="7" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>JIN, HEE WON</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918997067" load-source="patent-office" sequence="7" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>JIN, HEE WON</last-name><address><street>No.106-2203, Lotte Apt., 1263, Guro-5-dong,</street><city>Guro-gu Seoul</city><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918173036" load-source="docdb" sequence="8" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>KIM HYE RYUNG</last-name><address><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918152472" load-source="docdb" sequence="8" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>KIM, HYE RYUNG</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918997062" load-source="patent-office" sequence="8" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>KIM, HYE RYUNG</last-name><address><street>No.403-2002, Hyoseong Apt., Sinbong-dong, Suji-gu</street><city>Yongin-si Gyeonggi-do</city><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918997069" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Samsung Electronics Co., Ltd.</last-name><iid>101328413</iid><address><street>129, Samsung-ro Yeongtong-gu</street><city>SUWON-SI, GYEONGGI-DO, 443-742</city><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918997068" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Grünecker, Kinkeldey, Stockmair &amp; Schwanhäusser Anwaltssozietät</last-name><iid>100060488</iid><address><street>Leopoldstrasse 4</street><city>80802 München</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548828978" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548883964" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548828979" load-source="docdb">GB</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63957244" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001">BACKGROUND</heading><heading id="h0002">1. Field</heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to a washing machine and a method of washing. More particularly, the present invention relates to a washing machine comprising a sterilizer that sterilizes washing water and a circulator that circulates the washing water in the sterilizer.</p><heading id="h0003">2. Description of the Related Art</heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">In general, a washing machine washes the laundry in a washing tub by stirring the laundry together with washing water mixed with detergent.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">Such a washing machine comprises a body forming an external appearance, a water reservoir installed in the body and containing washing water, a detergent supply apparatus that mixes detergent with water supplied from an exterior and supplies the water to the water reservoir.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">Recently, an Ag solution supply apparatus, which supplies Ag solution by dissolving Ag ions exhibiting antibiotic and sterilization functions in washing water, has been added to the washing machine in order to wash the laundry and sterilize bacteria existing in the washing water and the laundry.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">The Ag solution supply apparatus comprises one pair ofAg electrodes to which voltage is applied, and supplies Ag ions, which are generated by an Ag plate during electrolysis when the washing water passes through the Ag electrodes, to a water reservoir.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">The Ag solution supply apparatus provided in the washing machine is installed on a water supply path, which supplies the washing water to the water reservoir, together with a detergent dissolver, and supplies the Ag ions to the washing water supplied to the water reservoir. However, the Ag solution supply apparatus cannot supply the Ag ions any more after the water supply is terminated, so antibiotic and sterilization functions cannot be continuously exhibited during washing and rinsing processes.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p><p id="p0007" num="0007">Further, the density of the Ag ions, which are generated by the Ag solution supply apparatus and provided to the washing water, is gradually reduced through reaction with other ions existing in the washing water, so the sterilization effect may be reduced. If many Ag ions are supplied to the washing water in consideration of the fact, consumption amount of Ag in the Ag plate may be increased, resulting in reduction of the life span of the Ag plate.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US20050252255A1"><text>US 2005/0252255A1</text></patcit> discloses a method and a system for washing wherein it is in particular referred to a laundry washing machine. The corresponding machine comprises a drum which is rotatably mounted within an outer tub. A drive unit is used for rotating the drum. Together with the washing machine, a filtration device is used. With respect to this device it is said that this is provided with wash liquor and a permeate outlet port wherein the last one is used to circulate the wash liquor. A disinfection zone is disposed in a conduit on the permeate outlet side of the filtration device and comprises an electrolysis chamber. A number of parallel plate-shaped electrodes are disposed within this chamber and it is further referred to a silver anode and two stainless cathodes on either side of the silver anode. The wash liquor is pumped through the filtration device and through the disinfection zone with its electrolysis chamber.</p><heading id="h0004">SUMMARY</heading><p id="p0009" num="0009">It is an object of the present invention to provide a washing machine capable of continuously exhibiting antibiotic and sterilization function during washing and rinsing processes, wherein simultaneously the sterilizer is prevented from being contaminated due to water remaining after the washing or rinsing processes.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">This object is solved by the features of claim 1.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">Advantageous embodiments are disclosed by the sub-claims.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">The sterilizer may comprise a first electrode including Ag and a second electrode including a metal having an ionization tendency lower than the ionization tendency of Ag.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">The second electrode may comprise Ti.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">The second electrode may also comprise Pt or Ir coated on a surface thereof.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">The washing machine may further comprise a power supply that supplies electric current to the first and second electrodes, and a controller that switches polarity of the electric current applied to the first and second electrodes.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">The controller can operate in a first mode, in which the first electrode becomes an anode and the second electrode becomes a cathode, or a second mode in which the second electrode becomes an anode and the first electrode becomes a cathode.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p><p id="p0017" num="0017">The circulation pipe may be provided along a circumference of the water reservoir.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">The water reservoir comprises an inlet to introduce the washing water to the circulation path, and an outlet to discharge the washing water having passed the circulation path to the water reservoir.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">The outlet may be provided at an upper portion of the water reservoir.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">The outlet may be provided with an injection nozzle that injects the washing water such that the washing water is uniformly spread in the water reservoir.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">The washing machine may further comprise a salt supply unit that supplies salt to the washing water.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">The salt supply unit may be provided in a detergent supply apparatus that supplies detergent to the water reservoir.</p><heading id="h0005">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading><p id="p0023" num="0023">These and/or other aspects and advantages of the invention will become apparent and more readily appreciated from the following description of the embodiments, taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings of which:
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic view illustrating an internal structure of a washing machine including a sterilizer used in embodiments of the present invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> is an exploded perspective view showing the construction of the sterilizer in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>; and</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic view showing an internal structure of the washing machine in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0006">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENTS</heading><p id="p0024" num="0024">Reference will now be made in detail to the embodiments of the present invention, examples of which are illustrated in the accompanying drawings, wherein like reference numerals refer to the<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> like elements throughout. The embodiments are described below to explain the present invention by referring to the figures.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025"><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic view showing an internal structure of a washing machine according to an embodiment of the present invention.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">The washing machine comprises a body 1 forming an external appearance, a water reservoir 2 installed in the body 1, and a drum 3 rotatably installed in the water reservoir 2.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">A door 4 is installed in the front of the body 1 to open and close the opened front of the body 1. Water supply valves 5, which are connected to an external water supply source, and a detergent supply apparatus 6 are installed at the upper portion of the water reservoir 2, in which the detergent supply apparatus 6 dissolves detergent in water supplied through the water supply valves 5 and supplies the water to the water reservoir 2.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">The detergent supply apparatus 6 comprises a housing 6a and a detergent box 6b detachably provided in the housing 6a.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">A circulation pipe 7 that forms a circulation path is installed at the outer side of the water reservoir 2 such that the washing water can be circulated in the water reservoir 2. A circulation pump 8 is installed on the circulation path formed by the circulation pipe 7.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">A three-way valve 9 is installed at the lower portion of the water reservoir 2 in order to switch a path between a drain pipe 12, which drains the washing water from the water reservoir 2, and the circulation pipe 7.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">The circulation pipe 7 interconnects the upper and lower portions of the water reservoir 2 such that the washing water in the lower portion of the water reservoir 2 can be moved to the upper portion of the water reservoir 2. At this time, the circulation pump 8 pumps the washing water, which is supplied to the circulation pump 8 from the lower portion of the water reservoir 2 along the circulation pipe 7, such that the washing water can be discharged from the upper portion of the water reservoir 2.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">A sterilizer 100 is installed above the circulation pump 8 to exhibit sterilization function by generating Ag ions through an electrolysis operation or activating the generated Ag ions.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033"><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> is an exploded perspective view showing the construction of the sterilizer in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></p><p id="p0034" num="0034">The sterilizer 100 comprises a storage container 110 having an inlet 110a, which has an opened upper surface and introduces washing water inside the sterilizer 100, and an outlet 1110b that discharges the washing water.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">A circulation pipe is connected between the inlet 110a and the outlet 110b, a cover 120 is installed at the opened upper surface of the storage container 110, and first and second electrodes 130 and 140 are installed at the cover 120 in order to form electrodes for electrolysis.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">The first and second electrodes 130 and 140 are installed in the path in the storage container 110 through slots 120a and 120b formed in the cover 120, and are immersed when the washing water passes through the storage container 110.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">Further, the first and second electrodes 130 and 140 have a plate shape as shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>, face each other, and are arranged in parallel with the flowing direction of the washing water in the storage container 110.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">As the first and second electrodes 130 and 140 have a plate shape, the contact area with the washing water can be increased. However, in other embodiments, the electrodes may also have a bar shape.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">The first and second electrodes 130 and 140 may comprise Ag and Ti, respectively. In addition to Ti, the second electrode 140 may also comprise other metals featuring an ionization tendency lower than that ofAg.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">When the second electrode 140 comprises Ti, metals (e.g. Pt and lr) having an ionization tendency lower than that of Ag may be coated on the surface of the second electrode 140 through plating in order to improve the corrosion-resistance.</p><p id="p0041" num="0041"><figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic view showing an internal structure of the washing machine in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">The water reservoir 2 is installed in the body 1 of the washing machine, and the drum 3 is installed in the water reservoir 2.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">The water supply valves 5 that supply water to the water reservoir 2 are connected to the detergent supply apparatus 6 through a water supply pipe 11 at the upper portion of the water reservoir 2, and an outlet 3b and an inlet 3a are formed at the upper and lower portions of the water reservoir 2, respectively.<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></p><p id="p0044" num="0044">The circulation pipe 7 that forms a circulation path 20 by interconnecting the outlet 3b and the inlet 3a is connected to the outer side of the water reservoir 2, and the circulation pump 8 and the sterilizer 100 are connected to the circulation path 20.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045">The inlet 3a is used as a waterway to drain the washing water in the water reservoir 2, and the three-way valve 9 is installed at the lower portion of the inlet 3a to switch the path such that the washing water introduced through the inlet 3a can be sent to the drain pipe 12 or the circulation pipe 7.</p><p id="p0046" num="0046">An injection nozzle 21 is installed at the outlet 3b such that the drained washing water can be spread over the wide range. The outlet 3b and the injection nozzle 21 are installed at the upper portion of the water reservoir 2, so that the washing water passing through the sterilizer 100 can be uniformly spread in the drum 3 and the water reservoir 2 when the washing water is discharged into the water reservoir 2.</p><p id="p0047" num="0047">As the washing or rinsing process starts, washing water is filled in the water reservoir 2 up to a predetermined water level, and the sterilizer 100 is positioned higher than the water level of the washing water. Accordingly, the electrodes 130 and 140 in the sterilizer 100 are not immersed in the washing water in a state when the circulation pump 8 is not operating, so that the sterilizer 100 can be prevented from being contaminated due to water remaining after the washing or rinsing process. In addition, even if the locking state of the door is released due to the abnormal operation of the washing machine, or other problems occur, electric shock can be prevented.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048">The two electrodes 130 and 140 of the sterilizer 100 are connected to a power supply 30 such that power can be supplied to the electrodes 130 and 140. The power supply 30 converts electric current such that DC power can be supplied to the electrodes 130 and 140.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">The polarity of the DC power supplied to the electrodes 130 and 140 can be changed by a controller 40 that controls the power supply 30.</p><p id="p0050" num="0050">The sterilizer 100 operates in two modes. In the first mode, the first electrode 130 serves as an anode because positive (+) polarity of the DC power is connected to the first electrode 130 by the controller 40 and the second electrode 140 serves as a cathode because negative (-) polarity of the DC power is connected to the second electrode 140. In the second mode, the polarity of the electrode is inversed as compared to the first mode, so the first electrode 130 serves as the cathode and the second electrode 140 serves as the anode.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p><p id="p0051" num="0051">In detail, in the first mode, the first electrode 130 comprising Ag serves as the anode to emit Ag ions into the washing water. That is, the first electrode 130 and the second electrode 140 become the anode and the cathode, respectively, so electric current flows in the two electrodes. In addition, Ag is electrolyzed in the first electrode 130, so Ag ions in Ag<sup>+</sup> state are generated and supplied to the circulated washing water.</p><p id="p0052" num="0052">In the second mode, the polarities of the first and second electrodes 130 and 140 are inversed as compared with the first mode, so the second electrode 140 comprising Ti becomes the anode, and the first electrode 130 (Ag electrode) becomes the cathode.</p><p id="p0053" num="0053">In such a case, the Ag ions are not emitted through the first electrode 130 and electrolysis of the electrode is not performed in the second electrode 140. Accordingly, ions (e.g. Ti<sup>+</sup>) are not generated in the second electrode 140, and electric current flows between the first electrode 130 and the second electrode 140 due to an electrolyte contained in the washing water or ions generated by the detergent.</p><p id="p0054" num="0054">In such a second mode, ions for sterilization are not directly generated, but ions contained in the washing water are activated. That is, compound in the neutral state contained in the washing water can be ionized through the electrolysis operation.</p><p id="p0055" num="0055">In particular, when Ag ions are emitted into the washing water in the first mode, if the Ag ions are reduced in the sterilization process and become electrically neutral, the sterilization effect is discontinued. Thus, the Ag ions in the neutral state are restored into Ag ions through the electrolysis operation.</p><p id="p0056" num="0056">In the second mode, the bacteria contained in the washing water are sterilized by the electric current flowing between the first electrode 130 and the second electrode 140. That is, the cell membrane of the bacteria contained in the washing water is partially destroyed by the electric current or pores may be formed in the cell membrane while the washing water is passing between the first electrode 130 and the second electrode 140.</p><p id="p0057" num="0057">The cell membrane of the bacteria subject to the electric current is destroyed and disappears. Even if the bacteria do not disappear, the Ag ions can easily penetrate into the bacteria. If the Ag ions have been emitted into the washing water in the first mode, the bacteria disappear due to penetration of the Ag ions.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></p><p id="p0058" num="0058">The effect on the bacteria due to the electric current flowing between the first electrode 130 and the second electrode 140 is increased in proportion to the density of the electric current flowing between the two electrodes 130 and 140, that is, the electric current per unit area.</p><p id="p0059" num="0059">The sterilization function in the first and second modes as described above can be variously applied throughout the entire washing process, and embodiments regarding the sterilization function will be described.</p><p id="p0060" num="0060">In one embodiment, the sterilizer 100 operates in the first mode in order to emit Ag ions, and the first mode is switched to the second mode after a predetermined time period passes.</p><p id="p0061" num="0061">This can be commonly applied to the washing and rinsing processes. In <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3</figref>, in a state where the washing water is supplied to the water reservoir 2 through the water supply valves 5 and the detergent supply apparatus 6, as the three-way valve 9 connects the inlet 3a to the circulation path 20 to form the circulation path 20, and the circulation pump 8 operates, the washing water is circulated through the circulation path 20 and the sterilizer 100 connected to the circulation path 20.</p><p id="p0062" num="0062">As the sterilizer 100 operates in the first mode, the Ag ions are emitted into the washing water through the first electrode 130, and the washing water containing the Ag ions are injected into the water reservoir 2 and the drum 3 through the injection nozzle 21, thereby exhibiting the antibiotic and sterilization functions.</p><p id="p0063" num="0063">After a predetermined time period passes, the sterilizer 100 operates in the second mode. That is, the cell membrane of the bacteria is subject to the electric current flowing between the two electrodes 130 and 140, so the bacteria is destroyed or disappears due to the Ag ions. Further, Ag, which has been emitted in the first mode and reduced through the sterilization process of the bacteria or other methods, is activated into Ag ions in the second mode.</p><p id="p0064" num="0064">The consumed Ag ions are restored through the procedure as described above, so that the operation time of the first mode can be shortened, and thus the consumption amount of Ag can be reduced in the first electrode.</p><p id="p0065" num="0065">In another embodiment, the sterilizer 100 operates in sequence of the second mode and the first mode. The reason of primarily operating the sterilizer 100 in the second mode is that the Ag ions emitted during the washing process may be affected by the high-density detergent dissolved in the washing water and other ions, and the sterilization function of the Ag ions may<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> be interrupted. Thus, the sterilizer 100 operates in the second mode during the washing process such that the sterilization function due to the electric current between the first electrode 130 and the second electrode 140 can be exhibited, and then the sterilizer 100 operates in the first mode during the rinsing process, in which the density of the detergent is reduced, such that the Ag ions can be supplied to the washing water.</p><p id="p0066" num="0066">In further another embodiment, the washing machine can operate in a washing mode, in which the water reservoir and the drum are washed, separately from the washing and rinsing processes.</p><p id="p0067" num="0067">The washing mode corresponds to a dedicated washing process of removing biofilms formed in the water reservoir and the drum due to the propagation of bacteria. That is, in a state where washing water is supplied to the water reservoir without the laundry, the circulation pump 8 operates to circulate the washing water and the sterilizer 100 operates in the second mode or the first mode.</p><p id="p0068" num="0068">In order to improve the washing effect by the circulated washing water, a salt supply unit (not shown) can be provided to supply salt to the supplied water. The salt supply unit can be additionally provided to the washing machine, or can also be provided to the detergent box 6b of the detergent supply apparatus 6 (see <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>).</p><p id="p0069" num="0069">As the salt is dissolved in the washing water, HOCI is generated through an electrolysis process. Since reaction and generation conditions for generation of the HOCI are well known to the skilled in the art, details thereof will be omitted here.</p><p id="p0070" num="0070">The HOCI generated in the sterilizer exhibits the sterilization function derived from the strong oxidation power, so that biofilms can be effectively prevented from being generated or can be removed by cleaning the water reservoir 2 and the drum 3 using the HOCl.</p><p id="p0071" num="0071">According to the washing machine of the present invention as described above, the sterilization effect can be maximized by using a small quantity of Ag and can be continued throughout the entire washing process, so that not only harmful microorganisms contained in the laundry but also microorganisms remaining or growing in the washing machine can be sterilized using the circulator, and thus the laundry can be prevented from being secondarily contaminated.</p><p id="p0072" num="0072">Although a few embodiments of the present invention have been shown and described, it would be appreciated by those skilled in the art that changes may be made in these embodiments<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> without departing from the scope of which is defined in the claims.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56979221" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Waschmaschine, die umfasst:
<claim-text>einen Wasserbehälter, der Waschwasser aufnimmt;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Sterilisiereinrichtung (100), die das Waschwasser über einen Elektrolyseprozesse sterilisiert; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Umwälzeinrichtung (7, 8), die das Waschwasser in der Sterilisiereinrichtung (100) umwälzt, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>die Sterilisiereinrichtung (100) höher positioniert ist als der Wasserpegel des Waschwassers, und</claim-text>
<claim-text>die Umwälzeinrichtung (7, 8) ein Umwälzrohr (7), das einen Umwälzweg bildet, so dass das Waschwasser in dem Wasserbehälter umgewälzt wird, und eine Umwälzpumpe (8) umfasst, die das Waschwasser auf dem Umwälzweg pumpt.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Waschmaschine nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Sterilisiereinrichtung (100) eine erste Elektrode (130), die Ag enthält, und eine zweite Elektrode (140) umfasst, die ein Metall mit einer lonisierungstendenz enthält, die geringer ist als die lonisierungstendenz von Ag.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Waschmaschine nach Anspruch 2, wobei die zweite Elektrode (140) Ti umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Waschmaschine nach Anspruch 2, wobei die zweite Elektrode (140) Pt oder Ir umfasst, mit dem eine Oberfläche derselben beschichtet ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Waschmaschine nach Anspruch 2, die des Weiteren eine Stromquelle (30), die der ersten und der zweiten Elektrode (130, 140) Strom zuführt, sowie eine Steuereinrichtung (40) umfasst, die eine Polarität des an die erste und die zweite Elektrode (130, 140) angelegten Stroms umschaltet.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Waschmaschine nach Anspruch 5, wobei die Steuereinrichtung (40) in einem ersten Modus, in dem die erste Elektrode (130) eine Anode wird und die zweite Elektrode (140) eine Kathode wird, oder in einem zweiten Modus arbeitet, in dem die zweite Elektrode (140) eine Anode wird und die erste Elektrode (130) eine Kathode wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Waschmaschine nach Anspruch 1, wobei das Umwälzrohr (7) an einem Umfang des Wasserbehälters vorhanden ist.<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Waschmaschine nach Anspruch 1, wobei der Wasserbehälter einen Einlass (3a) zum Einleiten des Waschwassers in den Umwälzweg sowie einen Auslass (3b) zum Ableiten des Waschwassers, das den Umwälzweg passiert hat, in den Wasserbehälter umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Waschmaschine nach Anspruch 8, wobei der Auslass (3b) an einem oberen Abschnitt des Wasserbehälters vorhanden ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Waschmaschine nach Anspruch 8, wobei der Auslass (3b) mit einer Einspritzdüse (21) versehen ist, die das Waschwasser so einspritzt, dass das Waschwasser gleichmäßig in dem Wasserbehälter verteilt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Waschmaschine nach Anspruch 1, die des Weiteren eine Salz-Zuführeinheit umfasst, die dem Waschwasser Salz zuführt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Waschmaschine nach Anspruch 11, wobei die Salz-Zuführeinheit in einer Waschmittel-Zuführvorrichtung (6) vorhanden ist, die dem Wasserbehälter Waschmittel zuführt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Waschmaschine nach Anspruch 1, wobei die erste und die zweite Elektrode (130, 140) vor Verunreinigung geschützt werden, wenn die Umwälzeinrichtung nicht umwälzt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Waschverfahren in einer Waschmaschine, das umfasst:
<claim-text>Zuführen von Waschwasser zu einem Behälter, in dem sich zu waschende Gegenstände befinden;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Sterilisieren des Waschwassers über einen Elektrolyseprozess; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Umwälzen des Waschwassers, während es sterilisiert wird,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei die erste und die zweite Elektrode (130, 140), die in der Sterilisiereinrichtung vorhanden sind, nicht in dem Waschwasser eingetaucht sind, wenn das Waschwasser nicht umgewälzt wird.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 14, wobei das Sterilisieren umfasst:
<claim-text>Zuführen von Strom zu einer ersten Elektrode (130), die Ag enthält, und einer zweiten Elektrode (140), die ein Metall mit einer lonisierungstendenz enthält, die geringer ist als die lonisierungstendenz von Ag; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Umschalten der Polarität des an die erste und die zweite Elektrode (130, 140) angelegten Stroms auf Basis eines gewünschten Betriebsmodus der Sterilisierung.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56979222" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A washing machine comprising:
<claim-text>a water reservoir to contain washing water;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a sterilizer (100) sterilizing the washing water through an electrolysis process; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a circulator (7,8) circulating the washing water in the sterilizer (100), <b>characterized in that</b> the sterilizer (100) is positioned higher than the water level of the washing water, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the circulator (7,8) comprises a circulation pipe (7), which forms a circulation path such that the washing water is circulated in the water reservoir, and a circulation pump (8) that pumps the washing water in the circulation path.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The washing machine of claim 1, wherein the sterilizer (100) comprises a first electrode (130) including Ag and a second electrode (140) including a metal having an ionization tendency lower than the ionization tendency of Ag.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The washing machine of claim 2, wherein the second electrode (140) comprises Ti.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The washing machine of claim 2, wherein the second electrode (140) comprises Pt or Ir coated on a surface thereof.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The washing machine of claim 2, further comprising a power supply (30) that supplies electric current to the first and second electrodes (130, 140), and a controller (40) that switches polarity of the electric current applied to the first and second electrodes (130, 140).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The washing machine of claim 5, wherein the controller (40) operates in a first mode, in which the first electrode (130) becomes an anode and the second electrode (140) becomes a cathode, or a second mode in which the second electrode (140) becomes an anode and the first electrode (130) becomes a cathode.<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The washing machine of claim 1, wherein the circulation pipe (7) is provided along a circumference of the water reservoir.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The washing machine of claim 1, wherein the water reservoir comprises an inlet (3a) to introduce the washing water to the circulation path, and an outlet (3b) to discharge the washing water having passed the circulation path to the water reservoir.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The washing machine of claim 8, wherein the outlet (3b) is provided at an upper portion of the water reservoir.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The washing machine of claim 8, wherein the outlet (3b) is provided with an injection nozzle (21) that injects the washing water such that the washing water is uniformly spread in the water reservoir.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>The washing machine of claim 1, further comprising a salt supply unit that supplies salt to the washing water.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>The washing machine of claim 11, wherein the salt supply unit is provided in a detergent supply apparatus (6) that supplies detergent to the water reservoir.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>The washing machine of claim 1 wherein the first and second electrodes (130,140) are protected from contamination when the circulator is not circulating.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>A washing method in a washing machine comprising:
<claim-text>supplying containing washing water to a reservoir where articles for washing are located;</claim-text>
<claim-text>sterilizing the washing water through an electrolysis process; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>circulating the washing water while it is being sterilized,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first and second electrodes (130,140) provided in the sterilizer are not immersed in the washing water when the washing water is not circulating.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>The method of claim 14, wherein the sterilizing comprises:
<claim-text>supplying electric current to a first electrode (130) including Ag and a second electrode (140) including a metal having an ionization tendency lower than the ionization tendency of Ag; and<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>switching the polarity of the electric current applied to the first and second electrodes (130,140) based on a desired mode of operation of the sterilizing;</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56979223" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>machine à laver comprenant :
<claim-text>un réservoir d'eau pour contenir l'eau de lavage,</claim-text>
<claim-text>un stérilisateur (100) qui stérilise l'eau de lavage par l'intermédiaire d'un procédé d'électrolyse, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un dispositif de circulation (7, 8) faisant circuler l'eau de lavage dans le stérilisateur (100), <b>caractérisé en ce que</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>le stérilisateur (100) est positionné plus haut que le niveau d'eau de l'eau de lavage, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>le dispositif de circulation (7, 8) comprend une tuyauterie de circulation (7) qui forme une ligne de circulation telle que l'ont fait circuler l'eau de lavage dans le réservoir d'eau, ainsi qu'une pompe de circulation (8) qui pompe l'eau de lavage dans la tuyauterie de circulation.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Machine à laver selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle le stérilisateur (100) comprend une première électrode (130) incluant de l'argent (Ag) et une seconde électrode (140) incluant un métal présentant une tendance à l'ionisation inférieure à la tendance à l'ionisation de l'Ag.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Machine à laver selon la revendication 2, dans laquelle la seconde électrode (140) comprend du Ti.<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Machine à laver selon la revendication 2, dans laquelle la seconde électrode comprend du Pt ou de l'Ir déposé sur la surface de celle-ci.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Machine à laver selon la revendication 2, comprenant en outre une alimentation (30) qui fournit du courant électrique aux première et seconde électrodes (130, 140), et un contrôleur (40) qui bascule la polarité du courant électrique appliqué aux première et seconde électrodes.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Machine à laver selon la revendication 5, dans laquelle le contrôleur (40) fonctionne selon un premier mode dans lequel la première électrode (130) devient une anode et la seconde électrode (140) devient une cathode, ou un second mode selon lequel la seconde électrode (140) devient une anode et la première électrode (130) devient une cathode.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Machine à laver selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle la tuyauterie de circulation (7) est prévue le long de la circonférence du réservoir d'eau.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Machine à laver selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle le réservoir d'eau comprend un orifice d'entrée (3a) pour introduire l'eau de lavage dans le dispositif de circulation, et un orifice de sortie (3b) pour évacuer l'eau de lavage ayant traversé le dispositif de circulation vers le réservoir d'eau.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Machine à laver selon la revendication 8, dans laquelle l'orifice de sortie (3b) est prévu au niveau d'une partie supérieure du réservoir d'eau.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Machine à laver selon la revendication 8, dans laquelle l'orifice de sortie (3b) est prévu avec une buse d'injection (21) qui injecte l'eau de lavage de telle sorte<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> que l'eau de lavage soit uniformément pulvérisée dans le réservoir d'eau.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Machine à laver selon la revendication 1, comprenant en outre une unité de fourniture en sel qui fournit du sel à l'eau de lavage.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Machine à laver selon la revendication 11, dans laquelle l'unité de fourniture de sel est prévue dans un appareil de fourniture de détergents (6) qui fournit du détergent au réservoir d'eau.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Machine à laver selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle les première et seconde électrodes (130, 140) sont protégées de la contamination lorsque le dispositif de circulation ne fait pas circuler d'eau.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Procédé de lavage dans une machine à laver comprenant :
<claim-text>la fourniture d'eau de lavage à un réservoir où sont situés des articles à laver,</claim-text>
<claim-text>la stérilisation de l'eau de lavage par l'intermédiaire d'un procédé d'électrolyse, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>la mise en circulation de l'eau de lavage alors qu'elle est en cours de stérilisation,</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel les première et seconde électrodes (130, 140) prévues dans le stérilisateur ne sont pas immergées dans l'eau de lavage lorsque l'eau de lavage ne circule pas.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 14, dans lequel la stérilisation comprend :
<claim-text>l'application d'un courant électrique sur une première électrode (130) comprenant du Ag et dans une seconde électrode (140) comprenant un métal présentant une tendance à l'ionisation inférieure à la tendance à l'ionisation de l'Ag, et<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>la commutation de la polarité du courant électrique appliqué aux première et seconde électrodes (130, 140) sur la base d'un mode souhaité de fonctionnement de la stérilisation.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16668804" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="165" he="173" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="123" he="183" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="162" he="153" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
