<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2680405-A2" country="EP" doc-number="2680405" kind="A2" date="20140101" family-id="48698922" file-reference-id="288601" date-produced="20180824" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146549665" ucid="EP-2680405-A2"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2680405</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-13173467-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154823588" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>13173467</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20130624</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP200340155" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>13173467.5</doc-number><date>20130624</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140449904" ucid="KR-20120069847-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>KR</country><doc-number>20120069847</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120628</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1824866332" load-source="docdb">H02K   3/52        20060101AFI20170404BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1824866333" load-source="docdb">H02K  11/00        20160101ALI20170404BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1833766670" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H02K2203/03        20130101 LA20170329BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1955215099" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H02K   3/522       20130101 LI20160401BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1955218608" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H02K  11/00        20130101 LA20160331BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1991312172" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H02K  11/0094      20130101 FI20131226BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132181479" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Motor</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132181480" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Motor</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132181481" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Moteur</invention-title><citations><non-patent-citations><nplcit><text>None</text><sources><source mxw-id="PNPL45132176" load-source="docdb" name="APP"/></sources></nplcit></non-patent-citations></citations></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918166815" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>LG INNOTEK CO LTD</last-name><address><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918132655" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>LG INNOTEK CO., LTD.</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918990565" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>LG Innotek Co., Ltd.</last-name><iid>101287322</iid><address><street>20th Fl. Seoul Square 541, Namdaemunno 5-ga Jung-gu</street><city>Seoul 100-714</city><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918170748" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>RYU WOONGSEON</last-name><address><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918167945" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>RYU, WOONGSEON</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918989800" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>RYU, WOONGSEON</last-name><address><street>LG INNOTEK CO., LTD. 20th Fl. Seoul Square 541 Namdaemunno 5-ga Jung-gu</street><city>Seoul 100-714</city><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918982958" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Cabinet Plasseraud</last-name><iid>100784233</iid><address><street>52, rue de la Victoire</street><city>75440 Paris Cedex 09</city><country>FR</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548846484" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS548878438" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS548846486" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS548893874" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS548808522" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS548881125" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS548878439" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS548846487" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548881126" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS548881127" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS548880427" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS548893875" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS548808523" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548846488" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548881132" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS548846489" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS548878440" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS548880432" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS548881133" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS548893876" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS548881134" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS548893877" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS548806382" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS548893882" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS548893883" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS548806383" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS548806384" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS548880433" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS548899713" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS548880434" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS548893884" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS548878441" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS548893885" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS548880435" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS548808524" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS548899718" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS548899719" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS548806385" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states><ep-extended-states><ep-extended-state-data><country>BA</country></ep-extended-state-data><ep-extended-state-data><country>ME</country></ep-extended-state-data></ep-extended-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA128670334" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p id="pa01" num="0001">A motor is provided, the motor including a motor housing (10), a stator (20) mounted inside the motor housing and including a stator core and a coil wound on the stator core, a rotor (30) rotatably installed at a center of the stator, and a plate module (100) stacked with a plurality of plates, and coupled to the stator (20) and to an upper surface of a rotor (30) to supply an electric power to the coil.
<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="103" he="126" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA128499707" lang="EN" source="EPO" load-source="docdb"><p>A motor is provided, the motor including a motor housing (10), a stator (20) mounted inside the motor housing and including a stator core and a coil wound on the stator core, a rotor (30) rotatably installed at a center of the stator, and a plate module (100) stacked with a plurality of plates, and coupled to the stator (20) and to an upper surface of a rotor (30) to supply an electric power to the coil.</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES63955764" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001">BACKGROUND OF THE DISCLOSURE</heading><heading id="h0002">1. Field of the Disclosure</heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present disclosure relates to a brushless motor.</p><heading id="h0003">2. Discussion of the Related Art</heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">Generally, almost every vehicle employs an electric power-assist steering system. Such an electric power-assist steering system generates an assist force based on the steering torque and the steering angle in order to enhance the steering performance of the vehicle.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">That is, a steering system that assists a steering force of a vehicle with a separate power is used to enhance the motion stability of a vehicle.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">Conventionally, the auxiliary steering device uses hydraulic pressure, but an Electronic Power Steering (EPS) system adapted to transmit a rotation output of an electric motor to a steering shaft via a speed reduction mechanism has been increasingly employed these days from a viewpoint of a reduction in engine load, a reduction in weight, an enhanced steering stability and a quick restoring force.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> The EPS system is configured such that an Electronic Control Unit (ECU) drives a motor in response to steering conditions detected by a speed sensor, a torque angle sensor and a torque sensor to enhance a steering stability and provide a quick restoring force, whereby a driver can safely steer a vehicle.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">The EPS system is also such that a motor assists a torque manipulating a steering wheel to allow a driver to steer a vehicle with less power, where the motor employs a Brushless Direct Current (BLDC) motor.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">The BLDC motors have been increasingly used because the brushless motors are excellent in maintenance property, have a small size, and are capable of generating a high torque.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">The BLDC motor generally forms an exterior look by coupling of a housing with a cover member, an inner circumferential surface of the housing is provided with a stator, and the stator is centrally formed with a rotor rotatably mounted in electrical interaction with the stator. The rotor is rotatably supported by a rotation shaft, and an upper surface of the rotation shaft is connected by a steering shaft of a vehicle to provide a power assisting the steering of the vehicle as mentioned above. The stator of EPS motor thus configured serves to supply an electric power to a wound coil via busbar.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">The stator includes a core and a coil wound on the core, and in general, a motor<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> used for a vehicle is employed with a plurality of coils connected in parallel for loss reduction. Thus, the coil is extended to an input/output terminal, and integrated and connected at the terminal during parallel connection. In order to integrate and connect the coil arranged in parallel, a busbar is coupled to an upper surface of the stator, and in order to couple the busbar, a coil terminal of coils respectively wound on the upper surface of stator, and the busbar is connected to the coil terminal.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">The busbar is fixedly arranged with a plurality of metal members electrically connected to the coil terminal which is then insulated by an insulator. The busbar takes an approximate shape of a doughnut to correspond to a shape of the stator. The busbar is arranged at a periphery with terminals for connecting the coil terminal.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">The shape of a busbar is change in response to a connected electrical power, and in general, the EPS motor is configured such that respective input/output terminals are sequentially arranged to a periphery of the busbar through a 3-phase circuit.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">However, there is a disadvantage in a connecting process of a busbar to a coil, in a case the busbar is used to connect the coil, and in miniaturizing a motor because a height of an EPS motor increases as high as a height of the busbar.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">Another disadvantage is that a processing time is excessively required to<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> manufacture a busbar, because of a complicated process such as mold-formation of a busbar body using an insulator by formation of a busbar.</p><heading id="h0004">BRIEF SUMMARY</heading><p id="p0013" num="0013">The present disclosure is directed to cope with the abovementioned problems/disadvantages and it is an object of the present disclosure to provide a structure-improved brushless motor configured to improve motor assembly and motor miniaturization.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">In one general aspect of the present disclosure, there is provided a motor, the motor comprising:
<ul><li>a motor housing;</li><li>a stator mounted inside the motor housing and including a stator core and a coil wound on the stator core;</li><li>a rotor rotatably installed at a center of the stator; and</li><li>a plate module stacked with a plurality of plates, and coupled to the stator and to an upper surface of a rotor to supply an electric power to the coil.</li></ul></p><p id="p0015" num="0015">Preferably, but not necessarily, the plate module may include first to fourth plates each having a same diameter.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">Preferably, but not necessarily, the first plate may include first to third through holes each having a first diameter, and a first terminal through hole having a<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> second diameter smaller than the first diameter.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">Preferably, but not necessarily, the number of first terminal through hole may be same as a sum of the number of first to third coil through holes.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">Preferably, but not necessarily, the number of the first terminal through holes may be 12, and each number of the first to third coil through holes may be 3, such that a total number of first to third coil through holes may be 12.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">Preferably, but not necessarily, the second plate may include a fourth coil through hole having a first diameter, and a second terminal through hole having a second diameter smaller than the first diameter.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">Preferably, but not necessarily, the number of fourth coil through holes may be 20, and the number of second terminal through holes may be 4.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">Preferably, but not necessarily, the third plate may include a fifth coil through hole having a first diameter, and a third terminal through hole having a second diameter smaller than the first diameter.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">Preferably, but not necessarily, the number of fifth coil through holes may be 20, and the number of third terminal through holes may be 4.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">Preferably, but not necessarily, the fourth plate may include a sixth coil through<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> hole having a first diameter, and a fourth terminal through hole having a second diameter smaller than the first diameter.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">Preferably, but not necessarily, the number of sixth coil through holes may be 20, and the number of fourth terminal through holes may be 4.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">Preferably, but not necessarily, the second diameter may correspond to a diameter of the coil.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">Preferably, but not necessarily, each of the first to fourth plates may take a shape of a ring having an external diameter and a minor diameter.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">Preferably, but not necessarily, the first to fourth plates may include at least four (4) ounces of copper.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">Preferably, but not necessarily, the minor diameter may be formed greater than a diameter of the rotor.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">There is an advantageous effect in the motor according to an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure in that a motor height can be reduced to provide a further miniaturized motor, because each polarity and common terminal connections of electric power can be enabled by stacking a plurality of plate members instead of the conventionally used complicated structure of busbar.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> Another advantageous effect is that productivity of motor assembly can be improved by replacing the complicated process of connecting a distal ends of coils wound on a stator to a terminal of busbar with a process of inserting the distal ends of coils into a plate member, and heating and soldering using a heating gun.</p><heading id="h0005">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading><p id="p0030" num="0030"><ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG.1</figref> is a partially cut-out cross-sectional view illustrating a motor according to an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG.2</figref> is an exploded perspective view illustrating a plate module according to an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> is a plan view illustrating a first plate of <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG.2</figref>.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003 f0004">FIGS.4 to 6</figref> are plan views illustrating second to fourth plates of <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG.2</figref>.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005">FIG.7</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a stator core wound with a coil.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0006">FIG.8</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a state in which a distal end of a coil wound on a stator core of <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG.7</figref> is stripped and a plate module inserted into.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 9</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a state in which a stripped portion of the coil protruded to an upper surface of the plate module of <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG.8</figref> is cut out.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0008">FIG.10</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a state in which the upper surface of the plate module of <figref idrefs="f0007">FIG.9</figref> is soldered using a conductive member.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0006">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading><!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --><p id="p0031" num="0031">Now, a motor according to the exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure will be described in detail with reference to the accompanying drawings.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032"><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG.1</figref> is a partially cut-out cross-sectional view illustrating a motor according to an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure, <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG.2</figref> is an exploded perspective view illustrating a plate module according to an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure, <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> is a plan view illustrating a first plate of <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG.2</figref>, <figref idrefs="f0003 f0004">FIGS.4 to 6</figref> are plan views illustrating second to fourth plates of <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG.2</figref>, <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG.7</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a stator core wound with a coil, <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG.8</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a state in which a distal end of a coil wound on a stator core of <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG.7</figref> is stripped and a plate module inserted into, <figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 9</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a state in which a stripped portion of the coil protruded to an upper surface of the plate module of <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG.8</figref> is cut out, and <figref idrefs="f0008">FIG.10</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a state in which the upper surface of the plate module of <figref idrefs="f0007">FIG.9</figref> is soldered using a conductive member.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG.1</figref>, an EPS motor according to an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure includes a motor housing (10), a stator (20), and a rotor (30), and may further include a plate module (100) for supplying an electric power to a coil (22) wound on the stator (20).</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">The motor housing (10) takes an approximate shape of a cylinder, and is formed with at an upper surface with an opening and closed at a bottom surface. The motor housing (10) is installed therein with the stator (20), the rotor (30) and a<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> rotation shaft (30a) rotatably supporting the rotor (30). The stator (20) includes a stator core (21), a coil (22) and a coil terminal (25) formed by stripping a distal end of the coil. The stator core (21) may be provided with a plurality of teeth, and the teeth may be circumferentially wound with the coil (22) while the teeth are mounted with an insulator. The distal end of the coil (22) is stripped to form the coil terminal (25), where the coil terminal (25) may be provided in a cylindrical shape having a predetermined length and a predetermined diameter, as illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG.2</figref>.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">The rotor (30) is rotatably mounted at a center of the stator (20), and is formed by a plurality of magnets being mounted at a periphery of rotor core. The rotation shaft (30a) is coaxially formed with the rotor (30), where one end of the rotation shaft (30a) is rotatably supported by a bottom bearing mounted at a floor surface of the motor housing (10), and the other end of the rotation shaft (30a) is supported by an upper bearing installed on a cover member (not shown).</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">A sensing unit (34) includes a plate (31), a sensing magnet (32) and a magnetic element (33). The plate is provided with an approximate shape of a disc, and is fixed at an upper surface by the sensing magnet (32) using an adhesive. The sensing magnet (32) may be centrally provided with a through hole. The magnetic element (33) serves to detect changes in magnetic field of the sensing magnet (32), and is installed opposite to the sensing magnet (32). The magnetic element (33) may be installed on a PCB (Printed Circuit Board) arranged at an upper surface of the rotor (30).<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></p><p id="p0037" num="0037">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG.2</figref> again, the plate module (100) is formed by being stacked with first to fourth plates (110∼140) each having a same external shape. At this time, each of the first to fourth plates (110∼140) takes a ring shape and is centrally formed with a through hole, and a diameter of the through hole may be greater than a diameter of the rotor (30). The through hole may be formed with a size not interfering with the PCB (35) as shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG.1</figref>.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">The first plate (110) functions as a common terminal as illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG.3</figref>, and may be formed at a periphery with a plurality of through holes. At this time, the through hole may be provided with a first coil through hole (111) having a first diameter, a second coil through hole (112), a third coil through hole (113) and a first terminal through hole (115) having a second diameter smaller than the first diameter. The first to third coil through holes (111∼113) and the first terminal through hole (115) may be alternatively arranged as illustrated in the drawing.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">That is, the first coil through hole (111) may be followed by the first terminal through hole (115), the second coil through hole (112) may be arranged thereaside, the first terminal through hole (115) thereaside, the third coil through hole (113) thereaside, and the first terminal through hole (115) thereaside in that order. The reason of this arrangement will be explained later.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG.4</figref>, the second plate (120) may be provided in a ring shape having a periphery and an inner surface same as those of the first plate (110). The<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> second plate (120) may include a fourth coil through hole (121) having a diameter corresponding to the first diameter, and a second terminal through hole (122) having a second diameter corresponding to that of the first terminal through hole (115).</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">Referring now to <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG.5</figref>, the third plate (130) may be provided in a ring shape having a periphery and an inner surface same as those of the first plate (110). The third plate (130) may include a fifth coil through hole (121) having a diameter corresponding to the first diameter, and a third terminal through hole (132) having a second diameter corresponding to that of the first terminal through hole (115).</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">Referring now to <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG.6</figref>, the fourth plate (140) may be provided in a ring shape having a periphery and an inner surface same as those of the first plate (110). The fourth plate (140) may include a sixth coil through hole (121) having a diameter corresponding to the first diameter, and a fourth terminal through hole (142) having a second diameter corresponding to that of the first terminal through hole (115).</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">The first to fourth terminal through holes (115, 122, 132, 142) may be formed with conductive material, and the second diameter may be configured to have a diameter corresponding to a diameter of the coil (22).</p><p id="p0044" num="0044">At this time, an inner surface of first to fourth terminal through holes (115, 122,<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> 132, 142) may be conductively connected with the coil (22) passing the first to fourth terminal through holes (115, 122, 132, 142) using a tool such as a hot gun by performing a solder coating in a case heat is applied.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045">Furthermore, the first to fourth plates (110∼140) may be commonly formed at an outer surface or at an inner surface with a conductive layer conductively arranged with the first to fourth terminal through holes (115, 122, 132, 142), and in a case the conductive layer is arranged at an upper surface or a bottom surface, an insulation paint may be coated or painted to prevent occurrence of an outside short-circuit, and in a case the conductive layer is arranged thereinside, a member wrapping the conductive layer may be formed with an insulation member.</p><p id="p0046" num="0046">Meanwhile, weight of conductive member instead of thickness or area of the conductive member is important for the conductive layer, and according to an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure, the conductive member is a copper material, and weight of the copper material may be at least four (4) or more ounces. At this time, diameter and thickness of the plate module (100) may increase or decrease in response to a diameter of the motor, and in a case the weight of the copper which is a conductive material is maintained at four (4) or more ounces, the thickness may be freely adjusted, where each thickness of the plates (110∼140) may be configured not to exceed 1mm at the maximum.</p><p id="p0047" num="0047">Generally, because the plate module (100) using four (4)-ounce copper is manufactured in a ring shape, an etching process required for formation of a<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> general PCB may be omitted to reduce the manufacturing cost.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048">Meanwhile, the number of through holes may vary based on connected polarity, and because the motor according to an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure is connected to a 3-phase electrical power, a total of 24 through holes may be formed for each plate (110∼140). Therefore, the first plate (110) may be formed with a total of 12 first terminal through holes (115), and the first to third coil through holes (111∼113) may have three (3) holes, so a total of 12 holes may be formed.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">Furthermore, each of the second to fourth plates (120∼140) has a same shape and structure, and the second plate (120) may have a total of 20 four coil through holes (121) each having a first diameter, and a total of 4 second terminal through holes (122) each having a second diameter. Each of the third and fourth plates (130, 140) may also have a total of 20 fifth and sixth coil through holes (131, 141) each having a first diameter, and a total of four third and fourth terminal through holes (132, 142) each having a second diameter.</p><p id="p0050" num="0050">Meanwhile, the plate module (100) as noted above is formed by plate-stacking, where when stacking, it is necessary to arrange each through hole at a specific position. That is, as illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG.2</figref>, the first plate (110) of common terminal may be arranged at the lowermost side. Furthermore, an upper surface of the first plate (110) may be stacked with the second plate (120) having a first polarity and connected to an electric power source, and the second terminal through hole<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> (122) of the second plate (120) may be arranged opposite to the first coil through hole (111). In the like manner, the third terminal through hole (132) of the third plate (130) may be arranged opposite to the second coil through hole (112), and the fourth terminal through hole (142) of the fourth plate (140) may be arranged opposite to the third coil through hole (113).</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">Now, a coupling method of the plate module (100) will be described with reference to <figref idrefs="f0005 f0006 f0007 f0008">FIGS.7 to 10</figref> according to the present disclosure.</p><p id="p0052" num="0052">The present disclosure relates to a brushless motor using a 3-phase (U, V, W) electric power source, and a general construction of the stator (20) has been already described along with <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG.1</figref>.</p><p id="p0053" num="0053">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG.7</figref>, a distal end (23) of coil (22) wound on the stator core (21) may be arranged in an erect state on an upper surface of the stator core while being wrapped in an insulated coating that wraps the coil (22). At this time, the distal end (23) of the coil (22) is arranged at an erect state to a direction parallel with a lengthwise direction of the stator core (21), and the distal end (23) of the coil (22) is made to pass through the plurality of through holes formed on the plate module (100).</p><p id="p0054" num="0054">A stripped portion (24) formed by stripping the distal end (23) of the coil (22) having passed the first terminal through hole (115) passes through the fourth to sixth coil through holes (121, 131, 141) of the second to fourth plates (120, 130,<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> 140) whereby the conductive connection may be realized only on the first terminal through hole (115).</p><p id="p0055" num="0055">Furthermore, a stripped portion (24) formed by stripping the distal end (23) of the coil (22) having passed the second terminal through hole (122) of the second plate (120) passes through the fifth to sixth coil through holes (131, 141) of the third and fourth plates (130, 140) whereby the conductive connection may be realized only on the second terminal through hole (122).</p><p id="p0056" num="0056">Still furthermore, a stripped portion (24) formed by stripping the distal end (23) of the coil (22) having passed the fourth coil through hole (121) of the second plate (120) passes through the third terminal through hole (132) of the third plate (130), and passes the sixth coil through hole (141) of the fourth plate (140), whereby the conductive connection may be realized only on the third terminal through hole (132).</p><p id="p0057" num="0057">Still furthermore, a stripped portion (24) formed by stripping the distal end (23) of the coil (22) having passed the third coil through hole (113) passes through the fourth and fifth coil through holes (121, 131) of the second and third plates (120, 130), and passes through the fourth terminal through hole (142) of the fourth plate (130, whereby the conductive connection may be realized only on the fourth terminal through hole (142).</p><p id="p0058" num="0058">Now, once the connection is finished as explained above, the stripped portion<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> (24) protruded to an upper surface of the plate module (100) is removed to form a coil terminal (25), as illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0007">FIG.9</figref>, and a portion o the coil terminal (25) is soldered using a conductive member (200) such as a lead whereby the assembly may be completed.</p><p id="p0059" num="0059">Furthermore, albeit not being illustrated, as noted above, a periphery of the first to fourth terminal through holes (115, 122, 132, 142) is pre-performed with solder coating, heat is applies using a heat gun after assembly of the plate member (100) is finished, the pre-performed solder coating is melted, and the coil stripped portion (24) having passed the first to fourth terminal through holes (115, 122, 132, 142) may be conductively connected to the first to fourth plates (110∼140). At this time, each diameter of the first to fourth terminal through holes (115, 122, 132, 142) has the second diameter corresponding to the diameter of the coil (22), and the first to sixth coil through holes (111, 112, 113, 121, 131, 141) has the first diameter greater than the second diameter, such that if a soldering process using lead is performed on the upper surface as illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0008">FIG.10</figref>, the stripped portion (24) may be conductively connected only to the first to fourth terminal through holes (115, 122, 132, 142).</p><p id="p0060" num="0060">As apparent from the foregoing, the exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure has an advantageous effect in that a conventional busbar is removed, and same function as that of the busbar can be achieved by coupling of plate module (100) formed by stacking the first to fourth plates (110∼140), each having a same ring-shaped external look to thereby enhance the assemble and<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> productivity.</p><p id="p0061" num="0061">Meanwhile, the abovementioned exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure has illustrated and explained a case where a 3-phase electric power source is applied, such that the number of plates forming the plate module (100) may be increased or decreased if polarities of applied electric power source increase or decrease.</p><p id="p0062" num="0062">Although embodiments have been described with reference to a number of illustrative embodiments thereof, it should be understood that numerous other modifications and embodiments can be devised by those skilled in the art that will fall within the spirit and scope of the principles of this disclosure. More particularly, various variations and modifications are possible in the component parts and/or arrangements of the subject combination arrangement within the scope of the disclosure, the drawings and the appended claims.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56976684" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --><claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A motor including a motor housing (10), a stator (20) mounted inside the motor housing and including a stator core and a coil wound on the stator core, and a rotor (30) rotatably installed at a center of the stator , the motor <b>characterized by</b>:
<claim-text>a plate module (100) stacked with a plurality of plates, and coupled to the stator (20) and to an upper surface of a rotor (30) to supply an electric power to the coil.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The motor of claim 1, <b>characterized in that</b> the plate module (100) includes first to fourth plates each having a same diameter.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The motor of claim 2, <b>characterized in that</b> the first plate (110) includes first to third coil through holes (111, 112, 113) each having a first diameter, and a first terminal through hole (115) having a second diameter smaller than the first diameter.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The motor of claim 3, <b>characterized in that</b> the number of first terminal through hole (115) is same as a sum of the number of first to third coil through holes (111, 112, 113).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The motor of claim 3, <b>characterized in that</b> the number of the first terminal through holes is 12, and each number of the first to third coil through holes is 3, such that a total number of first to third coil through holes is 12.<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The motor of claim 2, <b>characterized in that</b> the second plate includes a fourth coil through hole having a first diameter, and a second terminal through hole having a second diameter smaller than the first diameter.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The motor of claim 6, <b>characterized in that</b> the number of fourth coil through holes (121) is 20, and the number of second terminal through holes (122) is 4.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The motor of claim 2, <b>characterized in that</b> the third plate includes a fifth coil through hole (131) having a first diameter, and a third terminal through hole (132) having a second diameter smaller than the first diameter.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The motor of claim 8, <b>characterized in that</b> the number of fifth coil through hole (131) is 20, and the number of third terminal through hole (132) is 4.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The motor of claim 2, <b>characterized in that</b> the fourth plate (140) includes a sixth coil through hole (141) having a first diameter, and a fourth terminal through hole (142) having a second diameter smaller than the first diameter.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>The motor of claim 10, <b>characterized in that</b> the number of sixth coil through hole (141) is 20, and the number of fourth terminal through hole (142) is 4.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>The motor of claim 3, <b>characterized in that</b> the second diameter corresponds to a diameter of the coil.<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>The motor of claim 2, <b>characterized in that</b> each of the first to fourth plates (110∼140) takes a shape of a ring having an external diameter and a minor diameter.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>The motor of claim 13, <b>characterized in that</b> the first to fourth plates (110∼40) include at least four (4) ounces of copper.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>The motor of claim 13, <b>characterized in that</b> the minor diameter is formed greater than a diameter of the rotor (30).</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16667462" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="145" he="130" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="135" he="179" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3,4"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="130" he="226" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --><figure id="f0004" num="5,6"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="136" he="231" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --><figure id="f0005" num="7"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="152" he="194" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --><figure id="f0006" num="8"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="152" he="194" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --><figure id="f0007" num="9"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="152" he="194" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --><figure id="f0008" num="10"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="152" he="194" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
