<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2519762-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2519762" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="43728783" file-reference-id="315059" date-produced="20180825" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146587780" ucid="EP-2519762-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2519762</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-10787604-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154849972" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>10787604</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20101112</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140553553" ucid="US-2010056504-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>2010056504</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20101112</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140548440" ucid="US-64869509-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>64869509</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20091229</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130621</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989323880" load-source="docdb">F16K  37/00        20060101AFI20110722BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2079678610" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G05B  23/0256      20130101 FI20150401BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2079678740" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F16K  37/0083      20130101 LI20150401BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132367973" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">VORRICHTUNG, VERFAHREN UND PROGRAMM ZUR TESTEN SICHERHEITSINSTRUMENTSYSTEME FÜR MAGNETSPULEN</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132367974" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">APPARATUS, METHOD AND PROGRAM TO TEST SAFETY INSTRUMENTED SYSTEM SOLENOIDS</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132367975" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">APPAREIL, MÉTHODE ET PROGRAMME POUR TESTER DES SYSTÈMES D'INSTRUMENTATION DE SÉCURITÉ POUR SOLÉNOÏDES</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919516846" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>FISHER CONTROLS INT</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919537244" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>FISHER CONTROLS INTERNATIONAL LLC</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919529990" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>SNOWBARGER JIMMIE L</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919511183" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>SNOWBARGER, JIMMIE, L.</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919020010" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>SNOWBARGER, JIMMIE, L.</last-name><address><street>3046 280th Street</street><city>Marshalltown IA 50158</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919020012" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Fisher Controls International Llc</last-name><iid>101132810</iid><address><street>205 South Center St.</street><city>Marshalltown, IA 50158</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919020011" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Bohnenberger, Johannes</last-name><iid>100026679</iid><address><street>Meissner, Bolte &amp; Partner GbR Postfach 86 06 24</street><city>81633 München</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="US-2010056504-W"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2010056504</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20101112</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2011081728-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2011081728</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20110707</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549921216" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS549778049" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549921217" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549885181" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549861316" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549777894" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549778050" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549793198" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549921218" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549777895" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549863625" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549885186" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549885187" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549921219" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549921220" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549921221" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549778051" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549861317" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549921222" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549885188" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549777896" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549793199" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549778052" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549793200" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549793209" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549865949" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS549865958" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549885189" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549863634" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549885194" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549865959" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549885195" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549865960" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS549885196" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549865961" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549861322" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549861323" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS549793210" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63960215" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001">FIELD OF THE DISCLOSURE</heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">This disclosure relates generally to safety instrumented systems (SIS) and, more particularly, to methods, apparatus and articles of manufacture to test SIS solenoids.</p><heading id="h0002">BACKGROUND</heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">Process control systems, like those used in chemical, petroleum or other processes, typically include one or more centralized process controllers communicatively coupled to at least one host or operator workstation and to one or more field devices via analog, digital and/or combined analog/digital buses. The field devices, which may be, for example, valves, valve positioners, switches and/or transmitters (e.g., temperature sensors, pressure sensors and flow rate sensors), perform functions within the process such as opening and/or closing valves and/or measuring process parameters. The process controllers receive signals indicative of process measurements made by the field devices and/or other information pertaining to the field devices, use this information to implement control routines and then generate control signals that are sent over the buses and/or other communication paths to the field devices to control the operation of the process. Information from the field devices and the controllers may be made available to one or more applications executed by the operator workstation to enable an operator to perform desired functions with respect to the process, such as viewing the current state of the process, modifying the operation of the process, etc.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">Many process control systems also include one or more application stations. Typically, these application stations are implemented using a personal computer, workstation, or the like that is communicatively coupled to the controllers, operator workstations, and other systems within the process control system via a local area network (LAN). Each application station may execute one or more software applications that perform campaign management functions, maintenance management functions, virtual control functions, diagnostic functions, real-time monitoring functions, safety-related functions, configuration functions, etc. within the process control system.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p><p id="p0004" num="0004">Some process control systems or portions thereof may present significant safety risks. For example, chemical processing plants, power plants, etc. may implement critical processes that, if not properly controlled and/or shut down rapidly using a predetermined shut down sequence, could result in significant damage to people, the environment and/or equipment. To address the safety risks associated with process control systems having such critical processes, many process control system providers offer products compliant with safety-related standards such as, for example, the International Electrotechnical Commission (IEC) 61508 standard and the IEC 61511 standard.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">Process control systems that are compliant with one or more known safety-related standards are typically implemented using an SIS architecture. In SIS architectures, the controllers and field devices associated with the basic process control system, which is responsible for the continuous control of the overall process, are physically and logically separate from special-purpose field devices and other special-purpose control elements associated with the SIS, which is responsible for the performance of safety instrumented functions to ensure the safe shutdown of the process in response to control conditions that present a significant safety risk. In particular, compliance with many known safety-related standards requires a basic process control system to be supplemented with special-purpose control elements such as logic solvers, SIS controllers, safety certified field devices (e.g., sensors, final control elements such as, for example, pneumatically actuated valves and/or solenoid valves), data redundancy devices and routines (e.g., redundancy links, cyclical redundancy checks, etc.), and safety certified software or code (e.g., certified applications, function modules, function blocks, etc.).</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">Some process plants, in addition to process control valves, include a safety shut-off valve (e.g., an emergency shut-off valve) for each of the process control valves to quickly stop the flow of fluid in response to, for example, a system failure. These safety shut-off valves are controlled by the SIS. An example safety shut-off valve is a solenoid valve where the SIS selects or controls a power supply of a solenoid to control the solenoid valve. When a solenoid is powered it and, thus, the solenoid valve will be in a first position or state (e.g., open). When power is removed from the solenoid, the solenoid and, thus, the solenoid valve will be in a second position or state (e.g., closed). Solenoid valves are typically of two types: fail-to-open, for which the valve is open when power is removed from the solenoid, and fail-to-close, for which the valve is closed when power is removed from the<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> solenoid. Example solenoid valves include the EF8316 and EF8310 solenoid valves manufactured by Asco® Valve, Inc.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US2007018127A"><text>US 2007/018127</text></patcit> discloses a system for controlling an emergency shutdown valve through a shutdown controller, which provides a signal to a valve controller coupled to the emergency shutdown valve.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">Additionally, <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="US5665898A"><text>US 5,665,898</text></patcit> discloses a system for testing solenoids in a safety system by using pneumatic means. The operation of the solenoids are controlled by a human operator through manual operation of handles and switches.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">Furthermore, <patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="WO9917042A"><text>WO 99/17042</text></patcit> discloses a system for running a diagnostic test on a valve having a movable valve member. The system disconnects a control signal and forces the valve to perform a predetermined set of operations.</p><heading id="h0003">SUMMARY</heading><p id="p0010" num="0010">The present invention provides a valve position control apparatus as described in claim 1, and a method according to claim 9. Further embodiments of the present invention may be realised according to the corresponding dependent claims.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">Example methods, apparatus and articles of manufacture to test safety instrumented system solenoids are disclosed. A disclosed valve position control apparatus includes a relay to control a state of a solenoid and a valve positioner including a transmitter to transmit a solenoid test signal to the relay, electrical contacts to communicatively couple the solenoid test signal to the relay via one or more wires, and a solenoid tester to generate the solenoid test signal and to monitor a response of the solenoid when the solenoid test signal is transmitted to the relay to verify an operation of the solenoid.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">An example method includes selecting a power supply interruption control signal to select a state of a safety instrumented system (SIS) solenoid, transmitting the power supply interruption control signal from a valve controller to a relay via one or more wires to configure the SIS solenoid to the selected state, and monitoring a response of the SIS solenoid to the selected state to verify an operation of the SIS solenoid.</p><heading id="h0004">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading><p id="p0013" num="0013"><ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic illustration of an example process control system having a valve positioner according to one or more aspects of the present disclosure.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates an example manner of implementing the example valve positioner of <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic illustration of another example process control system having a valve positioner according to one or more aspects of the present disclosure.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates an example manner of implementing the example valve positioner of <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 3</figref>.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 5</figref> is a flowchart representative of an example process that may be carried out to implement the example valve positioner of <figref idrefs="f0001 f0002">FIGS. 1-4</figref>.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 6</figref> is a schematic illustration of an example processor platform that may be used and/or programmed to carry out the example process of <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 5</figref>, and/or to implement any of all of the methods, apparatus and articles of manufacture disclosed herein.</li></ul></p><p id="p0014" num="0014">Certain examples are shown in the above-identified figures and described in detail below. The figures are not necessarily to scale and certain features and certain views of the figures may be shown exaggerated in scale or in schematic for clarity and/or<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --><!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> conciseness. It is to be understood that while the following disclosure provides many different embodiments or examples for implementing different features of various embodiments, other embodiments may be implemented and/or structural changes may be made without departing from the scope of this disclosure. Further, while specific examples of components and arrangements are described below these are, of course, merely examples and are not intended to be limiting. In addition, the present disclosure may repeat reference numerals and/or letters in the various examples. This repetition is for the purpose of clarity and does not in itself dictate a relationship between the various embodiments and/or example configurations discussed. Moreover, the depiction or description of a first feature over or on a second feature may include embodiments in which the first and second elements are implemented in direct contact, and may also include embodiments in which other elements may be interposed between the first and second elements, such that the first and second elements need not be in direct contact.</p><heading id="h0005">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading><p id="p0015" num="0015">Traditionally, safety instrumented system (SIS) controllers test the safety overrides of process control valves by temporarily interrupting a solenoid valve power supply signal. Such temporary interruptions of the power supply signal should cause the solenoid valve to trip and cause a respective process control valve to begin moving toward its emergency or safety position (e.g., fully closed or fully open depending on the process). If the power supply signal is only temporarily interrupted, the process control valve will only be partially stroked or partially moved toward its emergency or safety position. If the process control valve is detected as moving in the correct direction in response to the temporary interruption of the power supply signal, the SIS controller can determine that the solenoid valve and the process control valve are collectively operating as intended. However, if the process control valve does not move as expected, the example SIS controller cannot determine whether it is the solenoid valve and/or the process control valve that is not operating as intended. This type of test of the process control valve by the example SIS controller is often referred to in the industry as a partial stroke test (PST).</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">To overcome at least these deficiencies, the example valve positioners disclosed herein include a solenoid tester to test the solenoid and/or the solenoid valve separately from the process control valve. The disclosed example valve positioners also include integrated contacts, terminals and/or connectors that may be used to electrically<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> couple control signals from the solenoid tester to a solid-state relay (SSR). The SSR is controlled via the control signals to trip the solenoid. An example solenoid tester monitors an output, state and/or position of the solenoid and/or the solenoid valve while the solenoid is temporarily tripped to determine whether the solenoid and/or the solenoid valve are operating as intended. In some examples, the output of the solenoid and/or the position of a solenoid plunger are monitored. Additionally or alternatively, a pneumatic output of the solenoid valve may be monitored.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017"><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> depicts an example process control system 100 having a valve positioner 105 to, among other things, test an SIS solenoid valve 110 and/or an SIS solenoid 155 associated with the solenoid valve. <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates an example manner of implementing the example valve positioner 105 of <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>. The example valve positioner 105 includes any type of valve position controller 205 (<figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 2</figref>) to control the position (e.g., percentage open or closed) of a process control valve 115 based on a valve control signal 120 received from a process controller 125 via one or more wires and/or communication buses 130. The example valve position controller 205 controls the position of the example process control valve 115 by controlling, adjusting and/or selecting a pressure of a pneumatic control line 135. The pressure of the pneumatic control line 135 controls the position of an actuator 140 associated with the process control valve 115 and, thus, the position of the process control valve 115. The pressure of the pneumatic control line 135 may be controlled by regulating a flow of fluid from a pneumatic supply 137 into the pneumatic control line 135. The example valve position controller 205 receives one or more signals representative of the present or current position of the process control valve 115 via any number and/or type(s) of communication signals and/or communication paths, which are not depicted in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1 or 2</figref> for purposes of clarity. Using any number and/or type(s) of algorithm(s), method(s) and/or logic, the example valve position controller 205 controls the pressure of the pneumatic control line 135 so that the process control valve 115 has a position substantially corresponding to a position specified and/or indicated by the valve control signal 120.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">The example wire(s) and/or bus(es) 130 are electrically coupled to a terminal box or housing 145 of the example valve positioner 105 via one or more contacts, connectors and/or terminals 210 (<figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 2</figref>) within the terminal housing 145. To receive the valve control signal 120, the example terminal box 145 also includes a receiver 215 to convert the analog valve control signal 120 into digital values and/or digital samples suitable for processing by the example valve position controller 205. In some examples, there are two<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> wires 130 and two contacts 210, the valve control signal 120 comprises a 4-20 mA loop current signal propagated on the two wires 130, and the example receiver 215 comprises a highway addressable remote transducer (HART) receiver. While the example contacts 210, receiver 215, transmitter 225 and solenoid test contacts 230 are depicted in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 2</figref> as being implemented within the example terminal housing 145, it may be implemented elsewhere within the valve positioner 105.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">To allow an SIS controller 150 to quickly stop the flow of fluid(s) and/or other material(s) through the process control valve 115 in response to, for example, a system failure or an emergency, the example solenoid valve 110 is pneumatically interposed in the pneumatic control line 135 between the valve positioner 105 and the process control valve 115. By controlling the state or position of the solenoid 155 of the solenoid valve 110, the example SIS controller 150 can interrupt or depressurize the pneumatic control line 135 controlling the position of the process control valve 115. The SIS controller 150 controls the state or position of the solenoid 155 by controlling, selecting or adjusting a power supply signal 160 of the solenoid 155. When the power supply signal 160 is selected to have a first voltage (e.g., 24 VDC, 48 VDC, 110 VAC or 220 VAC), the solenoid 155 is in a first state allowing the valve positioner 105 to control the pressure in the pneumatic control line 135. However, when the power supply signal 160 is interrupted (e.g., is 0 V), the solenoid 155 is in a second or different state disconnecting the valve positioner 105 from the pneumatic control line 135. Alternatively, a 0 V power supply signal 160 can correspond to the first state and a non-zero voltage (e.g., 24 VDC, 48 VDC, 110 VAC or 220 VAC) correspond to the second state. By selecting, adjusting and/or controlling the voltage of the power supply 160 of the solenoid 155 the SIS controller can override the position of the process control valve 115 for safety or emergency reasons.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">Traditionally, the example SIS controller 150 tests the safety override of the process control valve 115 by temporarily interrupting the power supply signal 160. Such temporary interruptions of the power supply signal 160 should cause the process control valve 115 to begin moving toward its emergency or safety position (e.g., fully closed or fully open depending on the process). However, because the power supply signal 160 is only temporarily interrupted, the process control valve 115 will only be partially stroked or moved toward its emergency or safety position. If the process control valve 115 is detected as moving in the correct direction in response to the temporary interruption of the power supply signal 160, the SIS controller 150 can determine that the solenoid valve 110 and the process<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> control valve 115 are collectively operating as intended. However, if the process control valve 115 does not move as expected, the example SIS controller 150 cannot determine whether it is the solenoid valve 110 and/or the process control valve 115 that is not operating as intended.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">To allow the valve positioner 105 to test the solenoid valve 110 independent of the example process control valve 115, the system 100 of <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> includes an SSR 165. The example SSR 165 of <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is electrically interposed between the power supply signal 160 provided by the SIS controller 150 and the solenoid valve 110. A solenoid tester 220 (<figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 2</figref>) of the valve positioner 105 is configured to control the state or position of the SSR 165 via a control signal 170. The example solenoid tester 220 can control the SSR 165 via the control signal 170 to a first state where the power supply signal 160 is electrically coupled to the solenoid valve 110 or to a second state where the power supply signal 160 is disconnected and/or electrically isolated from the solenoid valve 110. In other words, the control signal 170 represents a power supply interruption signal that indicates to the SSR 165 whether or not to interrupt, disconnect and/or electrically isolate the power supply signal 160 from the solenoid valve 110. Example solid-state relays that may be used to implement the example SSR 165 include, but are not limited to, a photo-coupled relay such as the model # 348-431 relay manufactured by Radionics, a transformer-coupled relay such as the model # HDA-3V25 relay manufactured by Power-IO™, and a hybrid SSR such as the model #24D25-17 relay manufactured by Opto 22.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">The example control signal 170 is transmitted to the SSR 165 by a transmitter 225 via one or more solenoid test contacts, terminals and/or connectors 230 and respective wires 175. The example transmitter 225 and the example solenoid test contacts 230 may be implemented within the terminal box or housing 145 as depicted in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 2</figref>. Alternatively, the transmitter 225 and/or the example solenoid test contacts 230 may be implemented elsewhere within the example valve positioner 105.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">The example transmitter 225 converts digital control values and/or digital control samples generated by the solenoid tester 220 into the analog control signal 170 suitable for transmission to the SSR 165 via the contact(s) 230 and the wire(s) 175. In some examples, there are two wires 175 and two solenoid test contacts 230, with a first of the wires 175 carrying a ground signal or voltage and a second of the wires 175 carrying an analog control voltage that controls the state of the solenoid 155.<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --></p><p id="p0024" num="0024">The example solenoid tester 220 monitors the position, state and/or operation of the solenoid 155 and/or the solenoid valve 110 via a monitor signal 180. Example monitor signals 180 include, but are not limited to, a signal representing an electrical or pneumatic output of the solenoid 155 used to control the position of the solenoid valve 110, and a signal representing a solenoid plunger position. Such monitor signals 180 may be used by the solenoid tester 220 to determine whether a plunger 156 of the solenoid 155 travels sufficiently in response to an interruption of the power supply 160 by the SSR 165 that it can operate the solenoid valve 110 as intended during emergency or safety-based shutdowns.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">A receiver 240 (<figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 2</figref>) converts the monitor signal 180 into a digital signal and/or digital samples representative of the position and/or state of the solenoid 155 and/or the solenoid valve 110. By monitoring the digitized monitor signal 180 when the test control signal 170 is transmitted to the SSR 165, the example solenoid tester 220 can determine whether the solenoid 155 and/or the solenoid valve 110 are operating as intended. Because the test control signal 170 is used to only temporarily trip or change the state of the solenoid 155, the position of the process control valve 115 should only temporarily change by a small amount and for a short time period. Once the test control signal 170 is discontinued and/or is used to control the SSR 165 to return to its nominal state, the valve positioner 105 can restore the position of the process control valve 115 as needed. An example process that may be carried out by the example solenoid tester 220 and/or, more generally, by the example valve positioner 105 to test the solenoid 155 and/or the solenoid valve 110 is described below in connection with <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 5</figref>.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">Additionally or alternatively, the solenoid tester 220 may monitor any number and/or type(s) of additional and/or alternative monitor signals. For example, the solenoid tester 220 may monitor the pressure of the pneumatic control line 135 downstream from the solenoid valve 110. If, for example, the actuator 140 is a single-acting actuator and, thus only a single pneumatic control line 135 is needed to control the position of the valve 115, an unused pneumatic port B of the valve positioner 105 may be pneumatically coupled to the pneumatic control line 135 to monitor the pressure of the pneumatic control line 135 downstream from the solenoid valve 110. In such an example, the receiver 240 may comprise a pressure transducer. When the state of the solenoid 155 is changed by the SSR 165, the solenoid tester 220 can monitor for an expected change in the pressure at the port B<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> to determine whether the solenoid 155 and the solenoid valve 110 are collectively operating as intended.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027"><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 3</figref> depicts another example process control system 300 having a valve positioner 305 to, among other things, test an operation of the safety instrumented system (SIS) solenoid valve 110. <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates an example manner of implementing the example valve positioner 305 of <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 3</figref>. Because some elements of the illustrated examples of <figref idrefs="f0002">FIGS. 3 and 4</figref> are identical to those discussed above in connection with <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, the description of identical elements is not repeated here. Instead, identical elements are illustrated with identical reference numerals in <figref idrefs="f0001 f0002">FIGS. 1-4</figref>, and the interested reader is referred back to the descriptions presented above in connection with <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref> for a complete description of those like-numbered elements.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">In contrast to the illustrated example of <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGS. 1 and 2</figref>, in the example process control system 300 of <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 3</figref>, the example transmitter 225 transmits the control signal 170 to the SSR 165 via the same contacts, terminals and/or connectors 210 that are used to electrically couple the process controller 125 to the receiver 215 via the example wires 130. As such, wires 305 and 306 are electrically coupled between respective ones of the wires 130 and corresponding terminals, contacts or connectors 310 of a filter 315. In other words, the process controller 125, the example receiver 215, the example transmitter 225 and the example filter 315 communicate via and/or on the same communication bus 130, 305, 306. In some examples, signals and/or commands are communicated on the shared bus 130, 305, 306 using 4-20 mA loop currents, the example receiver 215 and the example filter 315 comprise respective HART receivers, and the example transmitter 225 comprises a HART transmitter.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">The example filter 315 filters HART commands received via the wires 305 and 306 to identify and/or detect the solenoid valve test command 170. When the solenoid test command 170 is detected on the bus 305, 306, the example filter 315 changes the state of the SSR 165. In some examples, a first HART command is used to change the state of the SSR 165 to a first state and a second HART command is used to change the state of the SSR 165 to a second or different state. In other examples, a HART command is used to toggle between the first and second states of the SSR 165. While certain examples described herein implement HART communications and/or commands, the methods and apparatus disclosed herein may use any number and/or type(s) of additional and/or alternative communication<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> protocol(s) and/or commands, such as those associated with Foundation Fieldbus and/or Profibus.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">While an example process control systems 100 and 300 have been illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0001 f0002">FIGS. 1-4</figref>, the elements illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0001 f0002">FIGS. 1-4</figref> may be combined, divided, rearranged, eliminated and/or implemented in any way. Further, the example valve position controller 205, the example receiver 215, the example solenoid tester 220, the example transmitter 225, the example receiver 240, the example filter 315 and/or, more generally, the example valve positioners 105 and 305 may be implemented by hardware, software, firmware and/or any combination of hardware, software and/or firmware. Thus, for example, any of the example valve position controller 205, the example receiver 215, the example solenoid tester 220, the example transmitter 225, the example receiver 240, the example filter 315 and/or, more generally, the example valve positioners 105 and 305 may be implemented by one or more circuit(s), programmable processor(s), application specific integrated circuit(s) (ASIC(s)), programmable logic device(s) (PLD(s)) and/or field programmable logic device(s) (FPLD(s)), etc. When any of the appended apparatus claims are read to cover a purely software and/or firmware implementation, at least one of the example valve position controller 205, the example receiver 215, the example solenoid tester 220, the example transmitter 225, the example receiver 240, the example filter 315 and/or, more generally, the example valve positioners 105 and 305 are hereby expressly defined to include a tangible medium such as a memory, a digital versatile disc (DVD), a compact disc (CD), etc. storing the software and/or firmware. Further still, the example process control systems 100 and 300 may include elements in addition to, or instead of, those illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0001 f0002">FIGS. 1-4</figref>, and/or may include more than one of any or all of the illustrated elements. For example, while a single valve positioner 105, a single solenoid valve 110 and a single process control valve 115 are shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGS. 1</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0002">3</figref>, the example process control systems 100 and 300 may include any number and/or type(s) of process controllers, SIS controllers, valve positioners, solenoid valves and/or process control valves. Any or all of the additional valve positioners may implement the example solenoid tester 220, the example transmitter 225, the example test contacts 230 and the example receiver 240 to test a respective solenoid valve 110 via a respective SSR 165 and/or a respective filter 315.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031"><figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 5</figref> is a flowchart representative of an example process that may be carried out to implement the example solenoid tester 220 and/or the example valve positioners 105 and 305 of <figref idrefs="f0001 f0002">FIGS. 1-4</figref>. The example process of <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 5</figref> may be carried upon<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> when commanded by the example process controller 125 and/or the example SIS controller 150, and/or may be automatically carried out by the valve positioner 105, 305 on a periodic or aperiodic basis. The example process of <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 5</figref> may be carried out by a processor, a controller and/or any other suitable processing device. For example, the process of <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 5</figref> may be embodied in coded instructions stored on any article of manufacture, such as any tangible computer-readable medium. Example tangible computer-readable medium include, but are not limited to, a flash memory, a CD, a DVD, a floppy disk, a read-only memory (ROM), a random-access memory (RAM), a programmable ROM (PROM), an electronically-programmable ROM (EPROM), and/or an electronically-erasable PROM (EEPROM), an optical storage disk, an optical storage device, magnetic storage disk, a magnetic storage device, and/or any other medium which can be used to carry or store program code and/or instructions in the form of machine-accessible instructions or data structures, and which can be electronically accessed by a processor, a general-purpose or special-purpose computer, or other machine with a processor (e.g., the example processor platform P100 discussed below in connection with <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 6</figref>). Combinations of the above are also included within the scope of computer-readable media. Machine-accessible instructions comprise, for example, instructions and/or data that cause a processor, a general-purpose computer, special-purpose computer, or a special-purpose processing machine to implement one or more particular processes. Alternatively, some or all of the example process of <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 5</figref> may be implemented using any combination(s) of ASIC(s), PLD(s), FPLD(s), discrete logic, hardware, firmware, etc. Also, some or all of the example process of <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 5</figref> may instead be implemented manually or as any combination of any of the foregoing techniques, for example, any combination of firmware, software, discrete logic and/or hardware. Further, many other methods of implementing the example operations of <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 5</figref> may be employed. For example, the order of execution of the blocks may be changed, and/or one or more of the blocks described may be changed, eliminated, sub-divided, or combined. Additionally, any or all of the example process of <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 5</figref> may be carried out sequentially and/or carried out in parallel by, for example, separate processing threads, processors, devices, discrete logic, circuits, etc.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">The example process of <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 5</figref> begins with the example solenoid tester 220 sending a solenoid test control signal 170 to the filter 315 and/or the SSR 165 via the example transmitter 225 (block 505). The solenoid tester 220 monitors the state, output and/or position of the solenoid 155 and/or the solenoid valve 110 via the monitor signal 180<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> (block 510). For example, the solenoid tester 220 can monitor the position of the solenoid plunger 156.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">If the monitor signal 180 represents an intended operation of the solenoid 155 and/or the solenoid valve 110 (block 515), the example solenoid tester 220 sends a second test control signal 170 to the filter 315 and/or the SSR 165 to restore the previous state of the solenoid 155 and/or the solenoid valve 110 (block 520). Control then exits from the example process of <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 5</figref>.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">If the monitor signal 180 does not represent an intended operation of the solenoid 155 and/or the solenoid valve 110 (block 515), the solenoid 155 and/or the solenoid valve 110 is flagged and/or identified as potentially faulty (block 525). Control then proceeds to block 520.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035"><figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 6</figref> is a schematic diagram of an example processor platform P100 that may be used and/or programmed to implement the example solenoid tester 220 and/or the example valve positioners 105 and 305 of <figref idrefs="f0001 f0002">FIGS. 1-4</figref>. For example, the processor platform P100 can be implemented by one or more general-purpose processors, processor cores, microcontrollers, etc.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">The processor platform P100 of the example of <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 6</figref> includes at least one general purpose programmable processor P105. The processor P105 executes coded and/or machine-accessible instructions P110 and/or P112 stored in main memory of the processor P105 (e.g., within a RAM P115 and/or a ROM P120). The processor P105 may be any type of processing unit, such as a processor core, a processor and/or a microcontroller. The processor P105 may execute, among other things, the example process of <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 5</figref> to implement the example methods, apparatus and articles of manufacture described herein.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">The processor P105 is in communication with the main memory (including a ROM P 120 and/or the RAM P 115) via a bus P 125. The RAM P115 may be implemented by DRAM, SDRAM, and/or any other type of RAM device, and ROM may be implemented by flash memory and/or any other desired type of memory device. Access to the memory P115 and the memory P120 may be controlled by a memory controller (not shown).</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">The processor platform P100 also includes an interface circuit P 125. The interface circuit P125 may be implemented by any type of interface standard, such as an external memory interface, serial port, general-purpose input/output, etc. One or more input devices P130 and one or more output devices P130 are connected to the interface circuit P125. The input devices P135 may be used to, for example, implement the example receivers<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> 215 and 240. The output devices P140 may be used to, for example, implement the example transmitter 225.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">Although certain example methods, apparatus and articles of manufacture have been described herein, the scope of coverage of this patent is not limited thereto. On the contrary, this patent covers all methods, apparatus and articles of manufacture fairly falling within the scope of the appended claims.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56983382" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Ventilstellungsregelvorrichtung (100), Folgendes umfassend:
<claim-text>ein Relais (165) zum Regeln eines Zustands eines Elektromagneten (155); und</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Ventilstellungseinrichung (105), die aufweist:
<claim-text>einen Sender (225) zum Übertragen eines Elektromagnetprüfsignals (170) an das Relais (165);</claim-text>
<claim-text>elektrische Kontakte (230) zum kommunikativen Einkoppeln des Elektromagnetprüfsignals (170) in das Relais (165) über einen Draht oder mehrere Drähte (175); und</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Elektromagnetprüfer (220) zum Generieren des Elektromagnetprüfsignals (170) und zum Überwachen eines Ansprechens des Elektromagneten (155), wenn das Elektromagnetprüfsignal (170) an das Relais (165) übertragen ist, um einen Betrieb des Elektromagneten (155) zu überprüfen.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Ventilstellungsregelvorrichtung (100) nach Anspruch 1, darüber hinaus umfassend: ein Prozesssteuerungsventil (115); und<br/>
einen Sicherheitssystem-(SIS)-Regler (150) zum Prüfen eines Sicherheitsbetriebs des Prozesssteuerungsventils (115), indem ein Energieversorgungssignal (160) für den Elektromagneten (155) ausgewählt und eine Stellung des Prozesssteuerungsventils (115) im Ansprechen auf die Auswahl des Energieversorgungssignals (160) überwacht wird, wobei das Relais (165) dazu bestimmt ist, eine elektrische Einkopplung des ausgewählten Energieversorgungssignals (160) in den Elektromagneten (155) beim Eingang des Elektromagnetprüfsignals (170) zu unterbrechen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Ventilstellungsregelvorrichtung (100) nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Ventilstellungseinrichtung (105) darüber hinaus einen Empfänger (240) zum Empfangen eines Signals (180) umfasst, das für eine Elektromagnettauchankerstellung repräsentativ<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> ist, wobei der Elektromagnetprüfer (220) dazu bestimmt ist, den Betrieb des Elektromagneten (155) auf Grundlage des empfangenen Signals (180) zu überprüfen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Ventilstellungsregelvorrichtung (100) nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Ventilstellungseinrichtung (105) darüber hinaus einen Empfänger (240) zum Empfangen eines Signals (180) umfasst, das für einen Druck eines Pneumatikausgangs eines mit dem Elektromagneten (155) verbundenen Magnetventils (110) repräsentativ ist, wobei der Elektromagnetprüfer (220) dazu bestimmt ist, den Betrieb des Magnetventils (110) auf Grundlage des empfangenen Signals (180) zu überprüfen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Ventilstellungsregelvorrichtung (100) nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Ventilstellungseinrichtung (105) darüber hinaus umfasst:
<claim-text>einen Empfänger (215) zum Empfangen eines Ventilstellungsregelsignals (120); und</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Ventilstellungsregler (205) zum Regeln der Stellung eines Prozesssteuerungsventils (115) im Ansprechen auf das empfangene Ventilstellungsregelsignal (120).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Ventilstellungsregelvorrichtung (100) nach Anspruch 1, wobei das Relais (165) dazu bestimmt ist, eine elektrische Einkopplung eines Energieversorgungssignals (160) in den Elektromagneten (155) beim Eingang des Elektromagnetprüfsignals (170) zu unterbrechen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Ventilstellungsregelvorrichtung (100) nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Ventilstellungseinrichtung (105) darüber hinaus umfasst:
<claim-text>einen Empfänger (215) zum Empfangen eines Ventilstellungsregelsignals (120) über den einen Draht oder die mehreren Drähte (130); und</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Ventilstellungsregler (205) zum Regeln der Stellung eines Prozesssteuerungsventils (115) im Ansprechen auf das empfangene Ventilstellungsregelsignal<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> (120), wobei der Sender (225) einen mittels Datenbus adressierbaren Fernmesswertaufnehmer-(HART)-Sender umfasst, und das Elektromagnetprüfsignal (170) ein HART-Steuersignal umfasst.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Ventilstellungsregelvorrichtung (100) nach Anspruch 7, darüber hinaus einen HART-Messwertaufnehmer umfassend, der kommunikativ mit dem Relais (165) gekoppelt ist, wobei der HART-Messwertaufnehmer dazu bestimmt ist, das Elektromagnetprüfsignal (170) vom Sender (225) über den einen Draht oder die mehreren Drähte (175) zu empfangen und einen Zustand des Relais (165) im Ansprechen auf das Elektromagnetprüfsignal (170) zu regeln.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Verfahren, Folgendes umfassend: Auswählen eines Energieversorgungsunterbrechungssteuersignals (170) zum Auswählen eines Zustands eines Sicherheitssystem-(SIS)-Elektromagneten (110);<br/>
Übertragen des Energieversorgungsunterbrechungssteuersignals (170) von einem Ventilstellungsregler (105) an ein Relais (165) über einen Draht oder mehrere Drähte (175), um den SIS-Elektromagneten (110) auf den ausgewählten Zustand zu konfigurieren; und<br/>
Überwachen eines Ansprechens des SIS-Elektromagneten (110) auf den ausgewählten Zustand, um einen Betrieb des SIS-Elektromagneten (110) zu überprüfen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 9, wobei das Übertragen des Energieversorgungsunterbrechungssteuersignals (170) an das Relais (165) einen Zustand des Relais (165) zum Unterbrechen eines Energieversorgungssignals (160) des SIS-Elektromagneten (110) verändert.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 9, wobei das Überwachen des Ansprechens des SIS-Elektromagneten (110) auf den ausgewählten Zustand umfasst:
<claim-text>Empfangen eines Signals (180), das für einen gegenwärtigen Zustand eines Elektromagneten des SIS-Elektromagneten (110) repräsentativ ist; und Bestimmen, ob das Energieversorgungsunterbrechungssteuersignal (170) den SIS-Elektromagneten<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> (110) auf den ausgewählten Zustand konfiguriert hat, und zwar auf Grundlage des empfangenen Signals (180).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 9, darüber hinaus umfassend:
<claim-text>Empfangen eine Ventilstellungsregelsignals (120) über den einen Draht oder die mehreren Drähte (130); und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Regeln der Stellung eines Prozesssteuerungsventils (115) im Ansprechen auf das empfangene Ventilstellungsregelsignal (120).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 9, wobei das Ventilstellungsregelsignal (120) einen ersten mittels Datenbus adressierbaren Fernmesswertaufnehmer-(HART)-Befehl umfasst, und das Energieversorgungsunterbrechungssteuersignal (170) einen zweiten HART-Befehl umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Programm, das dazu angepasst ist, das Verfahren der Ansprüche 9 bis 13 durchzuführen, und in Form von maschinenlesbaren Anweisungen gespeichert ist, die, wenn sie ausgeführt werden, bewirken, dass eine Maschine:
<claim-text>ein Energieversorgungsunterbrechungssteuersignal (170) zum Auswählen eines Zustands eines Sicherheitssystem-(SIS)-Elektromagneten (110) auswählt;</claim-text>
<claim-text>das Energieversorgungsunterbrechungssteuersignal (170) von einem Ventilregler (105) an ein Relais (165) über einen Draht oder mehrere Drähte (175) überträgt, um den SIS-Elektromagneten (110) auf den ausgewählten Zustand zu konfigurieren;</claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Ansprechen des SIS-Elektromagneten (110) auf den ausgewählten Zustand überwacht, um einen Betrieb des SIS-Elektromagneten (110) zu überprüfen;</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Zustand des Relais (165) zum Unterbrechen eines Energieversorgungssignals (160) des SIS-Elektromagneten (110) verändert;<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Signal (180) empfängt, das für einen gegenwärtigen Zustand eines Elektromagneten des SIS-Elektromagneten (110) repräsentativ ist, um zu bestimmen, ob das Energieversorgungsunterbrechungssteuersignal (170) den SIS-Elektromagneten (110) auf den ausgewählten Zustand konfiguriert hat, und zwar auf Grundlage des empfangenen Signals (180);</claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Ventilstellungsregelsignal (120) über den einen oder die mehreren Drähte (130) empfängt; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>die Stellung eines Prozesssteuerungsventils (115) im Ansprechen auf das empfangene Ventilstellungsregelsignal (120) regelt.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56983383" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A valve position control apparatus (100) comprising:
<claim-text>a relay (165) to control a state of a solenoid (155); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a valve positioner (105) including:
<claim-text>a transmitter (225) to transmit a solenoid test signal (170) to the relay (165);</claim-text>
<claim-text>electrical contacts (230) to communicatively couple the solenoid test signal (170) to the relay (165) via one or more wires (175); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a solenoid tester (220) to generate the solenoid test signal (170) and to monitor a response of the solenoid (155) when the solenoid test signal (170) is transmitted to the relay (165) to verify an operation of the solenoid (155).</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>A valve position control apparatus (100) as defined in claim 1, further comprising: a process control valve (115); and<br/>
a safety instrumented system (SIS) controller (150) to test a safety operation of the process control valve (115) by selecting a power supply signal (160) for the solenoid (155) and monitoring a position of the process control valve (115) in response to the selection of the power supply signal (160), wherein the relay (165) is to interrupt electrical coupling of the selected power supply signal (160) to the solenoid (155) when the solenoid test signal (170) is received.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>A valve position control apparatus (100) as defined in claim 1, wherein the valve positioner (105) further comprises a receiver (240) to receive a<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> signal (180) representative of a solenoid plunger position, wherein the solenoid tester (220) is to verify the operation of the solenoid (155) based on the received signal (180).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>A valve position control apparatus (100) as defined in claim 1, wherein the valve positioner (105) further comprises a receiver (240) to receive a signal (180) representative a pressure of a pneumatic output of a solenoid valve (110) associated with the solenoid (155), wherein the solenoid tester (220) is to verify the operation of the solenoid valve (110) based on the received signal (180).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>A valve position control apparatus (100) as defined in claim 1, wherein the valve positioner (105) further comprises:
<claim-text>a receiver (215) to receive a valve position control signal (120); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a valve position controller (205) to control the position of a process control valve (115) in response to the received valve position control signal (120).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>A valve position control apparatus (100) as defined in claim 1, wherein the relay (165) is to interrupt electrical coupling of a power supply signal (160) to the solenoid (155) when the solenoid test signal (170) is received.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>A valve position control apparatus (100) as defined in claim 1, wherein the valve positioner (105) further comprises:
<claim-text>a receiver (215) to receive a valve position control signal (120) via the one or more wires (130); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a valve position controller (205) to control the position of a process control valve (115) in response to the received valve position control signal (120), wherein the transmitter (225) comprises a highway addressable remote transducer (HART) transmitter and the solenoid test signal (170) comprises a HART control signal.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>A valve position control apparatus (100) as defined in claim 7, further comprising a HART transducer communicatively coupled to the relay (165), the HART transducer to receive the solenoid test signal (170) from the transmitter (225) via the one or more wires (175) and to control a state of the relay (165) in response to the solenoid test signal (170).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>A method comprising: selecting a power supply interruption control signal (170) to select a state of a safety instrumented system (SIS) solenoid (110);<br/>
transmitting the power supply interruption control signal (170) from a valve controller (105) to a relay (165) via one or more wires (175) to configure the SIS solenoid (110) to the selected state; and<br/>
monitoring a response of the SIS solenoid (110) to the selected state to verify an operation of the SIS solenoid (110).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>A method as defined in claim 9, wherein transmitting the power supply interruption control signal (170) to the relay (165) changes a state of the relay (165) to interrupt a power supply signal (160) of the SIS solenoid (110).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>A method as defined in claim 9, wherein monitoring the response of the SIS solenoid (110) to the selected state comprises:
<claim-text>receiving a signal (180) representative of a present state of a solenoid of the SIS solenoid (110); and determining whether the power supply interruption control signal (170) configured the SIS solenoid (110) to the selected state based on the received signal (180).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>A method as defined in claim 9, further comprising:
<claim-text>receiving a valve position control signal (120) via the one or more wires (130); and<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>controlling the position of a process control valve (115) in response to the received valve position control signal (120).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>A method as defined in claim 9, wherein the valve position control signal (120) comprises a first highway addressable remote transducer (HART) command and the power supply interruption control signal (170) comprises a second HART command.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>A program adapted to perform the method of claims 9 to 13 and stored as machine-readable instructions that, when executed, cause a machine to:
<claim-text>select a power supply interruption control signal (170) to select a state of a safety instrumented system (SIS) solenoid (110);</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmit the power supply interruption control signal (170) from a valve controller (105) to a relay (165) via one or more wires (175) to configure the SIS solenoid (110) to the selected state;</claim-text>
<claim-text>monitor a response of the SIS solenoid (110) to the selected state to verify an operation of the SIS solenoid (110);</claim-text>
<claim-text>change a state of the relay (165) to interrupt a power supply signal (160) of the SIS solenoid (110);</claim-text>
<claim-text>receive a signal (180) representative of a present state of a solenoid of the SIS solenoid (110) to determine whether the power supply interruption control signal (170) configured the SIS solenoid (110) to the selected state based on the received signal (180);</claim-text>
<claim-text>receive a valve position control signal (120) via the one or more wires (130); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>control the position of a process control valve (115) in response to the received valve position control signal (120).</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56983384" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Appareil de commande de position de vanne comprenant :
<claim-text>un relais (165) pour commander un état d'un électro-aimant (155) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un positionneur de vanne (105) comprenant :
<claim-text>un émetteur (225) pour transmettre un signal de test d'électro-aimant (170) au relais (165) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>des contacts électriques (230) pour coupler de façon communicante le signal de test d'électro-aimant (170) au relais (165) par l'intermédiaire d'un ou plusieurs fils(175) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un testeur d'électro-aimant (220) pour produire le signal de test d'électro-aimant (170), et pour surveiller une réponse de l'électro-aimant (155) lorsque le signal de test d'électro-aimant (170) est transmis au relais (165) pour vérifier un fonctionnement de l'électro-aimant (155).</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Appareil de commande de position de vanne (100) selon la revendication 1, comprenant en outre : une vanne de commande de traitement (115) ; et<br/>
une commande (150) de système de sécurité actif (SIS) pour tester une opération de sécurité de la vanne de commande de traitement (115) en sélectionnant un signal d'alimentation électrique (160) pour l'électro-aimant (155) et en surveillant une position de la vanne de commande de traitement (115) en réponse à la sélection du signal d'alimentation électrique (160), dans lequel le relais (165) est destiné à interrompre le couplage électrique du signal d'alimentation électrique sélectionné (160) avec l'électro-aimant (155) lorsque le signal de test d'électro-aimant (170) est reçu.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Appareil de commande de position de vanne (100) selon la revendication 1, dans lequel le positionneur de vanne (105) comprend en outre un récepteur (240) pour recevoir un signal (180) représentatif d'une position de piston plongeur d'électro-aimant, dans lequel le testeur d'électro-aimant (220) est destiné à<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --> vérifier le fonctionnement de l'électro-aimant (155) sur la base du signal reçu (180).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Appareil de commande de position de vanne selon la revendication 1, dans lequel le positionneur de vanne (105) comprend en outre un récepteur (240) pour recevoir un signal (180) représentatif d'une pression d'une sortie pneumatique d'une électrovanne (110) associée à l'électro-aimant (155), dans lequel le testeur d'électro-aimant (220) est destiné à vérifier le fonctionnement de l'électrovanne (110) sur la base du signal reçu (180).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Appareil de commande de position de vanne (100) selon la revendication 1, dans lequel le positionneur de vanne (105) comprend en outre :
<claim-text>un récepteur (215) pour recevoir un signal de commande de position de vanne (120) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>une commande de position de vanne (205) pour commander la position d'une vanne de commande de traitement (115) en réponse au signal de commande de position de vanne reçu (120).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Appareil de commande de position de vanne (100) selon la revendication 1, dans lequel le relais (165) est destiné à interrompre un couplage électrique d'un signal d'alimentation électrique (160) avec l'électro-aimant (155) lorsque le signal de test d'électro-aimant (170) est reçu.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Appareil de commande de position de vanne (100) selon la revendication 1, dans lequel le positionneur de vanne (105) comprend en outre :
<claim-text>un récepteur (215) pour recevoir un signal de commande de position de vanne (120) par l'intermédiaire des un ou plusieurs fils (130) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>une commande de position de vanne (205) pour commander la position d'une vanne de commande de traitement (115) en réponse au signal de commande de position de vanne reçu (120), dans lequel l'émetteur (225) comprend un émetteur<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> de transducteur à distance adressable par bus (HART) et le signal de test de l'électro-aimant (170) comprend un signal de commande de HART.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Appareil de commande de position de vanne (100) selon la revendication 7, comprenant en outre un transducteur HART couplé en communication avec le relais (165), le transducteur HART étant destiné à recevoir le signal de test d'électro-aimant (170) provenant de l'émetteur (225) par l'intermédiaire des un ou plusieurs fils (175) et à commander un état du relais (165) en réponse au signal de test d'électro-aimant (170).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Procédé comprenant : la sélection d'un signal de commande d'interruption d'alimentation électrique (170) pour sélectionner l'état d'un électro-aimant (110) de système de sécurité actif (SIS);<br/>
la transmission du signal de commande d'interruption d'alimentation électrique (170) provenant d'une commande de vanne (105) à un relais (165) par l'intermédiaire d'un ou plusieurs fils (175) pour configurer l'électro-aimant de SIS (110) dans l'état sélectionné ; et<br/>
la surveillance d'une réponse de l'électro-aimant de SIS (110) à l'état sélectionné pour vérifier un fonctionnement de l'électro-aimant de SIS (110).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 9, dans lequel la transmission du signal de commande d'interruption d'alimentation électrique (170) vers le relais (165) change un état du relais (165) pour interrompre un signal d'alimentation électrique (160) de l'électro-aimant de SIS (110).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 9, dans lequel la surveillance de la réponse de l'électro-aimant de SIS (110) à l'état sélectionné consiste à :
<claim-text>réceptionner un signal (180) représentatif d'un état actuel d'un électro-aimant de l'électro-aimant de SIS (110) ; et déterminer si le signal de commande d'interruption d'alimentation électrique (170) a configuré l'électro-aimant de SIS (110) à l'état sélectionné sur la base du signal reçu (180).</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 9, consistant en outre à :
<claim-text>recevoir un signal de commande de position de vanne (120) par l'intermédiaire des un ou plusieurs fils (130) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>commander la position d'une vanne de commande de traitement (115) en réponse au signal de commande de position de vanne reçu (120).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 9, dans lequel le signal de commande de position de vanne (120) comprend une première instruction de transducteur à distance adressable par bus (HART) et le signal de commande d'interruption de l'alimentation électrique (170) comprend une seconde instruction de HART.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Programme adapté pour exécuter le procédé des revendications 9 à 13 et mémorisé sous forme d'instructions lisibles par machine qui, lorsqu'elles sont exécutées, amènent une machine à :
<claim-text>sélectionner un signal de commande d'interruption d'alimentation électrique 170) pour sélectionner un état d'électro-aimant (110) d'un système de sécurité actif (SIS) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmettre le signal de commande d'interruption d'alimentation électrique (170) provenant d'une commande de vanne (105) à un relais (165) par l'intermédiaire d'un ou plusieurs fils (175) pour configurer l'électro-aimant de SIS (110) dans l'état sélectionné ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>surveiller une réponse de l'électro-aimant de SIS (110) à l'état sélectionné pour vérifier un fonctionnement de l'électro-aimant de SIS (110) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>changer l'état du relais (165) pour interrompre un signal d'alimentation électrique (160) de l'électro-aimant de SIS (110) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>recevoir un signal (180) représentatif d'un état actuel d'un électro-aimant de l'électro-aimant de SIS (110) pour déterminer si le signal de commande d'interruption d'alimentation électrique (170) a configuré l'électro-aimant de SIS (110) dans l'état sélectionné sur la base du signal reçu (180) ;<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>recevoir un signal de commande de position de vanne (120) par l'intermédiaire des un ou plusieurs fils (130) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>commander la position d'une vanne de commande de traitement (115) en réponse au signal de commande de position de vanne reçu (120).</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16671537" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1,2"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="165" he="222" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --><figure id="f0002" num="3,4"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="165" he="226" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --><figure id="f0003" num="5"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="114" he="191" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --><figure id="f0004" num="6"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="126" he="167" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
