<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2442595-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2442595" kind="B1" date="20140101" family-id="43308427" file-reference-id="318281" date-produced="20180823" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146552397" ucid="EP-2442595-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2442595</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-10785749-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154826320" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>10785749</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20100609</date><lang>ZH</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140454909" ucid="CN-200910086566-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>CN</country><doc-number>200910086566</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20090609</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140450846" ucid="CN-2010073702-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>CN</country><doc-number>2010073702</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20100609</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130731</date></intention-to-grant-date><search-report-dispatch-date><date>20121203</date></search-report-dispatch-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988123631" load-source="ipcr">H04W   4/20        20090101AFI20121127BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988131815" load-source="ipcr">H04L   1/00        20060101ALI20121127BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988135261" load-source="ipcr">H04W  52/02        20090101ALI20121127BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988099908" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04L   1/0025      20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988102885" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04L   1/0003      20130101 FI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988121861" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04W  28/18        20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988132236" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04W   4/06        20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132189675" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">DATENÜBERTRAGUNGSVERFAHREN UND -SYSTEM SOWIE VORRICHTUNG DAFÜR</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132189676" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">DATA TRANSMISSION METHOD, SYSTEM AND APPARATUS THEREOF</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132189677" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">PROCÉDÉ D'ÉMISSION DE DONNÉES, SYSTÈME ET APPAREIL ASSOCIÉS</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918164364" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>CHINA ACADEMY OF TELECOMM TECH</last-name><address><country>CN</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918161134" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>CHINA ACADEMY OF TELECOMMUNICATIONS TECHNOLOGY</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918171358" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>ZHAO YI</last-name><address><country>CN</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918162818" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>ZHAO, YI</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918994950" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>ZHAO, YI</last-name><address><street>No. 29 Xueyuan Road Haidian</street><city>Beijing 100083</city><country>CN</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918162416" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>DING YU</last-name><address><country>CN</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918166305" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>DING, YU</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918994952" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>DING, YU</last-name><address><street>No. 29 Xueyuan Road Haidian</street><city>Beijing 100083</city><country>CN</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918143625" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>YANG XIAODONG</last-name><address><country>CN</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918159479" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>YANG, XIAODONG</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918994951" load-source="patent-office" sequence="3" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>YANG, XIAODONG</last-name><address><street>No. 29 Xueyuan Road Haidian</street><city>Beijing 100083</city><country>CN</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918994953" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>China Academy of Telecommunications Technology</last-name><iid>101243508</iid><address><street>40, Xueyuan Road</street><city>Haidian District Beijing 100191</city><country>CN</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918994954" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Leszczynski, André</last-name><iid>101291537</iid><address><street>Cabinet Nony 3, rue de Penthièvre</street><city>75008 Paris</city><country>FR</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="CN-2010073702-W"><document-id><country>CN</country><doc-number>2010073702</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20100609</date><lang>ZH</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2010142236-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2010142236</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20101216</date><lang>ZH</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548947372" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS548948545" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS548822187" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS548959414" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS548875125" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS548822188" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS548953620" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS548947373" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548822189" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS548822190" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS548958560" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS548959415" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS548875126" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548947374" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548822191" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS548947375" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS548953621" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS548875127" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS548822192" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS548959416" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS548822193" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS548959417" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS548948546" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS548959422" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS548959423" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS548948547" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS548948548" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS548958561" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS548847152" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS548958562" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS548959424" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS548953622" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS548958563" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS548875128" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS548847153" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS548847154" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS548948549" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63956815" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001"><b>Field of the Invention</b></heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to the field of communications and particularly to a data transmission method, system and device.</p><heading id="h0002"><b>Background of the Invention</b></heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">The technology of Multimedia Broadcast Multicast Service (MBMS) is intended to provide a user in radio cellular systems with a multimedia broadcast and multicast service. The MBMS in a Long Term Evolution (LTE) system is also referred to as an evolved MBMS (eMBMS). The eMBMS in an existing LTE Release 9 (LTE R9) system is performed in MBMS/Unicast-mixed cells, that is, a unicast service can also be transmitted in a cell where an MBMS is transmitted to perform coordinated transmission of the unicast service and the MBMS by transmitting the MBMS at some instances of time and the unicast service at other instances of time. Furthermore, the MBMS is transmitted in the LTE R9 system with Multicast Broadcast Single Frequency Network (MBSFN) mode, that is, the same content of information is transmitted concurrently in multiple cells at the same frequency at the same time.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">A logical channel is such an interface to a high layer protocol that is defined at a Media Access Control (MAC) layer which provides the logical channel with a data transmission service. The type of transmitted data service on different logical channel is distinguished by the type of the logical channel. A transport channel is an interface provided at a physical layer for a high layer (e.g., the MAC layer) to transmit data, and the type of the transport channel is defined dependent upon a transmission characteristic and a transmission scheme of the data at the physical layer.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">In the LTE system, existing logical channels involved in transmission of an MBMS generally include a Broadcast Control Channel (BCCH), a Multicast Control Channel (MCCH) and a Multicast Traffic Channel (MTCH). Transport channels generally include a Multicast Channel (MCH), a Broadcast Channel (BCH) and a Downlink Shared Channel (DL-SCH), all of which are downlink channels.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">In the LTE R9 system, logical channels and transport channels have a mapping<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> relationship as illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, where the BCCH is mapped onto the BCH or the DL-SCH, and in the MBMS/Unicast-mixed cells, the MTCH and the MCCH are mapped onto the MCH. These channels primarily function as follows.</p><heading id="h0003">(1) BCCH</heading><p id="p0006" num="0006">System information is transmitted over the broadcast control channel from a network to a User Equipment (UE). For the MBMS, configuration information of the MCCH, e.g., the repetition period of the MCCH, an offset of a starting sub-frame of the MCCH, an amount of sub-frames occupied by the MCCH, and a configuration of Radio Link Control Unacknowledged Mode (RLC UM), is carried over the BCCH so that the UE can locate the resource of the MCCH, but no specific MBMS traffic information is carried over the BCCH.</p><heading id="h0004">(2) MCCH</heading><p id="p0007" num="0007">The multicast control channel is a point-to-multipoint downlink channel over which MBMS-related control information is transmitted to the UE from the network, and one MCCH may correspond to one or more MTCHs, that is, control information of a plurality of MTCHs may be carried over the MCCH.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">Information carried over the MCCH includes configuration information of an MBMS logical channel (e.g., the MTCH, and an MSCH), information of an MBMS Radio Bearer (RB) (e.g., the RB index information of RBs provided in a modification period of the MCCH), information of an MBMS Session Start, and information of an MBMS Session Stop.</p><heading id="h0005">(3) MTCH</heading><p id="p0009" num="0009">The multicast traffic channel is a point-to-multipoint downlink channel over which specific MBMS traffic data is transmitted to the UE from the network.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">The MTCH and the MCCH may be mapped onto the same MCH, that is, the MTCH and the MCCH are multiplexed at the MAC layer. The MTCH and the MCCH may be multiplexed at the MAC layer through Time Division Multiplexing (TDM), or TDM-based internal multiplexing in a Transport Block (TB).</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">Particularly, transmission of data over a transport channel through TDM refers to time-division transmission of data of logical channels multiplexed over the same transport channel, that is, data of only one of the logical channels multiplexed over the transport channel<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> can be transmitted in one sub-frame allocated to the transport channel. With multiplexing through TDM, data information over the MTCH and the MCCH is transmitted respectively over different sub-frames corresponding to the MCH, as illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2</figref>.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">As illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 3</figref>, if the entire resource of a sub-frame can not be occupied by data of a logical channel, the remaining part of the sub-frame shall be filled with padding bits. Therefore, transmission of data over a transport channel through TDM-based internal multiplexing in a TB means that firstly data of a specific logical channel (or a set of logical channels), e.g., data of the MCCH, or a combination of data of the MCCH and another logical channel (e.g., the MBMS Scheduling Channel (MSCH) over which scheduling information of an MBMS is transmitted), is transmitted through TDM, and when all of the data over the specific logical channel or the set of logical channels in a specific sub-frame has been transmitted but the resource available from the TB of the sub-frame has not been exhausted, data of another logical channel (or a set of logical channels) is allowed to be transmitted in the same TB.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">In the existing LTE system, one sub-frame corresponds to one TB for each transport channel, and only one Modulation and Coding Scheme (MCS) is adopted for the TB. Data of only one MCH transport channel may be present in an MBSFN sub-frame occupied for MBMS transmission. Since MBMS-related control information is carried over the MCCH, a different modulation and coding scheme from that for transmission of data of another logical channel (e.g., the MTCH) is typically adopted to improve the reliability of reception at the UE so that the UE can receive the MBMS-related control information reliably. However, when data of logical channels, such as the MCCH and the MTCH, is multiplexed over the same MCH, if a modulation and coding scheme preset for the MCCH is adopted for all of the sub-frames of the MCH, the spectrum efficiency will be low; or if a modulation and coding scheme preset for another logical channel (or a set of logical channels), e.g., the MTCH, is adopted for all of the sub-frames of the MCH, the reliability of the MCCH will fail to be ensured.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">In summary, it is impossible in the existing LTE system to satisfy different transmission quality requirements of data over a plurality of types of MBMS-related logical channels mapped onto the same transport channel for which only one MCS can be adopted.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">It is disclosed in <nplcit id="ncit0001" npl-type="s"><text>Alcatel-Lucent Shanghai Bell et al: "Considerations on MCCH<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> transmission scheme", 3GPP draft R2-093094</text></nplcit>, whereon the preamble of claim 1 is based, that MCCH and MTCH are multiplexed into one TB. That means in one MAC PDU the MCCH and MTCH are multiplexed as different logical channel data to form different MAC SDU. However, since QoS requirement for control information and service data is different and MCCH transmission would be transmitted in different MBSFN subframe according to RP and MP setting which would lead to multiplex with different service data transmission, some rules should be defined in order to have a fixed MCS or to inform the UE in advance (e.g., the MCS for MCCH could be standardized and used for MCCH/MTCH multiplexed TB or another option could rely on using system information to configure the MCS for MCCH and for MCCH and MTCH multiplexing TB in advanced).</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">It is disclosed in Etsi Mcc: "Draft report of 3GPP TSG RAN WG2 meeting 66" that if MCCH and MTCH are multiplexed in the same MCH, it would be possible to work with a different QoS if the MCCH subframes are specifically indicated on BCH. However, it is not sure different QoS is needed and a varying QoS would have implication for the scheduling. Further, BCCH indicates PMCH configuration, including MSAP and MCS.</p><heading id="h0006"><b>Summary of the Invention</b></heading><p id="p0017" num="0017">Embodiments of the invention provide a data transmission method, system and device as recited in the accompanying claims to satisfy transmission quality requirements of data of a plurality of types of MBMS-related logical channels mapped onto the same transport channel.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">In the embodiments of the invention, a plurality of Modulation and Coding Schemes (MCSs) required for the same transport channel onto which a plurality of types of logical channels are mapped, are determined at the network side, and a user equipment is notified of a corresponding relationship between the logical channels and the MCSs; and data of the logical channels mapped onto the transport channel is modulated and encoded at the network side according to the MCSs required for the transport channel and then transmitted to the user equipment over the transport channel, so that the MCSs can be adopted over the transport channel, onto which the plurality of types of MBMS-related logical channels are mapped, to thereby satisfy transmission quality requirements of data of the plurality of types of logical channel.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></p><heading id="h0007"><b>Brief Description of the Drawings</b></heading><p id="p0019" num="0019"><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is a schematic diagram of a mapping relationship between logical channels and transport channels;</p><p id="p0020" num="0020"><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2</figref> is a schematic diagram of multiplexing MCCH data and MTCH data through TDM;</p><p id="p0021" num="0021"><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 3</figref> is a schematic diagram of multiplexing MCCH data and MTCH data through TDM-based transport block multiplexing;</p><p id="p0022" num="0022"><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 4</figref> is a schematic diagram of a general flow of a data transmission method according to an embodiment of the invention;</p><p id="p0023" num="0023"><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 5</figref> is a schematic diagram of a transmission scheme of MCCH data according to an embodiment of the invention;</p><p id="p0024" num="0024"><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 6</figref> is a schematic structural diagram of a data transmission device according to an embodiment of the invention;</p><p id="p0025" num="0025"><figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 7</figref> is a schematic structural diagram of an MCS notification unit according to an embodiment of the invention;</p><p id="p0026" num="0026"><figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 8</figref> is a schematic structural diagram of another MCS notification unit according to an embodiment of the invention;</p><p id="p0027" num="0027"><figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 9</figref> is a schematic structural diagram of a transmission processing unit according to an embodiment of the invention; and</p><p id="p0028" num="0028"><figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 10</figref> is a schematic structural diagram of a user equipment according to an embodiment of the invention.</p><heading id="h0008"><b>Detailed Description of the Embodiments</b></heading><p id="p0029" num="0029">Embodiments of the invention provide a data transmission method, system and device to satisfy transmission quality requirements of data over a plurality of types of MBMS-related logical channels mapped onto the same transport channel.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">Technical solutions according to the embodiments of the invention will be described hereinafter with reference to the drawings.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 4</figref>, a data transmission method according to an embodiment of the<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> invention includes the following steps.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">S101. A plurality of Modulation and Coding Schemes (MCSs) required for the same transport channel, onto which a plurality of types of logical channels are mapped, are determined at the network side, and a user equipment is notified of a corresponding relationship between the logical channels and the MCSs.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">S102. Data of the logical channels mapped onto the transport channel is modulated and encoded at the network side according to the required MCSs and then transmitted to the user equipment over the transport channel.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">Preferably, the corresponding relationship between the logical channels and the MCSs may be represented as a corresponding relationship between the logical channels and indexes of the MCSs. Here a type of logical channel corresponds to only one MCS at a transmission instance of time, and each type of logical channel may or may not correspond to the same MCS.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">In an embodiment of the invention, the user equipment may be notified of the corresponding relationship in the step S101 in the following two ways:
<ul><li>the user equipment is notified of the corresponding relationship over a BCCH; or</li><li>one or more types of specific logical channels among the plurality of types of logical channels mapped onto the same transport channel are determined; a corresponding relationship between the specific logical channel(s) and MCS(s) or index(es) of the MCS(s) is transmitted to the user equipment over the BCCH; and a corresponding relationship between the other logical channels mapped onto the same transport channel than the specific logical channel(s) and MCSs or indexes of the MCSs is transmitted to the user equipment over the specific logical channel(s).</li></ul></p><p id="p0036" num="0036">Preferably, the method further includes: before the data of the plurality of types of logical channels is transmitted at the network side to the user equipment over the same transport channel,<br/>
the user equipment is notified at the network side of an amount of sub-frames and/or serial numbers of the sub-frames occupied respectively for the plurality of types of logical channels mapped onto the same transport channel.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">In an embodiment of the invention, the data of the logical channels mapped onto the same transport channel may be modulated and encoded at the network side according to the<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> MCSs required for the transport channel in the step S 102 in the following two ways:
<ul><li>when the data of the plurality of types of logical channels is transmitted over the same transport channel through TDM, data of each type of logical channel is modulated and encoded at the network side according to an MCS corresponding to the logical channel; and</li><li>when the data of the plurality of types of logical channels is transmitted over the same transport channel through TDM-based transport block multiplexing, data of more than one types of logical channels to be transmitted in the same sub-frame is modulated and encoded at the network side according to an MCS with the highest reliability among MCSs corresponding respectively to the more than one types of logical channels while modulating and encoding data of one of the types of logical channels to be transmitted in a separate sub-frame according to an MCS corresponding to the logical channel.</li></ul></p><p id="p0038" num="0038">A description will be given below of how to satisfy transmission quality requirements of data over a plurality of types of MBMS-related logical channels mapped onto the same transport channel by way of an example in which an MCCH and an MTCH are mapped onto the same transport channel MCH.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">In a system providing an MBMS service, MBMS control information is transmitted over an MCCH while ensuring reliable reception of the MBMS control information at a UE; and specific MBMS traffic information is transmitted over an MTCH while ensuring the spectrum efficiency to some extent. In an embodiment of the invention, MCSs of a transport channel are configured so that the reliability of reception of the MCCH can be improved while ensuring the spectrum efficiency of transmitting the MTCH when the MCCH and the MTCH are mapped onto the same transport channel MCH. A specific design of modulation and coding schemes of the transport channel MCH is as follows:
<ul><li>when data of the MCCH and the MTCH is multiplexed through TDM as illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2</figref>, the data of the MCCH is transmitted in a part of sub-frames allocated to the MCH onto which the MCCH and the MTCH are mapped, and the data of the MTCH is transmitted in another part of the sub-frames. Different MCSs are adopted respectively for the sub-frames for transmitting the MCCH data and the sub-frames for transmitting the MTCH data.</li><li>when the data of the MCCH and the MTCH is multiplexed through TDM-based<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> Transport Block (TB) multiplexing as illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 3</figref>, that is, the MCCH data and the MTCH data may be transmitted in the same sub-frame, an MCS preset for the MCCH is adopted for a sub-frame carrying the MCCH data, and an MCS preset for the MTCH is adopted for a sub-frame without any MCCH data.</li></ul></p><p id="p0040" num="0040">The UE may know of which MCS is adopted for which type of logical channel in numerous ways.</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">In a first approach, MCSs adopted for the same MCH are transmitted and a corresponding relationship between the MCCH and an index of an MCS is transmitted to a user equipment over a BCCH; and a corresponding relationship between the MTCH and an index of an MCS is transmitted to the user equipment over the MCCH.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">The user equipment may determine, from the corresponding relationship between the MCCH and the index of the MCS, the MCS adopted for the MCCH data transmitted over the MCH and determine, from the corresponding relationship between the MTCH and the index of the MCS, the MCS adopted for the MTCH data transmitted over the MCH.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">Particularly, the MCSs adopted for the same MCH are transmitted over the BCCH by configuring subsets including such parameters as a TDM Period, an Offset, a Transmission Length, and an MCS, for example:
<ul><li>Subset 1: (TDM Period 1, Offset 1, Transmission Length 1, MCS 1)</li><li>Subset 2: (TDM Period 2, Offset 2, Transmission Length 2, MCS 2)</li><li>Subset 3: (TDM Period 3, Offset 3, Transmission Length 3, MCS 3)</li></ul></p><p id="p0044" num="0044">The MCS included in the subset may also be replaced with the index of the MCS, that is, a corresponding relationship between the indexes of the MCSs and the different logical channels may be transmitted directly at the network side instead of the specific MCSs after negotiation about the MCSs required for the logical channels is performed in advance between the network side and the user equipment.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045">The data of the MCCH and the MTCH may be mapped according to the different subsets at the network side, for example, the data of the MCCH is transmitted according to the parameters in the Subset 1, and the data of the MTCH is transmitted according to the parameters in the Subset 2.<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --></p><p id="p0046" num="0046">Particularly, the TDM Period refers to a period at which a logical channel (or a set of logical channels constituted of a plurality of types of logical channels) appears over the MCH.</p><p id="p0047" num="0047">It shall be noted that in an embodiment of the invention each type of logical channel corresponds to only one MCS and each MCS may correspond to one type of logical channel or to a set of logical channels constituted of a plurality of types of logical channels, i.e., to a plurality of types of logical channels.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048">The TDM Period may be defined by a radio frame and particularly defined by the parameter of radioFramePeriod, for example, radioFramePeriod equal=5 indicates that data of a logical channel (or a set of logical channels) appears once in every 5 radio frames.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">The TDM Period may alternatively be defined based on another event period, for example, an MBMS scheduling period, where if the MBMS scheduling period is 320 milliseconds (ms), a configuration parameter of SchedbasedPeriod based upon the MBMS scheduling period (a scheduling-based period, that is, a period at which a logical channel appears is set based upon a scheduling period) is set, for example, SchedbasedPeriod=2 indicates that data of a logical channel (or a set of logical channels) appears once in every 2 MBMS scheduling periods.</p><p id="p0050" num="0050">The TDM Period may mean differently according to different types of logical channels, for example, for the MCCH, the TDM Period may be a repetition period or a modification period of the MCCH; for the MTCH, the TDM Period may be a scheduling period of the MTCH; and for the MSCH, the TDM Period may be a repetition period or a modification period of the MSCH.</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">The data of the MCCH is transmitted as illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 5</figref>, where each small square represents the data of the MCCH transmitted in a modification period of the MCCH and/or a repetition period of the MCCH. The data of the MCCH is unchanged in the modification period of the MCCH, and if there is a repetition period of the MCCH, the data of the MCCH is retransmitted in the repetition period of the MCCH, and the UE may receive a plurality of pieces of the same information in the modification period of the MCCH and can acquire the current MCCH data as long as it receives correctly the data once. The data of the MCCH may or may not be different between different modification cycles of the MCCH, that is, the data of the MCCH may or may not be modified at the network side upon arrival of each modification<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> period of the MCCH.</p><p id="p0052" num="0052">The Offset refers to the location of a specific sub-frame over the MCH in which data of a logical channel starts, for example, for the TDM Period defined based upon a radio frame, the offset=3 indicates that transmission of data of a logical channel (or a set of logical channels) is started from a third sub-frame in a radio frame of a first TDM period or transmission of the data of the logical channel (or the set of logical channels) is started from a third sub-frame of MBSFN available sub-frames in the radio frame of the first TDM period or transmission of the data of the logical channel (or the set of logical channels) is started from a third sub-frame of MCH occupied sub-frames to which the MBSFN available sub-frames in the radio frame of the first TDM period are mapped.</p><p id="p0053" num="0053">The Transmission Length refers to an amount of sub-frames occupied for data of a logical channel (or a set of logical channels) transmitted in each TDM period of the logical channel (or the set of logical channels).</p><p id="p0054" num="0054">The MCS refers to an MCS adopted in a sub-frame in which data of a logical channel (or a set of logical channels) is transmitted over the transport channel.</p><p id="p0055" num="0055">For example, the MCCH corresponds to the Subset 1, and the user equipment may know from the parameter of Offset 1 the starting instance of time at which the MCCH data is received; the user equipment may know from the parameter of Transmission Length 1 the amount of sub-frames occupied for the MCCH data upon each reception of the MCCH data; the user equipment may know from the parameter of MCS 1 which MCS is adopted to receive the MCCH data; and the user equipment may know from the TDM Period an interval at which the MCCH data is received.</p><p id="p0056" num="0056">Therefore, the user equipment can receive correctly the data of the logical channel according to the parameters carried in the subset corresponding to the logical channel.</p><p id="p0057" num="0057">It shall be noted that all the foregoing parameters may not be present during configuration, for example, when a fixed amount of sub-frames are occupied for data of a logical channel (or a set of logical channels), the fixed value may be appointed in advance between the network side and the user equipment so that the parameter of "Transmission Length" may not be configured in a subset.<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --></p><p id="p0058" num="0058">In the first approach, the parameters of the respective subsets are transmitted over the BCCH, and only a corresponding relationship between logical channels (or sets of logical channels), such as the MTCH, and indexes of the subsets is carried over the MCCH.</p><p id="p0059" num="0059">Of course, the corresponding relationship between the logical channels and the subsets (including the MCSs or the indexes of the MCSs) may be transmitted over the BCCH.</p><p id="p0060" num="0060">In a second approach, since the user equipment receives firstly the MCCH data and then the MTCH data, the corresponding relationship between the MCCH and the MCS may be transmitted to the user equipment over the BCCH, and the corresponding relationship between the MTCH and the MCS may be transmitted to the user equipment over the MCCH.</p><p id="p0061" num="0061">In the case that the MCSs are stored in advance in the user equipment, the corresponding relationship between the MCCH and the index of the MCS may be transmitted to the user equipment over the BCCH, and the corresponding relationship between the MTCH and the index of the MCS may be transmitted to the user equipment over the MCCH.</p><p id="p0062" num="0062">The index of the MCS as described in the embodiment of the invention may be an identifier of the MCS.</p><p id="p0063" num="0063">The user equipment knows from the BCCH the MCS adopted for the sub-frame carrying the MCCH data and knows from the MCCH the MCS adopted for the sub-frame carrying the MTCH data.</p><p id="p0064" num="0064">Specifically, in the second approach, an MCS may be carried in a subset as in the first approach, and the corresponding relationship between the MCCH and the subset is transmitted over the BCCH and the corresponding relationship between the MTCH and the subset is transmitted over the MCCH.</p><p id="p0065" num="0065">In the embodiment of the invention, the operations at the network side may be performed by a base station or another network node.</p><p id="p0066" num="0066">Correspondingly, a data reception method according to an embodiment of the invention includes the following steps.</p><p id="p0067" num="0067">In a first step, a user equipment acquires a corresponding relationship between logical channels and MCSs (or indexes of the MCSs), which is notified from the network side.</p><p id="p0068" num="0068">In a second step, the user equipment determines, from the corresponding relationship,<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> an MCS adopted for data of a logical channel among data of a plurality of types of logical channels transmitted over the same transport channel from the network side.</p><p id="p0069" num="0069">In a third step, the user equipment demodulates and decodes the data of the corresponding logical channel according to the MCS determined in the second step.</p><p id="p0070" num="0070">In the foregoing embodiment, if the user equipment is going to receive data of some of the logical channels mapped onto the same transport channel, it will be sufficient if MCSs corresponding to those logical channels to be received are determined in the second step.</p><p id="p0071" num="0071">The user equipment acquires, from the Broadcast Control Channel (BCCH), the MCSs corresponding to the logical channels among the types of logical channels mapped onto the same transport channel, which is notified from the network side, where the logical channels may or may not correspond to the same MCS.</p><p id="p0072" num="0072">The user equipment may acquire the corresponding relationship between the logical channels among the types of logical channels mapped onto the same transport channel and the MCSs, which is notified from the network side, as follows:
<ul><li>the user equipment acquires, from the Broadcast Control Channel (BCCH), a corresponding relationship between a specific logical channel determined at the network side and an MCS or an index of the MCS; and the user equipment acquires over the specific logical channel the corresponding relationship between the other logical channels mapped onto the same transport channel than the specific logical channel and the MCSs or the indexes of the MCSs</li></ul></p><p id="p0073" num="0073">Before the user equipment demodulates and decodes the data of the corresponding logical channel, the method may further includes: the user equipment acquires the amount of sub-frames and/or the serial numbers of sub-frames occupied respectively for the plurality of types of logical channels, which are transmitted from the network side.</p><p id="p0074" num="0074">When the data of the plurality of types of logical channels is transmitted from the network side through Time Division Multiplexing (TDM), the user equipment may demodulate and decode the data of each type of logical channel according to the corresponding MCS.</p><p id="p0075" num="0075">When the data of the plurality of types of logical channels is transmitted from the network side through TDM-based transport block multiplexing, the user equipment may<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> demodulate and decode the data of more than one types of logical channels to be transmitted in the same sub-frame according to the MCS with the highest reliability among the MCSs corresponding to the more than one types of logical channels, and demodulate and decode the data of one type of logical channel to be transmitted in a separate sub-frame according to the MCS corresponding to the logical channel.</p><p id="p0076" num="0076">Three specific embodiments will be given below.</p><p id="p0077" num="0077">In a first embodiment, the MCCH data and the MTCH data are multiplexed through TDM.</p><p id="p0078" num="0078">As illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2</figref>, in a period of time, the MCH onto which the MCCH and the MTCH are mapped together includes six sub-frames in total and the MCCH and the MTCH are multiplexed through TDM, that is, a sub-frame in which the MCCH data is transmitted is different from a sub-frame in which the MTCH data is transmitted. As stipulated in advance, MBMS control information shall firstly be transmitted by occupying 3 sub-frames, so the base station modulates and encodes the first three sub-frames over the MCH occupied for transmission of the MCCH data according to the MCS 1 with the high reliability and modulates and encodes the sub-frames occupied for subsequent transmission of the MTCH data according to the MCS 2 with a high spectrum efficiency.</p><p id="p0079" num="0079">The user equipment receives the MCCH data according to the MCS 1 notified from the base station and the amount of sub-frames and/or the serial numbers of sub/frames occupied for the MCCH data, which are appointed in advance (or notified in a broadcast message), and receives sub-frames occupied for the MTCH data according to the MCS 2 notified from the base station.</p><p id="p0080" num="0080">In a second embodiment, the MCCH data and the MTCH data are multiplexed through TDM-based transport block multiplexing.</p><p id="p0081" num="0081">As illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 3</figref>, in a period of time, the MCH onto which the MCCH and the MTCH are mapped together includes six sub-frames in total and the data of the MCCH and the MTCH are multiplexed through TDM-based transport block multiplexing. As stipulated in advance, MBMS control information shall firstly be transmitted by occupying 3 sub-frames, so the base station modulates and encodes sub-frames, in which the MCCH data is transmitted,<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> according to the MCS 1 with the high reliability (although some of the sub-frames may include the data of the MTCH) and modulates and encodes sub-frames in which no MCCH data is included according to the MCS2 with a high spectrum efficiency.</p><p id="p0082" num="0082">The user equipment receives the MCCH data according to the MCS1 notified from the base station and the amount of sub-frames and/or the serial numbers of sub-frames occupied for the MCCH data, which are appointed in advance (or notified in a broadcast message), and receives the sub-frames occupied for the MTCH data according to the MCS 2 notified from the base station.</p><p id="p0083" num="0083">Only the scenario in which an MCCH and an MTCH are mapped onto the same MCH has been described above, and of course the method according to the embodiment of the invention may also be applied to another scenario, for example, in which an MCCH, an MTCH, an MSCH or a Media Access Control Control Element (MAC CE) for scheduling and other logical channel(s) are multiplexed onto the same MCH. These logical channels may be multiplexed as illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2</figref> or <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 3</figref>. Different MCSs may be set for the different logical channels, and the UE may be notified of the different MCSs corresponding to the different logical channels over a BCCH and/or an MCCH. Furthermore, the logical channels may alternatively be grouped, and the same MCS may be adopted for the same set of logical channels, for example, data of the Multicast Scheduling Channel (MSCH) and data of the MAC CE may be modulated and encoded according to the same dedicated MCS, or multiplexed with data of the MCCH and/or the MTCH in the same sub-frame and modulated and encoded according to the same MCS as the MCS corresponding to the MCCH and/or the MTCH.</p><p id="p0084" num="0084">Devices according to embodiments of the invention will be introduced below.</p><p id="p0085" num="0085">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 6</figref>, a data transmission device according to an embodiment of the invention includes:
<ul><li>an MCS notification unit 11 configured to determine a plurality of Modulation and Coding Schemes (MCSs) required for the same transport channel, onto which a plurality of types of logical channels are mapped, and notify a user equipment of a corresponding relationship between the logical channels and the MCSs or indexes of the MCSs; and</li><li>a transmission processing unit 12 configured to modulate and encode data of the<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> logical channels mapped onto the same transport channel according to the MCSs required for the transport channel and then transmit the data to the user equipment over the transport channel.</li></ul></p><p id="p0086" num="0086">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 7</figref>, the MCS notification unit 11 includes:
<ul><li>an MCS determination unit 111 configured to determine the MCSs required for the same transport channel onto which the plurality of types of logical channels are mapped; and</li><li>a BCCH transmission unit 112 configured to notify the user equipment of the corresponding relationship between the logical channels and the MCSs or the indexes of the MCSs over a Broadcast Control Channel (BCCH).</li></ul></p><p id="p0087" num="0087">Alternatively, referring to <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 8</figref>, the MCS notification unit 11 includes:
<ul><li>an MCS determination unit 113 configured to determine the MCSs required for the same transport channel onto which the plurality of types of logical channels are mapped;</li><li>a specific logical channel determination unit 114 configured to determine one or more types of specific logical channels among the plurality of types of logical channels mapped on the same transport channel;</li><li>a BCCH transmission unit 115 configured to transmit a corresponding relationship between the specific logical channel(s) and an MCS(s) or an index(es) of the MCS(s) to the user equipment over a Broadcast Control Channel (BCCH); and</li><li>a specific logical channel transmission unit 116 configured to transmit a corresponding relationship between the other logical channels mapped onto the same transport channel than the specific logical channel(s) and MCSs or indexes of the MCSs to the user equipment over the specific logical channel(s).</li></ul></p><p id="p0088" num="0088">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 6</figref>, the device preferably further includes:
<ul><li>a sub-frame information notification unit 13 configured to notify the user equipment of an amount of sub-frames and/or serial numbers of sub-frames occupied respectively for the plurality of types of logical channels.</li></ul></p><p id="p0089" num="0089">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 9</figref>, the transmission processing unit 12 preferably includes:
<ul><li>a modulation and encoding unit 121 configured to modulate and encode the data of the logical channel according to the MCS corresponding to the logical channel when the data of<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> the plurality of types of logical channels mapped onto the same transport channel is transmitted through Time Division Multiplexing (TDM); or modulate and encode the data of more than one types of logical channels to be transmitted in the same sub-frame according to the MCS with the highest reliability among the MCSs corresponding to the more than one types of logical channels and modulate and encode the data of one type of logical channel to be transmitted in a separate sub-frame according to the MCS corresponding to the logical channel when the data of the plurality of types of logical channels mapped onto the same transport channel is transmitted through TDM-based transport block multiplexing; and</li><li>a transmission unit 122 configured to transmit to the user equipment over the transport channel the data of the logical channels mapped onto the same transport channel, which is encoded by the modulation and encoding unit 121.</li></ul></p><p id="p0090" num="0090">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 10</figref>, a data reception device according to an embodiment of the invention, e.g., a user equipment, may include:
<ul><li>a corresponding relationship acquisition unit 21 configured to acquire a corresponding relationship between a logical channel among a plurality of types of logical channels mapped onto the same transport channel and a Modulation and Coding Scheme (MCS) or an index of the MCS, which is notified from the network side;</li><li>an MCS determination unit 22 configured to determine, from the corresponding relationship acquired by the corresponding relationship acquisition unit 21, the MCS adopted for data of the logical channel among data of the plurality of types of logical channels transmitted over the same transport channel from the network side; and</li><li>a processing unit 23 configured to demodulate and decode the data of the logical channel according to the MCS determined by the MCS determination unit 22.</li></ul></p><p id="p0091" num="0091">It shall be noted that in the foregoing embodiment, if the user equipment is going to receive the data over some of the logical channels mapped onto the same transport channel, the MCS determination unit may determine only the MCSs corresponding to those logical channels to be received.</p><p id="p0092" num="0092">The corresponding relationship acquisition unit 21 is configured to acquire over a Broadcast Control Channel (BCCH) the corresponding relationship between the logical channel<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> among the plurality of types of logical channels mapped onto the same transport channel and the MCS, which is notified from the network side.</p><p id="p0093" num="0093">The corresponding relationship acquisition unit 21 is configured to acquire a corresponding relationship between a specific logical channel determined at the network side and an MCS or an index of the MCS over a Broadcast Control Channel (BCCH) and acquire a corresponding relationship between the other logical channels mapped onto the same transport channel than the specific logical channel and MCSs or indexes of the MCSs over the specific logical channel.</p><p id="p0094" num="0094">The device may further include a first acquisition unit configured to acquire an amount of sub-frames and/or serial numbers of sub-frames occupied respectively for the plurality of types of logical channels, which are transmitted from the network side, before the user equipment demodulates and decodes the data of the logical channel.</p><p id="p0095" num="0095">The processing unit 23 is configured to demodulate and decode the data of the logical channel according to the corresponding MCS.</p><p id="p0096" num="0096">The processing unit 23 is configured to demodulate and decode the data of more than one types of logical channels to be transmitted in the same sub-frame according to the MCS with the highest reliability among the MCSs corresponding to the more than one types of logical channels, and demodulate and decode the data of one type of logical channel to be transmitted in a separate sub-frame according to the MCS corresponding to the logical channel.</p><p id="p0097" num="0097">Preferably, a communication system according to an embodiment of the invention includes a base station and at least one user equipment.</p><p id="p0098" num="0098">The base station is configured to determine a plurality of Modulation and Coding Schemes (MCSs) required for the same transport channel, onto which a plurality of types of logical channels are mapped, and notify the user equipment of a corresponding relationship between the logical channels and the MCSs; and modulate and encode data of the logical channels mapped onto the transport channel according to the MCSs required for the transport channel and then transmit the data to the user equipment over the transport channel. The corresponding relationship between the logical channels and the MCSs may be represented as a corresponding relationship between the logical channels and indexes of the MCSs.<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --></p><p id="p0099" num="0099">The user equipment is configured to acquire the corresponding relationship between the logical channels and the MCSs, which is transmitted from the base station, determine from the corresponding relationship an MCS adopted for data of a logical channel and demodulate and decode the data of the logical channel according to the determined MCS.</p><p id="p0100" num="0100">The base station and the user equipment may interact dependent upon the foregoing implementations of the network side and the user equipment, and a repeated description thereof will not be repeated here.</p><p id="p0101" num="0101">In summary, in the embodiments of the invention, a plurality of Modulation and Coding Schemes (MCSs) required for the same transport channel, onto which a plurality of types of logical channels are mapped, are determined at the network side, and a user equipment is notified of a corresponding relationship between the logical channels and the MCSs or the indexes of the MCSs; and data of the logical channels mapped onto the transport channel is modulated and encoded at the network side according to the MCSs required for the transport channel and then transmitted to the user equipment over the transport channel, so that the MCSs may be adopted over the transport channel, onto which the plurality of types of MBMS-related logical channels are mapped, to thereby satisfy transmission quality requirements of data of the plurality of types of logical channels.<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --></p><p id="p0102" num="0102">It will be appreciated that one skilled in the art may make various modifications and alterations to the present invention without departing from the scope of the present invention. Accordingly, if these modifications and alterations to the present invention fall within the scope of the claims of the present invention and their equivalents, the present invention intends to include all these modifications and alterations.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56977934" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Datenübertragungsverfahren mit:
<claim-text>Bestimmen, auf Seiten des Netzwerkes, einer Vielzahl von Modulations- und Kodierungsschemata, MCSs, die für denselben Transportkanal erforderlich sind, auf welchen eine Vielzahl von Typen von MBMS-bezogenen logischen Kanälen abgebildet werden, und Mitteilen einer entsprechenden Beziehung zwischen den logischen Kanälen und den MCSs an eine Einrichtung eines Benutzers (S101); und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Modulieren und Kodieren, auf Seiten des Netzwerkes, von Daten der entsprechend den benötigten MCSs auf dem Transportkanal abgebildeten logischen Kanäle, und Übermitteln der Daten über den Transportkanal an die Einrichtung des Benutzers (S 102);</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die Mitteilung der entsprechenden Beziehung zwischen den logischen Kanälen und den MCSs an die Einrichtung des Benutzers umfasst:
<claim-text>Bestimmen, auf Seiten des Netzwerkes, einer oder mehrerer Typen von spezifschen logischen Kanälen unter der Vielzahl der Typen der logischen Kanäle, die auf denselben Transportkanal abgebildet werden;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Übermitteln, auf Seiten des Netzwerkes, einer entsprechenden Beziehung zwischen dem spezifischen logischen Kanal oder den spezifischen logischen Kanälen und einem mehreren MCSs oder eines oder mehrerer Idizes der MCSs an die Einrichtung des Benutzers über einen Broadcast Control Channel, (BCCH); und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Übermitteln, auf Seiten des Netzwerkes, einer entsprechenden Beziehung zwischen den anderen auf denselben Transportkanal abgebildeten Kanälen als dem oder den spezifischen logischen Kanälen und den MCSs an die Einrichtung des Benutzers über den spezifischen logischen Kanal oder die spezifischen logischen Kanäle.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, weiterbin umfassend: vor der Übermittlung der Daten der mehreren Typen von logischen Kanälen auf Seiten des Netzwerkes über den Transportkanal an die Einrichtung des Benutzers,<br/>
Mitteilen, auf Seiten des Netzwerkes, einer Menge von Sub-Frames und/oder Seriennummern von Sub-Frames, die jeweils für die Vielzahl von Typen von logischen Kanälen belegt werden, an die Einrichtung des Benutzers.<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1 oder 2, bei dem das Modulieren und Kodieren der gemäß den benötigten MCSs auf den Transportkanal abgebildeten logischen Kanäle auf Seiten des Netzwerkes umfasst:
<claim-text>wenn die Daten der mehreren Typen der logischen Kanäle durch Zeitmultiplex, TDM, übermittelt werden, Modulieren und Kodieren der Daten jedes Typs von logischen Kanälen gemäß einem entsprechenden MCS auf Seiten des Netzwerkes, oder,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wenn die Daten der mehreren Typen von logischen Kanälen durch TDM-basiertes Transportblock-Multiplex übertragen werden, Modulieren und Kodieren, auf Seiten des Netzwerkes, der Daten von mehr als einem Typ logischer Kanäle, die in demselben Sub-Frame zu übermitteln sind, gemäß einem MCS mit der höchsten Zuverlässigkeit unter den MCSs entsprechend den mehr als einem Typen von logischen Kanälen, und Modulieren und Kodieren der Daten eines Typs von logischen Kanälen, die in einem separaten Sub-Frame zu übermitteln sind, gemäß einem dem logischen Kanal entsprechenden MCS.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1 oder 2, bei dem die entsprechende Beziehung zwischen den logischen Kanälen und den MCSs repräsentiert wird als eine entsprechende Beziehung zwischen den logischen Kanälen und Indizes der MCSs.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Verfahren zum Empfang von Daten, mit:
<claim-text>Gewinnen, durch eine Einrichtung eines Benutzers, einer entsprechenden Beziehung zwischen einem logischen Kanal und einer Vielzahl von Typen von MBMSbezogenen logischen Kanälen, die auf denselben Transportkanal abgebildet sind, und eines MCS, das von Seiten des Netzwerkes mitgeteilt wird;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Bestimmen, durch die Einrichtung des Benutzers, des MCS, dass dem von Seiten des Netzwerkes auf den Transportkanal abgebildeten logischen Kanal entspricht, anhand der entsprechenden Beziehung zwischen dem logischen Kanal und dem MCS; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Demodulieren und Dekodieren, durch die Einrichtung des Benutzers, von Daten des logischen Kanals gemäß dem bestimmten MCS;</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> das Gewinnen der entsprechenden Beziehung zwischen dem logischen Kanal unter der Vielzahl von Typen von MBMS-bezogenen logischen Kanälen, die auf denselben Transportkanal abgebildet sind, und dem MCS, dass von Seiten des Netzwerks mitgeteilt wurde, durch die Einrichtung des Benutzers umfasst:<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> -->
<claim-text>Gewinnen, durch die Einrichtung des Benutzers, einer entsprechenden Beziehung zwischen einem spezifischen logischen Kanal, der auf Seiten des Netzwerks bestimmt wird, und einem MCS über einen Broadcast Control Channel, BCCH, und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Gewinnen, durch die Einrichtung des Benutzers, einer entsprechenden Beziehung zwischen den anderen auf denselben Transportkanal abgebildeten logischen Kanälen als dem spezifischen logischen Kanal und von MCSs über den spezifischen logischen Kanal.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 5, weiterhin umfassend: bevor die Einrichtung des Benutzers die Daten des logischen Kanals demoduliert und dekodiert,<br/>
Gewinnen, durch die Einrichtung des Benutzers, einer Menge von Sub-Frames und/oder Seriennummern von Sub-Frames, die jeweils von der Vielzahl von Typen von logischen Kanälen belegt werden, die von Seiten des Netzwerks übermittelt werden.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 5 oder 6, bei dem, wenn Daten der Vielzahl von Typen von logischen Kanälen von Seiten des Netzwerks durch Zeitmultiplex, TDM, übermittelt werden, das Demodulieren und Dekodieren der Daten des logischen Kanals umfasst:
<claim-text>Demodulieren und Dekodieren, durch die Einrichtung des Benutzers, von Daten jedes Typs von logischen Kanälen gemäß einem MCS, das dem logischen Kanal entspricht;</claim-text>
<claim-text>und bei dem, wenn Daten der mehreren Typen von logischen Kanälen durch TDM-basiertes Transportblock-Multiplex übermittelt werden, das Demodulieren und Dekodieren der Daten des logischen Kanals umfasst:
<claim-text>Demodulieren und Dekodieren, durch die Einrichtung des Benutzers, von Daten von mehr als einem Typ von logischen Kanälen, die in demselben Sub-Frame zu übermitteln sind, gemäß einem MCS mit der höchsten Zuverlässigkeit unter den MCSs, die den mehr als einem Typen von logischen Kanälen entsprechen, und Demodulieren und Dekodieren von Daten eines Typs von logischen Kanälen, der in einem separaten Sub-Frame zu übermitteln ist, gemäß einem MCS, das dem einen Typ von logischen Kanälen entspricht.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zur Übermittlung von Daten, mit:<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> -->
<claim-text>einer MCS- Mitteilungseinheit (11), die dazu konfiguriert ist, eine Vielzahl von Modulations- und Kodierungsschemata, MCSs, zu bestimmen, die für denselben Transportkanal benötigt werden, auf den eine Vielzahl von Typen von MBMS-bezogenen logischen Kanälen abgebildet werden, und Mitteilen einer entsprechenden Beziehung zwischen den logischen Kanälen und den MCSs an eine Einrichtung eines Benutzers, und</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Übermittlungs-Verarbeitungseinheit (12), die dazu konfiguriert ist, Daten der logischen Kanäle, die auf den Transportkanal abgebildet sind, gemäß den benötigten MCSs zu modulieren und zu kodieren und die Daten über den Transportkanal an die Einrichtung des Benutzers zu übermitteln,</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die MCS-Mitteilungseinheit (11) umfasst:
<claim-text>eine MCS-Bestimmungseinheit (113), die dazu konfiguriert ist, die für denselben Transportkanal, auf de die mehreren Typen von logischen Kanälen abgebildet werden, benötigten MCSs zu bestimmen;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Bestimmungseinheit (114) für einen spezifischen logischen Kanal, die dazu bestimmt ist, einen oder mehrere Typen von spezifischen logischen Kanälen unter der Vielzahl von Typen von logischen Kanälen zu bestimmen, die auf denselben Transportkanal abgebildet sind;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine BCCH-Übermittlungseinheit (115), die dazu konfiguriert ist, eine entsprechende Beziehung zwischen dem oder den spezifischen logischen Kanälen und einer oder mehreren MCSs oder eines oder mehrerer Indizes der MCSs über einen Broadcast Control Channel, BCCH, an die Einrichtung des Benutzers zu übermitteln; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Übertragungseinheit (116) für einen spezifischen logischen Kanal, die dazu konfiguriert ist, eine entsprechende Beziehung zwischen den anderen auf denselben Transportkanal abgebildeten logischen Kanälen als dem oder den spezifischen logischen Kanälen und der oder den MCSs oder dem oder den Indizes der MCSs über den oder die spezifischen logischen Kanäle an die Einrichtung des Benutzers zu übermitteln.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Vorrichtung nach Anspruch 8, weiterhin umfassend: eine Sub-Frame Informationsmitteilungseinheit (13), die dazu konfiguriert ist, der Einrichtung des Benutzers eine Menge von Sub-Frames und/oder Seriennummern von Sub-Frames mitzuteilen, die jeweils für die Vielzahl von Typen von logischen Kanälen belegt werden.<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Vorrichtung nach Anspruch 8 oder 9, bei der die Übermittlungs-Verarbeitungseinheit (12) umfasst: eine Modulations- und Kodiereinheit (121), die dazu konfiguriert ist, Daten jedes Typs von logischen Kanälen gemäß einem MCS, das dem logischen Kanal entspricht, zu modulieren und zu kodieren, wenn Daten der Mehrzahl von Typen von logischen Kanälen durch Zeitmultiplex, TDM, übermittelt werden, oder Daten von mehr als einem Typ von logischen Kanälen, die in demselben Sub-Frame zu übermitteln sind, gemäß einem MCS mit der höchsten Zuverlässigkeit unter den MCSs, die den ein oder mehreren Typen von logischen Kanälen entsprechen, zu modulieren und zu kodieren und Daten eines Typs von logischen Kanälen, die in einem separaten Sub-Frame zu übermitteln sind, gemäß einem MCS zu modulieren und zu kodieren, das dem logischen Kanal entspricht, wenn Daten der mehreren Typen von logischen Kanälen durch TDM-basiertes Transportblock-Multiplex übermittelt werden; und<br/>
eine Übertragungseinheit (122), die dazu konfiguriert ist, die von der Modulations- und Kodiereinheit (121) verarbeiteten Daten über den Transportkanal an die Einrichtung des Benutzers zu übermitteln.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Empfang von Daten, mit:
<claim-text>einer Gewinnungseinheit (21) für eine entsprechende Beziehung, die dazu konfiguriert ist, eine entsprechende Beziehung zwischen einem logischen Kanal unter einer Vielzahl von Typen von MBMS-bezogenen logischen Kanälen, die auf denselben Transportkanal abgebildet werden, und einem Modulations- und Kodierungsschema, MCS, zu bestimmen, dass von Seiten des Netzwerkes mitgeteilt wird;</claim-text>
<claim-text>einer MCS-Bestimmungseinheit (22), die dazu konfiguriert ist, anhand der entsprechenden Beziehung zwischen dem logischen Kanal und dem MCS, das MCS zu bestimmen, das für die Daten des logischen Kanals ausgewählt wird, die von Seiten des Netzwerkes über denselben Transportkanal übermittelt werden, und</claim-text>
<claim-text>einer Verarbeitungseinheit (23), die dazu konfiguriert ist, die Daten des logischen Kanals gemäß dem durch die MCS-Bestimmungseinheit (22) bestimmten MCS zu demodulieren und zu dekodieren;</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die Gewinnungseinheit (21) für die entsprechende Beziehung dazu konfiguriert ist, eine entsprechende Beziehung zwischen einem spezifischen logischen Kanal, der auf Seiten des Netzwerks bestimmt wurde, und einem MCS<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --> oder einem Index des MCS über einen Broadcast Control Channel, BCCH, zu gewinnen, und eine entsprechende Beziehung zwischen den anderen auf denselben Transportkanal abgebildeten logischen Kanälen als der spezifische logische Kanal und einem oder mehreren MCSs oder einem oder mehreren Indizes von MCSs über den spezifischen logischen Kanal zu gewinnen.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Vorrichtung nach Anspruch 11, weiterhin umfassend eine erste Gewinnungseinheit, die dazu konfiguriert ist, eine Menge von Sub-Frames und/oder Seriennummern von Sub-Frames zu gewinnen, die jeweils für die Vielzahl von Typen von logischen Kanälen belegt werden, die von Seiten des Netzwerkes übermittelt werden, bevor die Einrichtung des Benutzers die Daten des logischen Kanals demoduliert und dekodiert.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Vorrichtung nach Anspruch 11 oder 12, bei der die Verarbeitungseinheit (23) dazu konfiguriert ist, die Daten jedes Typs von logischen Kanälen gemäß einem entsprechenden MCS zu demodulieren und zu dekodieren;<br/>
oder bei der die Verarbeitungseinheit (23) dazu konfiguriert ist, Daten von mehr als einem Typ von logischen Kanälen, die in demselben Sub-Frame zu übermitteln sind, gemäß einem MCS mit der höchsten Zuverlässigkeit unter den MCSs, die den mehr als einem Typen von logischen Kanälen entsprechen, zu demodulieren und zu dekodieren, und Daten eines Typs von logischen Kanälen, die in einem separaten Sub-Frame zu übermitteln sind, gemäß einem dem logischen Kanal entsprechenden MCS zu demodulieren und zu dekodieren.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56977935" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A data transmission method, comprising:
<claim-text>determining, at the network side, a plurality of Modulation and Coding Schemes, MCSs, required for the same transport channel onto which a plurality of types of MBMS-related logical channels are mapped, and notifying a user equipment of a corresponding relationship between the logical channels and the MCSs (S101); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>modulating and encoding, at the network side, data of the logical channels mapped onto the transport channel according to the required MCSs, and transmitting the data to the user equipment over the transport channel (S102);</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>characterized in that</b> the notifying the user equipment of the corresponding relationship between the logical channels and the MCSs comprises:
<claim-text>determining, at the network side, one or more types of specific logical channels among the plurality of types of logical channels mapped onto the same transport channel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting, at the network side, a corresponding relationship between the specific logical channel(s) and an MCS(s) or an index(es) of the MCS(s) to the user equipment over a Broadcast Control channel, BCCH; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting, at the network side, a corresponding relationship between the other logical channels mapped onto the same transport channel than the specific logical channel(s) and MCSs to the user equipment over the specific logical channel(s).</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The method of claim 1, further comprising: before transmitting at the network side the data of the plurality of types of logical channels to the user equipment over the transport channel,<br/>
notifying, at the network side, the user equipment of an amount of sub-frames and/or serial numbers of sub-frames occupied respectively for the plurality of types of logical channels.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The method of claim 1 or 2, wherein modulating and encoding at the network side the data of the logical channels mapped onto the transport channel according to the required MCSs comprises:
<claim-text>when the data of the plurality of types of logical channels is transmitted through Time Division Multiplexing, TDM, modulating and encoding, at the network side, data of each type of logical channel according to a corresponding MCS; or</claim-text>
<claim-text>when the data of the plurality of types of logical channels is transmitted through TDM-based transport block multiplexing, modulating and encoding, at the network side, data of more than one types of logical channels to be transmitted in the same sub-frame according to an<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> MCS with the highest reliability among MCSs corresponding to the more than one types of logical channels, and modulating and encoding data of one type of logical channel to be transmitted in a separate sub-frame according to an MCS corresponding to the logical channel.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The method of claim 1 or 2, wherein the corresponding relationship between the logical channels and the MCSs is represented as a corresponding relationship between the logical channels and indexes of the MCSs.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>A data reception method, comprising:
<claim-text>acquiring, by a user equipment, a corresponding relationship between a logical channel among a plurality of types of MBMS-related logical channels mapped onto the same transport channel and an MCS, which is notified from the network side;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining, by the user equipment, from the corresponding relationship between the logical channel and the MCS, the MCS corresponding to the logical channel mapped at the network side onto the transport channel; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>demodulating and decoding, by the user equipment, data of the logical channel according to the determined MCS;</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>characterized in that</b> the acquiring by the user equipment the corresponding relationship between the logical channel among the plurality of types of MBMS-related logical channels mapped onto the same transport channel and the MCS, which is notified from the network side, comprises:</claim-text>
<claim-text>acquiring, by the user equipment, a corresponding relationship between a specific logical channel determined at the network side and an MCS over a Broadcast Control Channel, BCCH; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>acquiring, by the user equipment, a corresponding relationship between the other logical channels mapped onto the same transport channel than the specific logical channel and MCSs over the specific logical channel.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The method of claim 5, further comprising: before the user equipment demodulates and decodes the data of the logical channel,<br/>
acquiring, by the user equipment, an amount of sub-frames and/or serial numbers of sub-frames occupied respectively for the plurality of types of logical channels, which are transmitted from the network side.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The method of claim 5 or 6, wherein when data of the plurality of types of logical channels is transmitted from the network side through Time Division Multiplexing, TDM, demodulating and decoding the data of the logical channel comprises:
<claim-text>demodulating and decoding, by the user equipment, data of each type of logical channel according to an MCS corresponding to the logical channel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>and wherein when data of the plurality of types of logical channels is transmitted through<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> TDM-based transport block multiplexing, demodulating and decoding the data of the logical channel comprises:
<claim-text>demodulating and decoding, by the user equipment, data of more than one types of logical channels to be transmitted in the same sub-frame according to an MCS with the highest reliability among MCSs corresponding to the more than one types of logical channels, and demodulating and decoding data of one type of logical channel to be transmitted in a separate sub-frame according to an MCS corresponding to the one type of logical channel.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>A data transmission device comprising:
<claim-text>an MCS notification unit (11) configured to determine a plurality of Modulation and Coding Schemes, MCSs, required for the same transport channel, onto which a plurality of types of MBMS-related logical channels are mapped, and notify a user equipment of a corresponding relationship between the logical channels and the MCSs; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a transmission processing unit (12) configured to modulate and encode data of the logical channels mapped onto the transport channel according to the required MCSs and transmit the data to the user equipment over the transport channel;</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>characterized in that</b> the MCS notification unit (11) comprises:
<claim-text>an MCS determination unit (113) configured to determine the MCSs required for the same transport channel onto which the plurality of types of logical channels are mapped;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a specific logical channel determination unit (114) configured to determine one or more types of specific logical channels among the plurality of types of logical channels mapped on the same transport channel;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a BCCH transmission unit (115) configured to transmit a corresponding relationship between the specific logical channel(s) and an MCS(s) or an index(es) of the MCS(s) to the user equipment over a Broadcast Control Channel, BCCH; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a specific logical channel transmission unit (116) configured to transmit a corresponding relationship between the other logical channels mapped onto the same transport channel than the specific logical channel(s) and MCSs or indexes of the MCSs to the user equipment over the specific logical channel(s).</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The device of claim 8, further comprising:
<claim-text>a sub-frame information notification unit (13) configured to notify the user equipment of an amount of sub-frames and/or serial numbers of sub-frames occupied respectively for the plurality of types of logical channels.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The device of claim 8 or 9, wherein the transmission processing unit (12) comprises:
<claim-text>a modulation and encoding unit (121) configured to modulate and encode data of each type<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> of logical channel according to an MCS corresponding to the logical channel when data of the plurality of types of logical channels is transmitted through Time Division Multiplexing, TDM; or modulate and encode data of more than one types of logical channels to be transmitted in the same sub-frame according to an MCS with the highest reliability among MCSs corresponding to the more than one types of logical channels and modulate and encode data of one type of logical channel to be transmitted in a separate sub-frame according to an MCS corresponding to the logical channel when data of the plurality of types of logical channels is transmitted through TDM-based transport block multiplexing; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a transmission unit (122) configured to transmit the data processed by the modulation and encoding unit (121) to the user equipment over the transport channel.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>A data reception device, comprising:
<claim-text>a corresponding relationship acquisition unit (21) configured to acquire a corresponding relationship between a logical channel among a plurality of types of MBMS-related logical channels mapped onto the same transport channel and a Modulation and Coding Scheme, MCS, which is notified from the network side;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an MCS determination unit (22) configured to determine, from the corresponding relationship between the logical channel and the MCS, the MCS adopted for data of the logical channel transmitted over the same transport channel from the network side; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a processing unit (23) configured to demodulate and decode the data of the logical channel according to the MCS determined by the MCS determination unit (22);</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>characterized in that</b> the corresponding relationship acquisition unit (21) is configured to acquire a corresponding relationship between a specific logical channel determined at the network side and an MCS or an index of the MCS over a Broadcast Control Channel, BCCH, and acquire a corresponding relationship between the other logical channels mapped onto the same transport channel than the specific logical channel and MCSs or indexes of the MCSs over the specific logical channel.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>The device of claim 11, further comprising a first acquisition unit configured to acquire an amount of sub-frames and/or serial numbers of sub-frames occupied respectively for the plurality of types of logical channels, which are transmitted from the network side, before the user equipment demodulates and decodes the data of the logical channel.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>The device of claim 11 or 12, wherein the processing unit (23) is configured to demodulate and decode data of each type of logical channel according to a corresponding MCS;<br/>
or wherein the processing unit (23) is configured to demodulate and decode data of more than one types of logical channels to be transmitted in the same sub-frame according to an MCS with the highest reliability among MCSs corresponding to the more than one types of logical channels, and demodulate and decode data of one type of logical channel to be transmitted in a<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --> separate sub-frame according to an MCS corresponding to the logical channel.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56977936" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Procédé de transmission de données, consistant à :
<claim-text>déterminer, à partir du côté de réseau, une pluralité de schémas de modulation et codage, MCS, requis pour le même canal de transport sur lequel une pluralité de types de canaux logiques connexes à un service MBMS sont mis en correspondance, et signaler, à un équipement d'utilisateur, une relation correspondante entre les canaux logiques et les schémas MCS (S101) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>moduler et coder, à partir du côté de réseau, des données des canaux logiques mis en correspondance sur le canal de transport selon les schémas MCS requis, et transmettre les données à l'équipement d'utilisateur sur le canal de transport (S102) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>caractérisé en ce que</b> l'étape consistant à signaler, à l'équipement d'utilisateur, la relation correspondante entre les canaux logiques et les schémas MCS, consiste à :
<claim-text>déterminer, à partir du côté de réseau, un ou plusieurs types de canaux logiques spécifiques parmi la pluralité de types de canaux logiques mis en correspondance sur le même canal de transport ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmettre, à partir du côté de réseau, une relation correspondante entre le ou les canaux logiques spécifiques et un ou des schémas MCS ou un ou des indices du ou des schémas MCS, à l'équipement d'utilisateur, sur un canal de commande de diffusion, BCCH ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmettre, à partir du côté de réseau, une relation correspondante entre les autres canaux logiques mis en correspondance sur le même canal de transport que<!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --> le ou les canaux logiques spécifiques et les schémas MCS, à l'équipement d'utilisateur, sur le ou les canaux logiques spécifiques.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, consistant en outre à : avant de transmettre, à partir du côté de réseau, les données de la pluralité de types de canaux logiques, à l'équipement d'utilisateur, sur le canal de transport :
<claim-text>signaler, à partir du côté de réseau, à l'équipement d'utilisateur, une quantité de sous-trames et/ou des numéros de série de sous-trames qui sont respectivement occupées pour la pluralité de types de canaux logiques.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1 ou 2, dans lequel l'étape consistant à moduler et coder, à partir du côté de réseau, les données des canaux logiques mis en correspondance sur le canal de transport selon les schémas MCS requis, consiste à :
<claim-text>lorsque les données de la pluralité de types de canaux logiques sont transmises par le biais d'un multiplexage par répartition dans le temps, TDM, moduler et coder, à partir du côté de réseau, des données de chaque type de canal logique selon un schéma MCS correspondant ; ou</claim-text>
<claim-text>lorsque les données de la pluralité de types de canaux logiques sont transmises par le biais d'un multiplexage de blocs de transport basé sur le multiplexage TDM, moduler et coder, à partir du côté de réseau, des données de plus d'un type de canaux logiques à transmettre dans la même sous-trame, selon un schéma MCS offrant la fiabilité la plus élevée parmi les schémas<!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --> MCS correspondant audit plus d'un type de canaux logiques, et moduler et coder des données d'un type de canal logique à transmettre dans une sous-trame individuelle, selon un schéma MCS correspondant au canal logique.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1 ou 2, dans lequel la relation correspondante entre les canaux logiques et les schémas MCS est représentée sous la forme d'une relation correspondante entre les canaux logiques et des indices des schémas MCS.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Procédé de réception de données, consistant à :
<claim-text>acquérir, par le biais d'un équipement d'utilisateur, une relation correspondante entre un canal logique parmi une pluralité de types de canaux logiques connexes à un service MBMS mis en correspondance sur le même canal de transport et un schéma MCS, laquelle relation est signalée à partir du côté de réseau ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>déterminer, par le biais de l'équipement d'utilisateur, à partir de la relation correspondante entre le canal logique et le schéma MCS, le schéma MCS correspondant au canal logique mis en correspondance à partir du côté de réseau sur le canal de transport ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>démoduler et décoder, par le biais de l'équipement d'utilisateur, des données du canal logique selon le schéma MCS déterminé ;</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>caractérisé en ce que</b> l'étape d'acquisition, par le biais de l'équipement d'utilisateur, de la relation correspondante entre le canal logique parmi la pluralité de types de canaux logiques connexes à un service MBMS<!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --> mis en correspondance sur le même canal de transport et le schéma MCS, laquelle est signalée à partir du côté de réseau, consiste à :
<claim-text>acquérir, par le biais de l'équipement d'utilisateur, une relation correspondante entre un canal logique spécifique déterminé à partir du côté de réseau et un schéma MCS sur un canal de commande de diffusion, BCCH ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>acquérir, par le biais de l'équipement d'utilisateur, une relation correspondante entre les autres canaux logiques mis en correspondance sur le même canal de transport que le canal logique spécifique et les schémas MCS sur le canal logique spécifique.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 5, consistant en outre à : avant que l'équipement d'utilisateur ne démodule et ne décode les données du canal logique :
<claim-text>acquérir, par le biais de l'équipement d'utilisateur, une quantité de sous-trames et/ou des numéros de série de sous-trames qui sont respectivement occupées pour la pluralité de types de canaux logiques, lesquelles sont transmises à partir du côté de réseau.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 5 ou 6, dans lequel lorsque des données de la pluralité de types de canaux logiques sont transmises, à partir du côté de réseau, à travers un multiplexage par répartition dans le temps, TDM, l'étape de démodulation et décodage des données du canal logique consiste à :
<claim-text>démoduler et décoder, par le biais de l'équipement d'utilisateur, des données de chaque type de canal<!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --> logique selon un schéma MCS correspondant au canal logique ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel, lorsque des données de la pluralité de types de canaux logiques sont transmises par le biais d'un multiplexage de blocs de transport basé sur le multiplexage TDM, l'étape de démodulation et décodage des données du canal logique consiste à :
<claim-text>démoduler et décoder, par le biais de l'équipement d'utilisateur, des données de plus d'un type de canaux logiques à transmettre dans la même sous-trame, selon un schéma MCS offrant la fiabilité la plus élevée parmi les schémas MCS correspondant audit plus d'un type de canaux logiques, et démoduler et décoder des données d'un type de canal logique à transmettre dans une sous-trame individuelle, selon un schéma MCS correspondant audit un type de canal logique.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Dispositif de transmission de données, comportant :
<claim-text>une unité de notification de schéma MCS (11) configurée de manière à déterminer une pluralité de schémas de modulation et codage, MCS, requis pour le même canal de transport, sur lequel une pluralité de types de canaux logiques connexes à un service MBMS sont mis en correspondance, et à signaler, à un équipement d'utilisateur, une relation correspondante entre les canaux logiques et les schémas MCS ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>une unité de traitement de transmission (12) configurée de manière à moduler et coder des données des canaux logiques mis en correspondance sur le canal de transport selon les schémas MCS requis, et à transmettre les données à l'équipement d'utilisateur sur le canal de<!-- EPO <DP n="36"> --> transport ;</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>caractérisé en ce que</b> l'unité de notification de schéma MCS (11) comporte :
<claim-text>une unité de détermination de schéma MCS (113) configurée de manière à déterminer les schémas MCS requis pour le même canal de transport sur lequel la pluralité de types de canaux logiques est mise en correspondance ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une unité de détermination de canal logique spécifique (114) configurée de manière à déterminer un ou plusieurs types de canaux logiques spécifiques parmi la pluralité de types de canaux logiques mis en correspondance sur le même canal de transport ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une unité de transmission de canal BCCH (115) configurée de manière à transmettre une relation correspondante entre le ou les canaux logiques spécifiques et un ou des schémas MCS ou un ou des indices du ou des schémas MCS, à l'équipement d'utilisateur, sur un canal de commande de diffusion, BCCH ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>une unité de transmission de canal logique spécifique (116) configurée de manière à transmettre une relation correspondante entre les autres canaux logiques mis en correspondance sur le même canal de transport que le ou les canaux logiques spécifiques et les schémas MCS ou les indices des schémas MCS, à l'équipement d'utilisateur, sur le ou les canaux logiques spécifiques.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Dispositif selon la revendication 8, comportant en outre :
<claim-text>une unité de notification d'informations de sous-trame (13) configurée de manière à signaler, à l'équipement d'utilisateur, une quantité de sous-trames<!-- EPO <DP n="37"> --> et/ou des numéros de série de sous-trames qui sont respectivement occupées pour la pluralité de types de canaux logiques.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Dispositif selon la revendication 8 ou 9, dans lequel l'unité de traitement de transmission (12) comporte :
<claim-text>une unité de modulation et codage (121) configurée de manière à moduler et coder des données de chaque type de canal logique, selon un schéma MCS correspondant au canal logique, lorsque des données de la pluralité de types de canaux logiques sont transmises par le biais d'un multiplexage par répartition dans le temps, TDM ; ou à moduler et coder des données de plus d'un type de canaux logiques à transmettre dans la même sous-trame, selon un schéma MCS offrant la fiabilité la plus élevée parmi les schémas MCS correspondant audit plus d'un type de canaux logiques, et à moduler et coder des données d'un type de canal logique à transmettre dans une sous-trame individuelle, selon un schéma MCS correspondant au canal logique, lorsque des données de la pluralité de types de canaux logiques sont transmises par le biais d'un multiplexage de blocs de transport basé sur le multiplexage TDM ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>une unité de transmission (122) configurée de manière à transmettre les données traitées par l'unité de modulation et codage (121), à l'équipement d'utilisateur, sur le canal de transport.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Dispositif de réception de données, comportant :
<claim-text>une unité d'acquisition de relation correspondante (21) configurée de manière à acquérir une relation<!-- EPO <DP n="38"> --> correspondante entre un canal logique parmi une pluralité de types de canaux logiques connexes à un service MBMS mis en correspondance sur le même canal de transport et un schéma de modulation et codage, MCS, laquelle relation est signalée à partir du côté de réseau ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une unité de détermination de schéma MCS (22) configurée de manière à déterminer, à partir de la relation correspondante entre le canal logique et le schéma MCS, le schéma MCS adopté pour des données du canal logique, transmises sur le même canal de transport, à partir du côté de réseau ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>une unité de traitement (23) configurée de manière à démoduler et décoder les données du canal logique selon le schéma MCS déterminé par l'unité de détermination de schéma MCS (22) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>caractérisé en ce que</b> l'unité d'acquisition de relation correspondante (21) est configurée de manière à acquérir une relation correspondante entre un canal logique spécifique déterminé à partir du côté de réseau et un schéma MACS ou un indice du schéma MCS sur un canal de commande de diffusion, BCCH, et à acquérir une relation correspondante entre les autres canaux logiques mis en correspondance sur le même canal de transport que le canal logique spécifique et les schémas MCS ou les indices des schémas MCS sur le canal logique spécifique.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Dispositif selon la revendication 11, comportant en outre une première unité d'acquisition configurée de manière à acquérir une quantité de sous-trames et/ou des numéros de série de sous-trames qui sont respectivement occupées pour la pluralité de types de canaux logiques,<!-- EPO <DP n="39"> --> lesquelles sont transmises à partir du côté de réseau, avant que l'équipement d'utilisateur ne démodule et ne décode les données du canal logique.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Dispositif selon la revendication 11 ou 12 dans lequel l'unité de traitement (23) est configurée de manière à démoduler et décoder des données de chaque type de canal logique selon un schéma MCS correspondant ; ou<br/>
dans lequel l'unité de traitement (23) est configurée de manière à démoduler et décoder des données de plus d'un type de canaux logiques à transmettre dans la même sous-trame, selon un schéma MCS offrant la fiabilité la plus élevée parmi les schémas MCS correspondant audit plus d'un type de canaux logiques, et à démoduler et décoder des données d'un type de canal logique à transmettre dans une sous-trame individuelle, selon un schéma MCS correspondant au canal logique.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16668433" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="40"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1,2"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="135" he="204" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="41"> --><figure id="f0002" num="3,4"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="154" he="188" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="42"> --><figure id="f0003" num="5,6"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="165" he="167" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="43"> --><figure id="f0004" num="7,8"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="165" he="168" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="44"> --><figure id="f0005" num="9,10"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="87" he="214" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
