<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2508425-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2508425" kind="B1" date="20140101" family-id="45952940" file-reference-id="318302" date-produced="20180823" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146552192" ucid="EP-2508425-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2508425</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-12162298-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154826115" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12162298</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120329</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140449622" ucid="US-201161473189-P" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>201161473189</doc-number><kind>P</kind><date>20110408</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140448156" ucid="US-201213422599-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>201213422599</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120316</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20131010</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988096818" load-source="docdb">B64D  15/00        20060101AFI20130131BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988098636" load-source="docdb">B64D  15/12        20060101ALI20130131BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988101693" load-source="docdb">H02J  17/00        20060101ALI20130131BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2107916692" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H05B   6/80        20130101 LI20150122BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2107916841" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B64D  15/12        20130101 FI20150122BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132189060" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Rotorschaufel-Enteisungssystem</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132189061" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Rotor blade de-icing system</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132189062" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Système de dégivrage de pales de rotor</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918145715" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>BELL HELICOPTER TEXTRON INC</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918155739" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>BELL HELICOPTER TEXTRON INC.</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918172768" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>MCCOLLOUGH JAMES M</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918161843" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>MCCOLLOUGH, JAMES M.</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918994808" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>MCCOLLOUGH, JAMES M.</last-name><address><street>2314 Shisperton Drive</street><city>Arlington, TX Texas 76016</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918160150" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>AUBERT ROGER</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918142152" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>AUBERT, ROGER</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918994805" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>AUBERT, ROGER</last-name><address><street>3402 Woodside Drive</street><city>Arlington, TX Texas 76016</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918994807" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Bell Helicopter Textron Inc.</last-name><iid>100085435</iid><address><street>P.O. Box 482</street><city>Fort Worth, TX 76101</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918994806" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Lawrence, John</last-name><iid>100029147</iid><address><street>Barker Brettell LLP 100 Hagley Road</street><city>Edgbaston Birmingham B16 8QQ</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548952288" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS548873316" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS548844978" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS548948710" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS548945060" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS548844979" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS548955873" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS548952289" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548844980" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS548844981" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS548942341" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS548948711" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS548948712" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548952290" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548844982" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS548952291" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS548955874" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS548945061" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS548844983" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS548948713" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS548844984" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS548952292" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS548873317" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS548948782" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS548948783" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS548873318" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS548873319" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS548873320" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS548955875" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS548873321" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS548844985" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS548821164" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS548844986" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS548873322" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS548952293" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS548955876" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS548955877" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS548942342" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63956783" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001"><b>BACKGROUND</b></heading><heading id="h0002"><b>1. Field of the Invention</b></heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present application relates generally to de-icing systems, and more particularly, to de-icing systems for rotary aircraft.</p><heading id="h0003"><b>2. Description of Related Art</b></heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">Aircraft configured to operate in icy weather conditions must utilize one or more de-icing systems to break apart ice formed on the wings, rotors, and/or other airfoils used to create lift. Conventional rotary aircraft, such as helicopters, create lift with rotor blades susceptible to ice formations. The ice formations results in the aircraft losing lift, which in turn could cause the aircraft to crash.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">Commonly known rotor blade de-icing systems utilize heaters carried by the rotor blades. This known embodiment includes a plurality of electrical wires that pass through the interior of the main rotor mast. The wires conductively couple the heaters to a power source. Running wires through the rotor mast is an undesired feature, resulting in the use of valuable space typically reserved for other systems.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">Alternative embodiments could utilize a slip-ring having two conductive members that extend peripherally around the rotor shaft. This exemplary embodiment eliminates the need to run wires through the rotor mast. However, slip-rings increase the overall weight of the aircraft and result in additional maintenance costs.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">Although great strides have been made in abovementioned de-icing systems, considerable shortcomings remain.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p><p id="p0006" num="0006"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US4060212A"><text>US 4,060,212</text></patcit> discloses a system for effecting the removal of ice from external surfaces of aircraft, and particularly from helicopter rotor blades, by the transmission of microwave electromagnetic energy into the ice so that it functions as a surface waveguide. The system includes a permanent surface waveguide with a dielectric constant close to that of ice, so that a composite surface waveguide is formed. The permanent surface waveguide is formed from a characteristically low-loss material, so that the microwave energy is dissipated as heat primarily in the ice layer, thereby very efficiently melting or heating the ice.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p><heading id="h0004"><b>DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</b></heading><p id="p0007" num="0007">The novel features believed characteristic of the invention are set forth in the appended claims. However, the invention itself, as well as a preferred mode of use, and further objectives and advantages thereof, will best be understood by reference to the following detailed description when read in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, wherein:
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001"><b>FIG. 1</b></figref> is a side view of a rotary aircraft utilizing a de-icing system according to the preferred embodiment of the present application;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002"><b>FIGS. 2 and 3</b></figref> are oblique views of a rotor blade of the de-icing system of <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003"><b>FIGS. 4-6</b></figref> are cross-sectional views of different embodiments of the rotor blade of <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 3</figref>; and</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004"><b>FIG. 7</b></figref> is a flow chart showing the preferred method.</li></ul></p><p id="p0008" num="0008">While the system and method of the present application is susceptible to various modifications and alternative forms, specific embodiments thereof have been shown by way of example in the drawings and are herein described in detail. It should be understood, however, that the description herein of specific embodiments is not intended to limit the invention to the particular embodiment disclosed, but on the contrary, the intention is to cover all modifications, equivalents, and alternatives falling within the scope of the process of the present application as defined by the appended claims.</p><heading id="h0005"><b>DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</b></heading><p id="p0009" num="0009">Illustrative embodiments of the system and method are provided below. It will of course be appreciated that in the development of any actual embodiment, numerous implementation-specific decisions will be made to achieve the developer's specific goals, such as compliance with system-related and business-related constraints, which will vary from one implementation to another. Moreover, it will be appreciated that<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> such a development effort might be complex and time-consuming, but would nevertheless be a routine undertaking for those of ordinary skill in the art having the benefit of this disclosure.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">The de-icing system of the present application overcomes common problems associated with conventional de-icing systems by removing ice formations without the need for wires passing through the rotor mast and/or the use of a slip-ring. The system includes the features of transmitting heat energy to a heat absorbing material carried on the rotor blades. Thereafter, the absorbed heat energy warms the rotor blades and subsequently breaks apart any ice formed thereon. Further discussion of these features is provided below with reference to the accompanying drawings.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">Referring now to the drawings wherein like reference characters identify corresponding or similar elements throughout the several views, <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> shows a side view of an aircraft 101 utilizing a de-icing system 103 according a preferred embodiment of the present application.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">In the illustrative embodiment, aircraft 101 is a helicopter; however, it will be appreciated that the de-icing system 103 could easily be adapted for use on other types of aircraft, for example, a tiltrotor aircraft. It is also contemplated utilizing the features discussed herein with other types of aircraft in lieu of a rotary aircraft. Although contemplated utilizing the de-icing system with rotary blades, the feature discussed herein can be employed with other types of airfoils such as a wing of a fixed wing aircraft.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">Aircraft 101 includes a fuselage 105, a tail boom 107 attached to and extending from fuselage 105, a main rotor system 109 carried by fuselage 105, and a tail rotor 111 carried by tail boom 107. Main rotor system 109 includes a rotor hub 113, a rotor mast 115, and a plurality of rotor blades 117. Tail rotor 111 includes a vertical fin 119 and a plurality of tail rotor blades 121.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">De-icing system 103 includes a power source 123 for providing energy to one or more transmitters 125. In the exemplary embodiment, aircraft 101 is shown having four transmitters 125 selectively positioned at various locations on the aircraft. Specifically, transmitters 125 are attached to fuselage 105, tail boom 107, tail rotor<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> 111, and rotor hub 113. It should be appreciated that aircraft 101 could include more or less transmitters 125 in different embodiments.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">Power source 123 conductively couples to transmitter 125 via one or more conductors 127. In the preferred embodiment, power source 123 is a source of electrical energy, for example, a generator driven by the aircraft engine (not shown). During operation, power source 123 provides electrical energy to the transmitter 125 that in turn transmits heat energy, as depicted with a plurality of waves 129, to one or more heat absorbent materials, for example, absorbent materials 131, 133, and 134, selectively positioned on or disposed within rotor blade 117 and/or tail rotor blade 121. The absorbent materials are configured to absorb and heat the blade, which in turn breaks apart any ice formations on rotor blade 117.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">The exemplary embodiment illustrates the absorbent materials being secured to the rotor blades; however, it should be appreciated that the absorbent material can also be utilized on other components of the aircraft. For example, the absorbent material can be carried on the aircraft windshield, panels, fuselage, tail boom, and/or other areas of the aircraft susceptible to ice formations.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">Transmitters 125 are preferably configured to transmit a form of heat energy such as microwave energy to the absorbent material; thus, the transmitter can be referred to as a heat transmitter and the absorbent material can be referred to as a heat absorbent material. It should be appreciated that microwave energy has been shown to be an effective means for transmitting and heating areas susceptible to ice formations. However, it should be understood that alternative forms of energy could be transmitted to the absorbent material in alternative embodiments.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">De-icing system 103 is further provided with a control system 135 operably associated with power source 123. Control system 135 activates power source 123 upon detection of ice buildup, deactivates power source 123 as the rotor surface reaches a predetermined temperature, selectively transitions between activation and deactivation in a predetermined fashion, and/or is adapted to regulate the output, direction, and duration of heat energy transmitted by transmitter 125.<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></p><p id="p0019" num="0019">Control system 135 includes one or more of a control box 137 conductively coupled to power source 123, a first sensor 139, and a second sensor 141. Control box 137 includes the required software, hardware, switches, ports, and other electrical circuitry necessary to control de-icing system 103.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">Sensor 139 is configured to sense and relay the sensed temperature readings to control box 137. In the contemplated embodiment, sensor 139 senses weather conditions likely to cause ice formations on the rotor blades, the blade temperature, and/or ice-buildup. For example, sensor could determine the outside air temperature, liquid water content, and/or water droplet size while flying through a cloud formation. Sensor 139 could also be utilized to determine the blade temperature, which is particularly desired to avoid overheating.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">Sensor 141 is utilized to determine the location of the rotor blades relative to the transmitters. This feature allows control system 135 to selectively control the heat energy applied to the rotor blades as they pass over transmitter 125.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">During operation, sensors 139 and 141 sense and relay the sensed data to control system 135 by conductive means, for example, conductive wires, and/or by wireless means.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">The illustrative embodiment shows sensors 139 and 141 located on respective rotor blade 117 and fuselage 105; however, it will be appreciated that alternative embodiments could position these sensors in different locations. For example, sensor 139 could be attached to fuselage 105 in alternative embodiments.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">Control system 135 is configured to control the amplitude of power and duration that the heat energy is transmitted to the absorbent material. In one embodiment, control system 135 activates transmitter 125 solely upon detection of rotor blade 117 as it passes near sensor 141. In another embodiment, control system 135 could be adapted to selectively activate transmitter 125 such that transmitter 125 is active during every third blade passage on a 4-bladed main rotor - this feature is particularly desired when regulating the heat applied to blade 117. Further, control system 135 is contemplated utilizing the required operably associated systems to automatically activate de-icing system 103 upon detection of ice buildup. An alternative embodiment would include<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> the required switches and electrical components for manually activating de-icing system 103 upon detection of ice-buildup.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">The illustrative embodiment depicts the various components and subsystems of de-icing system 103 attached to the outer surfaces of fuselage 105, tail boom 107, and tail rotor 111. However, it should be understood that de-icing system 103 is preferably carried within one or more of these structures. For example, power source 123, heat transmitter 125, conductors 127, control system 135, and other components of de-icing system 103 are preferably carried in one or more inner cavities of the aircraft 101 or disposed within the walls of fuselage 105 and tail boom 107.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">Referring now to <figref idrefs="f0002">Figures 2 and 3</figref> in the drawings, oblique views of a portion of main rotor blade 117 is shown detached from aircraft 101. Rotor blade 117 includes a tip 201, a root 203, and a surface 205 extending from tip 201 and root 203. Surface 205 includes a leading edge 207 and a trailing edge 209. A suction surface 211 and a pressure surface 213 extend from leading edge 207 to trailing edge 209.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">In <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 3</figref>, an oblique view of rotor blade 117 is shown with absorbent material 133 attached to surface 205. In the exemplary embodiment, absorbent material 133 is applied to leading edge 207, where rotor blade 117 is susceptible to ice buildup; however, it should be understood that the absorbent material can be applied to any surface on blade 117 in alternative embodiments.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">In the contemplated embodiment, the absorbent material 133 is secured to the outer surface of the structures; however, it should be understood that alternative embodiments could include absorbent material being partially or fully disposed within the thickness of the structure. In one embodiment, the absorbent material could be positioned within a hollow cavity of airfoil or added as a layer sandwiched between one or more composite layers during manufacturing of a rotor blade.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0003">Figures 4-6</figref>, three different embodiments of a rotor blade with absorbent material are shown. The three embodiments illustrate various configurations of attaching the absorbent material to the rotor blades. Of course, it should be understood that other embodiments for securing the absorbent material to the blades are contemplated in alternative embodiments.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></p><p id="p0030" num="0030">In <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 4</figref>, a transverse cross-sectional view of rotor blade 117 is shown taken at IV-IV of <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 3</figref>. In one preferred embodiment, absorbent material 131 includes a plurality of ports 401 extending through the thickness of material 131 and adapted to provide channeling means for heat energy to pass therethrough, as depicted with arrow A. Thereafter, the heat energy travels through the inner thickness 403 of rotor blade 117 and is absorbed by material 133 positioned on surface 205. Ports 401 are preferably channels extending lengthwise relative to the longitudinal length of rotor blade 117. However, it will be appreciated that ports 401 could include holes, slots, and/or other suitable geometric configurations in lieu of the preferred embodiment. As is shown, the heat energy are absorbed by material 131 and 133, which in turn heats the surfaces of the rotor blade 117, as depicted with arrows Q, to break apart any ice buildup 405 formed thereon.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">In <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 5</figref>, an alternative embodiment is shown. <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 5</figref> depicts a transverse cross-sectional view of rotor blade 117. In this embodiment, a first absorbent material 501 is applied to surface 213 and a second absorbent material 503 is applied to surface 205 of rotor blade 117. The two absorbent materials connect via a heat conductor 505, which transfers energy from material 501 to material 503.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">In <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 6</figref>, another alternative embodiment is show. <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 6</figref> depicts a transverse cross-sectional view of rotor blade 117. In this embodiment, both the first heat absorbent material 601 and the second heat absorbent material 603 are fully disposed within the thickness 403 of rotor blade 117. Heat energy travels through surface 213 to reach materials 601 and 603. It will be appreciated that materials 601 and 603 can include conductor 505 and/or ports 401 discussed above.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">Referring next to <figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 7</figref> in the drawings, a flow chart 701 of the preferred de-icing method is shown. The method includes the process of creating and transferring energy to a transmitter, as depicted in box 703. Thereafter, the energy is transmitted to an absorbent material carried by the rotor blades, which in turn heats the rotor blades and breaks apart any ice buildup thereon, as depicted in boxes 705, 707, and 709.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">It is apparent that a system and method with significant advantages has been described and illustrated. The particular embodiments disclosed above are illustrative only, as<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> the embodiments may be modified and practiced in different but equivalent manners apparent to those skilled in the art having the benefit of the teachings herein. It is therefore evident that the particular embodiments disclosed above may be altered or modified, and all such variations are considered within the scope of the application. Accordingly, the protection sought herein is as set forth in the description. Although the present embodiments are shown above, they are not limited to just these embodiments, but are amenable to various changes and modifications.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56977838" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Ein Flugzeug (101) mit:
<claim-text>einer für Eisbildung anfälligen Tragfläche,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wärmeabsorbierendem Material (131, 133, 134), das von der Tragfläche getragen wird;</claim-text>
<claim-text>einem Transmitter (125) zur Übertragung von Wärmeenergie auf das wärmeabsorbierende Material (131, 133, 134); und</claim-text>
<claim-text>einem Kontrollsystem (135), das in Verbindung mit dem Transmitter (125) betrieben werden kann;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei das Kontrollsystem (135) den Transmitter (125) nach Feststellen von Eisbildung aktiviert und den Transmitter (125) deaktiviert, wenn keine Eisbildung festgestellt wird; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei das wärmeabsorbierende Material (131, 133, 134) die Wärmeenergie absorbiert, was wiederum die Tragfläche erwärmt und die hierauf entstandene Einbildung auflöst.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Das Flugzeug (101) entsprechend Anspruch 1, wobei das Kontrollsystem (135) Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>einen Sensor (139) zur Feststellung der Eisbildung;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei der Sensor (139) nach Feststellen der Eisbildung die erfasste Information an das Kontrollsystem (135) weiterleitet, das dann wiederum den Transmitter (125) aktiviert.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Das Flugzeug (101) entsprechend Anspruch 2, wobei der Sensor (139) Bedingungen feststellt, die wahrscheinlich zu Eisbildung führen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Das Flugzeug (101) entsprechend Anspruch 2 oder Anspruch 3, wobei das Kontrollsystem (135) Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>einen Sensor (141) zur Feststellung des Vorhandenseins der Tragfläche.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Das Flugzeug (101) entsprechend Anspruch 1 oder einem der Ansprüche 2 bis 4, wobei das wärmeabsorbierende Material (131, 133, 134) Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>ein erstes wärmeabsorbierendes Material (501), das an einer Saugfläche (211) der Tragfläche befestigt ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>ein zweites wärmeabsorbierendes Material (503), das an einer Druckfläche (213) der Tragfläche befestigt ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Das Flugzeug (101) entsprechend Anspruch 5 weiterhin bestehend aus:
<claim-text>einer Öffnung (401), die sich über eine Länge des zweiten wärmeabsorbierenden Materials (503) erstreckt;<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei ein Teil der Wärmeenergie durch die Öffnung (401) strömt und vom ersten wärmeabsorbierenden Material (501) absorbiert wird.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Das Flugzeug (101) entsprechend Anspruch 5 oder Anspruch 6, zu dem weiterhin Folgendes gehört:
<claim-text>ein Wärmeleiter (505), der das erste wärmeabsorbierende Material (501) leitfähig mit dem zweiten wärmeabsorbierenden Material (503) verbindet;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei der Wärmeleiter (505) die Wärmeenergie vom zweiten wärmeabsorbierenden Material (503) zum ersten wärmeabsorbierenden Material (501) überträgt.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Das Flugzeug (101) entsprechend Anspruch 1 oder einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei das wärmeabsorbierende Material (601, 603) innerhalb der Dicke der Tragfläche positioniert ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Das Flugzeug (101) entsprechend Anspruch 1 oder einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei:
<claim-text>das Flugzeug (101) ein Hubschrauber ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>die Tragfläche ein Rotorflügel (117, 121) des Hubschraubers ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Das Flugzeug (101) entsprechend Anspruch 1 oder einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei:
<claim-text>der Transmitter (125) Mikrowellenenergie überträgt; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>das wärmeabsorbierende Material (131, 133, 134) Mikrowellenenergie absorbiert.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Das Flugzeug (101) entsprechend Anspruch 2 oder einem der Ansprüche 3 bis 10, wenn diese von Anspruch 2 abhängig sind, wobei das Kontrollsystem (135) Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>einen ersten Sensor (139) zur Feststellung der Eisbildung; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen zweiten Sensor (141) zur Feststellung des Vorhandenseins der Tragfläche.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Das Flugzeug (101) entsprechend einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, zu dem weiterhin Folgendes gehört:
<claim-text>ein zweiter Mikrowellentransmitter (125), der sich an einem Heckausleger (107) des Flugzeugs (101) befindet; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>ein zweites wärmeabsorbierendes Material (125), das an einem Heckausleger (111) angebracht ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Ein Verfahren zur Enteisung einer Tragfläche bestehend aus:<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> -->
<claim-text>Übertragen von Wärmeenergie nach Feststellen von Eisbildung auf ein wärmeabsorbierendes Material, das an der Tragfläche befestigt ist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Absorbieren der übertragenen Wärmeenergie mit dem wärmeabsorbierenden Material;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Erwärmen der Tragfläche mit dem wärmeabsorbierenden Material;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Deaktivieren der übertragenen Wärmeenergie, wenn keine Eisbildung festgestellt wird; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei die angewandte Wärme Enteisung der Tragfläche verursacht.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Das Verfahren entsprechend Anspruch 13, bestehend aus:
<claim-text>Feststellen von Eisbildung auf der Tragfläche; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Kontrollieren der übertragenen Wärmeenergie nach Feststellen der Eisbildung.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Das Verfahren entsprechend Anspruch 13 oder Anspruch 14, wobei der Prozess der Übertragung von Wärmeenergie durch Mikrowellen erzielt wird.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56977839" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>An aircraft (101), comprising:
<claim-text>an airfoil susceptible to an ice buildup;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a heat absorbent material (131, 133, 134) carried by the airfoil;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a transmitter (125) for transmitting heat energy to the heat absorbent material (131, 133, 134); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a control system (135) operably associated with the transmitter (125);</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the control system (135) activates the transmitter (125) upon detection of the ice buildup and deactivates the transmitter (125) upon no detection of the ice buildup; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the heat absorbent material (131, 133, 134) absorbs the heat energy that in turn warms the airfoil and breaks apart ice buildup formed thereon.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The aircraft (101) of claim 1, the control system (135) comprising:
<claim-text>a sensor (139) for detecting the ice buildup;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein upon detection of the ice buildup, the sensor (139) relays the sensed information to the control system (135), which in turn activates the transmitter (125).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The aircraft (101) of claim 2, wherein the sensor (139) detects conditions likely to create the ice buildup.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The aircraft (101) of claim 2 or claim 3, the control system (135) comprising:
<claim-text>a sensor (141) for detecting the presence of the airfoil.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The aircraft (101) of claim 1 or of any one of claims 2 to 4, the heat absorbent material (131, 133, 134) comprising:
<claim-text>a first heat absorbent material (501) secured to a suction surface (211) of the airfoil; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second heat absorbent material (503) secured to a pressure surface (213) of the airfoil.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The aircraft (101) of claim 5, further comprising:
<claim-text>a port (401) extending a length of the second heat absorbent material (503);<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a portion of the heat energy passes through the port (401) and is absorbed by the first heat absorbent material (501).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The aircraft (101) of claim 5 or of claim 6, further comprising:
<claim-text>a heat conductor (505) conductively coupling the first heat absorbent material (501) to the second heat absorbent material (503);</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the heat conductor (505) transfers the heat energy from the second heat absorbent material (503) to the first heat absorbent material (501).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The aircraft (101) of claim 1 or of any preceding claim, wherein the heat absorbent material (601, 603) is disposed within the thickness of the airfoil.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The aircraft (101) of claim 1 or of any preceding claim, wherein:
<claim-text>the aircraft (101) is a helicopter; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the airfoil is a rotor blade (117, 121) of the helicopter.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The aircraft (101) of claim 1 or of any preceding claim, wherein:
<claim-text>the transmitter (125) transmits microwave energy; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the heat absorbent material (131, 133, 134) absorbs microwave energy.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>The aircraft (101) of claim 2, or of any of claims 3 to 10 when dependent on claim 2, the control system (135) comprising:
<claim-text>a first sensor (139) for detecting the ice buildup; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second sensor (141) for detecting the presence of the airfoil.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>The aircraft (101) of any one of the preceding claims, further comprising:
<claim-text>a second microwave transmitter (125) carried on a tail boom (107) of the aircraft (101); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second heat absorbent material (125) secured to a tail rotor (111).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>A method to de-ice an airfoil, comprising:
<claim-text>transmitting heat energy to a heat absorbent material secured to the airfoil upon detection of the ice buildup;</claim-text>
<claim-text>absorbing the transmitted heat energy with the heat absorbent material;</claim-text>
<claim-text>heating the airfoil with the heat absorbent material;<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>deactivating the transmitted heat energy upon no detection of the ice buildup; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the heat applied causes de-icing of the airfoil.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>The method of claim 13, further comprising:
<claim-text>detecting the presence of an ice buildup on the airfoil; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>controlling the transmitted heat energy upon detection of the ice buildup.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>The method of claim 13 or claim 14, wherein the process of transmitting heat energy is achieved through microwaves.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56977840" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Un aéronef (101), comprenant :
<claim-text>une surface portante pouvant être sujette à une accumulation de givre,</claim-text>
<claim-text>un matériau d'absorption thermique (131, 133, 134) placé sur la surface portante,</claim-text>
<claim-text>un émetteur (125) pour le transmission d'une énergie thermique au matériau d'absorption thermique (131, 133, 134), et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un système de commande (135) opérationnellement associé à l'émetteur (125),</claim-text>
<claim-text>où le système de commande (135) active l'émetteur (125) en cas de détection de l'accumulation de givre et désactive l'émetteur (125) en cas de non-détection de l'accumulation de givre, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>où le matériau d'absorption thermique (131, 133, 134) absorbe l'énergie thermique qui à son tour chauffe la surface portante et élimine l'accumulation de givre formée sur celle-ci.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>L'aéronef (101) selon la Revendication 1, le système de commande (135) comprenant :
<claim-text>un capteur (139) de détection de l'accumulation de givre,</claim-text>
<claim-text>où, en cas de détection de l'accumulation de givre, le capteur (139) relaie l'information détectée au système de commande (135) qui à son tour active l'émetteur (125).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>L'aéronef (101) selon la Revendication 2, où le capteur (139) détecte des conditions susceptibles de créer l'accumulation de givre.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>L'aéronef (101) selon la Revendication 2 ou 3, le système de commande (135) comprenant :
<claim-text>un capteur (141) de détection de la présence de la surface portante.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>L'aéronef (101) selon la Revendication 1 ou selon l'une quelconque des Revendications 2 à 4, le matériau d'absorption thermique (131, 133, 134) comprenant :
<claim-text>un premier matériau d'absorption thermique (501) fixé sur une surface d'aspiration (211) de la surface portante, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un deuxième matériau d'absorption thermique (503) fixé sur une surface de pression (213) de la surface portante.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>L'aéronef (101) selon la Revendication 5, comprenant en outre :
<claim-text>un port (401) s'étendant sur une longueur du deuxième matériau d'absorption thermique (503),</claim-text>
<claim-text>où une partie de l'énergie thermique passe au travers du port (401) et est absorbée par le premier matériau d'absorption thermique (501).</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>L'aéronef (101) selon la Revendication 5 ou 6, comprenant en outre :
<claim-text>un conducteur thermique (505) couplant de manière conductrice le premier matériau d'absorption thermique (501) au deuxième matériau d'absorption thermique (503),</claim-text>
<claim-text>où le conducteur thermique (505) transfère l'énergie thermique du deuxième matériau d'absorption thermique (503) au premier matériau d'absorption thermique (501).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>L'aéronef (101) selon la Revendication 1 ou selon l'une quelconque des Revendications précédentes, où le matériau d'absorption thermique (601, 603) est disposé à l'intérieur de l'épaisseur de la surface portante.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>L'aéronef (101) selon la Revendication 1 ou selon l'une quelconque des Revendications précédentes, où :
<claim-text>l'aéronef (101) est un hélicoptère, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>la surface portante est une pale de rotor (117, 121) de l'hélicoptère.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>L'aéronef (101) selon la Revendication 1 ou selon l'une quelconque des Revendications précédentes, où :
<claim-text>l'émetteur (125) transmet énergie à micro-ondes, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>le matériau d'absorption thermique (131, 133, 134) absorbe l'énergie à micro-ondes.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>L'aéronef (101) selon la Revendication 2, ou selon l'une quelconque des Revendications 3 à 10 lorsqu'elle dépend de la Revendication 2, le système de commande (135) comprenant :
<claim-text>un premier capteur (139) de détection de l'accumulation de givre, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un deuxième capteur (141) de détection de la présence de la surface portante.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>L'aéronef (101) selon l'une quelconque des Revendications précédentes, comprenant en outre :
<claim-text>un deuxième émetteur à micro-ondes (125) installé sur une poutre de queue (107) de l'aéronef (101), et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un deuxième matériau d'absorption thermique (125) fixé sur un rotor de queue (111).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Un procédé de dégivrage d'une surface portante, comprenant :
<claim-text>la transmission d'une énergie thermique à un matériau d'absorption thermique fixé sur la surface portante en cas de détection de l'accumulation de givre,</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'absorption de l'énergie thermique transmise avec le matériau d'absorption thermique,</claim-text>
<claim-text>le chauffage de la surface portante avec le matériau d'absorption thermique,<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>la désactivation de l'énergie thermique transmise en cas de non-détection de l'accumulation de givre, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>où la chaleur appliquée provoque un dégivrage de la surface portante.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Le procédé selon la Revendication 13, comprenant en outre :
<claim-text>la détection de la présence d'une accumulation de givre sur la surface portante, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>la régulation de l'énergie thermique transmise en cas de détection de l'accumulation de givre.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Le procédé selon la Revendication 13 ou 14, où le processus de transmission d'une énergie thermique est mis en oeuvre par l'intermédiaire de micro-ondes.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16668401" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="114" he="204" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2,3"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="137" he="210" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --><figure id="f0003" num="4,5,6"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="165" he="204" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --><figure id="f0004" num="7"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="154" he="170" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
