<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2384054-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2384054" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="44260422" file-reference-id="315065" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146588496" ucid="EP-2384054-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2384054</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-11160195-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154850688" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>11160195</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20110329</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP254928398" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>11160195.1</doc-number><date>20110329</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140550233" ucid="KR-20100038819-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>KR</country><doc-number>20100038819</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20100427</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130726</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989325809" load-source="docdb">H04W  36/30        20090101AFI20110720BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1699697221" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04W  76/10        20180201 LA20180203BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2102353287" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04W  36/18        20130101 LI20140729BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2102356423" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04W  36/08        20130101 LA20140729BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2102362179" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04W  64/00        20130101 FI20140729BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2102365427" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04W  36/30        20130101 LI20140730BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370121" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Kommunikationsverfahren für eine versorgende Mikrobasisstation und eine benachbarte Mikrobasisstation in einer mehrzelligen Gruppe</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370122" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Communication method of a serving micro base station and a neighbor micro base station in a multi-cell group</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370123" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Procédé de communication d'une station de base micro de desserte et d'une station de base micro voisine dans un groupe de plusieurs cellules</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919508114" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>SAMSUNG ELECTRONICS CO LTD</last-name><address><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919511503" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>SAMSUNG ELECTRONICS CO., LTD.</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919520543" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>KOREA ADVANCED INST SCI &amp; TECH</last-name><address><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919520011" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>KOREA ADVANCED INSTITUTE OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919544368" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>KWON TAE SOO</last-name><address><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919517849" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>KWON, TAE SOO</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919023388" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>KWON, TAE SOO</last-name><address><street>Samsung Advanced Institute of Technology Mt. 14-1, Nongseo-dong, Giheung-gu, Yongin-si</street><city>446-712 Gyeonggi-do</city><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919541932" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>AHN WOO GEUN</last-name><address><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919536461" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>AHN, WOO GEUN</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919023390" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>AHN, WOO GEUN</last-name><address><street>Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology 373-1 Guseong-dong, Yuseong-gu</street><city>305-701 Daejeon</city><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919532939" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>CHO DONG HO</last-name><address><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919528896" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>CHO, DONG HO</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919023387" load-source="patent-office" sequence="3" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>CHO, DONG HO</last-name><address><street>Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology 373-1 Guseong-dong, Yuseong-gu</street><city>305-701 Daejeon</city><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919543048" load-source="docdb" sequence="4" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>KANG MIN SUK</last-name><address><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919532072" load-source="docdb" sequence="4" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>KANG, MIN SUK</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919023389" load-source="patent-office" sequence="4" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>KANG, MIN SUK</last-name><address><street>Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology 373-1 Guseong-dong, Yuseong-gu</street><city>305-701 Daejeon</city><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919023392" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Samsung Electronics Co., Ltd.</last-name><iid>101328413</iid><address><street>129, Samsung-ro Yeongtong-gu</street><city>SUWON-SI, GYEONGGI-DO, 443-742</city><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></assignee><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919023393" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology</last-name><iid>101394579</iid><address><street>373-1 Guseong-Dong Yuseong-Gu</street><city>Daejeon 305-701</city><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919023391" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Jacobs, Bart</last-name><suffix>et al</suffix><iid>101211562</iid><address><street>Arnold &amp; Siedsma Sweelinckplein 1</street><city>2517 GK Den Haag</city><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549870812" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS549893641" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549880388" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549875921" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549786107" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549880389" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549893642" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549870813" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549880394" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549880395" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549786374" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549875930" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549786108" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549870834" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549880396" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549870835" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549893643" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549786113" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549880397" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549875931" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549880430" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549875932" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549803302" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549875933" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549875938" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549803303" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS549803308" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549786375" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549924281" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549786376" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549803309" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549786114" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549803310" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS549786389" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549893644" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549924282" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549924283" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS549875939" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63960917" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001"><b><u>BACKGROUND</u></b></heading><heading id="h0002"><b>1. Field</b></heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The following description relates to a communication method of a base station and a vehicular mobile terminal, and more particularly, to a communication method of a serving micro base station, a neighbor micro base station, a macro base station, and a vehicular mobile terminal.</p><heading id="h0003"><b>2. Description of Related Art</b></heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">In a mobile communication system, a terminal may be mobile. Because of this mobility, when the terminal moves near the edge of or beyond the service coverage of a base station serving the terminal, a handover of the terminal to a new base station is needed in order to maintain service. In a wireless communication system, determining whether to perform a handover is based on various qualities, for example, the quality of a downlink channel between a terminal to be handed over and a target base station.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">A base station serving a terminal to be handed over may request the terminal to measure qualities of a neighbor base station and a wireless link, and report about the measurement results to the base station. The serving base station may request the new target base station for a<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> handover based on reported values of the qualities of a wireless channel, and the target base station may provide a response to the request.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">When receiving an acceptance message of the handover from the target base station, the serving base station may transmit a message to instruct performance of the handover to the terminal, and the terminal may send a response message to the base station in service indicating that the handover is to be performed.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">A communication method of a serving base station that is serving a vehicular mobile terminal is known from <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US2009028112A1"><text>US 2009/028112 A1</text></patcit>, which discloses a handover scheme utilizing both a downlink channel quality indication between a serving base station and a mobile terminal and uplink channel quality indications amongst the terminal and a set of target base stations. To generate uplink channel quality indications the terminal transmits a sounding reference signal. The serving base station receives uplink channel state information from the target base stations through backhaul communication.</p><heading id="h0004"><b><u>SUMMARY</u></b></heading><p id="p0006" num="0006">In one general aspect, there is provided a communication method of a serving micro base station that is serving a vehicular mobile terminal as defined in claim 1.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">The method may further comprise determining a preparation level of a handover associated with a level of an operation used for the serving micro base station and a neighbor micro base station to perform the handover.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --><!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p><p id="p0008" num="0008">The determining of the preparation level of the handover may comprise determining a preparation level of the handover based on the uplink broadcast information received by the serving micro base station and uplink broadcast information received by the neighbor micro base station.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">The determining of the preparation level of the handover may comprise determining a preparation level of the handover based on at least one of a mobility of the vehicular mobile terminal, an estimated cell residence time of the vehicular mobile terminal, a backhaul environment between the serving micro base station and the neighbor micro base station, an amount of data used by the vehicular mobile terminal, a load of the serving micro base station, and a load of the neighbor micro base station.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">The method may further comprise reporting about the determined preparation level of the handover to the neighbor micro base station.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">The determining of the preparation level of the handover may comprise determining a preparation level of the handover to be at one of a plurality of levels including at least one of a preregistration, an uplink synchronization setup, an acceptance of a handover and performance of the handover, a joint interference control for the vehicular mobile terminal, a joint processing on the vehicular mobile terminal, and a cell merger.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">The method may further comprise estimating a cell residence time of the vehicular mobile terminal based on the uplink broadcast information received from the serving micro base station.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">The vehicular mobile terminal may comprise at least one of a femto base station, a moving relay, and a mobile terminal.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></p><p id="p0014" num="0014">In another aspect, there is provided a communication method of a neighbor micro base station as defined in claim 8.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">The reporting information about the receiving state of the uplink broadcast information may comprise reporting the information about the receiving state of the uplink broadcast information in order to determine a preparation level of a handover associated with a level of an operation used for the serving micro base station and a neighbor micro base station to perform the handover.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">The method may further comprise identifying the preparation level of the handover based on a report of the serving micro base station.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">The method may further comprise performing the handover of the vehicular mobile terminal based on the preparation level of the handover.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">The identifying of the unique access code may comprise receiving information about a channel allocated for the unique access code from the macro base station.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">The method may further comprise performing coordinated communication with the serving micro base station based on the determination of the serving micro base station, when the preparation level of the handover is determined to be a level including at least one of joint interference control<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> for the vehicular mobile terminal and joint processing on the vehicular mobile terminal.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">The method may further comprise estimating an uplink timing offset or estimating a quality of service (QoS) of the vehicular mobile terminal, based on the uplink broadcast information.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p><p id="p0021" num="0021">In another aspect, there is provided a computer-readable storage medium having stored therein program instructions to cause a processor to implement the communication method of a serving micro base station as defined in claim 1 or the communication method of a neighbor micro base station as defined in claim 8.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">Other features and aspects may be apparent from the following description, the drawings, and the claims.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --><!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --></p><heading id="h0005"><b><u>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</u></b></heading><p id="p0023" num="0023"><ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a diagram illustrating an example of a multi-cell group.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> is a diagram illustrating an example of a vehicular mobile terminal communicating with a macro base station and a vehicular mobile terminal communicating with a micro base station using different channels in the multi-cell group.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">FIGS. 3A</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0004">3B</figref> are diagrams illustrating examples of a process of performing a handover based on uplink broadcast information in a multi-cell group.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 4</figref> is a diagram illustrating an example of a switch from a general handover scheme based on a measurement report of a downlink signal to a handover scheme based on uplink broadcast information.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 5</figref> is a diagram illustrating an example of a preparation level of a handover that is determined differently in each cell of a multi-cell group.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 6</figref> is a flowchart illustrating an example of a communication method of a serving micro base station in a multi-cell group.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 7</figref> is a flowchart illustrating an example of a communication method of a neighbor micro base station in a multi-cell group.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 8</figref> is a flowchart illustrating an example of a communication method of a vehicular mobile terminal in a multi-cell group.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0010">FIG. 9</figref> is a flowchart illustrating an example of a communication method of a macro base station in a multi-cell group.</li></ul></p><p id="p0024" num="0024">Throughout the drawings and the description, unless otherwise described, the same drawing reference numerals should be understood to refer to the same elements,<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> features, and structures. The relative size and depiction of these elements may be exaggerated for clarity, illustration, and convenience.</p><heading id="h0006"><b><u>DESCRIPTION</u></b></heading><p id="p0025" num="0025">The following description is provided to assist the reader in gaining a comprehensive understanding of the methods, apparatuses, and/or systems described herein. Accordingly, various changes, modifications, and equivalents of the methods, apparatuses, and/or systems described herein may be suggested to those of ordinary skill in the art. Also, description of well-known functions and constructions may be omitted for increased clarity and conciseness.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">In the following description, a vehicular mobile terminal may include a mobile terminal which is installed in a vehicle and a mobile terminal which is transportable by a user. The term "mobile" may refer to an object in motion or to an object at rest that is capable of being set into motion.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027"><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates an example of a multi-cell group.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, the multi-cell group includes a macro cell 100, a macro base station 110, a plurality of micro cells 120 within a cell coverage of the macro base station 110, a plurality of micro base stations 130 within the cell coverage of the macro base station 110, and a vehicular mobile terminal 140.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">For example, the plurality of micro cells 120 may be fully or partially included in the coverage area of the macro cell 100, and the micro cells 120 may each include a respective micro base station 130.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">The plurality of micro base stations 130 may include a serving micro base station that is currently serving the vehicular mobile terminal 140 and the neighbor micro base<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> stations that may operate as a serving micro base station when a handover is performed.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">For example, the macro base station 110 may allocate a unique access code and a channel for the unique access code to the vehicular mobile terminal 140 that is travelling within the macro cell 100 based on a mobility of the vehicular mobile terminal 140.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">The unique access code and the channel for the unique access code may be allocated to the vehicular mobile terminal 140 based on the mobility of the vehicular mobile terminal 140, for example, the unique access code and the channel for the unique access code may be allocated to the vehicular mobile terminal 140 based on a predetermined speed and the like.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">For example, the mobility of the vehicular mobile terminal 140 may include a traveling speed, a traveling direction, an estimated cell residence time, a traveling path, and the like, of the vehicular mobile terminal 140.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">In this example, the estimated cell residence time may be changed based on a radius of the cell coverage. The mobility may also include an intensity of a signal received from the vehicular mobile terminal 140 to the serving micro base station and the neighbor micro base stations.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">As an example, the unique access code allocated to the vehicular mobile terminal 140 may be available for a channel measurement of the vehicular mobile terminal 140, uplink synchronization, a joint cell formation, a handover determination, and the like. The unique access code and the channel for the unique access code allocated to the vehicular mobile terminal 140 may be maintained within the coverage of the same macro base station 110. For example, the unique access code and the channel for the unique access code allocated to the vehicular mobile terminal 140 may be<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> renewed or maintained when a handover is performed between the macro cell 100 and another macro cell.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">The vehicular mobile terminal 140 has the unique access code within the multi-cell such as the micro cells 120 or the macro cell 100 and vehicular mobile terminal 140 broadcasts uplink broadcast information including the unique access code to the micro base stations 130 in the macro cell 100.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">The micro base stations 130 may receive the uplink broadcast information including the unique access code from the vehicular mobile terminal 140. For example, the serving micro base station may collect uplink broadcast information or information about the uplink broadcast information, for example, uplink reception power, received from a neighbor micro base station. The serving micro base station may use the collected information to perform a handover.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">As an example, the vehicular mobile terminal 140 may include at least one of a femto base station, a moving relay, a mobile terminal, and the like.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039"><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates an example of a vehicular mobile terminal communicating with a macro base station and a vehicular mobile terminal communicating with a micro base station using different channels in a multi-cell group.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040"><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> illustrates an example in which a vehicular mobile terminal 240 that communicates with a macro base station 210 and a vehicular mobile terminal 245 that communicates with a micro base station 230 coexist using a same-frequency channel. In this example, different channels may be allocated to a unique access code of the vehicular mobile terminal 240 in the macro cell 200 and a unique access code of the vehicular mobile terminal 245 in the micro cell 220, respectively.<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --></p><p id="p0041" num="0041">For example, different channels may be allocated to prevent the unique access codes transmitted by the vehicular mobile terminals 245 in the micro cell 220 from going undetected, for example, due to a power of the unique access code transmitted by the vehicular mobile terminal 240 with a high power communicating with the macro base station 210 positioned on a cell boundary. As an example, a power level of the unique access code transmitted by each of the vehicular mobile terminals 240 and 245 may be set by the macro base station 210 or the micro base station 230.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">A transmission power of the unique access code transmitted by each of the vehicular mobile terminals 245 in the micro cell 220 may be determined based on a transmission power offset value of a representative vehicular mobile terminal traveling in the cell, shown in dotted line.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">For example, the transmission power offset value of the representative vehicular mobile terminal traveling in the cell (a vehicular mobile terminal in a dotted line) may be obtained, and the micro base station 230 may broadcast the value such that an adjacent vehicular mobile terminal may use the value. For example, the above scheme may be based on an adjacent vehicular mobile terminal travelling on a road having similar conditions of position and speed, and thus, communication paths and link qualities may be similar.</p><p id="p0044" num="0044"><figref idrefs="f0003">FIGS. 3A</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0004">3B</figref> illustrate examples of a process of performing a handover based on uplink broadcast information in a multi-cell group.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0003">FIGS. 3A</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0004">3B</figref>, the multi-cell group includes a vehicular mobile terminal 301, a macro base station 305, and various micro base stations 303, 307, and 309. The macro base station 305 has a corresponding macro cell, and the micro base stations 303, 307, and 309 have corresponding micro cells.<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></p><p id="p0046" num="0046">When the vehicular mobile terminal 301 within a cell coverage of the macro base station 305 gains initial random access to the macro base station 305, in 311, the macro base station 305 registers the vehicular mobile terminal 301, for example, through communication with a serving micro base station 303, in 313. For example, the vehicular mobile terminal 301 may include at least one of a femto base station, a moving relay, and a mobile terminal.</p><p id="p0047" num="0047">The macro base station 305 identifies a mobility of the vehicular mobile terminal 301 in the multi-cell group, in 315, and the macro base station 305 detects a change in the mobility of the vehicular mobile terminal 301, in 317.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048">For example, the mobility of the vehicular mobile terminal 301 may include a traveling speed, a traveling direction, an estimated cell residence time, a traveling path, and the like, of the vehicular mobile terminal 301. For example, the estimated cell residence time may be changed based on a radius of the cell coverage. For example, the estimated cell residence time may be changed based on GPS information of the vehicular mobile terminal 301, traveling speed information of the vehicular mobile terminal 301, information about road conditions such as change time information of a traffic light, and the like. In some embodiments, an intensity of a signal (for example, uplink broadcast information) received from the vehicular mobile terminal 301 to the serving micro base station 303 and the neighbor micro base stations 307 and 309 may also be represented by a mobility function.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">The macro base station 305 allocates a unique access code and a channel for the unique access code to the vehicular mobile terminal 301, for example, based on the mobility of the vehicular mobile terminal 301, in 319.<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --></p><p id="p0050" num="0050">The unique access code allocated to the vehicular mobile terminal 301 is identified by the vehicular mobile terminal 301 in the multi-cell group, the serving micro base station 303 that is providing a communication service to the vehicular mobile terminal 301, and the neighbor micro base stations 307 and 309, in 321.</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">The vehicular mobile terminal 301 broadcasts uplink broadcast information including the unique access code to the plurality of micro base stations 303 and 307 within the cell coverage of the macro base station 305, in 323. For example, the uplink broadcast information including the unique access code broadcasted by the vehicular mobile terminal 301 may only reach the neighbor micro base station 1 307, and may not reach the micro base station 2 309.</p><p id="p0052" num="0052">In 323, for example, the neighbor micro base station 1 307 may overhear the uplink broadcast information including the unique access code from the vehicular mobile terminal 301. Accordingly, in 323 the neighbor micro base station 1 307 may report information about a receiving state of the uplink broadcast information to the serving micro base station 303 of the vehicular mobile terminal 301.</p><p id="p0053" num="0053">For example, the plurality of neighbor micro base stations (here, the neighbor micro base station 1 307) within the cell coverage of the macro base station 305 may estimate an uplink timing offset or quality of service (QoS) of the vehicular mobile terminal 301 based on the overheard uplink broadcast information including the unique access code. As another example, the serving micro base station 303 and the neighbor micro base stations (here, the neighbor micro base station 1 307) within the cell coverage of the macro base station 305 may estimate a cell residence time of the vehicular mobile terminal 301 based on the uplink<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> broadcast information received from the vehicular mobile terminal 301.</p><p id="p0054" num="0054">To estimate the cell residence time of the vehicular mobile terminal 301, the serving micro base station 303 and the neighbor micro base stations (here, the neighbor micro base station 1 307) may use, for example, GPS information of the vehicular mobile terminal 301, traveling speed information of the vehicular mobile terminal 301, information about road conditions such as change time information of a traffic light, and the like.</p><p id="p0055" num="0055">The serving micro base station 303 collects information about the receiving state of the uplink broadcast information of the neighbor micro base station 1 307 based on the report from the neighbor micro base station 1 307, in 325.</p><p id="p0056" num="0056">The serving micro base station 303 may determine whether to perform a handover of the vehicular mobile terminal 301 based on the uplink broadcast information. In addition, the serving micro base station 303 may determine a preparation level of the handover associated with a level of an operation used for the serving micro base station 303 and the neighbor micro base station 1 307 to perform the handover. For example, the serving micro base station 303 may determine the preparation level of the handover based on the uplink broadcast information received by the serving micro base station 303 and the uplink broadcast information received by the neighbor micro base station 1 307.</p><p id="p0057" num="0057">The serving micro base station 303 may determine the preparation level of the handover as one of a plurality of levels, For example, the plurality of the levels may include at least one of a preregistration of each of the serving micro base station 303 and the neighbor micro base station 1 307, an uplink synchronization setup, an acceptance of a<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> handover and performance of the handover, a joint interference control for the vehicular mobile terminal 301, a joint processing on the vehicular mobile terminal 301, a cell merger, and the like.</p><p id="p0058" num="0058">An example in which the preparation level of the handover is determined is joint processing on the vehicular mobile terminal 301 in operation 327 is described with reference to the examples of <figref idrefs="f0003">FIGS. 3A</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0004">3B</figref>.</p><p id="p0059" num="0059">In this example, the serving micro base station 303 exchanges new topology information for a joint processing on the vehicular mobile terminal 301 with the neighbor micro base station 1 307, in 329. For example, the new topology information may include information used for communication with the neighbor micro base station 1 307 based on a joint processing on the vehicular mobile terminal 301.</p><p id="p0060" num="0060">The vehicular mobile terminal 301 transmits and receives data for the vehicular mobile terminal 301 in cooperation with the neighbor micro base station 1 307, in 331. The vehicular mobile terminal 301 broadcasts the uplink broadcast information including the unique access code again, in 333. For example, the uplink broadcast information including the unique access code may be broadcasted to not only the neighbor micro base station 1 307 but also to the neighbor micro base station 2 309 due to the mobility of the vehicular mobile terminal 301.</p><p id="p0061" num="0061">The serving micro base station 303 may collect information about a receiving state of the uplink broadcast information from not only the neighbor micro base station 1 307 but also the neighbor micro base station 2 309, in 335.</p><p id="p0062" num="0062">The serving micro base station 303 determines the preparation level of the handover again based on the collected information in operation 335, and may determine a joint processing on the vehicular mobile terminal 301 with<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> the neighbor micro base station 1 307 and the neighbor micro base station 2 309, in 337. The data is then processed in 339.</p><p id="p0063" num="0063">For example, when the serving micro base station 303 determines a joint processing on the vehicular mobile terminal 301, the serving micro base station 303 may transmit and receive data for the vehicular mobile terminal 301 in cooperation with the neighbor micro base station 1 307 and the neighbor micro base station 2 309, in 331. Accordingly, the data may be joint-processed by the serving micro base station 303 and the vehicular mobile terminal 301 in cooperation with the neighbor micro base station 1 307 and the neighbor micro base station 2 309.</p><p id="p0064" num="0064">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 3B</figref>, the vehicular mobile terminal 301 continually broadcasts the uplink broadcast information according to the mobility of the vehicular mobile terminal 301, in 341, and the serving micro base station collects information of a receiving state of the uplink broadcast information from the neighbor micro base stations 307 and 309, in operation 343.</p><p id="p0065" num="0065">When it is determined that a handover is needed for the vehicular mobile terminal 301, the serving micro base station 303 may determine the preparation level of the handover to be a handover performance. For example, in 345 the serving micro base station 303 may determine a handover to the neighbor micro base station 1 307 which is a neighbor micro base station that the vehicular mobile terminal 301 is approaching.</p><p id="p0066" num="0066">In 345, the serving micro base station 303 may determine the preparation level of the handover based on the uplink broadcast information received by the serving micro base station 303, and the uplink broadcast information and the information about the receiving state of the uplink<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> broadcast information received by the neighbor micro base stations 307 and 309.</p><p id="p0067" num="0067">Based on the determining the need for the handover, the micro base station 303 that was acting as a serving micro base station becomes a neighbor micro base station, and the base station 307 that was acting as a neighbor micro base station becomes a serving micro base station.</p><p id="p0068" num="0068">After the handover, the vehicular mobile terminal 301 with mobility continually broadcasts the uplink broadcast information, in 347, and the new serving micro base station 307 collects information about a receiving state of the uplink broadcast information from the neighbor micro base stations 303 and 309, in 349.</p><p id="p0069" num="0069">The new serving micro base station 307 determines a preparation level of a handover to be a handover performance to the neighbor micro base station 2 309 based on the mobility of the vehicular mobile terminal 301, in 351.</p><p id="p0070" num="0070">In 351, for example, the serving micro base station 307 may determine the preparation level of the handover based on the uplink broadcast information received from the vehicular mobile terminal 301, and the uplink broadcast information and the information about the receiving state of the uplink broadcast information collected from the neighbor adjacent micro base stations 303 and 309.</p><p id="p0071" num="0071">Based on the determination of performance of the handover in 351, the serving micro base station 307 transmits new topology information to the vehicular mobile terminal 301 and the neighbor micro base station 309 to be a next serving micro base station, in 353. For example, the neighbor micro base station 2 309 may become a serving micro base station based on the performance of the handover.<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --></p><p id="p0072" num="0072">The vehicular mobile terminal 301 broadcasts the uplink broadcast information including the unique access code based on the mobility, in 355.</p><p id="p0073" num="0073">The serving micro base station 309 receiving the uplink broadcast information including the unique access code from the vehicular mobile terminal 301 detects that the vehicular mobile terminal 301 is leaving the cell coverage of the macro base station 305, in 357.</p><p id="p0074" num="0074">The macro base station 305 regains the unique access code and the channel for the unique access code allocated to the vehicular mobile terminal 301 when the vehicular mobile terminal 301 moves beyond the coverage of the macro cell, in 359.</p><p id="p0075" num="0075">As described above, the serving micro base station 307 may allocate or regain a unique access code and a channel for the access code to the vehicular mobile terminal 301 instead of the macro base station 305, and may report about this to the macro base station 305.</p><p id="p0076" num="0076">The aforementioned handover based on the uplink broadcast information may be used along with a general handover scheme, which is described with reference to <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 4</figref>.</p><p id="p0077" num="0077"><figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 4</figref> illustrates an example of a switch from a general handover scheme based on a measurement report of a downlink signal and to a handover scheme based on uplink broadcast information.</p><p id="p0078" num="0078">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 4</figref>, the multi-cell group includes a vehicular mobile terminal 401 and various micro base stations 403, 405, and 407. The micro base stations 403, 405, and 407 have corresponding micro cells.</p><p id="p0079" num="0079">For example, when a vehicular mobile terminal 401 stops or travels at a low speed, a handover may be performed according to a general handover scheme. In 410, a serving<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> micro base station 403 and a neighbor micro base station 1 405 transmit a preamble and a synchronization channel to the vehicular mobile terminal 401.</p><p id="p0080" num="0080">For example, the vehicular mobile terminal 401 measures a preamble signal or a synchronization signal received through a downlink, and transmits a measurement report to the serving micro base station 403, in 415.</p><p id="p0081" num="0081">The serving micro base station 403 determines to perform a handover based on the report, in 420, and performs the handover, in 425. As a result of the handover, the base station 403 that was the serving micro base station becomes a neighbor micro base station, and the base station 405 that was the neighbor micro base station becomes a serving micro base station.</p><p id="p0082" num="0082">In an area where the vehicular mobile terminal 401 travels at a high speed, the serving micro base station 405 may identify the high speed mobility of the vehicular mobile terminal, in 430.</p><p id="p0083" num="0083">In 435, the serving micro base station 405 allocates a unique access code and a channel for the unique access code to the vehicular mobile terminal 401 according to a mobility of the vehicular mobile terminal 401.</p><p id="p0084" num="0084">Subsequently, in operations 440 to 455, a neighbor micro base station 2 407 may become a new serving micro base station. Operations 440 to 455 are similar to operations 341 to 345 described above with reference to <figref idrefs="f0003">FIGS. 3A</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0004">3B</figref>, and thus description thereof will not be repeated.</p><p id="p0085" num="0085">When serving micro base station detects that the vehicular mobile terminal 401 to which the unique access code is allocated decreases in mobility or has no mobility, in 460, the serving micro base station 407 may request the vehicular mobile terminal 401 to return the unique access code and the channel for the unique access code, in 465.<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --></p><p id="p0086" num="0086">The serving micro base station 407 regains the unique access code and the channel for the unique access code from the vehicular mobile terminal 401, in 470.</p><p id="p0087" num="0087">Accordingly, as described with reference to <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 4</figref>, a micro base station may perform a general handover based on a measurement report of a downlink. In addition, a micro base station may perform a handover based on uplink broadcast info. The micro base station may switch between a general handover and a handover based on uplink broadcast info. For example, the micro base station may switch a handover method when a handover is requested from a mobile terminal, based on the current mobility of the mobile terminal.</p><p id="p0088" num="0088"><figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 5</figref> illustrates an example of a preparation level of a handover that is determined differently in each cell of a multi-cell group.</p><p id="p0089" num="0089">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 5</figref>, the multi-cell group includes a base station of a micro cell 1 510, a base station of a micro cell 2 520, a base station of a micro cell 3 530, and a vehicular mobile terminal 540. In this example, the micro cells 510, 520, and 530 are adjacent to each other.</p><p id="p0090" num="0090">In this example, the backhaul environment of the multi-cell group includes a non-data sharing environment such as X2 interface or internet, and the vehicular mobile terminal 540 has a mobility from the micro cell 1, the micro cell 2, to the micro cell 3. Also in this example, the micro base station of the micro cell 1 510 functions as a serving micro base station, the micro base station of the micro cell 2 520 is a neighbor micro base station, and the micro base station of the micro cell 3 530 is another neighbor micro base station.</p><p id="p0091" num="0091">When the vehicular mobile terminal 540 has a low mobility, for example, a low traveling speed of the vehicular mobile terminal 540, the serving micro base<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> station 510 may determine to perform a handover to the microcell 2 when determining a preparation level of a handover of the vehicular mobile terminal 540.</p><p id="p0092" num="0092">For example, the serving micro base station 510 may determine the preparation level of the handover to perform a joint interference control for the vehicular mobile terminal 540 with the neighbor micro base station 520.</p><p id="p0093" num="0093">Accordingly, the neighbor micro base station 520 may accept the handover of the vehicular mobile terminal 540, may perform an uplink synchronization process, and may perform a joint interference control with the serving micro base station 510.</p><p id="p0094" num="0094">When the vehicular mobile terminal 540 changes from a low mobility to a medium mobility, for example, a medium traveling speed, it may become difficult to share a joint interference control signal because of the increase in traveling speed. That is, a joint interference control between the serving micro base station 510 and the neighbor micro base station 520 may be difficult to perform when the vehicular mobile terminal 540 that had a low mobility increases to a medium mobility.</p><p id="p0095" num="0095">In this example, when the serving micro base station 510 determines the handover to the micro cell 2 520, the neighbor micro base station 520 may accept the handover of the vehicular mobile terminal 540 and perform an uplink synchronization process.</p><p id="p0096" num="0096">When the vehicular mobile terminal 540 has a high mobility, for example, a high traveling speed of the vehicular mobile terminal 540, a handover to the micro cell 3 may be performed in a short time after the handover to the micro cell 2. Thus, the neighbor micro base station 530 may perform a preregistration process and an uplink synchronization process in advance.<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --></p><p id="p0097" num="0097">For example, the backhaul environment of the multi-cell group may be a data sharing environment such as remote radio head (RRH), and the vehicular mobile terminal 540 may have a mobility from the micro cell 1, the micro cell 2, to the micro cell 3.</p><p id="p0098" num="0098">When the backhaul environment of the multi-cell group is RRH, data sharing is possible. When the vehicular mobile terminal 540 has a low mobility, for example, a low traveling speed of the vehicular mobile terminal 540, the serving micro base station 510 may determine a handover to the micro cell 2. The serving micro base station 510 may perform a joint interference control during data sharing, for example, joint processing with the neighbor micro base station 520.</p><p id="p0099" num="0099">The neighbor micro base station 520 may accept the handover of the vehicular mobile terminal 540 and may perform an uplink synchronization process and a joint interference control during data sharing.</p><p id="p0100" num="0100">The serving micro base station 510 and the neighbor micro base station 520 may perform the same preparation level of the handover in the vehicular mobile terminal 540 having medium or high mobility as in the backhaul environment of a non-data sharing environment.</p><p id="p0101" num="0101">In this example, the micro cell 3 is not immediately adjacent to the micro cell 1 corresponding to the serving micro base station 510. When the vehicular mobile terminal 540 has a high mobility, the neighbor micro base station 530 corresponding to the micro cell 3, may perform a preregistration process through a backhaul of the preparation level of the handover, and may further perform an uplink synchronization process.</p><p id="p0102" num="0102">As described above, the serving micro base station 510 and the neighbor micro base stations 520 and 530 may receive<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --> uplink broadcast information including a unique access code received from the vehicular mobile terminal 540.</p><p id="p0103" num="0103">For example, the serving micro base station 510 may determine the preparation level of the handover based on at least one of a mobility of the vehicular mobile terminal 540 in the multi-cell group, an estimated cell residence time of the vehicular mobile terminal 540, a backhaul environment between the serving micro base station 510 and the neighbor micro base stations 520 and 530, an amount of data used by the vehicular mobile terminal 540, a load of the serving micro base station 510, a load of the respective neighbor micro base stations 520 and 530, and the like.</p><p id="p0104" num="0104"><figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates an example of a communication method of a serving micro base station in a multi-cell group.</p><p id="p0105" num="0105">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 6</figref>, the serving micro base station identifies a unique access code allocated to a vehicular mobile terminal in the multi-cell group, in 610. In this example, the multi-cell group includes at least a macro base station and a plurality of micro base stations within a cell coverage of the macro base station. In 620, the serving micro base station receives uplink broadcast information including the unique access code from the vehicular mobile terminal.</p><p id="p0106" num="0106">The serving micro base station collects information about a receiving state of the uplink broadcast information of a neighbor micro base station from the neighbor micro base station positioned in the multi-cell group, in 630. For example, the information about the receiving state of the uplink broadcast information may include information useful to determine a preparation level of a handover for each cell such as the load of each neighbor micro base station, information about wireless conditions, and the like.<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --></p><p id="p0107" num="0107">The serving micro base station determines whether a handover is needed based on the uplink broadcast information received by the serving micro base station and the uplink broadcast information received by the neighbor micro base station, in 640. Based on the result of the determination in 640, the serving micro base station may determine a preparation level of a handover based on the aforementioned information when the handover is needed, in 650.</p><p id="p0108" num="0108">The preparation level of the handover determined in 650 may be any one of a plurality of levels, for example, at least one of a preregistration, an uplink synchronization setup, an acceptance of a handover and performance of the handover, a joint interference control for the vehicular mobile terminal, a joint processing on the vehicular mobile terminal, a cell merger, and the like.</p><p id="p0109" num="0109">For example, the joint interference control for the vehicular mobile terminal may be used to minimize interference in a channel, for example, frequency and time, which is allocated to the vehicular mobile terminal and being used. The joint interference control may enable coordinated communication by an exchange of control information between the serving micro base station and neighbor micro base stations.</p><p id="p0110" num="0110">Further, the joint processing on the vehicular mobile terminal may denote a shared joint processing and may enable a coordinated communication by sharing of data about the vehicular mobile terminal between the serving micro base station and neighbor micro base stations.</p><p id="p0111" num="0111">For example, the preparation level of the handover may be determined to be at least one preparation level from a preregistration having a low preparation complexity to a cell merger having a high preparation complexity. Further, the preparation level of the handover may be determined<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --> differently in each micro base station in which a handover is performed.</p><p id="p0112" num="0112">An example in which the vehicular mobile terminal has a high mobility and travels from a micro cell 1 to a micro cell 2 as described above with reference to <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 5</figref> is described herein.</p><p id="p0113" num="0113">When the serving micro base station determines to perform a handover of the vehicular mobile terminal, a preparation level of the handover of the serving micro base station may be a performance of the handover, and a preparation level of the handover of a neighbor micro base station 1 may be an acceptance of the handover and a performance of an uplink synchronization process. In addition, a preparation level of the handover of a neighbor micro base station 2 may be a preregistration process and may further include a performance an uplink synchronization process as necessary.</p><p id="p0114" num="0114">As described above, for example, the preparation level of the handover may be determined differently based on a mobility of the vehicular mobile terminal, an estimated cell residence time of the vehicular mobile terminal, a backhaul environment between the serving micro base station and the neighbor micro base stations, an amount of data used by the vehicular mobile terminal, a load of the serving micro base station, a load of the neighbor micro base station, a wireless environment, and the like.</p><p id="p0115" num="0115">For example, the estimated cell residence time may be determined based on a size of a cell, a level of an uplink reception signal, a speed of the vehicular mobile terminal, a path of the vehicular mobile terminal, and the like.</p><p id="p0116" num="0116">The serving micro base station reports about the preparation level of the handover determined in 650 to the neighbor micro base station, in 660. At the same time, the<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --> serving micro base station may request a handover to the neighbor micro base station to perform the handover.</p><p id="p0117" num="0117">When receiving an acceptance of the handover, for example, an acknowledgement (ACK) signal from a micro base station that requested the handover, in 670, the serving micro base station performs the handover of the vehicular mobile terminal according to the preparation level of the handover determined, in 680.</p><p id="p0118" num="0118"><figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 7</figref> illustrates an example of a communication method of a neighbor micro base station in a multi-cell group.</p><p id="p0119" num="0119">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 7</figref>, in 710 the neighbor micro base station identifies a unique access code allocated to a vehicular mobile terminal in the multi-cell group. The multi-cell group includes at least a macro base station and a plurality of micro base stations within a cell coverage of the macro base station.</p><p id="p0120" num="0120">For example, in 710 the neighbor micro base station may receive information about a channel allocated for the unique access code from the macro base station. For example, the information about the channel may include information about a pattern of the access code and time or frequency allocated to the access code. The neighbor micro base station may estimate an uplink timing offset or QoS of a mobile terminal based on uplink broadcast information.</p><p id="p0121" num="0121">The neighbor micro base station overhears the uplink broadcast information including the unique access code from the vehicular mobile terminal, in 720.</p><p id="p0122" num="0122">In 730, the neighbor micro base station reports information about a receiving state of the uplink broadcast information to the serving micro base station of the vehicular mobile terminal.</p><p id="p0123" num="0123">In 730, the neighbor micro base station may report the information about the receiving state of the uplink<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --> broadcast information in order to determine a preparation level of a handover associated with a level of an operation used for the serving micro base station and the neighbor micro base station to perform the handover.</p><p id="p0124" num="0124">The neighbor micro base station may determine whether there is a request for a handover from the serving micro base station, in 740. The neighbor micro base station may identify a preparation level of a handover based on a report by the serving micro base station before and/or after performing 740.</p><p id="p0125" num="0125">For example, when the preparation level of the handover is determined to be a level including at least one of a joint interference control for the vehicular mobile terminal and a joint processing on the vehicular mobile terminal, the neighbor micro base station may respond to the request from the serving micro base station and perform a coordinated communication with the serving micro base station.</p><p id="p0126" num="0126">When there is a request for a handover from the serving micro base station in 740, the neighbor micro base station determines whether it is possible to accept the handover as the preparation level of the handover reported by the serving micro base station, in 750.</p><p id="p0127" num="0127">The neighbor micro base station accepts the handover when it is possible to accept the handover as the preparation level of the handover reported in 750, and reports about an acceptance of the handover to the serving micro base station, in 760, for example, by transmitting an ACK.</p><p id="p0128" num="0128">The neighbor micro base station performs the handover of the vehicular mobile terminal based on the preparation level of the handover agreed with the serving micro base station, in 770.<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --></p><p id="p0129" num="0129"><figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 8</figref> illustrates an example of a communication method of a vehicular mobile terminal in a multi-cell group.</p><p id="p0130" num="0130">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 8</figref>, in 810 the vehicular mobile terminal in the multi-cell group identifies a unique access code allocated to the vehicular mobile terminal in the multi-cell group. The multi-cell group includes a macro base station and a plurality of micro base stations within a cell coverage of the macro base station. The unique access code may be allocated by the macro base station. The vehicular mobile terminal broadcasts uplink broadcast information including the unique access code to the plurality of micro base stations, in 820.</p><p id="p0131" num="0131">In 820, the vehicular mobile terminal may receive information about a channel allocated for the unique access code from the macro base station, and may broadcast the uplink broadcast information using the channel allocated for the unique access code.</p><p id="p0132" num="0132">For example, the vehicular mobile terminal may include at least one of a femto base station, a moving relay, and a mobile terminal.</p><p id="p0133" num="0133">For example, the methods of the serving micro base station and the neighbor micro base station described above with reference to <figref idrefs="f0007">FIGS. 6</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0008">7</figref> may be realized by a moving relay mounted on a vehicle. For example, a handover may be performed between a serving moving relay and a neighbor moving relay.</p><p id="p0134" num="0134"><figref idrefs="f0010">FIG. 9</figref> illustrates an example of a communication method of a macro base station in a multi-cell group.</p><p id="p0135" num="0135">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0010">FIG. 9</figref>, in 910 the macro base station in the multi-cell group identifies a mobility of a vehicular mobile terminal in the cell. The multi-cell group includes at least the macro base station and a plurality of micro<!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --> base stations within a cell coverage of the macro base station.</p><p id="p0136" num="0136">In 920, the macro base station allocates a unique access code and a channel for the unique access code to the vehicular mobile terminal according to the mobility of the vehicular mobile terminal.</p><p id="p0137" num="0137">The unique access code and the channel for the unique access code may be allocated, for example, to the vehicular mobile terminal having a mobility of a predetermined speed.</p><p id="p0138" num="0138">For example, the unique access code may be available for a channel measurement of the vehicular mobile terminal, uplink synchronization, a joint cell formation, and a handover determination.</p><p id="p0139" num="0139">For example, the mobility of the vehicular mobile terminal may include a traveling speed, a traveling direction, an estimated cell residence time, and a traveling path of the vehicular mobile terminal. The estimated cell residence time may be changed on a radius of the cell coverage or a level of an uplink reception signal.</p><p id="p0140" num="0140">As another example, the estimated cell residence time may be estimated using GPS information of the vehicular mobile terminal, traveling speed information of the vehicular mobile terminal, information about road conditions such as traffic light information, and the like, based on uplink broadcast information including the unique access code received from a serving micro base station.</p><p id="p0141" num="0141">The macro base station reports about the unique access code and the channel for the unique access code allocated to the vehicular mobile terminal, to the plurality of micro base stations, in 930.</p><p id="p0142" num="0142">For example, the plurality of micro base stations may include the serving micro base station to provide a communication service to the vehicular mobile terminal and a<!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --> neighbor micro base station adjacent to the serving micro base station.</p><p id="p0143" num="0143">The macro base station may regain the unique access code and the channel for the unique access code based on the mobility of the vehicular mobile terminal.</p><p id="p0144" num="0144">For example, as described above with reference to <figref idrefs="f0003 f0004">FIGS. 3</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0005">4</figref>, the macro base station may regain the unique access code and the channel for the unique access code allocated to the vehicular mobile terminal when the vehicular mobile terminal moves beyond coverage of a macro cell or decreases in mobility.</p><p id="p0145" num="0145">The macro base station may forward data about the vehicular mobile terminal from the serving micro base station to one or more neighbor micro base stations according to a renewed data forwarding path when a preparation level of a handover associated with a level of an operation used for the serving micro base station and the neighbor micro base station to perform the handover uses cooperation between the serving micro base station and the neighbor micro base station.</p><p id="p0146" num="0146">In addition, the macro base station may forward the data about the vehicular mobile terminal to a neighbor micro base station when the preparation level of the handover associated with a level of an operation used for a serving micro base station and the neighbor micro base station to perform the handover requests cooperation between the serving micro base station and the neighbor micro base station.</p><p id="p0147" num="0147">As a non-exhaustive illustration only, the terminal device described herein may refer to mobile devices such as a cellular phone, a personal digital assistant (PDA), a digital camera, a portable game console, an MP3 player, a portable/personal multimedia player (PMP), a handheld e-book,<!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --> a portable lab-top personal computer (PC), a global positioning system (GPS) navigation, and devices such as a desktop PC, a high definition television (HDTV), an optical disc player, a setup box, and the like, capable of wireless communication or network communication consistent with that disclosed herein.</p><p id="p0148" num="0148">A computing system or a computer may include a microprocessor that is electrically connected with a bus, a user interface, and a memory controller. It may further include a flash memory device. The flash memory device may store N-bit data via the memory controller. The N-bit data is processed or will be processed by the microprocessor and N may be 1 or an integer greater than 1. Where the computing system or computer is a mobile apparatus, a battery may be additionally provided to supply operation voltage of the computing system or computer.</p><p id="p0149" num="0149">It should be apparent to those of ordinary skill in the art that the computing system or computer may further include an application chipset, a camera image processor (CIS), a mobile Dynamic Random Access Memory (DRAM), and the like. The memory controller and the flash memory device may constitute a solid state drive/disk (SSD) that uses a nonvolatile memory to store data.</p><p id="p0150" num="0150">The processes, functions, methods and/or software described above may be recorded, stored, or fixed in one or more computer-readable storage media that includes program instructions to be implemented by a computer to cause a processor to execute or perform the program instructions. The media may also include, alone or in combination with the program instructions, data files, data structures, and the like. Examples of computer-readable storage media include magnetic media such as hard disks, floppy disks, and magnetic tape; optical media such as CD ROM disks and DVDs;<!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --> magneto-optical media such as optical disks; and hardware devices that are specially configured to store and perform program instructions, such as read-only memory (ROM), random access memory (RAM), flash memory, and the like. Examples of program instructions include both machine code, such as produced by a compiler, and files containing higher level code that may be executed by the computer using an interpreter. The described hardware devices may be configured to act as one or more software modules in order to perform the operations and methods described above, or vice versa. In addition, a computer-readable storage medium may be distributed among computer systems connected through a network and non-transitory computer-readable codes or program instructions may be stored and executed in a decentralized manner.</p><p id="p0151" num="0151">A number of examples have been described above. Nevertheless, it should be understood that various modifications may be made. For example, suitable results may be achieved if the described techniques are performed in a different order and/or if components in a described system, architecture, device, or circuit are combined in a different manner and/or replaced or supplemented by other components or their equivalents. Accordingly, other implementations are within the scope of the following claims.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56985491" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="40"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Kommunikationsverfahren für eine dienende Mikrobasisstation, die einem fahrzeuginternen mobilen Endgerät (140) dient, wobei das Verfahren umfasst:
<claim-text>Identifizieren (610) eines dem fahrzeuginternen mobilen Endgerät in einer mehrzelligen Gruppe zugewiesenen eindeutigen Zugangscodes, wobei die mehrzellige Gruppe eine Makrobasisstation (110) und mehrere Mikrobasisstationen (130) umfasst, die sich innerhalb einer Zellabdeckung (100) der Makrobasisstation befinden, wobei die mehreren Mikrobasisstationen die dienende Mikrobasisstation und eine zur dienenden Mikrobasisstation benachbarte Mikrobasisstation umfassen, wobei der eindeutige Zugangscode dem fahrzeuginternen mobilen Endgerät auf Grundlage einer Mobilität des fahrzeuginternen mobilen Endgeräts zugewiesen wird;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Empfangen (620) von den eindeutigen Zugangscode einschließenden Uplink-Broadcast-Informationen aus dem fahrzeuginternen mobilen Endgerät;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Sammeln (630) von Informationen über einen Empfangsstatus der Uplink-Broadcast-Informationen, der benachbarten Mikrobasisstation, aus der benachbarten Mikrobasisstation in der mehrzelligen Gruppe;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Feststellen (640), ob ein Handover zwischen der dienenden Mikrobasisstation und der benachbarten Mikrobasisstation erforderlich ist, auf Grundlage der durch die dienende Mikrobasisstation empfangenen Uplink-Broadcast-Informationen und der gesammelten Informationen; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Durchführen (680) des Handovers, wenn festgestellt wird, dass das Handover erforderlich ist.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="41"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, das weiterhin das Feststellen (650) einer Vorbereitungsstufe eines Handovers in Zusammenhang mit einer Stufe eines Vorgangs umfasst, der für die dienende Mikrobasisstation und die benachbarte Mikrobasisstation verwendet wird, um das Handover durchzuführen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 2, wobei das Feststellen der Vorbereitungsstufe des Handovers das Feststellen einer Vorbereitungsstufe des Handovers auf Grundlage der durch die dienende Mikrobasisstation empfangenen Uplink-Broadcast-Informationen und der durch die benachbarte Mikrobasisstation empfangenen Uplink-Broadcast-Informationen umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 2, wobei das Feststellen der Vorbereitungsstufe des Handovers das Festellen einer Vorbereitungsstufe des Handovers auf Grundlage zumindest eines umfasst von einer Mobilität des fahrzeuginternen mobilen Endgeräts, einer geschätzten Zellverweildauer des fahrzeuginternen mobilen Endgeräts, einer Backhaul-Umgebung zwischen der dienenden Mikrobasisstation und der benachbarten Mikrobasisstation, einer Menge vom fahrzeuginternen mobilen Endgerät verwendeter Daten, einer Belastung der dienenden Mikrobasisstation und einer Belastung der benachbarten Mikrobasisstation;<br/>
wobei das Verfahren vorzugsweise weiterhin das Schätzen einer Zellverweildauer des fahrzeuginternen mobilen Endgeräts auf Grundlage der aus der dienenden Mikrobasisstation empfangenen Uplink-Broadcast-Informationen<!-- EPO <DP n="42"> --> umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 2, das weiterhin das Meldungmachen (660) über die festgestellte Vorbereitungsstufe des Handovers an die benachbarte Mikrobasisstation umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 2, wobei das Feststellen der Vorbereitungsstufe des Handovers das Feststellen umfasst, dass sich eine Vorbereitungsstufe des Handovers auf einer von mehreren Stufen befindet, die zumindest eines von einer Vorregistrierung, einem Uplink-Synchronisations-Setup, einer Akzeptanz eines Handovers und einer Durchführung des Handovers, einer gemeinsamen Störungskontrolle für das fahrzeuginterne mobile Endgerät, einer gemeinsamen Verarbeitung bei dem fahrzeuginternen mobilen Endgerät und einer Zellfusion einschließen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, wobei das fahrzeuginterne mobile Endgerät zumindest eines von einer Femtobasisstation, einem sich bewegenden Relais und einem mobilen Endgerät umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Kommunikationsverfahren für eine benachbarte Mikrobasisstation, wobei das Verfahren umfasst:
<claim-text>Identifizieren (710) eines einem fahrzeuginternen mobilen Endgerät (140) in einer mehrzelligen Gruppe zugewiesenen eindeutigen Zugangscodes, wobei die mehrzellige Gruppe eine Makrobasisstation (110) und mehrere Mikrobasisstationen (130) innerhalb einer Zellabdeckung (100) der Makrobasisstation umfasst, wobei die mehreren<!-- EPO <DP n="43"> --> Mikrobasisstationen eine dienende Mikrobasisstation, die dem fahrzeuginternen mobilen Endgerät dient, und die benachbarte Mikrobasisstation, die der dienenden Mikrobasisstation benachbart ist, umfassen, wobei der eindeutige Zugangscode dem fahrzeuginternen mobilen Endgerät auf Grundlage einer Mobilität des fahrzeuginternen mobilen Endgeräts zugewiesen wird, wobei das Identifizieren des eindeutigen Zugangscodes vorzugsweise das Empfangen von Informationen über einen für den eindeutigen Zugangscode zugewiesenen Kanal aus der Makrobasisstation umfasst;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Mithören (720) von den eindeutigen Zugangscode einschließenden Uplink-Broadcast-Informationen aus dem fahrzeuginternen mobilen Endgerät;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Melden (730) von Informationen über einen Empfangsstatus der Uplink-Broadcast-Informationen an die dienende Mikrobasisstation.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 8, wobei das Melden von Informationen über den Empfangsstatus der Uplink-Broadcast-Informationen das Melden der Informationen über den Empfangsstatus der Uplink-Broadcast-Informationen zwecks Feststellung einer Vorbereitungsstufe eines Handovers in Zusammenhang mit einer Stufe eines Vorgangs umfasst, der für die dienende Mikrobasisstation und eine benachbarte Mikrobasisstation verwendet wird, um das Handover durchzuführen;<br/>
wobei das Verfahren vorzugsweise weiterhin das Schätzen eines Uplink-Zeitversatzes oder das Schätzen einer Dienstgüte (QoS: Quality of Service) des fahrzeuginternen mobilen Endgeräts, auf Grundlage der Uplink-Broadcast-Informationen, umfasst.<!-- EPO <DP n="44"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 9, das weiterhin das Identifizieren der Vorbereitungsstufe des Handovers auf Grundlage einer Meldung der dienenden Mikrobasisstation umfasst;<br/>
wobei das Verfahren vorzugsweise weiterhin umfasst:
<claim-text>Durchführen (770) des Handovers des fahrzeuginternen mobilen Endgeräts auf Grundlage der Vorbereitungsstufe des Handovers; oder</claim-text>
<claim-text>Durchführen koordinierter Kommunikation mit der dienenden Mikrobasisstation auf Grundlage der Feststellung der dienenden Mikrobasisstation, wenn festgestellt wird, dass die Vorbereitungsstufe des Handovers eine Stufe ist, die zumindest eines von gemeinsamer Störungskontrolle für das fahrzeuginterne mobile Endgerät und gemeinsamer Verarbeitung bei dem fahrzeuginternen mobilen Endgerät einschließt.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Computerlesbares Speichermedium, das Programmanweisungen darin gespeichert aufweist, um einen Prozessor zu veranlassen, das Kommunikationsverfahren für eine dienende Mikrobasisstation nach Anspruch 1 oder das Kommunikationsverfahren für eine benachbarte Mikrobasisstation nach Anspruch 8 auszuführen.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56985492" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A communication method of a serving micro base station that is serving a vehicular mobile terminal (140), the method comprising:
<claim-text>identifying (610) a unique access code allocated to the vehicular mobile terminal in a multi-cell group, the multi-cell group comprising a macro base station (110) and a plurality of micro base stations (130) that are within a cell coverage (100) of the macro base station, said plurality of micro base stations comprising said serving micro base station and a micro base station neighboring said serving micro base station, wherein the unique access code is allocated to the vehicular mobile terminal based on a mobility of the vehicular mobile terminal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>receiving (620) uplink broadcast information including the unique access code from the vehicular mobile terminal;</claim-text>
<claim-text>collecting (630) information about a receiving state of the uplink broadcast information of the neighbor micro base station from the neighbor micro base station in the multi-cell group;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining (640) whether a handover is needed between the serving micro base station and said neighboring micro base station based on the uplink broadcast information received by the serving micro base station and said collected information; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>performing (680) said handover when it is determined that said handover is needed.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The method of claim 1, further comprising determining (650) a preparation level of a handover<!-- EPO <DP n="36"> --> associated with a level of an operation used for the serving micro base station and the neighbor micro base station to perform the handover.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The method of claim 2, wherein the determining of the preparation level of the handover comprises determining a preparation level of the handover based on the uplink broadcast information received by the serving micro base station and uplink broadcast information received by the neighbor micro base station.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The method of claim 2, wherein the determining of the preparation level of the handover comprises determining a preparation level of the handover based on at least one of a mobility of the vehicular mobile terminal, an estimated cell residence time of the vehicular mobile terminal, a backhaul environment between the serving micro base station and the neighbor micro base station, an amount of data used by the vehicular mobile terminal, a load of the serving micro base station, and a load of the neighbor micro base station;<br/>
the method preferably further comprising estimating a cell residence time of the vehicular mobile terminal based on the uplink broadcast information received from the serving micro base station.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The method of claim 2, further comprising reporting (660) about the determined preparation level of the handover to the neighbor micro base station.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The method of claim 2, wherein the determining of the preparation level of the handover comprises determining a preparation level of the handover to be at one<!-- EPO <DP n="37"> --> of a plurality of levels including at least one of a preregistration, an uplink synchronization setup, an acceptance of a handover and performance of the handover, a joint interference control for the vehicular mobile terminal, a joint processing on the vehicular mobile terminal, and a cell merger.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The method of claim 1, wherein the vehicular mobile terminal comprises at least one of a femto base station, a moving relay, and a mobile terminal.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>A communication method of a neighbor micro base station, the method comprising:
<claim-text>identifying (710) a unique access code allocated to a vehicular mobile terminal (140) in a multi-cell group, the multi-cell group comprising a macro base station (110) and a plurality of micro base stations (130) within a cell coverage (100) of the macro base station, said plurality of micro base stations comprising a serving micro base station that is serving the vehicular mobile terminal and said neighbor micro base station neighboring said serving micro base station, wherein the unique access code is allocated to the vehicular mobile terminal based on a mobility of the vehicular mobile terminal, wherein the identifying of the unique access code preferably comprises receiving information about a channel allocated for the unique access code from the macro base station;</claim-text>
<claim-text>overhearing (720) uplink broadcast information including the unique access code from the vehicular mobile terminal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>reporting (730) information about a receiving state of the uplink broadcast information to said serving micro base station.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="38"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The method of claim 8, wherein the reporting information about the receiving state of the uplink broadcast information comprises reporting the information about the receiving state of the uplink broadcast information in order to determine a preparation level of a handover associated with a level of an operation used for the serving micro base station and a neighbor micro base station to perform the handover;<br/>
the method preferably further comprising estimating an uplink timing offset or estimating a quality of service (QoS) of the vehicular mobile terminal, based on the uplink broadcast information.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The method of claim 9, further comprising identifying the preparation level of the handover based on a report of the serving micro base station;<br/>
wherein the method preferably further comprises:
<claim-text>performing (770) the handover of the vehicular mobile terminal based on the preparation level of the handover; or</claim-text>
<claim-text>performing coordinated communication with the serving micro base station based on the determination of the serving micro base station, when the preparation level of the handover is determined to be a level including at least one of joint interference control for the vehicular mobile terminal and joint processing on the vehicular mobile terminal.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>A computer-readable storage medium having stored therein program instructions to cause a processor to<!-- EPO <DP n="39"> --> implement the communication method of a serving micro base station as defined in claim 1 or the communication method of a neighbor micro base station as defined in claim 8.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56985493" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="45"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Procédé de communication concernant une micro-station de base de desserte qui dessert un terminal mobile véhiculaire (140), le procédé comprenant :
<claim-text>l'identification (610) d'un code d'accès unique attribué au terminal mobile véhiculaire dans un groupe pluricellulaire, le groupe pluricellulaire comprenant une macro-station de base (110) et une pluralité de micro-stations de base (130) qui se trouvent à l'intérieur d'une zone de couverture cellulaire (100) de la macro-station de base, ladite pluralité de micro-stations de base comprenant ladite micro-station de base de desserte et une micro-station de base voisine de ladite micro-station de base de desserte, dans lequel le code d'accès unique est attribué au terminal mobile véhiculaire en fonction d'une mobilité du terminal mobile véhiculaire ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>la réception (620) d'une information diffusée en liaison montante comprenant le code d'accès unique en provenance du terminal mobile véhiculaire ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>le recueil (630) d'informations concernant un état de réception de l'information diffusée en liaison montante de la micro-station de base voisine en provenance de la micro-station de base voisine dans le groupe pluricellulaire ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>la détermination (640) de la nécessité ou non d'un transfert entre la micro-station de base de desserte et ladite micro-station de base voisine en fonction de l'information diffusée en liaison montante reçue par la micro-station de base de desserte et desdites informations recueillies ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>la réalisation (680) dudit transfert lorsque la nécessité dudit transfert a été déterminée.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, comprenant en outre la détermination (650) d'un niveau de préparation d'un transfert associé à un niveau d'un fonctionnement utilisé pour que la micro-station de base de desserte et la micro-station de base voisine réalisent le transfert.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 2, dans lequel la détermination du niveau de préparation du transfert comprend la détermination d'un niveau de préparation du transfert en se fondant sur l'information diffusée en liaison montante reçue par la micro-station de base de desserte et sur l'information diffusée en liaison montante reçue par la micro-station de base voisine.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 2, dans lequel la détermination du niveau de préparation du transfert comprend la détermination d'un niveau de préparation du transfert en se fondant sur au moins un élément parmi une mobilité du terminal mobile véhiculaire, une estimation du temps de séjour cellulaire du terminal mobile véhiculaire, un environnement de liaison entre la micro-station de base de desserte et la micro-station de base voisine, une quantité de données utilisées par le<!-- EPO <DP n="46"> --> terminal mobile véhiculaire, une charge de la micro-station de base de desserte et une charge de la micro-station de base voisine ;<br/>
le procédé comprenant de préférence en outre l'estimation d'un temps de séjour cellulaire du terminal mobile véhiculaire en se fondant sur l'information diffusée en liaison montante reçue en provenance de la micro-station de base de desserte.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 2, comprenant en outre le signalement (660) de la détermination du niveau de préparation du transfert auprès de la micro-station de base voisine.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 2, dans lequel la détermination du niveau de préparation du transfert comprend la détermination d'un niveau de préparation du transfert qui soit à un niveau parmi une pluralité de niveaux, comprenant au moins un élément parmi une préinscription, un réglage de synchronisation en liaison montante, une acceptation d'un transfert et de la réalisation du transfert, une régulation conjointe des interférences pour le terminal mobile véhiculaire, un traitement conjoint sur le terminal mobile véhiculaire, et une fusion de cellules.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, dans lequel le terminal mobile véhiculaire comprend au moins un élément parmi une station de base femto, un relais mobile et un terminal mobile.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Procédé de communication d'une micro-station de base voisine, le procédé comprenant :
<claim-text>l'identification (710) d'un code d'accès unique attribué à un terminal mobile véhiculaire (140) dans un groupe pluricellulaire, le groupe pluricellulaire comprenant une macro-station de base (110) et une pluralité de micro-stations de base (130) à l'intérieur d'une zone de couverture cellulaire (100) de la macro-station de base, ladite pluralité de micro-stations de base comprenant une micro-station de base de desserte qui dessert le terminal mobile véhiculaire et ladite micro-station de base voisine proche de ladite micro-station de base de desserte, dans lequel le code d'accès unique est attribué au terminal mobile véhiculaire en fonction d'une mobilité du terminal mobile véhiculaire, dans lequel l'identification du code d'accès unique comprend de préférence la réception d'une information concernant un canal alloué pour le code d'accès unique à partir de la macro-station de base ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>la captation (720) d'une information diffusée en liaison montante comprenant le code d'accès unique en provenance du terminal mobile véhiculaire ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>le signalement (730) d'une information concernant un état de réception de l'information diffusée en liaison montante auprès d'une micro-station de base de desserte.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="47"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 8, dans lequel le signalement de l'information concernant l'état de réception de l'information diffusée en liaison montante comprend le signalement de l'information concernant l'état de réception de l'information diffusée en liaison montante de manière à déterminer un niveau de préparation d'un transfert associé à un niveau d'un fonctionnement utilisé pour que la micro-station de base de desserte et une micro-station de base voisine réalisent le transfert ;<br/>
le procédé comprenant de préférence en outre l'estimation d'un décalage temporel en liaison montante ou l'estimation d'une qualité de service (QoS) du terminal mobile véhiculaire, en se fondant sur l'information diffusée en liaison montante.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 9, comprenant en outre l'identification du niveau de préparation du transfert en se fondant sur un signalement de la micro-station de base de desserte ;<br/>
dans lequel le procédé comprend de préférence en outre :
<claim-text>la réalisation (770) du transfert du terminal mobile véhiculaire en fonction du niveau de préparation du transfert ; ou</claim-text>
<claim-text>la réalisation d'une communication coordonnée avec la micro-station de base de desserte en fonction de la détermination de la micro-station de base de desserte, lorsque le niveau de préparation du transfert a été déterminé pour être un niveau comprenant au moins un élément parmi une régulation conjointe des interférences pour le terminal mobile véhiculaire et un traitement conjoint sur le terminal mobile véhiculaire.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Support de stockage lisible par voie informatique comportant des instructions de programme qui y sont stockées, destinées à amener un processeur à mettre en oeuvre le procédé de communication d'une micro-station de base de desserte tel que défini dans la revendication 1 ou le procédé de communication d'une micro-station de base voisine tel que défini dans la revendication 8.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16672177" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="48"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="161" he="180" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="49"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="165" he="229" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="50"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3A"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="163" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="51"> --><figure id="f0004" num="3B"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="163" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="52"> --><figure id="f0005" num="4"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="165" he="228" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="53"> --><figure id="f0006" num="5"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="165" he="96" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="54"> --><figure id="f0007" num="6"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="164" he="228" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="55"> --><figure id="f0008" num="7"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="164" he="228" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="56"> --><figure id="f0009" num="8"><img id="if0009" file="imgf0009.tif" wi="146" he="92" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="57"> --><figure id="f0010" num="9"><img id="if0010" file="imgf0010.tif" wi="146" he="115" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
