<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2172176-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2172176" kind="B1" date="20140101" family-id="41445461" file-reference-id="318271" date-produced="20180822" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146553988" ucid="EP-2172176-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2172176</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-09008786-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154827911" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>09008786</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20090704</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP168004633" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>09008786.7</doc-number><date>20090704</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140450998" ucid="JP-2008258291-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>JP</country><doc-number>2008258291</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20081003</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130905</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988099471" load-source="docdb">E05C   3/16        20060101ALI20110615BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988102095" load-source="docdb">A61G  11/00        20060101AFI20100107BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2073288387" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 292/1061      20150401 LA20150410BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2073292238" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 292/0934      20150401 LA20150410BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2073297466" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 292/1052      20150401 LA20150410BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2073297513" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 292/0928      20150401 LA20150410BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2073298161" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 292/1051      20150401 LA20150410BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2073300811" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 292/0926      20150401 LA20150410BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2073946303" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61G  11/005       20130101 LA20140508BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2073946350" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61G  11/003       20130101 LA20140508BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2090153527" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61G  11/00        20130101 FI20140616BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2090158220" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">E05C   3/162       20130101 LI20140616BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2090158409" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61G  11/009       20130101 LI20140616BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132194448" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Inkubator mit Handeingriffstür</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132194449" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Incubator with hand insertion door</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132194450" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Couveuse avec porte d'accès manuelle</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918165828" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>ATOM MEDICAL CORP</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918142046" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>ATOM MEDICAL CORPORATION</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918164993" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>MATSUBARA TERUMI</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918173263" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>MATSUBARA, TERUMI</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918998600" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>MATSUBARA, TERUMI</last-name><address><street>c/o Atom Medical Corporation Research and Development Department 2-1, Dojo 2-chome, Sakura-ku</street><city>Saitama-shi, Saitama 338-0835</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918140587" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>KOIKE EIJI</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918144442" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>KOIKE, EIJI</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918998598" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>KOIKE, EIJI</last-name><address><street>c/o Atom Medical Corporation Research and Development Department 2-1, Dojo 2-chome, Sakura-ku</street><city>Saitama-shi, Saitama 338-0835</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918142753" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>HONMA NAOKI</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918143168" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>HONMA, NAOKI</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918998597" load-source="patent-office" sequence="3" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>HONMA, NAOKI</last-name><address><street>c/o Atom Medical Corporation Research and Development Department 2-1, Dojo 2-chome, Sakura-ku</street><city>Saitama-shi, Saitama 338-0835</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918141040" load-source="docdb" sequence="4" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>NAGAI YOKO</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918138843" load-source="docdb" sequence="4" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>NAGAI, YOKO</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918998599" load-source="patent-office" sequence="4" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>NAGAI, YOKO</last-name><address><street>c/o Atom Medical Corporation Research and Development Department 2-1, Dojo 2-chome, Sakura-ku</street><city>Saitama-shi, Saitama 338-0835</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918166471" load-source="docdb" sequence="5" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>MATSUBARA KAZUO</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918162068" load-source="docdb" sequence="5" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>MATSUBARA, KAZUO</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918998596" load-source="patent-office" sequence="5" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>MATSUBARA, KAZUO</last-name><address><street>c/o Atom Medical Corporation 18-15, Hongo 3-chome</street><city>Bunkyo-Ku, Tokyo 113-0033</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918998602" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Atom Medical Corporation</last-name><iid>101107569</iid><address><street>18-15 Hongo 3-chome</street><city>Bunkyo-ku Tokyo</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918998601" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Dreiss</last-name><iid>100060566</iid><address><street>Patentanwälte Postfach 10 37 62</street><city>70032 Stuttgart</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548989723" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS548886386" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS548871242" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS548982207" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS548831139" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS548989724" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS548991615" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548886387" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS548831140" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS548982864" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS548871243" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS548871244" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548991616" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548886388" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS548991617" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS548831141" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS548982208" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS548886389" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS548871245" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS548886390" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS548991618" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS548989725" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS548991619" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS548991620" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS548989726" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS548989727" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS548871246" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS548982209" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS548871247" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS548982865" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS548871248" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS548871249" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS548985324" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS548982210" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS548982211" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS548886391" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63957557" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001">{Technical Field}</heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to an incubator that includes: a hand insertion window formed in a side of a newborn chamber; a hand insertion door that opens and closes the hand insertion window by rotation; and a latch mechanism that holds the hand insertion door in a closing position.</p><heading id="h0002">{Background Art}</heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">An incubator has a newborn chamber to provide appropriate physiological environment for a newborn that cannot adjust its body temperature and others by itself. Substantially entire areas of the sides and top of a newborn chamber are formed from transparent members so that a newborn in the newborn chamber can be seen from the outside. Within the newborn chamber, not only temperature but also humidity,<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> oxygen concentration and others are controlled. A treating person, however, such as a doctor or a nurse gives treatment to a newborn in a newborn chamber, when necessary. Therefore, for relatively simple treatments, hand insertion windows are formed in certain sides of the newborn chamber. Additionally, the incubator has a hand insertion door that opens and closes the hand insertion window by rotation, and a latch mechanism that holds the hand insertion door in a closing position.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">In order that appropriate physiological environment in the newborn chamber is maintained for a newborn, it is usual that hand insertion windows are closed by hand insertion doors and that the hand insertion doors are held in their closing positions by their corresponding latch mechanisms. In order to treat a newborn, however, each hand insertion window has to be opened by rotating its hand insertion door to its opening position from its closing position. On the other hand, a treating person may have in its both hands a medical device, medical drug, or others for treating a newborn. Additionally, there may be a case where contamination of sterilized both hands has to be prevented. To meet such needs, conventional incubators (e.g., Patent Literatures 1 and 2) have a releasing member for releasing a latch mechanism such that the hand insertion window can easily be opened by only pressing the releasing member in a direction perpendicular to the corresponding side face of a newborn chamber with, for example, an elbow instead of a hand.</p><heading id="h0003">{Citation List}</heading><heading id="h0004">{Patent Literature}</heading><p id="p0004" num="0004"><ol><li>1. <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="JP2001070373A"><text>JP 2001-70373 A</text></patcit></li><li>2. <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="JP2198554A"><text>JP 2-198554 A</text></patcit></li></ol><!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p><heading id="h0005">{Summary of Invention}</heading><heading id="h0006">{Technical Problem}</heading><p id="p0005" num="0005">In the conventional incubators mentioned above, however, a hand insertion window can be opened by only pressing each releasing member in a direction perpendicular to the corresponding side of a newborn chamber. Therefore, if a treating person or others leans on the releasing member or the releasing member comes into contact with a wall during conveyance of the incubator, the hand insertion window may be opened unintentionally. Furthermore, in the conventional incubators mentioned above, there can happen a state where, although a hand insertion door is almost in contact with a latch mechanism, this hand insertion door is not securely held in its closing position and, therefore, the corresponding hand insertion window is incompletely closed. If the hand insertion window is unintentionally opened or incompletely closed when a newborn is in the newborn chamber, the inside of the newborn chamber will deviate from appropriate physiological environment for the newborn, and there is the possibility that the physical condition of the newborn gets out of order.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">Furthermore, in the conventional incubators mentioned above, the hand insertion door can rotate freely while it is not held in its closing position by the latch mechanism. Additionally, also the latch mechanism is suddenly activated by urging force when it holds the hand insertion door in its closing position. For these reasons, the hand insertion door or latch mechanism may bump against another part of the incubator. Noise and vibration by impact resulting from this bump may put stress on a newborn in the newborn chamber, and there is the additional possibility that the physical condition of the newborn gets out of order. It is accordingly an object of the present invention<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> to provide an incubator designed such that the physical condition of a newborn is less likely to get out of order though a hand insertion window can easily be opened by operation with, for example, an elbow instead of a hand.</p><heading id="h0007">{Solution to Problem}</heading><p id="p0007" num="0007">In an incubator according to the present invention, a latch in a latch mechanism has a spiral face that extends to at least part of the periphery of a rotation shaft that extends along a side of a newborn chamber. A releasing member in the latch mechanism presses the spiral face of the latch by movement along the side of the newborn chamber, and rotates the latch about the rotation shaft from a holding position to a releasing position for a hand insertion door. Accordingly, a hand insertion window can be opened by only pressing and moving the releasing member in the latch mechanism along the side of the newborn chamber.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">Additionally, in order to open the hand insertion window, the releasing member in the latch mechanism has to be pressed along the side of the newborn chamber.<br/>
Accordingly, even if a treating person or others leans on the releasing member or the releasing member comes into contact with a wall during conveyance of the incubator, the hand insertion window will not be opened. In addition, even if the latch in the latch mechanism rotates between the holding and releasing positions for the hand insertion door, the releasing member does not rotate, and therefore impact due to activation of the latch mechanism is less likely to occur.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">In another incubator according to the present invention, in the course of rotation of the hand insertion door in the direction in which the hand insertion window is closed, an opening mechanism comes into contact with the hand<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> insertion door before the hand insertion window is closed. Thereby, the opening mechanism urges the hand insertion door so as to rotate in the direction in which the hand insertion window is opened. Therefore, if the hand insertion window is not completely closed, the hand insertion window is opened, and it is easily aware that the hand insertion window is not closed. Accordingly, the hand insertion window is more likely to be again closed.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">In another incubator according to the present invention, a pressed portion, which is pressed by rotation of the hand insertion door, of the latch in the latch mechanism is made of impact-absorbent material. Accordingly, even if the hand insertion door bumps against the latch when the hand insertion door is rotated to close the hand insertion window, impact is less likely to occur.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">In another incubator according to the present invention, from some point in the course of rotation of the hand insertion door in the direction in which the hand insertion window is opened, a braking mechanism brakes the rotation of the hand insertion door. Accordingly, the hand insertion door does not stop suddenly when the hand insertion window has completely been opened, and impact is less likely to occur when the hand insertion window has completely been opened.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">In another incubator according to the present invention, an urging member in the latch mechanism urges the latch so as to rotate the latch from the releasing position to the holding position. Accordingly, if the latch is only rotated to the releasing position, the latch rotates automatically from the releasing position to the holding position without being manually rotated from the releasing position to the holding position and holds the hand insertion door.<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></p><p id="p0013" num="0013">Nevertheless, a braking member in the latch mechanism brakes rotation of the latch. Accordingly, even if the latch rotates automatically from the releasing position to the holding position, impact is less likely to occur at the holding position.</p><heading id="h0008">{Advantageous Effects of Invention}</heading><p id="p0014" num="0014">In the incubator according to the present invention, the hand insertion window can be opened by only pressing and moving the releasing member in the latch mechanism along the side of the newborn chamber. Accordingly, the hand insertion window can easily be opened by operation with, for example, an elbow instead of a hand. Additionally, even if a treating person or others leans on the releasing member or the releasing member comes into contact with a wall during conveyance of the incubator, the hand insertion window will not be opened. Therefore, the inside of the newborn chamber is less likely to deviate from appropriate physiological environment for a newborn. Furthermore, impact due to the activation of the latch mechanism is less likely to occur. Therefore, less stress is put on a newborn in the newborn chamber when the latch mechanism is activated. Accordingly, the physical condition of the newborn is less likely to get out of order.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">In the other incubator according to the present invention, if the hand insertion window is not completely closed, the hand insertion window is opened, and it is easily aware that the hand insertion window is not closed. Therefore, the hand insertion window is more likely to be again closed. Accordingly, the inside of the newborn chamber is less likely to deviate from appropriate physiological environment for a newborn, and physical condition of the newborn is less likely to get out of order.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p><p id="p0016" num="0016">In the other incubator according to the present invention, even if the hand insertion door bumps against the latch when the hand insertion door is rotated to close the hand insertion window, impact is less likely to occur. Accordingly, less stress is put on the newborn in the newborn chamber when the hand insertion window is close, and physical condition of the newborn is less likely to get out of order.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">In the other incubator according to the present invention, the hand insertion door does not stop suddenly when the hand insertion window has completely been opened, and impact is less likely to occur when the hand insertion window has completely been opened. Accordingly, less stress is put on the newborn in the newborn chamber when the hand insertion window is opened, and physical condition of the newborn is less likely to get out of order.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">In the other incubator according to the present invention, if the latch in the latch mechanism is only rotated to the releasing position, the latch rotates automatically from the releasing position to the holding position without being manually rotated from the releasing position to the holding position and holds the hand insertion door. Accordingly, it is easy to close the hand insertion window with the hand insertion door. Nevertheless, even if the latch rotates automatically from the releasing position to the holding position, impact is less likely to occur at the holding position. Accordingly, less stress is put on the newborn in the newborn chamber when the hand insertion window is opened, and physical condition of the newborn is less likely to get out of order.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></p><heading id="h0009">{Brief Description of Drawings}</heading><p id="p0019" num="0019"><ul><li>{<figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>} Sectional view of a latch mechanism of an incubator according to one embodiment of the present invention.</li><li>{<figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2</figref>} Perspective view of a latch in the latch mechanism of the incubator according to the embodiment of the present invention.</li><li>{<figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 3</figref>} Partial perspective view of a packing provided for a hand insertion window of the incubator according to the embodiment of the present invention.</li><li>{<figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 4</figref>} Partial perspective view of a hand insertion door of the incubator according to the embodiment of the present invention.</li><li>{<figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5</figref>} Partial sectional view of the hand insertion window of the incubator according to the embodiment of the present invention, in which the hand insertion door is in an opening position.</li><li>{<figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 6</figref>} Perspective view of a braking mechanism of the incubator according to the embodiment of the present invention.</li><li>{<figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 7</figref>} Sectional view of a latch mechanism of the incubator according to the embodiment of the present invention, in which the hand insertion door is in contact with the latch.</li><li>{<figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 8</figref>} Sectional view of the latch mechanism of the incubator according to the embodiment of the present invention, in which the latch has rotated to its releasing position.</li><li>{<figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 9</figref>} Sectional view of the latch mechanism of the incubator according to the embodiment of the present invention, in which the hand insertion door has been held by the latch.</li><li>{<figref idrefs="f0009">Fig. 10</figref>} One of a pair of left and right hand insertion doors and one of a pair of left and right latch mechanisms of the incubator according to the<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> embodiment of the present invention, in which (a) is a front view and (b) is a sectional view taken along a line B-B in (a).</li><li>{<figref idrefs="f0010">Fig. 11</figref>} Side view of an incubator according to the embodiment of the present invention where the incubator is in a closed type.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0010">{Description of Embodiments}</heading><p id="p0020" num="0020">Hereinafter, referring to <figref idrefs="f0001 f0002 f0003 f0004 f0005 f0006 f0007 f0008 f0009 f0010">Figs. 1 to 11</figref>, there will be described one embodiment of the present invention applied to a switching type incubator capable of switching between a closed type and open type as required by lowering or raising a canopy of a newborn chamber. Hereinafter, the present embodiment will be described according to the following list.
<ol><li>(1) An Outline of the Overall Incubator</li><li>(2) Opening and Closing of the Hand Insertion Window</li><li>(3) Awareness of any Unclosed State of the Hand Insertion Window</li><li>(4) Making Operation of Opening and Closing the Hand Insertion Window Quiet</li></ol></p><heading id="h0011">(1) An Outline of the Overall Incubator</heading><p id="p0021" num="0021"><figref idrefs="f0010">Fig. 11</figref> shows an incubator of the present embodiment in a closed type. In the incubator 11, wheels 13 and a support 14 are attached to a frame 12. A base 15 is supported on the support 14. Within the base 15 is a control mechanism (not shown) for temperature, humidity and others. Disposed on the base 15 is a newborn chamber 16. A drawer 17 for use as storage is attached to the underside of the base 15. Pedals 18 are also attached to the frame 12 in order to adjust the height of the base 15 or others along the support 14.<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></p><p id="p0022" num="0022">A bed (not shown) is disposed in the newborn chamber 16. Formed in the sides of the newborn chamber 16 are: a pair of left and right treatment doors 21 which is located on the left and right sides of a newborn (not shown) lying on the bed; a foot end treatment door 22 which is located at the foot end; and a head end treatment wall 23 which is located at the head end. A pair of left and right posts 24 is also attached to the frame 12. Another post (not shown) is nested in the post 24. The other post is slidable within the post 24.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">A canopy 25 of the newborn chamber 16 and an infrared heater 26 are supported respectively by one and the other of the other left and right posts nested in posts 24. By sliding these other posts within the corresponding posts 24, the canopy 25 and infrared heater 26 can be raised or lowered independently. The canopy 25 is also made of transparent material. Attached also to the posts 24 is a protector 27 that prevents the infrared heater 26 from bumping against the wall (not shown) of a room.</p><heading id="h0012">(2) Opening and Closing of the Hand Insertion Window</heading><p id="p0024" num="0024">The left and right treatment doors 21 each have an outer wall 31 and an inner wall 32 (see <figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 9</figref>) that are transparent and form a double-wall structure. Each outer wall 31 and the corresponding inner wall 32 have: a pair of left and right hand insertion windows 33 (see <figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 9</figref>); a pair of left and right hand insertion doors 34 for closing and opening the corresponding hand insertion windows 33; and latch mechanisms 35 for holding the corresponding hand insertion doors 34 in their closing positions for closing the corresponding hand insertion windows 33. <figref idrefs="f0009">Fig. 10</figref> shows one of the pair of hand insertion doors 34 and the corresponding latch mechanism 35.<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --></p><p id="p0025" num="0025">A hand-insertion-door base plate 36 of annular shape and made of transparent rigid synthetic resin is fitted and screwed to the internal edge of the outer wall 31 of the hand insertion window 33 of the newborn chamber 16. The hand insertion door 34 is also made of a transparent rigid synthetic resin and has a dish-like shape. The hand insertion door 34 is supported diametrically opposite the latch mechanism 35 on the edge of the hand-insertion-door base plate 36. The hand insertion door 34 is rotatable about a rotation shaft 37 between a closing position in which the hand insertion door 34 closes the hand insertion window 33 as shown in <figref idrefs="f0008">Figs. 9</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0009">10</figref> and an opening position in which it opens the hand insertion window 33 as shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5</figref>. The hand insertion door 34 is urged from the above-mentioned closing position toward the above-mentioned opening position by a helical coil spring 38 in which the rotation shaft 37 is inserted.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026"><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> shows the latch mechanism 35 in <figref idrefs="f0009">Figs. 10</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0010">11</figref>.<br/>
The latch mechanism 35 includes a latch 41, a latch base plate 42, and a releasing member 43. The latch base plate 42 is fixed to the hand-insertion-door base plate 36. The latch 41 and the releasing member 43 are supported by the latch base plate 42. The latch 41 is rotatable about a rotation shaft 44 between a holding position in which the latch 41 holds the hand insertion door 34 in the closing position as shown in <figref idrefs="f0008">Figs. 9</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0009">10</figref> and a releasing position in which it releases the holding as shown in <figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 8</figref>.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">A helical coil spring 45, in which the rotation shaft 44 is inserted, is interposed between the latch 41 and the latch base plate 42. The latch 41 is urged by the helical coil spring 45 from the releasing position to the holding position. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2</figref>, the latch 41 has a spiral<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> face 46 that extends to part of the periphery of the rotation shaft 44.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, interposed between the releasing member 43 and the latch base plate 42 are a column 47 and a helical compression spring 51. The releasing member 43 is urged by the helical compression spring 51 in a direction extending from the base 15 toward the canopy 25, that is, upward along the outer wall 31 of the newborn chamber 16. In addition, a projection 52 is formed integrally with the releasing member 43 so as to be parallel with the column 47 and the helical compression spring 51. This projection 52 extends to an area above the spiral face 46 through an opening 53 made in the latch base plate 42.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">In order to shift the hand insertion door 34 from the state in which the hand insertion door 34 opens the hand insertion window 33 as shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5</figref> to the state in which it closes the hand insertion window 33 as shown in <figref idrefs="f0008">Figs. 9</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0009">10</figref>, the hand insertion door 34 is rotated against the urge applied from the helical coil spring 38. Thereby, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 7</figref>, a tongue portion 54, which is the rotating leading-end of the hand insertion door 34, presses a pressed portion 55 of the latch 41 which is in the holding position. With pressing by the tongue portion 54, the latch 41 rotates about the rotation shaft 44 to the releasing position, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 8</figref>, against the urge applied from the helical coil spring 45.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">With further rotation of the hand insertion door 34 from the releasing position shown in <figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 8</figref>, the tongue portion 54 of the hand insertion door 34 moves past the pressed portion 55 of the latch 41 towards the rotation shaft 44, and the latch 41 is rotated up to the holding position by the urge applied from the helical coil spring 45, as shown<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> in <figref idrefs="f0008">Figs. 9</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0009">10</figref>. As a result, the hand insertion door 34 is held by the latch 41 and the hand insertion door 34 closes the hand insertion window 33.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">On the other hand, in order to shift the hand insertion door 34 from the state in which the hand insertion door 34 closes the hand insertion window 33 as shown in <figref idrefs="f0008">Figs. 9</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0009">10</figref> to the state in which it opens the hand insertion window 33 as shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5</figref>, the releasing member 43 is pressed down in a direction extending from the canopy 25 toward the base 15, that is, downward along the outer wall 31 of the newborn chamber 16, against the urge of the releasing member 43. The urge of the releasing member 43 is applied from the helical compression spring 51 in a direction extending from the base 15 toward the canopy 25, that is, upward along the outer wall 31 of the newborn chamber 16. When the releasing member 43 is pushed down, the projection 52 of the releasing member 43 moves downward through the opening 53 and presses the spiral face 46 of the latch 41.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">As a result of pressing the releasing member 43, the latch 41 rotates about the rotation shaft 44 from the holding position to the releasing position against the urge applied from the helical coil spring 45. Consequently, the tongue portion 54 of the hand insertion door 34 is released from being held by the latch 41, and the hand insertion door 34 is rotated by the urge applied from the helical coil spring 38. Accordingly, the hand insertion door 34 opens the hand insertion window 33. When the releasing member 43 is released from being pressed down, the projection 52 of the releasing member 43 is moved upward through the opening 53 by the urge applied from the helical compression spring 51, and the projection 52 separates from the spiral face 46 of the latch 41 due to this upward movement. Accordingly, the latch 41 returns from the releasing position to the holding<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> position by the urge applied from the helical coil spring 45.</p><heading id="h0013">(3) Awareness of any Unclosed State of the Hand Insertion Window</heading><p id="p0033" num="0033">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0009">Fig. 10 (b)</figref>, a packing 56 of annular shape and made of silicone rubber is fitted along the internal edge of the hand-insertion-door base plate 36. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 3</figref>, most of the portion of the packing 56 that is in contact with the hand insertion door 34 closing the hand insertion window 33 is a fin-shaped portion 57 but the portion of the packing 56 near the rotation shaft 37 of the hand insertion door 34 is a thicker portion 61. Disposed on the thicker portion 61 is a projection 62 that prevents the packing 56 from being erroneously attached. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 4</figref>, a recess 63 into which the projection 62 fits is formed in the hand insertion door 34 near the rotation shaft 37.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">When the hand insertion door 34 is rotated from the state in which the hand insertion door 34 opens the hand insertion window 33 to the state in which the hand insertion door 34 closes the hand insertion window 33, the hand insertion door 34 comes into contact with the packing 56 before the hand insertion door 34 closes the hand insertion window 33. When the hand insertion door 34 is further rotated, the hand insertion door 34 presses and elastically deforms the packing 56 before the latch 41 holds the hand insertion door 34. This elastic deformation ensures airtight condition by the packing 56.<br/>
Additionally, elastic resilience is produced especially in the thicker portion 61 and projection 62 of the packing 56. This elastic resilience urges the hand insertion door 34 in the direction in which the hand insertion window 33 is opened.<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --></p><p id="p0035" num="0035">Accordingly, if the hand insertion window 33 is not completely closed by the hand insertion door 34 due to such a situation that a treating person recognizes erroneously that the hand insertion window 33 is closed although the hand insertion window 33 is not actually completely closed, or due to any other reason, the hand insertion door 34 is rotated in the direction in which the hand insertion window 33 is opened. For this reason, it is easily aware that the hand insertion window 33 is not closed, and the hand insertion window 33 is more likely to be again closed. Incidentally, the hand insertion door 34 is urged from the closing position to the opening position by the helical coil spring 38. If, however, this urging force is too strong, the hand insertion door 34 may rotate suddenly.<br/>
The urging force applied from the helical coil spring 38, therefore, should not be very strong.</p><heading id="h0014">(4) Making Operation of Opening and Closing the Hand Insertion Window Quiet</heading><p id="p0036" num="0036">The pressed portion 55 of the latch 41 is made of silicone rubber. Additionally, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, a spacer 64 is interposed between the latch 41 and the latch base plate 42 and about the rotation shaft 44. Rotation of the latch 41 by the urge applied from the helical coil spring 45 is braked by the spacer 64. On the other hand, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">Figs. 5</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0005">6</figref>, a braking mechanism 65 made of synthetic resin is mounted on the hand-insertion-door base plate 36. A lower-side edge 67 of an inclining face 66 is formed integrally with the other portion of the braking mechanism 65 whereas an upper-side edge 68 of the inclining face 66 is a free edge.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5</figref>, a portion near the braking mechanism 65 around the rotation shaft 37 of the hand insertion door 34 is not completely circular in its cross-section but has a<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> cross-section with radius such that when the hand insertion door 34 closes the hand insertion window 33, the portion near the braking mechanism 65 is separated from the inclining face 66 of the braking mechanism 65, and when the hand insertion door 34 opens the hand insertion window 33, the portion approaches the inclining face 66, comes into contact with the inclining face 66 in the course of the opening of the hand insertion window 33, and consequently presses the inclining face 66. When the inclining face 66 is thus pressed, the braking mechanism 65 is elastically deformed so that the upper-side edge 68 is moved farther from the lower-side edge 67 and that the height of the inclining face 66 is decreased, and the pressing force is absorbed.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">When the hand insertion door 34 is rotated from the state in which the hand insertion window 33 is opened as shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5</figref> to the state in which the opening 33 is closed, the tongue portion 54 of the hand insertion door 34 first comes into contact with the pressed portion 55 of the latch 41 as shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 7</figref>. However, since the pressed portion 55 is made of silicone rubber, impact is less likely to occur even if the tongue portion 54 comes into contact with the pressed portion 55 with great force. When the hand insertion door 34 is further rotated from the state shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 7</figref>, the pressed portion 55 is pressed and thereby the latch 41 rotates up to the releasing position as shown in <figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 8</figref>. When the hand insertion door 34 is further rotated, the tongue portion 54 enters the latch 41 as shown in <figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 9</figref>.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">When the tongue portion 54 enters the latch 41 and thereby the pressed portion 55 gets not to be pressed by the tongue portion 54, the latch 41 rotates from the releasing position to the holding position by the urge applied from<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> the helical coil spring 45 and holds the tongue portion 54. However, since rotation of the latch 41 due to the urge applied from the helical coil spring 45 is braked by the spacer 64, the latch 41 is prevented from rotating with great force and, hence, impact is less likely to occur when the rotation comes to an end.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">On the other hand, when the releasing member 43 is operated and thereby the tongue portion 54 of the hand insertion door 34 is released from being held by the latch 41, the urging force due to elastic resilience of the packing 56, especially of its thicker portion 61 and projection 62, and the urging force applied from the helical coil spring 38 act in the following manner: the hand insertion door 34 rotates from the state in which the hand insertion window 33 is closed as shown in <figref idrefs="f0008">Figs. 9</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0009">10</figref>, through the state as shown in <figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 8</figref>, to the state in which the hand insertion window 33 is opened as shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5</figref>. However, the braking mechanism 65 brakes the rotation of the hand insertion door 34 in the course of opening the hand insertion window 33, and impact is less likely to occur when the rotation comes to an end.</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">In the foregoing embodiment, the pressed portion 55 of the latch 41 is made of silicone rubber. However, the pressed portion 55 may be made of any impact-absorbent material in lieu of silicone rubber. Likewise, the packing 56 is also made of silicone rubber. However, the packing 56 may be made of any elastically resilient material in lieu of silicone rubber. Additionally, the foregoing embodiment is applied to a switching type incubator but it may also be applied to a closed type incubator.</p><heading id="h0015">{Industrial Applicability}</heading><!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --><p id="p0042" num="0042">The present invention can be utilized for, for example, manufacturing an incubator that includes: a hand insertion window in a side of a newborn chamber, a hand insertion door that opens and closes the hand insertion window, and a latch mechanism that holds the hand insertion door in a closing position.</p><heading id="h0016">{Reference Signs List}</heading><p id="p0043" num="0043"><dl id="dl0001" compact="compact"><dt>11</dt><dd>Incubator</dd><dt>16</dt><dd>Newborn chamber</dd><dt>33</dt><dd>Hand insertion window</dd><dt>34</dt><dd>Hand insertion door</dd><dt>35</dt><dd>Latch mechanism</dd><dt>37</dt><dd>Rotation shaft</dd><dt>38</dt><dd>Helical coil spring</dd><dt>41</dt><dd>Latch</dd><dt>42</dt><dd>Latch base plate</dd><dt>43</dt><dd>Releasing member</dd><dt>44</dt><dd>Rotation shaft</dd><dt>45</dt><dd>Helical coil spring (urging member)</dd><dt>46</dt><dd>Spiral face</dd><dt>51</dt><dd>Helical compression spring</dd><dt>55</dt><dd>Pressed portion</dd><dt>56</dt><dd>Packing</dd><dt>61</dt><dd>Thicker portion (opening mechanism)</dd><dt>62</dt><dd>Projection</dd><dt>64</dt><dd>Spacer (braking member)</dd><dt>65</dt><dd>Braking mechanism</dd></dl></p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980160" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Inkubator (11), aufweisend:
<claim-text>ein Handeingriffsfenster (33), das in einer Seite einer Kammer (16) für ein Neugeborenes gebildet wird;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Handeingriffstür (34), die das Handeingriffsfenster (33) durch Drehung öffnet und schließt; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Klinkenmechanismus (35), der die Handeingriffstür (34) in einer Schließstellung zum Schließen des Handeingriffsfensters hält,</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> der Klinkenmechanismus (35) besitzt:
<claim-text>eine Klinke (41) mit: einem Drehschaft (44), der sich entlang der Seite erstreckt und eine Drehung zwischen einer Haltestellung zum Halten der Handeingriffstür (34) und einer Freigabestellung zum Freigeben des Haltens der Handeingriffstür (34) ermöglicht, und einer Spiralfläche (46), die sich bis zu mindestens einem Teil eines Umfangs des Drehschafts (44) erstreckt; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Freigabeelement (43), das entlang der Seite beweglich ist und durch Bewegung die Spiralfläche (46) drückt, um die Drehung der Klinke (41) aus der Haltestellung in die Freigabestellung herbeizuführen.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Inkubator (11) nach Anspruch 1, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> er ferner eine Schraubendruckfeder (51) aufweist, die das Freigabeelement (43) in eine Richtung entgegen derjenigen Richtung, in welche die Spiralfläche (46) gedrückt wird, zwingt.<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Inkubator (11) nach Anspruch 1, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> er ferner einen Öffnungsmechanismus (61) aufweist, der so ausgestaltet ist, dass im Verlauf der Drehung der Handeingriffstür (34) in die Richtung, in die das Handeingriffsfenster (33) geschlossen wird, der Öffnungsmechanismus (61) mit der Handeingriffstür (34) in Berührung kommt, bevor das Handeingriffsfenster (33) geschlossen wird, und hierdurch die Handeingriffstür (34) zwingt, die Drehung in diejenige Richtung herbeizuführen, in welche das Handeingriffsfenster (33) geöffnet wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Inkubator (11) nach Anspruch 3, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b><br/>
eine Manschette (56) an einer inneren Kante des Handeingriffsfensters (33) angebracht ist und<br/>
die Manschette (56) als Öffnungsmechanismus (61) dient.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Inkubator (11) nach Anspruch 4, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die Manschette (56) aus Silikonkautschuk hergestellt ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Inkubator (11) nach Anspruch 4, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b><br/>
die Manschette (56) einen dickeren Abschnitt (61) hat und<br/>
der dickere Abschnitt (61) als Öffnungsmechanismus (61) dient.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Inkubator (11) nach Anspruch 6, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b><br/>
auf dem dickeren Abschnitt (61) ein Vorsprung (62) angeordnet ist, um zu verhindern, dass die Manschette (56) aus Versehen angebracht wird, und<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> -->der dickere Abschnitt (61) und der Vorsprung (62) als Öffnungsmechanismus (61) dienen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Inkubator (11) nach Anspruch 7, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b><br/>
ein Drehschaft (37) für die Drehung der Handeingriffstür (34) in eine Spiralfeder (38) eingesetzt ist und<br/>
der dickere Abschnitt (61), der Vorsprung (62) und die Schraubenfeder (38) als Öffnungsmechanismus (61) dienen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Inkubator (11) nach Anspruch 1, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b><br/>
die Klinke (41) einen gedrückten Abschnitt (55) hat, der durch die Drehung der Handeingriffstür (34) gedrückt wird und hierdurch die Drehung aus der Haltestellung in die Freigabestellung herbeiführt, und<br/>
der gedrückte Abschnitt (55) ist aus einem stoßabsorbierenden Material hergestellt ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Inkubator (11) nach Anspruch 9, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> das stoßabsorbierende Material Silikonkautschuk ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Inkubator (11) nach Anspruch 1, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> er ferner einen Bremsmechanismus (65) aufweist, der so ausgestaltet ist, dass von einem Punkt im Verlauf der Drehung der Handeingriffstür (34) in die Richtung, in die das Handeingriffsfenster (33) geöffnet wird, der Bremsmechanismus (65) die Drehung der Handeingriffstür (34) bremst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Inkubator (11) nach Anspruch 11, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b><br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> -->ein Abschnitt um einen Drehschaft (37) für die Drehung der Handeingriffstür (34) einen Querschnitt hat, der nicht vollständig kreisförmig ist, und<br/>
der Querschnitt im Verlauf der Drehung mit dem Bremsmechanismus (65) in Berührung kommt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Inkubator (11) nach Anspruch 12, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b><br/>
der Bremsmechanismus (65) elastisch verformbar ist und<br/>
durch die elastische Verformung der Bremsmechanismus (65) Druck, der aufgrund der Berührung ausgeübt wird, absorbiert.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Inkubator (11) nach Anspruch 1, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> der Klinkenmechanismus (35) besitzt:
<claim-text>ein Zwangselement (45) zum Erzwingen der Drehung der Klinke (41) aus der Freigabestellung in die Haltestellung; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Bremselement (64) zum Bremsen der Drehung der Klinke (41) .</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Inkubator (11) nach Anspruch 14, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b><br/>
der Klinkenmechanismus (35) eine Klinkenbasisplatte (42), die die Klinke (41) und das Freigabeelement (43) stützt, besitzt und<br/>
das Bremselement (64) ein Abstandsstück (64) ist, das zwischen der Klinke (41) und der Klinkenbasisplatte (42) und um den Drehschaft (44) angeordnet ist.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980161" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>An incubator (11) comprising:
<claim-text>a hand insertion window (33) formed in a side of a newborn chamber (16);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a hand insertion door (34) that opens and closes the hand insertion window (33) by rotation; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a latch mechanism (35) that holds the hand insertion door (34) in a closing position for closing the hand insertion window,</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>characterized in that</b> the latch mechanism (35) includes:
<claim-text>a latch (41) having: a rotation shaft (44) extending along the side and enabling rotation between a holding position for the holding of the hand insertion door (34) and an releasing position for releasing the holding of the hand insertion door (34), and a spiral face (46) extending to at least part of a periphery of the rotation shaft (44); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a releasing member (43) that is movable along the side, and presses the spiral face (46) by movement to cause the rotation of the latch (41) from the holding position to the releasing position.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The incubator (11) according to claim 1, <b>characterized by</b> further comprising a helical compression spring (51) urging the releasing member (43) in a direction opposite to the direction in which the spiral face (46) is pressed.<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The incubator (11) according to claim 1, <b>characterized by</b> further comprising an opening mechanism (61) configured such that in the course of the rotation of the hand insertion door (34) in the direction in which the hand insertion window (33) is closed, the opening mechanism (61) comes into contact with the hand insertion door (34) before the hand insertion window (33) is closed, and thereby urges the hand insertion door (34) to cause the rotation in the direction in which the hand insertion window (33) is opened.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The incubator (11) according to claim 3, <b>characterized in that</b><br/>
a packing (56) is attached to an internal edge of the hand insertion window (33), and<br/>
the packing (56) serves as the opening mechanism (61).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The incubator (11) according to claim 4, <b>characterized in that</b> the packing (56) is made of silicone rubber.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The incubator (11) according to claim 4, <b>characterized in that</b><br/>
the packing (56) has a thicker portion (61), and<br/>
the thicker portion (61) serves as the opening mechanism (61).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The incubator (11) according to claim 6, <b>characterized in that</b><br/>
disposed on the thicker portion (61) is a projection (62) for preventing the packing (56) from being erroneously attached, and<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> -->the thicker portion (61) and the projection (62) serve as the opening mechanism (61).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The incubator (11) according to claim 7, <b>characterized in that</b><br/>
a rotation shaft (37) for the rotation of the hand insertion door (34) is inserted in a helical coil spring (38), and<br/>
the thicker portion (61), the projection (62), and the helical coil spring (38) serve as the opening mechanism (61).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The incubator (11) according to claim 1, <b>characterized in that</b><br/>
the latch (41) has a pressed portion (55) that is pressed by the rotation of the hand insertion door (34), and thereby causes the rotation from the holding position to the releasing position, and<br/>
the pressed portion (55) is made of impact-absorbent material.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The incubator (11) according to claim 9, <b>characterized in that</b> the impact-absorbent material is silicone rubber.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>The incubator (11) according to claim 1, <b>characterized by</b> further comprising a braking mechanism (65) configured such that from some point in the course of the rotation of the hand insertion door (34) in the direction in which the hand insertion window (33) is<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> opened, the braking mechanism (65) brakes the rotation of the hand insertion door (34).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>The incubator (11) according to claim 11, <b>characterized in that</b><br/>
a portion around a rotation shaft (37) for the rotation of the hand insertion door (34) has a cross-section that is not completely circular, and<br/>
the cross-section comes into contact with the braking mechanism (65) in the course of the rotation.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>The incubator (11) according to claim 12, <b>characterized in that</b><br/>
the braking mechanism (65) is elastically deformable, and<br/>
by the elastic deformation, the braking mechanism (65) absorbs pressure applied due to the contact.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>The incubator (11) according to claim 1, <b>characterized in that</b> the latch mechanism (35) includes:
<claim-text>an urging member (45) for urging the rotation of the latch (41) from the releasing position to the holding position; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a braking member (64) for braking the rotation of the latch (41).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>The incubator (11) according to claim 14,<br/>
<b>characterized in that</b><br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> -->the latch mechanism (35) includes a latch base plate (42) supporting the latch (41) and the releasing member (43), and<br/>
the braking member (64) is a spacer (64) disposed between the latch (41) and the latch base plate (42) and around the rotation shaft (44).</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980162" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Couveuse (11) comprenant:
<claim-text>une ouverture de passage de main (33) formée sur un côté d'une chambre de nouveau-né (16);</claim-text>
<claim-text>une trappe de passage de main (34) qui libère et obture l'ouverture de passage de main (33) par rotation; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un mécanisme de verrouillage (35) qui maintient la trappe de passage de main (34) dans une position fermée afin d'obturer l'ouverture de passage de main,</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>caractérisée en ce que</b> le mécanisme de verrouillage (35) comporte:
<claim-text>un verrou (41) comprenant: un axe de rotation (44) s'étendant latéralement et permettant la rotation entre une position de maintien destinée assurer le maintien de la trappe de passage de main (34) et une position de libération destinée assurer la libération du maintien de la trappe de passage de main (34), et une face en spirale (46) s'étendant sur au moins une partie de la périphérie de l'axe de rotation (44); et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un élément de libération (43) qui peut être déplacé latéralement, et presse la face en spirale (46) par un mouvement provoquant la rotation du verrou (41) depuis la position de maintien vers la position de libération.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Couveuse (11) selon la revendication 1, <b>caractérisée en ce qu'</b>elle comprend en outre un ressort de compression hélicoïdal (51) appliquant l'élément de libération (43) dans une direction opposée à la direction suivant laquelle la face en spirale (46) est pressée.<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Couveuse (11) selon la revendication 1, <b>caractérisée en ce qu'</b>elle comprend en outre un mécanisme d'ouverture (61) configuré de telle manière qu'au cours de la rotation de la trappe de passage de main (34) dans la direction suivant laquelle l'ouverture de passage de main (33) est fermée, le mécanisme d'ouverture (61) entre en contact avec la trappe de passage de main (34) avant que l'ouverture de passage de main (33) soit fermée, et pousse ainsi la trappe de passage de main (34) afin de provoquer la rotation dans la direction suivant laquelle l'ouverture de passage de main (33) s'ouvre.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Couveuse (11) selon la revendication 3, <b>caractérisée en ce que</b>:
<claim-text>une garniture (56) est fixée sur un bord interne de l'ouverture de passage de main (33), et</claim-text>
<claim-text>la garniture (56) sert de mécanisme d'ouverture (61).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Couveuse (11) selon la revendication 4, <b>caractérisée en ce que</b> la garniture (56) est réalisée en un caoutchouc au silicone.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Couveuse (11) selon la revendication 4, <b>caractérisée en ce que</b>:
<claim-text>la garniture (56) présente une partie plus épaisse (61), et</claim-text>
<claim-text>la partie plus épaisse (61) sert de mécanisme d'ouverture (61).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Couveuse (11) selon la revendication 6, <b>caractérisée en ce que</b>:
<claim-text>sur la partie plus épaisse (61), il est formé une saillie (62) destinée à empêcher la fixation erronée de la garniture (56), et<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>la partie plus épaisse (61) et la saillie (62) servent de mécanisme d'ouverture (61).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Couveuse (11) selon la revendication 7, <b>caractérisée en ce que</b>:
<claim-text>un axe de rotation (37), destiné à assurer la rotation de la trappe de passage de main (34), est inséré sur un ressort à spire hélicoïdale (38), et</claim-text>
<claim-text>la partie plus épaisse (61), la saillie (62) et le ressort à spire hélicoïdale (38) servent de mécanisme d'ouverture (61).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Couveuse (11) selon la revendication 1, <b>caractérisée en ce que</b>:
<claim-text>le verrou (41) comprend une partie pressée (55) qui est pressée par la rotation de la trappe de passage de main (34), et provoque ainsi la rotation à partir de la position de maintien vers la position de libération, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>la partie pressée (55) est réalisée en un matériau absorbant les chocs.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Couveuse (11) selon la revendication 9, <b>caractérisée en ce que</b> le matériau absorbant les chocs est du caoutchouc au silicone.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Couveuse (11) selon la revendication 1, <b>caractérisée en ce qu'</b>elle comprend en outre un mécanisme de freinage (65) configuré de telle sorte que, à partir d'un certain point au cours de la rotation de la trappe de passage de main (34) dans le sens suivant lequel l'ouverture de passage de main (33) peut être ouverte, le mécanisme de freinage (65) freine la rotation de la trappe de passage de main (34).<!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Couveuse (11) selon la revendication 11, <b>caractérisée en ce que</b>:
<claim-text>une partie autour d'un axe de rotation (37), destinée à assurer la rotation de la trappe de passage de main (34),</claim-text>
<claim-text>présente une section transversale qui n'est pas totalement circulaire, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>la section transversale vient en contact avec le mécanisme de freinage (65) au cours de la rotation.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Couveuse (11) selon la revendication 12, <b>caractérisée en ce que</b>:
<claim-text>le mécanisme de freinage (65) peut être déformé de manière élastique et,</claim-text>
<claim-text>par la déformation élastique, le mécanisme de freinage (65) absorbe la pression appliquée du fait du contact.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Couveuse (11) selon la revendication 1, <b>caractérisée en ce que</b> le mécanisme de verrouillage (35) comporte:
<claim-text>un élément d'application (45) destiné à précharger la rotation du verrou (41) depuis la position de libération vers la position de maintien; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un élément de freinage (64) destiné à freiner la rotation du verrou (41).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Couveuse (11) selon la revendication 14, <b>caractérisée en ce que</b>:
<claim-text>le mécanisme de verrouillage (35) comporte une plaque de base de verrou (42) supportant le verrou (41) et l'élément de libération (43), et</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'élément de freinage (64) est une entretoise (64) disposée entre le verrou (41) et la plaque de base de verrou (42) et autour de l'axe de rotation (44).</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16669075" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1,2"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="126" he="212" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --><figure id="f0002" num="3"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="156" he="183" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --><figure id="f0003" num="4"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="144" he="198" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --><figure id="f0004" num="5"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="140" he="175" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="36"> --><figure id="f0005" num="6"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="127" he="82" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="37"> --><figure id="f0006" num="7"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="118" he="191" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="38"> --><figure id="f0007" num="8"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="147" he="222" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="39"> --><figure id="f0008" num="9"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="152" he="202" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="40"> --><figure id="f0009" num="10(a),10(b)"><img id="if0009" file="imgf0009.tif" wi="151" he="202" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="41"> --><figure id="f0010" num="11"><img id="if0010" file="imgf0010.tif" wi="138" he="153" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
