<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2495120-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2495120" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="45656497" file-reference-id="315082" date-produced="20180825" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146587861" ucid="EP-2495120-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2495120</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-12156642-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154850053" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12156642</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120223</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP196397367" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12156642.6</doc-number><date>20120223</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140550171" ucid="JP-2011043851-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>JP</country><doc-number>2011043851</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20110301</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20131024</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989324117" load-source="docdb">B60J  10/00        20060101AFI20130919BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989324118" load-source="docdb">B60J  10/08        20060101ALI20130919BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1919323351" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B60J  10/18        20160201 LI20160711BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1919323514" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B60J  10/0011      20130101 FI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1976572406" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B60J  10/24        20160201 LI20160201BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1976577652" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B60J  10/32        20160201 LI20160201BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1976578408" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B60J  10/84        20160201 LI20160201BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2142266146" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10S 277/921       20130101 LA20141028BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132368216" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Dichtung für eine Kraftfahrzeugöffnung und Verfahren zu ihrer Herstellung</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132368217" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Opening seal for automobiles and method of preparing the same</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132368218" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Joint d'ouverture pour automobiles et son procédé de fabrication</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919538115" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>NISHIKAWA RUBBER CO LTD</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919513845" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>NISHIKAWA RUBBER CO., LTD.</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919509164" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>NISHIMOTO YOSHITAKA</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919525870" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>NISHIMOTO, YOSHITAKA</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919020393" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>NISHIMOTO, YOSHITAKA</last-name><address><street>Nishikawa Rubber Co., Ltd. 2-8, Misasa-machi 2-chome Nishi-ku, Hiroshima-shi</street><city>Hiroshima-shi, Hiroshima</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919519270" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>NISHIKAWA SHINJI</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919516636" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>NISHIKAWA, SHINJI</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919020392" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>NISHIKAWA, SHINJI</last-name><address><street>Nishikawa Rubber Co., Ltd. 2-8, Misasa-machi 2-chome Nishi-ku, Hiroshima-shi</street><city>Hiroshima-shi, Hiroshima</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919518235" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>MCCABE BRIAN</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919533097" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>MCCABE, BRIAN</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919020394" load-source="patent-office" sequence="3" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>MCCABE, BRIAN</last-name><address><street>Nishikawa Cooper LLC 324 Morrow Street</street><city>Topeka, IN Indiana 46571</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919020396" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Nishikawa Rubber Co., Ltd.</last-name><iid>101281214</iid><address><street>2-8, Misasa-machi 2-chome Nishi-ku</street><city>Hiroshima-shi Hiroshima-ken, Hiroshima</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919020395" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Scholz, Volker</last-name><iid>100985467</iid><address><street>Boehmert &amp; Boehmert Pettenkoferstrasse 20-22</street><city>80336 München</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549779189" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS549864663" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549778821" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549794562" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549921588" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549778822" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549864664" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549779190" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549778823" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549778824" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549862852" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549794563" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549921589" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549779191" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549778829" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549779192" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549864665" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549921590" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549778830" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549794564" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549778831" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549794577" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549866960" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549794578" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549794579" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549866961" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS549866974" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549862853" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549886153" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549862862" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549794580" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549864670" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549794593" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS549862863" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549921591" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549886158" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549886159" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS549866975" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63960295" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to opening seals for automobiles and method of preparing the same having wire core embedded in installation base members thereof for increasing rigidity, which are installed along peripheries of door opening parts of automobile bodies for sealing openings between bodies and doors by making elastic contact with the doors when the doors are closed.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 8</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 9</figref>, an opening seal 10 for automobiles having a wire core 20 embedded therein has been well-known, which is mounted on a flange 3 installed along a periphery of a door 2 opening part on an automobile body 1 side for making elastic contact with the door 2 when the door 2 is closed to seal an opening between the body 1 and the door 2 (see, for example, the Japanese unexamined Patent Publication Nos. <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="JPH0382519B"><text>H03-82519</text></patcit> and <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="JP2004322768A"><text>2004-322768</text></patcit>).</p><p id="p0003" num="0003"><figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 8</figref> is a side view of an automobile having the opening seal 10 for automobiles mounted thereon; and <figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 9</figref> is an enlarged perspective view of an important part of 100 of <figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 8</figref>, showing the opening seal 10 for automobiles.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">The opening seal 10 for automobiles comprises a cross section roughly U-shaped installation base member 11 including an outer-cabin side wall 11a, an inner-cabin side wall 11b and a connecting wall 11c which connects the side walls 11a and 11b; a hollow seal member 12 provided on an outer-cabin side of the installation base member 11; and a protuberance 13 provided inside the inner-cabin side wall 11b of the installation base member 11, which makes elastic contact with and holds the flange 3. The outer-cabin side wall 11a has a plurality of projections 14 provided inside, which make elastic contact with the flange 3; and the installation base member 11 has a lip 15 provided on an inner-cabin side thereof. Decorative coating material 16 is provided from the<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> lip 15 to a surface of the connecting wall 11c of the installation base member 11 for decorating appearance from an inner-cabin side.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 10</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 11</figref>, the wire core 20 embedded in the installation base member 11 of the opening seal 10 for automobiles comprises<sup>:</sup> a skeletal wire body 21 formed by consecutively bending a wire; and yarns 22, 23 partially connected with the wire body 21 for preventing expansion of the wire body 21 in a longitudinal direction. The wire core 20 is finally embedded in a longitudinal direction of the installation base member 11 while the wire core 20, consecutively bent into U shapes in the same direction at regular intervals in advance, is bent into a rough U-shape.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">Examples of use of the yarns for preventing expansion of the wire body 21 in a longitudinal direction include: a plurality of non-thermo-fusible yarns 22 which do not melt at set vulcanization temperature for vulcanizing rubber component when preparing the opening seal 10 for automobiles as shown in <figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 9 and Fig. 10</figref> (six non-thermo-fusible yarns in <figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 9 and Fig. 10</figref>); and a combination of the non-thermo-fusible yarns 22 which do not melt at the set vulcanization temperature and thermo-fusible yarns 23 which do not melt at the time of an extrusion molding and melt at the set vulcanization temperature as shown in <figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 11</figref> (two non-thermo -fusible yarns 22 and six thermo-fusible yarns 23 in <figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 11</figref>).</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">Such a structure controls unnecessary expansion of the opening seal 10 for automobiles at the time of the extrusion molding and the preparation of the opening seal 10 for automobiles and improves rigidity of the installation base member 11 after molding, thereby improving assembly force of the opening seal 10 for automobiles on the flange 3.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">In the opening seal 10 for automobiles prepared by extrusion molding, parts with the non-thermo-fusible yarn 22 are greatly improved in strength compared with parts without the non-thermo-fusible yarn 22. But, in the resultant opening seal 10 for automobiles having the full length including a<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> corner part has caused problems that, on an outer peripheral side of a position 201 as an intersection of the hollow seal member 12 and a straight line 200, the hollow seal member 12 is subjected to force expanding toward an outer peripheral side whereas, on an inner peripheral side of the position 201, the hollow seal member 12 is subjected to contracting force which cause wrinkles. The straight line 200 connects the non-thermo-fusible yarn 22 (22a) embedded on a greater opening edge side on the outer-cabin side wall 11a of the installation base member 11 with the non-thermo-fusible yarn 22 (22b) embedded on a greater opening edge side on the inner-cabin side wall 11b of the installation base member 11.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">The expansion and contraction of the hollow seal member 12 hamper stabilization of the assembled state of the opening seal 10 for automobiles, which degrades external appearance and sealing function. Such problems are remarkable when the folding wrinkles 202 generate.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 11</figref>, the Japanese unexamined Patent Publication No. <patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="JPH0382519B"><text>H03-82519</text></patcit> discloses to connect each of three sides of the wire core 20, respectively embedded in the outer-cabin side wall 11a, an inner-cabin side wall 11b and a connecting wall 11c of the installation base member 11, with the yarns which are thermally degraded at the set vulcanization temperature and the yarns which are not thermally degraded (non-thermo-fusible yarn) at the set vulcanization temperature. The resultant opening seal is excellent in strength toward pulling force at the time of extrusion molding. But a way of disposing the yarns on each of the three sides of the wire core 20 is rough, only one side of the wire core 20 with the non-thermo-fusible yarn for example. Such a structure does not decrease expanding or contracting state on the hollow seal member 12 sufficiently, especially while the opening seal 10 for automobiles is assembled on the corner part.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">The Japanese unexamined Patent Publication No. <patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="JP2004322768A"><text>2004-322768</text></patcit> discloses to provide high melting point yarn (non-thermo-fusible yarn) on a<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> part of the inner-cabin side wall 11b, that is at least close to the connecting wall 11c. But the invention relates to weather strips installed on automobile bodies with curves which are swelled toward width direction of the automobiles. Accordingly, the invention does not decrease expanding or contracting state on the hollow seal member 12 sufficiently while the opening seal 10 for automobiles is assembled on the corner part.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">Therefore, an object of the present invention is to provide the opening seal for automobiles and method of preparing the same capable of remarkably decreasing the expanding or contracting state on the hollow seal member while the opening seal for automobiles is assembled on the corner part.</p><heading id="h0002">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading><p id="p0013" num="0013">In order to achieve the above-mentioned object, a first aspect of the invention provides an opening seal for automobiles, comprising: an installation base member (11) with a roughly U-shaped cross section mountable on a flange (3) installed along a periphery of a door (2) opening which is part of a vehicle body (1), the base member including an outer-cabin side wall (11a), an inner-cabin side wall (11b) and a connecting wall (11c) connecting the side walls (11a, 11b);<br/>
a hollow seal member (12) extending from an inner side position (301) and an outer side position (800) of said outer-cabin side wall (11a) of the installation base member (11) respectively toward an internal circumference side (305) and an outer circumference side (304) of a door, which is swelled and curved toward an outer-cabin side (304) for making elastic contact with said door (2) thereby sealing an inside and an outside of the automobile;<br/>
one or a plurality of protuberances (13) installed inside the inner-cabin side wall (11b) of said installation base member (11) for making elastic contact with and holding said flange (3); and<br/>
a wire core (20) embedded in a longitudinal direction of said installation base member (11) while being bent roughly in U-shape, including:<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> -->a skeletal wire body (21) formed by continuously bending a wire; and non-thermo-fusible yarn which does not melt at set vulcanization temperature, which is partially connected with the wire body (21) and is roughly linearly extending in a longitudinal direction while controlling expansion of the wire body (21) in a longitudinal direction; wherein<br/>
said wire core (20) has at least two non-thermo-fusible yarns (22) respectively provided on the outer-cabin side (306) and the inner-cabin side (307) thereof,<br/>
the non-thermo-fusible yarn (221) on the outer-cabin side is provided in a range (401) from a bending start position (21c) forming a shoulder (21a) on the outer-cabin side of the wire body (21) which is bent roughly in U-shape to a position (52) determined by offsetting a point (51), on the door internal circumference side (305) of an inner-side base (12a) of said hollow seal member (12), with respect to the wire body (21); and<br/>
the non-thermo-fusible yarn (222) on the inner-cabin side is provided in a range (501) from a bending start position (21e) forming a shoulder (21b) on the inner-cabin side of the wire body (21) which is bent roughly in U-shape, to a position (54) determined by offsetting a point (53), on an opening edge side (308) on said inner-cabin side wall (11b) of a base of the protuberance (13) which is positioned on a greater opening edge part side (309) on the inner-cabin side wall (11b) of said installation base member (11) among said one or a plurality of protuberances (13), with respect to the wire body (21).<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></p><p id="p0014" num="0014">A second aspect of the invention provides the opening seal for automobiles according to the first aspect of the invention, wherein: said non-thermo-fusible yarn (221) on the outer-cabin side (306) is provided in a range (402) from a bending end position (21d) forming a shoulder (21a) on the outer-ca.bin side of the wire body (21) which is bent roughly in U-shape to a position (52) determined by offsetting a point (51), on the door internal circumference side (305) of an inner-side base (12a) of said hollow seal member (12), with respect to the wire body (21).</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">A third aspect of the invention provides the opening seal for automobiles according to the first or second aspect of the invention, wherein: said non-thermo-fusible yarn (222) on the inner-cabin side (307) is provided in a range (502) from a position (55) on the inner-cabin side determined by offsetting a provided point of said non-thermo-fusible yarn (221) on the outer-cabin side (306) with respect to the wire body (21) to a position (54) determined by offsetting a point (53), on an opening edge side on said inner-cabin side wall (11b) of a base of the protuberance (13) that is positioned on the greater opening edge part side on the inner-cabin side wall (11b) of said installation base member (11) among said one or a plurality of protuberances, with respect to the wire body (21).</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">A fourth aspect of the invention provides the opening seal for automobiles according to the second aspect of the invention, wherein: said non-thermo-fusible yarn (222) on the inner-cabin side is provided in a range (503) from a position (57), where a straight line (100) connecting a point (56) on the door internal circumference side (305) on an internal side of the wall of said hollow seal member (12) and a provided point of said non-thermo-fusible yarn (221) on the outer-cabin side intersects the inner-cabin side of the wire body (21), to the position (54) determined by<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> offsetting the point (53), on the opening edge side on said inner-cabin side wall (11b) of the base of the protuberance (13) that is positioned on the greater opening edge part side on the inner-cabin side wall (11b) of said installation base member (11) among said one or a plurality of protuberances, with respect to the wire body (21).</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">A fifth aspect of the invention provides the opening seal for automobiles according to the second aspect of the invention, wherein: said non-thermo-fusible yarn (222) on the inner-cabin side is provided in a range (504) from a position (59), where a straight line (300) connecting a point (58) on the door internal circumference side (305) of an outer side of the wall of said hollow seal member (12) and a provided point of said non-thermo-fusible yarn (221) on the outer-cabin side intersects the inner-cabin side of the wire body (21), to the position (54) determined by offsetting the point (53), on the opening edge side on said inner-cabin side wall (11b) of the base of the protuberance (13) that is positioned on the greater opening edge part side on the inner-cabin side wall (11b) of said installation base member (11) among said one or a plurality of protuberances, with respect to the wire body (21).<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></p><p id="p0018" num="0018">An sixth aspect of the invention provides the opening seal for automobiles according to any one of the first to fifth aspects of the invention, wherein: the shoulder (21a) on the outer-cabin side of said installation base member (11) is provided with coating material (31) having higher specific gravity compared with material forming said installation base member (11).</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">Symbols in parentheses show constituents or items corresponding to Figures and DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENT.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">With the opening seal for automobiles and the method of preparing the same of the present invention, the installation base member mounted on the flange installed along the periphery of the door opening part of the body has the wire core embedded therein, including the skeletal wire body connected with the non-thermo-fusible yarn which does not melt at set vulcanization temperature. Accordingly, in a course of vulcanization and extrusion molding the opening seal for automobiles, the non-thermo-fusible yarn remains, not melts. Such a structure controls unnecessary expansion of the opening seal for automobiles together with the wire core for the effect of the non-thermo-fusible yarns even in case the wire core is pulled with strong force while extrusion molding the opening seal for automobiles in the course of preparation. Also, the structure improves assembly force of the opening seal for automobiles on the flange by improving the rigidity of the installation base member after molding.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">In addition, the wire core has at least two non-thermo-fusible yarns respectively provided on the outer-cabin side and the inner-cabin side thereof; the non-thermo-fusible yarn on the outer-cabin side is provided in the range from the bending start position forming the shoulder on the outer-cabin side of<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> the wire body which is bent roughly in U-shape to the position determined by offsetting the point, on the door internal circumference side of an inner-side base of the hollow seal member, with respect to the wire body; and the non-tbermo-fusible yarn on the inner-cabin side is provided in the range from the bending start position forming the shoulder on the inner-cabin side of the wire body which is bent roughly in U-shape to the position determined by offsetting the point, on the opening edge side on said inner-cabin side wall of a base of the protuberance which is positioned on the greater opening edge part side on the inner-cabin side wall of the installation base member, with respect to the wire body. The straight line which connects the position of the non-thermo-fusible yarn on the outer-cabin side and the position of the non-thermo-fusible yarn on the inner-cabin side leans toward the internal circumference side from the outer circumference side of a door (toward the connecting wall side from an opening part side of the installation base member) when the door is closed as faced toward the outer-cabin side from the inner-cabin side for the effect of the non-thermo-fusible yarn on the outer-cabin side thus provided.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">The leaned straight line as extended intersects the hollow seal member on a position on the internal circumference side of a door (on the connecting wall side from the opening part side of the installation base member) compared with the prior art (<figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 9</figref>) in which the leaned straight line as extended intersects hollow seal member on a position on the outer circumference side. Accordingly, contracting force functions within a smaller domain of the hollow seal member when the opening seal for automobiles is assembled on a corner part on the body side of the automobile, thereby preventing generation of folding wrinkles.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">Further, by leaning the straight line which connects the position of the non-thermo-fusible yarn on the outer-cabin side and the position of the non-thermo-fusible yarn on the inner-cabin side, fastening force of the<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> installation base member on the flange from the inner-cabin side wall side is increased, which enables the protuberance provided on the inner-cabin side wall side to hold the flange sufficiently.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">Such a structure enables stable assembly of the opening seal for automobiles on the corner part on the body side of the automobile and keeps the opening seal stably assembled after the assembly.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">In addition, according to the present invention, the non-thermo-fusible yarn on the outer-cabin side is provided from the bending end position, not bending start position forming the shoulder on the outer-cabin side of the wire body which is bent roughly in U-shape. Accordingly, the non-thermo-fusible yarn on the outer-cabin side is provided on the outer-cabin side wall side of the installation base member, changed from the connecting wall side. Such a structure improves balance when connecting the wire body and effectively controls unnecessary expansion of the opening seal for automobiles together with the wire core while the opening seal for automobiles together with the non-thermo-fusible yarn on the inner-cabin side is extrusion molded.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">In addition, according to the present invention, the non-thermo-fusible yarn on the inner-cabin side is provided in a further limited range: from the position on the inner-cabin side, determined by offsetting the providing point of the non-thermo-fusible yarn on the outer-cabin side with respect to the wire body; from the position where the straight line connecting the end on the door internal circumference side on the hollow side of the hollow seal member and the providing point of the non-thermo-fusible yarn on the outer-cabin side intersects the inner-cabin side of the wire body; or from the position where the straight line connecting the end on the door internal circumference side of the hollow seal member and the providing point of the non-thermo-fusible yarn on the outer-cabin side intersects the inner-cabin side of the wire body. The leaned straight line as extended intersects the hollow seal member on a position on the internal circumference side of the door, changed from the outer<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> circumference side, that is on the connecting wall side changed from the opening part side of the installation base member. Accordingly, the contracting force functions within a further smaller domain of the hollow seal member when the opening seal for automobiles is assembled on the corner part on the body side, thereby preventing generation of folding wrinkles.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">Also, the fastening force of the installation base member on the flange from the inner-cabin side wall side is increased, which enables the protuberance provided on the inner-cabin side wall side to hold the flange sufficiently.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">It is to be noted that the position on the opening edge side of the inner-cabin side wall of each range (501, 502, 503, 504 according to the following embodiment) is determined by offsetting the point, on the opening edge side on the inner-cabin side wall of the base of the protuberance that is positioned on the greater opening edge part side on the inner-cabin side wall of the installation base member among the one or plurality of protuberance, with respect to the wire body. In case the position on the opening edge side is further on the opening edge side compared with the above-mentioned position, the opening seal for automobiles in itself may lean when assembled on the corner part on the automobile body side, which is not a desired assembled state and not favorable.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">In case the non-thermo-fusible yarn on the inner-cabin side is provided in the range from the position where the straight line connecting the end on the door internal circumference side of the hollow seal member and the providing point of the non-thermo-fusible yarn on the outer-cabin side intersects the inner-cabin side of the wire body to the position determined by offsetting the point on the opening edge side on the inner-cabin side wall of the base of the protuberance that is positioned on the greater opening edge part side on the inner-cabin side wall of the installation base member among the one or plurality of protuberance with respect to the wire body, the straight<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> line which connects the position of the non-thermo-fusible yarn on the outer-cabin side and the position of the non-thermo-fusible yarn on the inner-cabin side, as extended, intersects the hollow seal member on the position which is the end on the door internal circumference side of the hollow seal member or further door internal circumference side. Accordingly, the contracting force does not function on the hollow seal member when the opening seal for automobiles is assembled on the corner part on the body side of the automobile.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">In case the non-thermo-fusible yarn on the inner-cabin side is provided on the position on which the straight line connecting the end on the door internal circumference side on the hollow side of the hollow seal member and the providing point of the non-thermo-fusible yarn on the outer-cabin side intersects the inner-cabin side of the wire body, the straight line which connects the position of non-thermo-fusible yarn on the outer-cabin side and the position of the non-thermo-fusible yarn on the inner-cabin side, as extended, intersects the hollow seal member on the position which is the end on the door internal circumference side on the hollow side of the hollow seal member when the door is closed. Accordingly, the contracting force functions only on thickness of the hollow seal member when the opening seal for automobiles is assembled on the corner part on the body side of the automobile so that the folding wrinkles hardly generates. In case the non-thermo-fusible yarn on the inner-cabin side is shifted from the position where the straight line connecting the end on the door internal circumference side on the hollow side of the hollow seal member and the providing point of the non-thermo-fusible yarn on the outer-cabin side intersects the inner-cabin side of the wire body to a position determined by offsetting the point on the opening edge side on the inner-cabin side wall of the base of the protuberance that is positioned on the greater opening edge part side on the inner-cabin side wall of the installation base member among the one or the plurality of<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> protuberance with respect to the wire body, the straight line which connects the position of the non-thermo-fusible yarn on the outer-cabin side and the position of the non-thermo-fusible yarn on the inner-cabin side, as extended, intersects the hollow seal member on the position which is further door internal circumference side compared with the end on the door internal circumference side on the hollow side of the hollow seal member when the door is closed. Accordingly, generation of the folding wrinkles is further prevented.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">In addition, according to the present invention, the wire body is partially connected with thermo-fusible yarn as well as the non-thermo-fusible yarn, which melts at set vulcanization temperature and roughly linearly extends in the longitudinal direction. Accordingly, the wire body is resistant to the pulling force before vulcanization. Also, the thermo-fusible yarn is provided on the connecting wall of the installation base member, on the outer-cabin side wall of the installation base member that is the opening edge side of the outer-cabin side wall compared with the providing point of the non-thermo-fusible yarn on the outer-cabin side and on the inner-cabin side wall of the installation base member that is the opening edge side of the inner-cabin side wall compared with the providing point of the non-thermo-fusible yarn on the inner-cabin side. Accordingly, the opening seal for automobiles is well-balanced and the thermo-fusible yarn that vanishes for the vulcanization does not cause expansion and contraction of the hollow seal member when the opening seal for automobiles is assembled on the corner part on the automobile body side.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">In addition, according to the present invention, the shoulder on the outer-cabin side of the installation base member is provided with coating material having higher specific gravity compared with material forming the installation base member. Accordingly, the opening seal for automobiles is stably assembled on the corner part on the automobile body side and wrinkles<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> do not generate on a part provided with the coating material. The non-thermo-fusible yarn on the inner-cabin side may be changed to the thermo-fusible yarn depending on strength of the material on the part.</p><heading id="h0003">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading><p id="p0033" num="0033"><ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is a cross section showing an opening seal for automobiles according to an embodiment of the present invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Figs. 2</figref> show a wire core shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, of which (a) is a plan view showing a state before the wire core is bent and (b) is a cross section showing a state after the wire core is bent;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> is a cross section showing an opening seal for automobiles according to another embodiment of the present invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 4</figref> is a block diagram showing a process of preparing the opening seal for automobiles of <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Figs. 5</figref> show each state of the opening seal for automobiles in each section of <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 4</figref>, of which (a) are a plan view and a cross section of the wire core in Section 601, (b) is a cross section of the wire core in Section 602, (c) is a cross section of the opening seal for automobiles in Section 603 and (d) is a cross section of the opening seal for automobiles in Section 604;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 6</figref> is a cross section showing an opening seal for automobiles according to still another embodiment of the present invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 7</figref> is a cross section showing an opening seal for automobiles according to still another embodiment of the present invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 8</figref> is an external side view of an automobile;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 9</figref> is an enlarged perspective view of partial cross section of 100 in <figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 8</figref>, showing a state that an opening seal for automobiles according to a prior art is mounted;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0007">Figs. 10</figref> show a state before a wire core embedded in the opening seal for automobiles of <figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 9</figref> is bent, of which (a) is a plan view and (b) is a cross<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> section; and</li><li><figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 11</figref> show a state before another wire core embedded in the opening seal for automobiles of <figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 9</figref> is bent, of which (a) is a plan view and (b) is a cross section.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0004">DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENT</heading><p id="p0034" num="0034">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>, an opening seal 10 for automobiles according to an embodiment of the present invention will be described. <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is a cross section showing an opening seal 10 for automobiles according to an embodiment of the present invention and <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> shows a cross section of a wire core 20 shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>. When constituents or items correspond to those in prior arts, the same symbols are used.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">The opening seal 10 for automobiles according to the embodiment of the present invention mainly comprises: an installation base member 11; a hollow seal member 12; a protuberance 13; and a wire core 20.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">The installation base member 11 is cross section roughly U-shaped, including an outer-cabin side wall 11a, an inner-cabin side wall 11b and a connecting wall 11c connecting the side walls 11a, 11b. In the same manner as <figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 8</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 9</figref>, the installation base member 11 is installed on a flange 3 installed along a periphery of a door 2 opening part of a body 1 in such a manner that the flange 3 is inserted into the installation base member 11 from an opening part side. The flange 3 extends inward along the periphery of the door 2 opening part.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">Bases 12a, 12b of the hollow seal member 12 extend from an inner side position and an outer side position of the outer-cabin side wall 11a of the installation base member 11 respectively toward an internal circumference side and an outer circumference side of a door, which is swelled and curved toward an outer-cabin side. The hollow seal member 12 makes elastic contact with the door 2 and seals an inside and an outside of the automobile<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> when the door 2 is closed.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">The protuberance 13 extends from an inside (outer-cabin side) of the inner-cabin side wall 11b of the installation base member 11 toward the connecting wall 11e side. The protuberance 13, together with the a plurality of (two in the present embodiment) projections 14 provided inside the outer-cabin side wall 11a of the installation base member 11, makes elastic contact with and holds the flange 3 by clasping. The installation base member 11 has a lip 15 provided on an inner-cabin side thereof. Decorative coating material 16 is provided from the lip 15 to a surface of the connecting wall 11c of the installation base member 11 for decorating appearance from an inner-cabin side.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2 (a)</figref>, a wire core 20 comprises: a skeletal wire body 21 formed by consecutively bending a wire; and yarn 22 partially connected with the wire body 21 for preventing expansion of the wire body 21 in a longitudinal direction. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2 (b)</figref>, the wire core 20 is finally embedded in a longitudinal direction of the installation base member 11 while the wire core 20, consecutively bent in U shapes in the same direction at regular intervals in advance, is bent into a rough U-shape by bending a shoulder 21a on the outer-cabin side and a shoulder 21b on the inner-cabin side. 21c is a bending start position forming the shoulder 21a on the outer-cabin side and 21d is a bending end position forming the shoulder 21a on the outer-cabin side. In the same manner, 21e is a bending start position forming a shoulder 21b on the inner-cabin side and 21f is a bending end position forming a shoulder 21b on the inner-cabin side.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">Yarn 22 for controlling expansion of the wire body 21 in a longitudinal direction is non-thermo-fusible yarn which does not melt at set vulcanization temperature for vulcanizing rubber component in the course of preparing the opening seal 10 for automobiles. Two non-thermo-fusible yarns 221, 222 are provided respectively on an outer-cabin side and an inner-cabin side.<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></p><p id="p0041" num="0041">Positions for providing the non-thermo-fusible yarn 221. on the outer-cabin side and the non-thermo-fusible yarn 222 on the inner-cabin side are defined as follows.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, the non-thermo-fusible yarn 221. on the outer-cabin side is provided, while the wire body 21 bent roughly in U-shape is embedded in the installation base member 11, in a range 401 from the bending start position 21c forming the shoulder 21a on the outer-cabin side of the wire body 21 which is bent roughly in U-shape to a position 52 determined by offsetting a point 51 on the door internal circumference side of the inner-side base 12a of the hollow seal member 12 with respect to the wire body 21. In case the non-thermo-fusible yarn 221 is positioned on the shoulder 21a on the outer-cabin side, the non-thermo-fusible yarn 221 is subjected to shift when bending the wire body 21 as shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2 (b)</figref> from a developed state shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2 (a)</figref>. Therefore, it is preferable not to position the non-thermo-fusible yarn 221 on the shoulder 21a on the outer-cabin side. Accordingly the non-thermo-fusible yarn 221 on the outer-cabin side may also be provided in a range 402 from the bending end position 21d forming the shoulder 21a on the outer-cabin side of the wire body 21 which is bent roughly in U-shape to the position 52 determined by offsetting the point 51 on the door internal circumference side of the inner-side base 12a of the hollow seal member 12 with respect to the wire body 21.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">In case the non-thermo-fusible yarn 221 on the outer-cabin side is provided from the bending end position 21d, not the bending start position 21c forming the shoulder 21a on the outer-cabin side of the wire body 21 which is bent roughly in U-shape, the non-thermo-fusible yarn 221 on the outer-cabin side is provided on the outer-cabin side wall 11a side of the installation base member 11, changed from the connecting wall 11c side. Such a structure improves balance when connecting the wire body 21 and effectively controls unnecessary expansion of the opening seal 10 for automobiles together with<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> the wire core 20 while the opening seal 10 for automobiles as well as the non-thermo-fusible yarn 222 on the inner-cabin side is extrusion molded.</p><p id="p0044" num="0044">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, the non-thermo-fusible yarn 222 on the inner-cabin side is provided, while the wire body 21 bent roughly in U-shape is embedded in the installation base member 11, in a range 501 from the bending start position 21e forming the shoulder 21b on the inner-cabin side of the wire body 21 which is bent roughly in U-shape to a position 54 determined by offsetting a point 53 on an opening edge side on the inner-cabin side wall 11b of a base of the protuberance 13 which is positioned on a greater opening edge part side on the inner-cabin side wall 11b of the installation base member 11, the protuberance 13 in the present embodiment because only one protuberance is provided, with respect to the wire body 21. In case the non-thermo-fusible yarn 222 is positioned on the shoulder 21b on the inner-cabin side, the non-thermo-fusible yarn 222 is subjected to shift when bending the wire body 21 as shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2 (b)</figref> from the developed state shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2 (a)</figref>. Therefore, it is preferable not to position the non-thermo-fusible yarn 222 on the shoulder 21b on the inner-cabin side. Accordingly, the non-thermo-fusible yarn 222 on the inner-cabin side may also be provided in a range from the bending end position 21f forming the shoulder 21b on the inner-cabin side of the wire body 21 which is bent roughly in U-shape to the position 54 determined by offsetting the point 53 on the opening edge side on the inner-cabin side wall 11b of the base of the protuberance 13 with respect to the wire body 21.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045">In case the non-thermo-fusible yarn 222 on the inner-cabin side is provided from the bending end position 21f, not bending start position 21e, forming the shoulder21b on the inner-cabin side of the wire body 21 which is bent roughly in U-shape, the non-thermo-fusible yarn 222 on the inner-cabin side is provided on the inner-cabin side wall 11b side of the installation base member 11, changed from the connecting wall 11c side. Such a. structure<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> improves balance when connecting the wire body 21 and effectively controls unnecessary expansion of the opening seal 10 for automobiles together with the wire core 20 while the opening seal 10 for automobiles as well as the non-thermo-fusible yarn 221 on the outer-cabin side is extrusion molded.</p><p id="p0046" num="0046">The non-thermo-fusible yarn 222 on the inner-cabin side may be provided in a range 502, which is limited by narrowing the range 501, from a position 55 on the inner-cabin side, determined by offsetting the providing point of the non-thermo-fusible yarn 221 on the outer-cabin side with respect to the wire body 21, to a position 54 determined by offsetting the point 53 on the opening edge side on the inner-cabin side wall 11b of the base of the protuberance 13 with respect to the wire body 21.</p><p id="p0047" num="0047">The non-thermo-fusible yarn 222 on the inner-cabin side may be provided in a range 503, which is limited by narrowing the range 502, from a position 57 where a straight line 100 connecting an end 56 on the door internal circumference side (door internal circumference side end part) on a hollow side of the hollow seal member 12 and the providing point of the non-thermo-fusible yarn 221 on the outer-cabin side intersects the inner-cabin side of the wire body 21 to the position 54 determined by offsetting the point 53 on the opening edge side on the inner-cabin side wall 11b of the base of the protuberance 13 with respect to the wire body 21.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>, in addition to the non-thermo-fusible yarn 221 on the outer-cabin side and the non-thermo-fusible yarn 222 on the inner-cabin side, the wire body 21 may be partially connected with thermo-fusible yarn 23 which melts at the set vulcanization temperature and roughly linearly extends in a longitudinal direction. In the present embodiment, five thermo-fusible yarns 23 are provided while the wire body 21 bent roughly in U-shape is embedded in the installation base member 11. Specifically, two thermo-fusible yarns 23 are provided on the connecting wall 11c side of the installation base member 11 except for the shoulders 21a, 21b; two<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> thermo-fusible yarns 23 are provided on the outer-cabin side wall 11a of the installation base member 11, that is the opening edge side of the outer-cabin side wall 11a compared with the providing point of the non-thermo-fusible yarn 221 on the outer-cabin side; and one thermo-fusible yarn 23 is provided on the inner-cabin side wall 11b of the installation base member 11, that is the opening edge side of the inner-cabin side wall 11b compared with the providing point of the non-thermo-fusible yarn 222 on the inner-cabin side.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">Also, the non-thermo-fusible yarn 22 can be further added. In <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>, two non-thermo-fusible yarns 223, 224 are provided on the inner-cabin side wall 11b of the installation base member 11 that is the connecting wall 11c side compared with the providing point of the non-thermo-fusible yarn 222 on the inner-cabin side for improving strength toward pulling force.</p><p id="p0050" num="0050">According to the structure, in addition to the non-thermo-fusible yarn 22, the wire body 21 is partially connected with thermo-fusible yarn 23 which melts at the set vulcanization temperature and roughly linearly extends in a longitudinal direction. Therefore, the wire body 21 is resistant to strong pulling force before vulcanization. Also, the thermo-fusible yarn 23 is provided on each of the three sides of the installation base member. Accordingly, the opening seal 10 for automobiles is well-balanced and the thermo-fusible yarn 23 that vanishes for the vulcanization does not cause contraction of the hollow seal member 12 when the opening seal 10 for automobiles is assembled on the corner part on the automobile body side.</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">Examples of the non-thermo-fusible yarn 22 (221, 222, 223, 224) include yarns made of polyester resin (e.g. PET (polyethylene terephthalate)), and polyamide resin (e.g. 6 nylon, 6-6 nylon), of which melting point is 230°C to 280 °C and which do not melt during the extrusion molding (around 100°C ) nor in a vulcanization furnace (200°C to 250°C).</p><p id="p0052" num="0052">Examples of the thermo-fusible yarn 23 include yarns made of polyolefin resin (e.g. PP (polypropylene), PE (polyethylene)) of which melting<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> point is 100 °C to 160 °C, which do not melt during the extrusion molding (around 100 °C) but melts in the vulcanization furnace (200 °C to 250 °C).</p><p id="p0053" num="0053">The opening seal 10 for automobiles is made of rubber material including EPDM but may also be made of other rubber materials. Also, a sealing surface side of the hollow seal member 12 is made of sponge material (e.g. EPDM sponge) whereas other parts of the of the hollow seal member 12 are made of solid material (e.g. EPDM solid) but the materials are not especially limited.</p><p id="p0054" num="0054">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 4</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5</figref>, an example of method of preparing the opening seal 10 for automobiles shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> is explained.</p><p id="p0055" num="0055">In a wire carrier (w/c) providing process, a wire core 20 in a developed state as shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5 (a)</figref> is sent out from a wire carrier (w/c) providing apparatus 41. The wire body 21 of the wire core 20 is partially connected with four non-thermo-fusible yarns (221, 222, 223, 224) and five thermo-fusible yarns 23 in a longitudinal direction.</p><p id="p0056" num="0056">As mentioned above and shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5 (d)</figref>, the non-thermo-fusible yarns 221. are provided in advance, while the wire body 21 bent roughly in U-shape is embedded in the installation base member 11 (state of a resultant product), in the range 401 from the bending start position 21c forming the shoulder 21a on the outer-cabin side of the wire body 21 which is bent roughly in U-shape to a position 52 determined by offsetting a point 51 on the door internal circumference side of the inner-side base 12a of the hollow seal member 12 with respect to the wire body 21, avoiding the shoulder 21a on the outer-cabin side.</p><p id="p0057" num="0057">In addition, as mentioned above and shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5 (d)</figref>, the non-thermo-fusible yarns 222 are provided in advance, while the wire body 21 bent roughly in U-shape is embedded in the installation base member 11, in the range 501 from the bending start position 21e forming the shoulder 21b on the inner-cabin side of the wire body 21 which is bent roughly in U-shape to<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> the position 54 determined by offsetting the point 53 on the opening edge side on the inner-cabin side wall 11b of the base of the protuberance 13 with respect to the wire body 21, avoiding the shoulder 21b on the inner-cabin side.</p><p id="p0058" num="0058">In addition, as mentioned above and shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5 (d)</figref>, five thermo-fusible yarns 23 are provided in advance, while the wire body 21 bent roughly in U-shape is embedded in the installation base member 11. Specifically, two thermo-fusible yarns 23 are provided on the connecting wall 11c side of the installation base member11 except for shoulders 21a, 21b; two thermo-fusible yarns 23 are provided on the outer-cabin side wall 11a of the installation base member 11, that is the opening edge side of the outer-cabin side wall 11a compared with the providing point of the non-thermo-fusible yarn 221 on the outer-cabin side; and one thermo-fusible yarn 23 is provided on the inner-cabin side wall 11b of the installation base member 11, that is the opening edge side of the inner-cabin side wall 11b compared with the providing point of the non-thermo-fusible yarn 222 on the inner-cabin side.</p><p id="p0059" num="0059">In addition, as mentioned above and shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5 (d),</figref> the non-thermo-fusible yarns 223, 224 are provided in advance, while the wire body 21 bent roughly in U-shape is embedded in the installation base member 11, on the inner-cabin side wall 11b of the installation base member 11 that is the connecting wall 11c side compared with the providing point of the non-thermo-fusible yarn 222 on the inner-cabin side.</p><p id="p0060" num="0060">Next, in a pre-bent process, the wire core 20 in the developed state is bent into a dish shape in cross section by bending both edge sides thereof in a pre-bent apparatus 42 as shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5 (b)</figref>. Also, only one edge side (one of the two edge sides) of the wire core 20 may be bent, not both edge sides.</p><p id="p0061" num="0061">Next, in an extrusion process, an extruder 43 forms the installation base member 11 into a dish shape by further widening an opening of the installation base member 11 as shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5 (c)</figref> compared with the rough U-shape in cross section (the opening is widened by around 45 degrees<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> respectively to the left and right compared with the rough U-shape in cross section) along the shape of the wire core 20 that is pre-bent into the dish shape in cross section and embedded in the installation base member 11. Then, in the extrusion process, the extruder 43 extrudes the opening seal 10 for automobiles into a vulcanization furnace 44. In the extrusion process, the hollow seal member 12, the protuberance 13, the projections 14, the lip 15 and the coating material 16 are integrally extrusion molded with the installation base member 11.</p><p id="p0062" num="0062">The vulcanization furnace 44 has a taking-out unit 45 on an exit side thereof for guiding the wire core 20 extruded from the extruder 43 together with the opening seal 10 for automobiles to the vulcanization furnace 44 with strong force.</p><p id="p0063" num="0063">In the vulcanization process, the opening seal 10 for automobiles is heat treated at 200 °C to 250 °C inside the vulcanization furnace 44, which vulcanizes the rubber component and assures stable elasticity and strength. While the thermo-fusible yarn 23 vanishes when passing through the vulcanization furnace 44, four non- thermo-fusible yarns 221, 222, 223, 224 do not melt even after passing through the vulcanization furnace 44. Therefore, the opening seal 10 for automobiles is not expanded in the vulcanization process.</p><p id="p0064" num="0064">In a forming machine 46, the vulcanized opening seal 10 for automobiles passes through a sizing die for narrowing the opening of the installation base member 11 to be the rough U-shape in cross section as shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5(d)</figref>.</p><p id="p0065" num="0065">Finally, after cooling treatment or the like, resultant opening seal 10 for automobiles is prepared.</p><p id="p0066" num="0066">According to the above-structured opening seal 10 for automobiles, the installation base member 11 mounted on the flange 3 installed along the periphery of the door opening part of the body 1 has the wire core 20<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --> embedded therein, including the skeletal wire body 21 connected with the non-thermo-fusible yarns 22 (221, 222, 223, 224) which do not melt at the set vulcanization temperature. Accordingly, while vulcanizing and extrusion molding the opening seal 10 for automobiles, the non-thermo-fusible yarns 22 remain without melting. Such a structure controls unnecessary expansion of the opening seal 10 for automobiles together with the wire core 20 for the effect of the non-thermo-fusible yarns 22 even in case the wire core 20 is pulled with strong force while extrusion molding the opening seal 10 for automobiles in the course of preparation. Also, the structure improves assembly force of the opening seal 10 for automobiles on the flange 3 by improving the rigidity of the installation base member 11 after molding.</p><p id="p0067" num="0067">In addition, at least two non-thermo-fusible yarns 22 are provided respectively on the outer-cabin side and the inner-cabin side. The non-thermo-fusible yarn 221 on the outer-cabin side is provided in the range 401 from the bending start position 21c forming the shoulder 21a on the outer-cabin side of the wire body 21 which is bent roughly in U-shape to the position 52 determined by offsetting a point 51 on the door internal circumference side of the inner-side base 12a of the hollow seal member 12 with respect to the wire body 21. The non-thermo-fusible yarn 222 on the inner-cabin side is provided in the range 501 from the bending start position 21e forming the shoulder 21b on the inner-cabin side of the wire body 21 which is bent roughly in U-shape to the position 54 determined by offsetting a point 53 on the opening edge side on the inner-cabin side wall 11b of the base of the protuberance 13. Accordingly, the straight line which connects the position of the non-thermo-fusible yarn 222 on the inner-cabin side and the position of the non-thermo-fusible yarn 221 on the outer-cabin side leans toward the internal circumference side of the door 2 from the outer circumference side (toward the connecting wall 11c side from the opening part side of the installation base member 11) as faced toward the outer-cabin side<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --> from the inner-cabin side.</p><p id="p0068" num="0068">The leaned straight line as extended intersects the hollow seal member 12 on the position on the internal circumference side of the door 2 compared with the prior art (<figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 9</figref>) in which the leaned straight line as extended intersects hollow seal member 12 on the position on the outer circumference side (on the connecting wall 11c side from the opening part side of the installation base member 11). Accordingly, contracting force functions within the smaller domain of the hollow seal member 12 when the opening seal for automobiles is assembled on the corner part on the body side, thereby preventing generation of the folding wrinkles 202.</p><p id="p0069" num="0069">Further, by leaning the straight line which connects the position of the non-thermo-fusible yarn 221 on the outer-cabin side and the position of the non-thermo-fusible yarn 222 on the inner-cabin side, fastening force of the installation base member 11 on the flange 3 from the inner-cabin side wall 11b side is increased, which enables the protuberance 13 provided on the inner-cabin side wall 11b side to hold the flange 3 sufficiently.</p><p id="p0070" num="0070">Such a structure enables stable assembly of the opening seal 10 for automobiles on the corner part on the body side of the automobile and keeps the opening seal 10 for automobiles stably assembled even after the assembly.</p><p id="p0071" num="0071">By gradually limiting the range for providing the non-thermo-fusible yarn 222 on the inner-cabin side from the range 501 to 502, 503, the leaned straight line as extended, which connects the position of the non-thermo-fusible yarn 221 on the outer-cabin side and the position of the non-thermo-fusible yarn 222 on the inner-cabin side, intersects the hollow seal member 12 on the position further on the internal circumference side of the door 2, shifted from the outer circumference side (on the connecting wall 11c side shifted from the opening part side of the installation base member 11). Accordingly, the contracting force functions within the smaller domain of the hollow seal member 12 when the opening seal 10 for automobiles is<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> assembled on the corner part on the body side of the automobile, thereby preventing generation of folding wrinkles 202.</p><p id="p0072" num="0072">Also, the fastening force of the installation base member 11 on the flange 3 from the inner-cabin side wall 11b side is increased, which enables the protuberance 13 provided on the inner-cabin side wall 11b side to hold the flange 3 sufficiently.</p><p id="p0073" num="0073">In case the non-thermo-fusible yarn 222 on the inner-cabin side is provided on the position 57 within the range 503, on which the straight line 100 connecting the position of the end 56 on the door internal circumference side on the hollow side of the hollow seal member 12 and the providing point of the non-thermo-fusible yarn 221 on the outer-cabin side intersects the inner-cabin side of the wire body 21, the straight line which connects the position of the non-thermo-fusible yarn 221 on the outer-cabin side and the position of the non-thermo-fusible yarn 222 on the inner-cabin side, as extended, intersects the hollow seal member 12 on the position which is the end 56 on the door internal circumference side on the hollow side of the hollow seal member 12. Accordingly, the contracting force functions only on thickness of the hollow seal member 12 when the opening seal 10 for automobiles is assembled on the corner part on the body side of the automobile so that the folding wrinkles 202 hardly generates. In case the non-thermo-fusible yarn 222 on the inner-cabin side is shifted from the position 57 where the straight line 100 intersects the inner-cabin side of the wire body 21 to the position 54 determined by offsetting the point 53 on the opening edge side on the inner-cabin side wall 11b of the base of the protuberance 13 with respect to the wire body 21, the straight line which connects the position of the non-thermo-fusible yarn 221 on the outer-cabin side and the position of the non-thermo-fusible yarn 222 on the inner-cabin side, as extended, intersects the hollow seal member 12 on the position, that is further on the door internal circumference side compared with the end 56 on<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --> the door internal circumference side. Accordingly, generation of the folding wrinkles is further prevented.</p><p id="p0074" num="0074">In the present embodiment, the base 12a of the hollow seal member 12, which extends from an inner side position of the outer-cabin side wall 11a of the installation base member 11, is laid toward the internal circumference side of the door 2 compared with the base 12b of the hollow seal member 12, which extends from an outer side position of the outer-cabin side wall 11a. But, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 6</figref>, the inner-side base 12a of the hollow seal member 12 may project from the outer-cabin side wall 11a of the installation base member 11 at the same angle as the base 12b on the outer side, thereby extending in a rough V-shape in cross section.</p><p id="p0075" num="0075">In the present embodiment, the non-thermo-fusible yarn 222 on the inner-cabin side is provided in the range 503 from the position 57 where the straight line 100 connecting the end 56 on the door internal circumference side (door internal circumference side end part) on the hollow side of the hollow seal member 12 and the providing point of the non-thermo-fusible yarn 221 on the outer-cabin side intersects the inner-cabin side of the wire body 21 to the position 54 determined by offsetting the point 53 on the opening edge side on the inner-cabin side wall 11b of the base of the protuberance 13 with respect to the wire body 21. But the range 503 may be limited by narrowing. Specifically, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 6</figref>, non-thermo-fusible yarn 222 on the inner-cabin side may be provided in the range 504 from the position 59 where the straight line 300 connecting the end 58 on the door internal circumference side (door internal circumference side end part) of the hollow seal member 12 and the providing point of the non-thermo-fusible yarn 221 on the outer-cabin side intersects the inner-cabin side of the wire body 21 to the position 54 determined by offsetting the point 53 on the opening edge side on the inner-cabin side wall 11b of the base of the protuberance 13 with respect to the wire body 21.<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --></p><p id="p0076" num="0076">According to the structure, the straight line which connects the position of the non-thermo-fusible yarn 221 on the outer-cabin side and the position of the non-thermo-fusible yarn 222 on the inner-cabin side, as extended, intersects the hollow seal member 12 on the position which is the end on the door internal circumference side of the hollow seal member 12 or further door internal circumference side. Accordingly, the contracting force does not function on the hollow seal member 12 when the opening seal 10 for automobiles is assembled on the corner part on the body side of the automobile.</p><p id="p0077" num="0077">In the present embodiment, one protuberance 13 is provided inside the inner-cabin side wall 11b of the installation base member 11. But, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 7</figref>, a plurality of the protuberances 13, 17 (two protuberances in <figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 7</figref>) may be provided. In this case, a limitation point for providing the non-thermo-fusible yarn 222 on the inner-cabin side on the opening edge side of the inner-cabin side wall 11b is the position 54 determined by offsetting the point 53, on the opening edge side on the inner-cabin side wall 11b of the base of the protuberance 13 as a benchmark among the plurality of the protuberances 13, 17 positioned on the greater opening edge part side on the inner-cabin side wall 11b of the installation base member 11, with respect to the wire body 21.</p><p id="p0078" num="0078">Also, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 7</figref>, the shoulder 21a on the outer-cabin side of the installation base member 11 is provided with coating material 31 having higher specific gravity (e.g. specific gravity of 0.9 to 1.3) compared with material forming the installation base member 11 over a wider range compared with the coating material 16. Accordingly, the opening seal 10 for automobiles is stably assembled on the on the corner part of a periphery of the door 2 opening part of the body 1 and wrinkles do not generate on the part provided with the coating material 31. The non-thermo-fusible yarn 221 on the inner-cabin side may be changed to the thermo-fusible yarn depending on<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --> strength of the material forming the part.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56983622" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Dichtung (10) für eine Öffnung eines Kraftfahrzeugs, umfassend: ein Einbaubasisteil (11) mit einem grob U-förmigen Querschnitt, das auf einem Flansch (3) befestigt werden kann, der entlang eines Umfangs einer Türöffnung (2) angebracht ist, die einen Teil einer Fahrzeugkarosserie (1) bildet, wobei das Basisteil eine außerhalb der Kabine befindliche Seitenwand (11a), eine innerhalb der Kabine befindliche Seitenwand (11b) und eine Verbindungswand (11c) aufweist, die die beiden Seitenwände (11a, 11b) miteinander verbindet;<br/>
ein hohles Dichtungsteil (12), das sich von einer innenseitigen Position (301) und einer außenseitigen Position (800) der genannten außerhalb der Kabine befindlichen Seitenwand (11a) des Einbaubasisteils (11) erstreckt, jeweils in Richtung einer inneren Umfangsseite (305) und einer äußeren Umfangsseite (304) einer Tür (2), das in Richtung einer außerhalb der Kabine befindlichen Seite (206) gewölbt und gekrümmt ist, um einen elastischen Kontakt mit der genannten Tür (2) herzustellen, wodurch eine Innenseite gegenüber einer Außenseite des Kraftfahrzeugs abgedichtet wird;<br/>
einen oder eine Anzahl von Vorsprüngen (13), die auf der Innenseite der innerhalb der Kabine befindlichen Seitenwand (11b) des genannten Einbaubasisteils (11) angeordnet sind, um einen elastischen Kontakt mit dem Flansch (3) herzustellen und diesen zu halten; und<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="35"> -->einen Drahtkern (20), der in einer Längsrichtung des genannten Einbaubasisteils (11) eingebettet ist, wobei dieser grob U-förmig gebogen ist und umfasst: einen skelettartigen Drahtkörper (21), der durch kontinuierliches Biegen eines Drahts gebildet ist; und einen nicht thermisch schmelzbaren Faden, der bei einer vorgegebenen Vulkanisierungstemperatur nicht schmilzt, der teilweise mit dem Drahtkörper (21) verbunden ist und sich grob linear in einer Längsrichtung erstreckt, während er eine Aufweitung des Drahtkörpers (21) in einer Längsrichtung kontrolliert; <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b><br/>
der genannte Drahtkern (20) zumindest zwei nicht thermisch schmelzbare Fäden (22) aufweist, die auf der außerhalb der Kabine befindlichen Seite (306) und auf der innerhalb der Kabine befindlichen Seite (307) davon angeordnet sind;<br/>
wobei der nicht thermisch schmelzbare Faden (221) auf der außerhalb der Kabine befindlichen Seite in einem Bereich (401) vorgesehen ist, der von einer Biegungsstartposition (21c) unter Ausbildung einer Schulter (21a) auf der außerhalb der Kabine befindlichen Seite des Drahtkörpers (21), der grob U-förmig gebogen ist, bis zu einer Position (52) reicht, die durch Verlagern eines Punkts (51) auf der inneren Umfangsseite (305) der Tür einer innenseitigen Basis (12a) des genannten hohlen Dichtungsteils (12) in Bezug auf den Drahtkörper (21) bestimmt ist; und<br/>
der nicht thermisch schmelzbare Faden (222) auf der innerhalb der Kabine befindlichen Seite in einem Bereich (501) vorgesehen ist, der von einer Biegestartposition (21e) unter Bildung einer Schulter (21b) auf der innerhalb der Kabine befindlichen Seite des Drahtkörpers (21), der grob U-förmig gebogen ist, bis zu einer Position (54) reicht, die durch Verlagern eines Punkts (53) auf einer Öffnungsrandseite (308) auf der innerhalb der Kabine befindlichen Seitenwand (11b) einer Basis des Vorsprungs (13), der auf einer größeren Öffnungsrandteilseite (309) der innerhalb der Kabine befindlichen Seitenwand (11b) des genannten<!-- EPO <DP n="36"> --> Einbaubasisteils (11) inmitten des oder einer Vielzahl von Vorsprüngen (13) in Bezug auf den Drahtkörper (21) bestimmt ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Dichtung für eine Öffnung eines Kraftfahrzeugs nach Anspruch 1, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> der genannte nicht thermisch schmelzbare Faden (221) auf der außerhalb der Kabine befindlichen Seite (306) in einem Bereich (402) vorgesehen ist, der zwischen einer Biegungsendposition (21d) unter Bildung einer Schulter (21a) auf der außerhalb der Kabine befindlichen Seite des Drahtkörpers (21), der grob U-förmig gebogen ist, bis zu einer Position (52), die durch Verlagern eines Punkts (51) auf der inneren Umfangsseite (305) der Tür einer innenseitigen Basis (12a) des genannten hohlen Dichtungsteils (12) in Bezug auf den Drahtkörper (21) bestimmt ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Dichtung für eine Öffnung eines Kraftfahrzeugs nach Anspruch 1 oder 2, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> der nicht thermisch schmelzbare Faden (222) auf der innerhalb der Kabine befindlichen Seite (307) in einem Bereich (502) vorgesehen ist, von einer Position (55) auf der innerhalb der Kabine befindlichen Seite, bestimmt durch Verlagern eines vorgesehenen Punkts des genannten nicht thermisch schmelzbaren Fadens (221) auf der außerhalb der Kabine befindlichen Seite (306) in Bezug auf den Drahtkörper (21) bis zu einer Position (54), bestimmt durch Verlagern eines Punkts (53) auf einer Öffnungskantenseite der genannten innerhalb der Kabine befindlichen Seitenwand (11b) einer Basis des Vorsprungs (13), der auf der größeren Öffnungsrandteilseite auf der innerhalb der Kabine befindlichen Seitenwand (11b) des genannten Einbaubasisteils (11) inmitten des oder der Anzahl von Vorsprüngen (13) positioniert ist, in Bezug auf den Drahtkörper (21).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Dichtung für eine Öffnung eines Kraftfahrzeugs nach Anspruch 2, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> der genannte nicht thermisch schmelzbare Faden (222) auf der innerhalb der Kabine befindlichen Seite in einem Bereich (503) vorgesehen ist, von einer Position (57), an der eine gerade Linie (100) einen Punkt (56) auf der inneren<!-- EPO <DP n="37"> --> Umfangsseite (305) der Tür auf einer inneren Seite der Wand des genannten hohlen Dichtungsteils (12) und einen vorgesehenen Punkt des nicht thermisch schmelzbaren Fadens (221) auf der außerhalb der Kabine befindlichen Seite die innerhalb der Kabine befindliche Seite des Drahtkörpers (21) schneidet, bis zu der Position (54), die bestimmt ist durch Verlagern des Punkts (53) auf der Öffnungsrandseite auf der innerhalb der Kabine befindlichen Seitenwand (11b) der Basis des Vorsprungs (13), der auf der größeren Öffnungsrandteilseite auf der innerhalb der Kabine befindlichen Seitenwand (11b) des Einbaubasisteils (11) inmitten des einen oder einer Anzahl von Vorsprüngen (13) positioniert ist, in Bezug auf den Drahtkörper (21).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Dichtung für eine Öffnung eines Kraftfahrzeugs nach Anspruch 2, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> der nicht thermisch schmelzbare Faden (222) auf der innerhalb der Kabine befindlichen Seite in einem Bereich (504) vorgesehen ist, von einer Position, an der eine gerade Linie (300) einen Punkt (58) auf der inneren Umfangsseite (305) der Tür einer äußeren Seite der Wand des genannten hohlen Dichtungsteils (12) und einen vorgesehenen Punkt des genannten nicht thermisch schmelzbaren Fadens (221) auf der außerhalb der Kabine befindlichen Seite verbindet, die innerhalb der Kabine befindliche Seite des Drahtkörpers (21) schneidet, bis zu der Position (54), bestimmt durch Verlagern des Punkts (53) auf der Öffnungsrandseite auf der genannten innerhalb der Kabine befindlichen Seitenwand (11b) der Basis des Vorsprungs (13), der auf der größeren Öffnungsrandteilseite auf der innerhalb der Kabine befindlichen Seitenwand (11b) des genannten Einbaubasisteils (11) inmitten des oder einer Anzahl von Vorsprüngen (13) positioniert ist, in Bezug auf den Drahtkörper (21).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Dichtung für eine Öffnung eines Kraftfahrzeugs nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 5, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die Schulter (21a) auf der außerhalb der Kabine befindlichen Seite des genannten Einbaubasisteils (11) mit einem Beschichtungsmaterial (31) versehen ist, das ein höheres spezifisches Gewicht im Vergleich zu einem Material aufweist, das das genannte Einbaubasisteil (11) bildet.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56983623" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>An opening seal (10) for automobiles comprising: an installation base member (11) with a roughly U-shaped cross section, mountable on a flange (3) installed along a periphery of a door (2) opening which is part of a vehicle body (1), the base member including an outer-cabin side wall (11a), an innercabin side wall (11b) and a connecting wall (11c) connecting the side walls (11a, 11b);<br/>
a hollow seal member (12) extending from an inner side position (301) and an outer side position (800) of said outer-cabin side wall (11a) of the installation base member (11) respectively toward an internal circumference side (305) and an outer circumference side (304) of a door (2), which is swelled and curved toward an outer-cabin side (306) for making elastic contact with said door (2) thereby sealing an inside and an outside of the automobile;<br/>
one or a plurality of protuberances (13) installed inside the inner-cabin side wall (11b) of said installation base member (11) for making elastic contact with and holding said flange (3); and<br/>
a wire core (20) embedded in a longitudinal direction of said installation base member (11) while being bent roughly in U-shape, including: a skeletal wire body (21) formed by continuously bending a wire; and non-thermo-fusible yam which does not melt at set vulcanization temperature, which is partially connected with the wire body (21) and is roughly linearly extending in a longitudinal direction while controlling expansion of the wire body (21) in a longitudinal direction; [wherein] <u><b>characterized in that</b></u><!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --> said wire core (20) has at least two non-thermo-fusible yarns (22) respectively provided on the outer-cabin side (306) and the inner-cabin side (307) thereof;<br/>
the non-thermo-fusible yarn (221) on the outer-cabin side is provided in a range (401) from a bending start position (21 c) forming a shoulder (21a) on the outer-cabin side of the wire body (21) which is bent roughly in U-shape to a position (52) determined by offsetting a point (51) on the door internal circumference side (305) of an inner-side base (12a) of said hollow seal member (12) with respect to the wire body (21); and<br/>
the non-thermo-fusible yarn (222) on the inner-cabin side is provided in a range (501) from a bending start position (21e) forming a shoulder (21b) on the inner-cabin side of the wire body (21) which is bent roughly in U-shape to a position (54) determined by offsetting a point (53) on an opening edge side (308) on said inner-cabin side wall (11b) of a base of the protuberance (13) which is positioned on a greater opening edge part side (309) on the inner-cabin side wall (11b) of said installation base member (11) among said one or a plurality of protuberances (13) with respect to the wire body (21).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The opening seal for automobiles as claimed in Claim 1, wherein: said non-thermo-fusible yam (221) on the outer-cabin side (306) is provided in a range (402) from a bending end position (21d) forming a shoulder (21a) on the outer-cabin side of the wire body (21) which is bent roughly in U-shape to a position (52) determined by offsetting a point (51) on the door internal circumference side (305) of an inner-side base (12a) of said hollow seal member (12) with respect to the wire body (21).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The opening seal for automobiles as claimed in Claim 1 or 2, wherein: said non-thermo-fusible yarn (222) on the inner-cabin side (307) is provided in a range (502) from a position (55) on the inner-cabin side determined by offsetting a provided point of said non-thermo-fusible yam<!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --> (221) on the outer-cabin side (306) with respect to the wire body (21) to a position (54) determined by offsetting a point (53) on an opening edge side on said inner-cabin side wall (11b) of a base of the protuberance (13) which is positioned on the greater opening edge part side on the inner-cabin side wall (11b) of said installation base member (11) among said one or a plurality of protuberances (13) with respect to the wire body (21).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The opening seal for automobiles as claimed in Claim 2, wherein: said non-thermo-fusible yam (222) on the inner-cabin side is provided in a range (503) from a position (57) where a straight line (100) connecting a point (56) on the door internal circumference side (305) on an internal side of the wall of said hollow seal member (12) and a provided point of said nonthermo-fusible yam (221) on the outer-cabin side intersects the inner-cabin side of the wire body (21) to the position (54) determined by offsetting the point (53) on the opening edge side on said inner-cabin side wall (11b) of the base of the protuberance (13) which is positioned on the greater opening edge part side on the inner-cabin side wall (11b) of said installation base member (11) among said one or a plurality of protuberances (13) with respect to the wire body (21).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The opening seal for automobiles as claimed in Claim 2, wherein: said non-thermo-fusible yam (222) on the inner-cabin side is provided in a range (504) from a position where a straight line (300) connecting a point (58) on the door internal circumference side (305) of an outer side of the wall of said hollow seal member (12) and a provided point of said non-thermo-fusible yam (221) on the outer-cabin side intersects the inner-cabin side of the wire body (21) to the position (54) determined by offsetting the point (53) on the opening edge side on said inner-cabin side wall (11b) of the base of the protuberance (13) which is positioned on the greater opening edge part side on the inner-cabin side wall (11b) of said installation base member (11) among said one or a plurality of protuberances (13) with respect to the wire body (21).<!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The opening seal for automobiles as claimed in any one of Claims 1 to 5, wherein: the shoulder (21a) on the outer-cabin side of said installation base member (11) is provided with coating material (31) having higher specific gravity compared with material forming said installation base member (11).</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56983624" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="38"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Joint d'étanchéité d'ouverture (10) pour des automobiles, comprenant : un élément de base d'installation (11) ayant une section transversale approximativement en forme de U pouvant être montée sur une bride (3) installée le long d'une périphérie d'une partie d'ouverture de porte (2) qui fait partie d'une carrosserie de véhicule (1), l'élément de base comportant une paroi latérale (11a) de cabine extérieure, une paroi latérale (11b) de cabine intérieure et une paroi de raccordement (11c) reliant les parois latérales (11a, 11b) ;<br/>
un élément creux (12) de joint d'étanchéité s'étendant à partir d'une position latérale intérieure (301) et une position latérale extérieure (300) de ladite paroi latérale (11a) de cabine extérieure de l'élément de base d'installation (11) respectivement vers un côté (305) de circonférence intérieur et un côté de circonférence extérieur (304) d'une porte (2), qui est gonflé et courbé vers un côté de cabine extérieure (306) pour établir un contact élastique avec ladite porte (2) ce qui permet d'assurer l'étanchéité de parties intérieure et extérieure de l'automobile ;<br/>
une ou plusieurs protubérance(s) (13) installée(s) à l'intérieur de la paroi latérale (11b) de cabine intérieure dudit élément de base d'installation (11) pour établir un contact élastique avec ladite bride (3) et maintenir celle-ci ; et<br/>
un âme de fil (20) intégré dans une direction longitudinale dudit élément de base d'installation (11) tout en étant plié approximativement en forme de U, comportant : un corps de fil squelettique (21) formé par un pliage continu d'un fil ; et un fil non thermo-fusible qui ne fond pas à une température de vulcanisation réglée, qui est partiellement raccordé au corps de fil (21) et s'étend approximativement de manière linéaire dans une direction longitudinale tout en commandant l'expansion du corps de<!-- EPO <DP n="39"> --> fil (21) dans une direction longitudinale ; <b>caractérisé en ce que</b><br/>
ledit âme de fil (20) a au moins deux fils non thermofusibles (22) prévus respectivement sur son côté de cabine extérieure (306) et son côté de cabine intérieure (307) ;<br/>
le fil non thermo-fusible (221) sur le côté de cabine extérieure est prévu dans une étendue (401) allant d'une position de début de pliage (21c) formant un épaulement (21a) sur le côté de cabine extérieure du corps de fil (21) qui est plié approximativement en forme de U jusqu'à une position (52) déterminée en décalant un point (51) sur le côté (305) de circonférence intérieur de porte d'une base de côté intérieur (12a) dudit élément creux (12) de joint d'étanchéité par rapport au corps de fil (21) ; et<br/>
le fil non thermo-fusible (222) sur le côté de cabine intérieure est prévu dans une étendue (501) allant d'une position de début de pliage (21e) formant un épaulement (21b) sur le côté de cabine intérieure du corps de fil (21) qui est plié approximativement en forme de U jusqu'à une position (54) déterminée en décalant un point (53) sur un côté de bord d'ouverture (308) sur ladite paroi latérale (11b) de cabine intérieure d'une base de la protubérance (13) qui est positionnée sur un côté (309) de partie de bord d'ouverture plus importante sur la paroi latérale (11b) de cabine intérieure dudit élément de base d'installation (11) parmi ladite/lesdites une ou plusieurs protubérance(s) (13) par rapport au corps de fil (21).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Joint d'étanchéité d'ouverture pour des automobiles tel que revendiqué dans la revendication 1, dans lequel : ledit fil non thermo-fusible (221) sur le côté de cabine extérieure (306) est prévu dans une étendue (402) allant d'une position de fin de pliage (21d) formant un épaulement (21a) sur le côté de cabine extérieure du corps de fil (21) qui est plié approximativement en forme de U jusqu'à une position (52) déterminée en décalant un point (51) sur le côté (305) de circonférence intérieur de porte d'une base<!-- EPO <DP n="40"> --> de côté intérieur (12a) dudit élément creux (12) de joint d'étanchéité par rapport au corps de fil (21).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Joint d'étanchéité d'ouverture pour des automobiles tel que revendiqué dans la revendication 1 ou 2, dans lequel : ledit fil non thermo-fusible (222) sur le côté de cabine intérieure (307) est prévu dans une étendue (502) allant d'une position (55) sur le côté de cabine intérieure déterminée en décalant un point prévu dudit fil non thermo-fusible (221) sur le côté de cabine extérieure (306) par rapport au corps de fil (21) jusqu'à une position (54) déterminée en décalant un point (53) sur un côté de bord d'ouverture sur ladite paroi latérale (11b) de cabine intérieure d'une base de la protubérance (13) qui est positionnée sur un côté de partie de bord d'ouverture plus importante sur la paroi latérale (11b) de cabine intérieure dudit élément de base d'installation (11) parmi ladite/lesdites une ou plusieurs protubérance(s) (13) par rapport au corps de fil (21).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Joint d'étanchéité d'ouverture pour des automobiles tel que revendiqué dans la revendication 2, dans lequel : ledit fil non thermo-fusible (222) sur le côté de cabine intérieure est prévu dans une étendue (503) allant d'une position (57) où une ligne droite (100) reliant un point (56) sur le côté (305) de circonférence intérieur de porte sur un côté intérieur de la paroi dudit élément creux (12) de joint d'étanchéité et un point prévu dudit fil non thermo-fusible (221) sur le côté de cabine extérieure coupe le côté de cabine intérieure du corps de fil (21) jusqu'à la position (54) déterminée en décalant le point (53) sur le côté de bord d'ouverture sur ladite paroi latérale (11b) de cabine intérieure de la base de la protubérance (13) qui est positionnée sur le côté de partie de bord d'ouverture plus importante sur la paroi latérale (11b) de cabine intérieure dudit élément de base d'installation (11) parmi ladite/lesdites une ou plusieurs protubérance(s) (13) par rapport au corps de fil (21).<!-- EPO <DP n="41"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Joint d'étanchéité d'ouverture pour des automobiles tel que revendiqué dans la revendication 2, dans lequel : ledit fil non thermo-fusible (222) sur le côté de cabine intérieure est prévu dans une étendue (504) allant d'une position où une ligne droite (300) reliant un point (58) sur le côté (305) de circonférence intérieur de porte d'un côté extérieur de la paroi dudit élément creux (12) de joint d'étanchéité et un point prévu dudit fil non thermo-fusible (221) sur le côté de cabine extérieure coupe le côté de cabine intérieure du corps de fil (21) jusqu'à la position (54) déterminée en décalant le point (53) sur le côté de bord d'ouverture sur ladite paroi latérale (11b) de cabine intérieure de la base de la protubérance (13) qui est positionnée sur le côté de partie de bord d'ouverture plus importante sur la paroi latérale (11b) de cabine intérieure dudit élément de base d'installation (11) parmi ladite/lesdites une ou plusieurs protubérance(s) (13) par rapport au corps de fil (21).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Joint d'étanchéité d'ouverture pour des automobiles tel que revendiqué dans l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 5, dans lequel : l'épaulement (21a) sur le côté de cabine extérieure dudit élément de base d'installation (11) est pourvu d'un matériau de revêtement (31) ayant un poids spécifique supérieur à celui d'un matériau formant ledit élément de base d'installation (11).</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16671604" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="42"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="165" he="177" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="43"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2(a),2(b)"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="139" he="175" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="44"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3,4"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="165" he="228" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="45"> --><figure id="f0004" num="5(a),5(b),5(c),5(d)"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="165" he="177" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="46"> --><figure id="f0005" num="6"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="154" he="164" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="47"> --><figure id="f0006" num="7,8"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="162" he="225" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="48"> --><figure id="f0007" num="9,10(a),10(b)"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="165" he="218" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="49"> --><figure id="f0008" num="11(a),11(b)"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="148" he="100" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
