<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2175667-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2175667" kind="B1" date="20140101" family-id="40685259" file-reference-id="299958" date-produced="20180822" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146553984" ucid="EP-2175667-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2175667</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-08290959-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154827907" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>08290959</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20081010</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140445257" ucid="EP-08290959-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>08290959</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20081010</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130724</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988110008" load-source="ipcr">H04M  11/06        20060101ALI20090612BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988126432" load-source="ipcr">H04Q  11/04        20060101AFI20090612BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988105371" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04Q2213/13302     20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988108596" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04M  11/068       20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988120059" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04M  11/062       20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988123346" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04Q2213/13306     20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988124404" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04Q2213/13034     20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988125368" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04Q2213/13216     20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988128123" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04Q2213/1332      20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988132192" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04Q2213/13209     20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988134974" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04Q2213/13039     20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988137700" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04Q  11/04        20130101 FI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988138339" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04Q2213/1319      20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132194436" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Universal-ISDN/POTS-Splitter</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132194437" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Universal ISDN/POTS splitter</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132194438" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Séparateur ISDN/POTS universel</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918133413" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>ALCATEL LUCENT</last-name><address><country>FR</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918166167" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>ALCATEL LUCENT</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918156752" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>OP DE BEECK EDMOND CELINA JOZEF</last-name><address><country>BE</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918170726" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>OP DE BEECK, EDMOND CELINA JOZEF</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918998590" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>OP DE BEECK, EDMOND CELINA JOZEF</last-name><address><street>Ruimtevaartstraat 28</street><city>2800 Mechelen</city><country>BE</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918998592" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Alcatel Lucent</last-name><iid>101190217</iid><address><street>3, Avenue Octave Gréard</street><city>75007 Paris</city><country>FR</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918998591" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Narmon, Gisèle Marie Thérèse</last-name><iid>100973522</iid><address><street>Alcatel-Lucent Bell NV Copernicuslaan 50</street><city>2018 Antwerpen</city><country>BE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548985222" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS548831119" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS548991529" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS548870907" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS548989710" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS548989711" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS548886370" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548831120" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS548831121" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS548982186" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS548991530" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS548991531" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548886371" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548831122" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS548886372" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS548989712" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS548870908" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS548831123" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS548991532" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS548831124" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS548886373" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS548985223" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS548991601" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS548886374" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS548985224" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS548982187" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS548982846" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS548982188" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS548985225" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS548870909" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS548982189" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS548989713" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS548982847" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS548991602" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63957555" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to a splitter for an ISDN/POTS telecommunication system, said splitter having first and second line terminals and first and second POTS/ISDN terminals, and comprising the cascade connection of a LC filter cell and a plurality of cascade connected elliptical filter cells, said LC filter cell comprising a first symmetrical coil having a first winding with a first terminal connected to said first line terminal and with a second terminal coupled to said first POTS/ISDN terminal via said plurality of elliptical filter cells, and having a second winding with a first terminal connected to said second line terminal and with a second terminal coupled to said second POTS/ISDN terminal via said plurality of elliptical filter cells, said LC filter cell further comprising a first capacitor coupled between the second terminal of the first winding of said first symmetrical coil and the second terminal of the second winding of said first symmetrical coil, each elliptical filter cell of said plurality comprising a second symmetrical coil having a first winding with a first terminal coupled to the second terminal of the first winding of said LC filter cell and with a second terminal coupled to said first POTS/ISDN terminal and having a second winding with a first terminal coupled to the second terminal of the second winding of said LC filter cell and with a second terminal coupled to said second POTS/ISDN terminal, each elliptical filter cell further comprising a second capacitor coupled between the second terminal of the first winding of the second symmetrical coil of said elliptical filter cell and the second terminal of the second winding of said second symmetrical coil, a third capacitor connected across the first winding of said second symmetrical coil and a fourth capacitor connected across the second winding of said second symmetrical coil.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002">Today's ISDN and Universal ISDN/POTS splitter circuits for xDSL are generally known in the art. These known splitters are based on 9<sup>th</sup> order low pass filters, consisting of 4 coils and the related high voltage capacitors (typically 10 capacitors) as shown at <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">This amount of large coils and capacitors per DSL line limits the integration of the number of splitter circuits per board (e.g. 72 ports per splitter<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> board) and prevent the integration of a high number of DSL line terminations and splitter lines on a single board. As the number of coils and capacitors is high, not only the required space but also the cost of the known 9<sup>th</sup> order ISDN splitter is relatively high.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">Moreover, the known Universal ISDN/POTS splitter low pass filters have to be standard compliant (ETSI TS 101 952-1-4). In most cases, two different filters with a same topology but different component values are required to cover the 2 ISDN standards: 2B1Q and 4B3T.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">An object of the present invention is to provide a splitter of the above known type but whereof the size and the cost are dramatically reduced while the splitter characteristics remain compliant to the ETSI standard ETSI TS 101 952-1-4, for 2B1Q and 4B3T ISDN standards.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">According to the invention, this object is achieved due to the fact that said splitter comprises at least one RL circuit constituted by the parallel coupling of a resistor and a coil and connected in series with the second capacitor of an elliptical filter cell of said plurality of elliptical cells.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">In this way, a 7<sup>th</sup> order ISDN or Universal ISDN/POTS splitter low pass filter is provided for replacing the known 9<sup>th</sup> order low pass filter. By eliminating 1 elliptical cell compared to the 9<sup>th</sup> order splitter low pass filter, and by adding at least one RL circuit associated to another elliptical filter cell, a size reduction of 25% and a significant cost reduction is achieved.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">This 7<sup>th</sup> order filter is full ETSI standard compliant (ETSI TS 101 952-1-4) for both 2B1Q and 4B3T ISDN standards. The present splitter further shows comparable dynamic performance compared to the 9<sup>th</sup> order splitter (transient rejection, noise impact on DSL signals, noise impact on ISDN signals).</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">It can further be proved that, with the present splitter, the xDSL stop-band attenuation characteristic, the ISDN pass-band return loss and insertion characteristic, both with and without ADSL impedance (Zadsl), and the POTS pass-band return loss and insertion loss characteristics for different impedances and conditions are similar to those of the known splitter.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p><p id="p0010" num="0010">It is to be noted that the European Patent Application <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="EP1783996A"><text>EP-A-1 783 996</text></patcit> of ALCATEL LUCENT [FR] entitled "Advanced ADSL splitter" discloses a telecommunication filter arrangement comprising two similar filter cells coupled in cascade to provide a POTS / ADSL splitter. The filter arrangement further comprises at third filter cell coupled in-between the two other filter cells and comprising a cell capacitor series coupled with the parallel connection of a cell coil and a cell resistor. A 3<sup>rd</sup> order filter is so provided and the filter arrangement behaves as known 5<sup>th</sup> order filter but with a fixed "switchable insertion loss circuit".</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">However, this known document do not disclose a 7<sup>th</sup> order ISDN or Universal ISDN/POTS splitter low pass filter provided for replacing the known 9<sup>th</sup> order low pass filter. The known document further also do not disclose nor teach the characteristic features of the present invention.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">Another characterizing embodiment of the present invention is that said splitter comprises another RL circuit constituted by the parallel coupling of a second resistor and a second coil and connected in series with the first capacitor of said LC filter cell between the second terminal of the first winding of said first symmetrical coil of said LC filter and the second terminal of the second winding of said first symmetrical coil of said LC filter.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">By providing a RL circuit in the LC filter cell in addition to the one or more RL circuits associated to the elliptical filter cells, the performances of the splitter are increased.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">In a preferred characterizing embodiment of the present invention, said splitter comprises the cascade connection of said LC filter cell, a first elliptical filter cell comprising a first second capacitor and a second elliptical filter cell comprising a second second capacitor and the second second capacitor of said second elliptical filter cell is connected in series with a second RL circuit constituted by the parallel coupling of a second resistor and a second coil between the second terminal of the first winding of the second symmetrical coil of said second elliptical filter cell and the second terminal of the second winding of the second symmetrical coil of said second elliptical filter cell.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p><p id="p0015" num="0015">This arrangement constitutes the optimal splitter with respect to size, cost and standard compliance.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">Further characterizing embodiments of the present a splitter for an ISDN/POTS telecommunication system are mentioned in the appended claims.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">It is to be noticed that the term 'comprising', used in the claims, should not be interpreted as being restricted to the means listed thereafter. Thus, the scope of the expression 'a device comprising means A and B' should not be limited to devices consisting only of components A and B. It means that with respect to the present invention, the only relevant components of the device are A and B.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">Similarly, it is to be noticed that the term 'coupled', also used in the claims, should not be interpreted as being restricted to direct connections only. Thus, the scope of the expression 'a device A coupled to a device B' should not be limited to devices or systems wherein an output of device A is directly connected to an input of device B. It means that there exists a path between an output of A and an input of B which may be a path including other devices or means.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">The above and other objects and features of the invention will become more apparent and the invention itself will be best understood by referring to the following description of an embodiment taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings wherein:
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> shows a splitter for an ISDN/POTS telecommunication system as known from the prior art;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> shows a splitter according to the invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> shows a variant of the splitter of <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>; and</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4</figref> shows a comparison between the space occupied by a prior art splitter with respect to the space occupied by the splitter of the present invention on a board.</li></ul></p><p id="p0020" num="0020">A splitter for an ISDN/POTS telecommunication system or more particularly the 9<sup>th</sup> order low pass filter thereof as known from the prior art is shown at <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>. This splitter has filter stages located between line terminals and<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> POTS/ISDN terminals. An additional Common Mode Coil and protector for overvoltages may also be provided but are not shown at <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">In more detail, the known splitter has a first line terminal Line+, a second line terminal Line-, a first POTS/ISDN terminal POTS/ISDN+ and a second POTS/ISDN terminal POTS/ISDN-. Between these line and POTS/ISDN terminals, the splitter comprises the cascade connection of a LC filter stage or cell L11a, L11b, C11 and three elliptical filter stages L12a, L12b, C12, C15, C16; L13a, L13b, C13, C17, C18; L14a, L14b, C14, C19, C1A, R11, R12.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">The LC filter cell comprises a first symmetrical coil L11 constituted by the windings L11a and L11b. The first winding L11a has a first terminal connected to the first line terminal Line+ and a second terminal coupled to the first POTS/ISDN terminal POTS/ISDN+ through the elliptical filter stages, whilst the second winding L11b has a first terminal connected to the second line terminal Line- and a second terminal coupled to the second POTS/ISDN terminal POTS/ISDN- through the elliptical filter stages. The LC filter cell further comprises a first capacitor C11 coupled between the second terminal of its first winding L11a and the second terminal of its second winding L11b.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">Each elliptical filter stage comprises a cell with a second symmetrical coil L12/ L13/ L14 respectively constituted by the windings L12a and L12b/ L13a and L13b/ L14a and L14b. The first winding L12a/ L13a/ L14a has a first terminal coupled to the second terminal of the first winding L11a of the above LC filter cell and a second terminal coupled to the first POTS/ISDN terminal POTS/ISDN+, whilst the second winding L12b/ L13b/ L14b has a first terminal coupled to the second terminal of the second winding L11b of the LC filter cell and a second terminal coupled to the second POTS/ISDN terminal POTS/ISDN-.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">In more detail, the first terminal of the first winding L12a of the first elliptical filter stage is connected to the second terminal of the first winding L11a of the LC filter cell and the first terminal of the second winding L12b of the first elliptical filter stage is connected to the second terminal of the second winding L11b of the LC filter cell.<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></p><p id="p0025" num="0025">The first terminal of the first winding L13a of the second elliptical filter stage is connected to the second terminal of the first winding L12a of the first elliptical filter stage and the first terminal of the second winding L13b of the second elliptical filter stage is connected to the second terminal of the second winding L12b of the first elliptical filter stage.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">The first terminal of the first winding L14a of the third elliptical filter stage is connected to the second terminal of the first winding L13a of the second elliptical filter stage and the first terminal of the second winding L14b of the third elliptical filter stage is connected to the second terminal of the second winding L13b of the second elliptical filter stage.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">Finally, the second terminal of the first winding L14a of the third elliptical filter stage is connected to the first POTS/ISDN terminal POTS/ISDN+, and the second terminal of the second winding L14b of the third elliptical filter stage is connected to the second POTS/ISDN terminal POTS/ISDN-.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">The 4 symmetrical coils L11 to L14, each with 2 windings (a and b) are typical RM4 or EP7 size coils.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">Each elliptical filter cell further comprises a second capacitor C12/ C13/ C14 coupled between the second terminal of the first winding L12a/L13a/ L14a of the second symmetrical coil and the second terminal of the second winding L12b/ L13b/ L14b of the second symmetrical coil, a third capacitor C15/ C17/ C19 connected across the respective first winding L12a/ L13a/ L14a of the second symmetrical coil and a fourth capacitor C16/ C18/C1A connected across the second winding L2b/ L3b/ L4b of the second symmetrical coil.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">Finally, in some cases, additional resistors are placed in series or in parallel with some of the capacitors for additional damping of the LC filter stages. For instance, the last elliptical filter cell L14, C19, C1A may have a resistor R11 connected in parallel across the third capacitor C19 and another resistor R12 connected in parallel across the fourth capacitor C1A.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">The main idea of the present invention is to reduce the area occupied by the splitter on a board by replacing the 9<sup>th</sup> order ISDN or Universal<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> ISDN/POTS splitter low pass filter, known from the prior art and shown at <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, by a 7<sup>th</sup> order low pass filter as shown at <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> or <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">In the splitter according to the invention and shown at <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>, this replacement is achieved by eliminating 1 elliptical filter stage, i.e. 1 symmetrical coil RM4 or EP7 type and 3 high voltage capacitors, and by adding 3 small, low cost SMD (Surface Mounted Devices) coils and resistors, as additional series resonance circuits.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">By carefully designing this 7<sup>th</sup> order filter and dimensioning the component values, the following is achieved:
<ul><li>full ETSI standard compliance of the 7<sup>th</sup> order filter (ETSI TS 101 952-1-4), for both 2B1Q and 4B3T ISDN standards, by 1 single filter implementation;</li><li>comparable dynamic performance compared to the 9<sup>th</sup> order splitter with respect to transient rejection, noise impact on DSL signals, noise impact on ISDN signals; and</li><li>smaller size (up to 25% smaller) and lower cost.</li></ul></p><p id="p0034" num="0034">A 7<sup>th</sup> order ISDN or Universal ISDN/POTS splitter low pass filter, consisting of 1 LC filter stage, 2 elliptical filter stages and 3 series resonance circuits is schematically represented at <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">Between the line terminals Line+ and Line- and the POTS/ISDN terminals POTS/ISDN+ and POTS/ISDN-, the 7<sup>th</sup> order splitter comprises the cascade connection of a LC filter stage L21a, L21b, C21, R21, L24, a first elliptical filter stage L22a, L22b, C24, C25, C22, R22, L25 and a second elliptical filter stage L23a, L23b, C26, C27, C23, R23, L26.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">In more detail, the line terminal Line+ is coupled to the POTS/ISDN terminal POTS/ISDN+ via the series connection of a first winding L21a of a first symmetrical coil L21 of the LC filter cell, a first winding L22a of a second symmetrical coil L22 of the first elliptical filter cell, and a first winding L23a of a third symmetrical coil L23 of the second elliptical filter cell.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">On the other hand, the line terminal Line- is coupled to the POTS/ISDN terminal POTS/ISDN- via the series connection of a second<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> winding L21b of the first symmetrical coil L21 of the LC filter cell, a second winding L22b of the second symmetrical coil L22 of the first elliptical filter cell, and a second winding L23b of the third symmetrical coil L23 of the second elliptical filter cell.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">The LC filter stage is completed by adding a first damped series resonance circuit to the LC filter cell. This first resonance circuit is constituted by a first capacitor C21 series connected with the parallel connection of a first resistor R21 and a first coil L24. The first resonance circuit is connected between the junction point of the first winding L21 a of the first symmetrical coil L21 of the LC filter cell with the first winding L22a of the second symmetrical coil L22 of the first elliptical filter cell and the junction point of the second winding L21b of the first symmetrical coil L21 of the LC filter cell with the second winding L22b of the second symmetrical coil L22 of the first elliptical filter cell.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">The first elliptical filter stage is completed by adding a second damped series resonance circuit to the first elliptical filter cell. This second resonance circuit is constituted by a second capacitor C22 series connected with the parallel connection of a second resistor R22 and a second coil L25. The second resonance circuit is connected between the junction point of the first winding L22a of the second symmetrical coil L22 of the first elliptical filter cell with the first winding L23a of the third symmetrical coil L23 of the second elliptical filter cell and the junction point of the second winding L22b of the second symmetrical coil L22 of the first elliptical filter cell with the second winding L23b of the third symmetrical coil L23 of the second elliptical filter cell.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">The second elliptical filter stage is completed by adding a third damped series resonance circuit to the second elliptical filter cell. This third resonance circuit is constituted by a third capacitor C23 series connected with the parallel connection of a third resistor R23 and a third coil L26. The third resonance circuit is connected between the junction point of the first winding L23a of the third symmetrical coil L23 of the second elliptical filter cell with the POTS/ISDN terminal POTS/ISDN+ and the junction point of the second winding<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> L23b of the third symmetrical coil L23 of the second elliptical filter cell with the POTS/ISDN terminal POTS/ISDN-.</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">A fourth capacitor C24 is provided in parallel across the first winding L22a of the second symmetrical coil L22 of the first elliptical filter cell, and a fifth capacitor C25 is provided in parallel across the second winding L22b of this second symmetrical coil L22.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">Similarly, a sixth capacitor C26 is provided in parallel across the first winding L23a of the third symmetrical coil L23 of the second elliptical filter cell, and a seventh capacitor C27 is provided in parallel across the second winding L23b of this third symmetrical coil L23.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">Damping resistors (not shown) may be provided in series or in parallel with the fourth C24, fifth C25, sixth C26 and/or seventh C27 capacitors.</p><p id="p0044" num="0044">An additional Common Mode Coil and protector for overvoltages may also be provided but are not shown at <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045">It is to be noted that the symmetrical coils L21, L22 and L23, each with first (a) and second (b) windings, are typically of the type EP7 or RM4.</p><p id="p0046" num="0046">The coils L24, L25 and L26 are small Surface Mounted SMD type coils, of low values, e.g. a few µH. As there is no DC current going through these coils, the size and cost of the coils is relatively small.</p><p id="p0047" num="0047">The resistors R21, R22, R23 are low-ohmic Surface Mounted SMD type of resistors, also of small size, as no DC current is flowing through these resistors.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048">The architecture of the low pass filter of this 7<sup>th</sup> order ISDN/Universal splitter results in characteristics that are similar to those of the above known 9<sup>th</sup> order filter.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">An optimized variant of the 7<sup>th</sup> order ISDN or Universal ISDN/POTS splitter low pass filter is shown at <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>. This splitter consists of 1 LC filter stage, 2 elliptical filter stages and 2 series resonance circuits.</p><p id="p0050" num="0050">In this more optimized embodiment of the 7<sup>th</sup> order ISDN or ISDN/POTS Universal splitter, only 2 series resonance circuits C31, R31, L34 and C32, R32, L35 are used. In other words, with respect to the embodiment<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> shown at <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>, the second elliptical filter cell is no longer associated with the third damped series resonance circuit comprising the third capacitor C23 series connected with the parallel connection of the third resistor R23 and the third coil L26, but only with third capacitor C33 as shown at <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>. This third capacitor C33 is thus directly connected between the junction point of the first winding L33a of the third symmetrical coil L33 of the second elliptical filter cell with the POTS/ISDN terminal POTS/ISDN+ and the junction point of the second winding L33b of the third symmetrical coil L33 of the second elliptical filter cell with the POTS/ISDN terminal POTS/ISDN-.</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">By correct dimensioning the component values, also with this filter shown at <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>, full compliancy to ETSI standard ETSI TS 101 952-1-4 is guaranteed and a dynamic performance (transient rejection, noise impact of ISDN on xDSL signals, noise impact of xDSL on ISDN signals), comparable to the known 9<sup>th</sup> order splitter is achieved.</p><p id="p0052" num="0052">Compared to the embodiment shown at <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>, this more optimized embodiment shown at <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> requires even less space and has a better cost advantage.</p><p id="p0053" num="0053"><figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4</figref> shows the size comparison of the 7<sup>th</sup> order splitter (right: 33 mm x 17 mm = 5.61 cm<sup>2</sup>) versus the 9<sup>th</sup> order splitter (left: 42 mm x 17 mm = 7.14 cm<sup>2</sup>) showing more than 25% size reduction with the 7<sup>th</sup> order splitter. Only the top side components are shown at <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4</figref>, not the SMD components at the bottom side, L representing coils and C representing capacitors.</p><p id="p0054" num="0054">It is to be noted that other implementation of the 7<sup>th</sup> order ISDN or ISDN/POTS /Universal splitter low pass filter, with e.g. series resistors for the elliptical caps, other positions of series resonance circuits, etc. may be derived from the basic architectures shown at <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>.</p><p id="p0055" num="0055">Derived implementations of the 7<sup>th</sup> order ISDN/POTS Universal splitter low pass filter are for instance:
<ul><li>implementations with 1, 2 or 3 series resonance circuits;</li><li>different positions for 1 or 2 series resonance circuits, e.g. together with C31, C32 or C33 in case of 1 series resonance circuit, together with C31 and<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> C32 (as shown at <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>), C31 and C33 or C32 and C33 in case of 2 series resonance circuits; and</li><li>use of series or parallel damping resistors on the fourth C24, fifth C25, sixth C26 and/or seventh C27 capacitors as mentioned above with respect to <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>.</li></ul></p><p id="p0056" num="0056">A final remark is that embodiments of the present invention are described above in terms of functional blocks. From the functional description of these blocks, given above, it will be apparent for a person skilled in the art of designing electronic devices how embodiments of these blocks can be manufactured with well-known electronic components. A detailed architecture of the contents of the functional blocks hence is not given.</p><p id="p0057" num="0057">While the principles of the invention have been described above in connection with specific apparatus, it is to be clearly understood that this description is merely made by way of example and not as a limitation on the scope of the invention, as defined in the appended claims.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980154" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Splitter für ein ISDN/POTS-Telekommunikationssystem, wobei der besagte Splitter einen ersten (Line+) und einen zweiten (Line-) Leitungsabschluss und einen ersten (POTS/ISDN+) und einen zweiten (POTS.ISDN-) POTS-ISDN-Abschluss aufweist, umfassend die Kaskadenschaltung einer LC-Filterzelle (L21a, L21b, C21) und eine Vielzahl von in Kaskade geschalteten elliptischen Filterzellen (L22a, L22b, C22, C24, C25; L23a, L23b, C23, C26, C27),<br/>
wobei die besagte LC-Filterzelle eine erste symmetrische Spule (L21a, L21b) mit einer ersten Wicklung (L21a), deren erster Abschluss an den besagten ersten Leitungsabschluss (Line+) angeschlossen ist, und deren zweiter Abschluss über die besagte Vielzahl von elliptischen Filterzellen an den besagten ersten POTS/ISDN-Abschluss (POTS/ISDN+) gekoppelt ist, und mit einer zweiten Wicklung (L21 b), deren erster Abschluss an den besagten zweiten Leitungsabschluss (Line-) angeschlossen ist, und deren zweiter Abschluss über die besagte Vielzahl von elliptischen Filterzellen an den besagten zweiten POTS/ISDN-Abschluss (POTS/ISDN-) gekoppelt ist, umfasst, wobei die besagte LC-Filterzelle weiterhin einen ersten Kondensator (C21) umfasst, welcher zwischen dem zweiten Abschluss der ersten Wicklung (L21a) der besagten ersten symmetrischen Spule und dem zweiten Abschluss der zweiten Wicklung (L21b) der besagten ersten symmetrischen Spule gekoppelt ist,<br/>
wobei jede elliptische Filterzelle der besagten Vielzahl eine zweite symmetrische Spule (L22a, L22b; L23a, L23b) mit einer ersten Wicklung (L22a; L23a), deren erster Abschluss an den zweiten Abschluss der ersten Wicklung (L21a) der besagten LC-Filterzelle gekoppelt ist, und deren zweiter Abschluss an den besagten ersten POTS/ISDN-Abschluss (POTS/ISDN+) gekoppelt ist, und mit einer zweiten Wicklung (L22b; L23b), deren erster Abschluss an den zweiten Abschluss der zweiten Wicklung (L21b) der besagten LC-Filterzelle gekoppelt ist, und deren zweiter Abschluss an den besagten zweiten POTS/ISDN-Abschluss (POTS/ISDN) gekoppelt ist, umfasst, wobei jede elliptische Filterzelle weiterhin einen zweiten Kondensator (C22; C23), welcher zwischen dem zweiten Abschluss der ersten Wicklung (L22a; L23a) der zweiten symmetrischen Spule der besagten elliptischen Filterzelle und dem zweiten Abschluss der zweiten Wicklung (L22b; L23b) der besagten zweiten symmetrischen Spule gekoppelt ist, eine dritten Kondensator (C24; C26), welcher durch die erste Wicklung (L22a; L23a) einer zweiten symmetrischen Spule hindurch angeschlossen ist, und einen vierten Kondensator (C25; C27), welcher durch die zweite Wicklung (L22b; L23b) der besagten zweiten symmetrischen Spule hindurch angeschlossen ist, umfasst.<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --><i><b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b></i> der besagte Splitter mindesten eine RL-Schaltung umfasst, welche aus der Parallelankopplung eines Widerstands (R22; R23) und einer Spule (L25; L26) besteht und mit dem zweiten Kondensator (C22; C23) einer elliptischen Filterzelle der besagten Vielzahl von elliptischen Filterzellen in Reihe geschaltet ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Splitter nach Anspruch 1, <i><b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b></i> der besagte Splitter eine weitere RL-Schaltung umfasst, welche aus der Parallelankopplung eines zweiten Widerstands (R21) und einer zweiten Spule (L24) besteht und mit dem ersten Kondensator (C21) der besagten LC-Filterzelle zwischen dem ersten Abschluss der ersten Wicklung (L21a) der besagten ersten symmetrischen Spule des besagten LC-Filters und dem zweiten Abschluss der zweiten Wicklung (L21b) der besagten ersten symmetrischen Spule des besagten LC-Filters in Reihe geschaltet ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Splitter nach einem beliebigen der Ansprüche 1 bis 2,<br/>
<i><b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b></i> der besagte Splitter die Kaskadenschaltung der besagten LC-Filterzelle (L21a, L21b), C21), einer ersten elliptischen Filterzelle (L22a, L22b, C22, C24, C25) mit einem ersten zweiten Kondensator (C22) und einer zweiten elliptischen Filterzelle (L23a, L23b, C23, C26, C27) mit einem zweiten zweiten Kondensator (C23) umfasst,<br/>
<i>und dass</i> der zweite zweite Kondensator (C23) der besagten zweiten elliptischen Filterzelle mit einer zweiten RL-Schaltung, welche aus der Parallelankopplung eines zweiten Widerstands (R23) und einer zweiten Spule (L26) zwischen dem zweiten Abschluss der ersten Wicklung (L23a) der zweiten symmetrischen Spule der besagten zweiten elliptischen Filterzelle und dem zweiten Abschluss der zweiten Wicklung (L23b) der zweiten symmetrischen Spule der besagten zweiten elliptischen Filterzelle besteht, in Reihe geschaltet ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Splitter nach Anspruch 1, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> der besagte Splitter weiterhin einen ersten Dämpfungswiderstand, welcher dem dritten Kondensator (C24; C26) durch die erste Wicklung (L22a; L23a) der zweiten symmetrischen Spule der besagten elliptischen Filterzellen (L22a, L22b, C22, C24, C25; L23a, L23b, C23, C26, C27) hindurch parallelgeschaltet ist, und einen zweiten Dämpfungswiderstand, welcher dem vierten Kondensator (C25; C27) durch die zweite Wicklung (L22b; L23b) der besagten zweiten symmetrischen Spule hindurch parallelgeschaltet ist, umfasst.<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Splitter nach Anspruch 1, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> der besagte Splitter weiterhin einen dritten Dämpfungswiderstand, welcher dem dritten Kondensator (C24; C26) durch die erste Wicklung (L22a; L23a) der zweiten symmetrischen Spule der besagten elliptischen Filterzellen (L22a, L22b, C22, C24, C25; L23a, L23b, C23, C26, C27) hindurch parallelgeschaltet ist, und einen vierten Dämpfungswiderstand, welcher dem vierten Kondensator (C25; C27) durch die zweite Wicklung (L22b; L23b) der besagten zweiten symmetrischen Spule hindurch parallelgeschaltet ist, umfasst.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980155" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A splitter for an ISDN/POTS telecommunication system, said splitter having first (Line+) and second (Line-) line terminals and first (POTS/ISDN+) and second (POTS/ISDN-) POTS/ISDN terminals, and comprising the cascade connection of a LC filter cell (L21a, L21b, C21) and a plurality of cascade connected elliptical filter cells (L22a, L22b, C22, C24, C25; L23a, L23b, C23, C26, C27),<br/>
said LC filter cell comprising a first symmetrical coil (L21a, L21b) having a first winding (L21a) with a first terminal connected to said first line terminal (Line+) and with a second terminal coupled to said first POTS/ISDN terminal (POTS/ISDN+) via said plurality of elliptical filter cells, and having a second winding (L21b) with a first terminal connected to said second line terminal (Line-) and with a second terminal coupled to said second POTS/ISDN terminal (POTS/ISDN-) via said plurality of elliptical filter cells, said LC filter cell further comprising a first capacitor (C21) coupled between the second terminal of the first winding (L21a) of said first symmetrical coil and the second terminal of the second winding (L21b) of said first symmetrical coil,<br/>
each elliptical filter cell of said plurality comprising a second symmetrical coil (L22a, L22b; L23a, L23b) having a first winding (L22a; L23a) with a first terminal coupled to the second terminal of the first winding (L21a) of said LC filter cell and with a second terminal coupled to said first POTS/ISDN terminal (POTS/ISDN+) and having a second winding (L22b; L23b) with a first terminal coupled to the second terminal of the second winding (L21b) of said LC filter cell and with a second terminal coupled to said second POTS/ISDN terminal (POTS/ISDN-), each elliptical filter cell further comprising a second capacitor (C22; C23) coupled between the second terminal of the first winding (L22a; L23a) of the second symmetrical coil of said elliptical filter cell and the second terminal of the second winding (L22b; L23b) of said second symmetrical coil, a third capacitor (C24; C26) connected across the first winding (L22a; L23a) of said second symmetrical coil and a fourth capacitor (C25; C27) connected across the second winding (L22b; L23b) of said second symmetrical coil,<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --><i><b>characterized in that</b></i> said splitter comprises at least one RL circuit constituted by the parallel coupling of a resistor (R22; R23) and a coil (L25; L26) and connected in series with the second capacitor (C22; C23) of an elliptical filter cell of said plurality of elliptical cells.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The splitter according to claim 1, <i><b>characterized in that</b></i> said splitter comprises another RL circuit constituted by the parallel coupling of a second resistor (R21) and a second coil (L24) and connected in series with the first capacitor (C21) of said LC filter cell between the second terminal of the first winding (L21a) of said first symmetrical coil of said LC filter and the second terminal of the second winding (L21b) of said first symmetrical coil of said LC filter.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The splitter according to any of the claims 1 or 2,<br/>
<i><b>characterized in that</b></i> said splitter comprises the cascade connection of said LC filter cell (L21a, L21b, C21), a first elliptical filter cell (L22a, L22b, C22, C24, C25) comprising a first second capacitor (C22) and a second elliptical filter cell (L23a, L23b, C23, C26, C27) comprising a second second capacitor (C23),<br/>
<i>and <b>in that</b></i> the second second capacitor (C23) of said second elliptical filter cell is connected in series with a second RL circuit constituted by the parallel coupling of a second resistor (R23) and a second coil (L26) between the second terminal of the first winding (L23a) of the second symmetrical coil of said second elliptical filter cell and the second terminal of the second winding (L23b) of the second symmetrical coil of said second elliptical filter cell.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The splitter according to claim 1, <i><b>characterized in that</b></i> said splitter further comprises a first damping resistor connected in parallel with the third capacitor (C24; C26) across the first winding (L22a; L23a) of the second symmetrical coil of said elliptical filter cells (L22a, L22b, C22, C24, C25; L23a, L23b, C23, C26, C27), and a second damping resistor connected in parallel<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> with the fourth capacitor (C25; C27) across the second winding (L22b; L23b) of said second symmetrical coil.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The splitter according to claim 1, <b><i>characterized in that</i></b> said splitter further comprises a third damping resistor connected in series with the third capacitor (C24; C26) across the first winding (L22a; L23a) of the second symmetrical coil of said elliptical filter cells (L22a, L22b, C22, C24, C25; L23a, L23b, C23, C26, C27), and a fourth damping resistor connected in series with the fourth capacitor (C25; C27) across the second winding (L22b; L23b) of said second symmetrical coil.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980156" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Séparateur pour un système de télécommunication RNIS/POTS, ledit séparateur ayant une première borne de ligne (Line+) et une deuxième borne de ligne (Line-) et une première borne POTS/RNIS (POTS/RNIS+) et une deuxième borne POTS/RNIS (POTS/RNIS-), et comprenant la connexion en cascade d'une cellule de filtrage LC (L21 a, L21 b, C21) et une pluralité de cellules de filtrage elliptiques connectées en cascade (L22a, L22b, C22, C24, C25 ; L23a, L23b, C23, C26, C27),<br/>
ladite cellule de filtrage LC comprenant une première bobine symétrique (L21a, L21 b) ayant un premier bobinage (L21 a) avec une première borne connectée à ladite première borne de ligne (Line+) et avec une deuxième borne couplée à ladite première borne POTS/RNIS (POTS/RNIS+) par l'intermédiaire de ladite pluralité de cellules de filtrage elliptiques, et ayant un deuxième bobinage (L21b) avec une première borne connectée à ladite deuxième borne de ligne (Line-) et avec une deuxième borne couplée à ladite deuxième borne POTS/RNIS (POTS/RNIS-) par l'intermédiaire de ladite pluralité de cellules de filtrage elliptiques, ladite cellule de filtrage LC comprenant en outre un premier condensateur (C21) couplé entre la deuxième borne du premier bobinage (L21 a) de ladite première bobine symétrique et la deuxième borne du deuxième bobinage (L21 b) de ladite première bobine symétrique,<br/>
chaque cellule de filtrage elliptique de ladite pluralité comprenant une deuxième bobine symétrique (L22a, L22b ; L23a, L23b) ayant un premier bobinage (L22a ; L23a) avec une première borne couplée à la deuxième borne du premier bobinage (L21a) de ladite cellule de filtrage LC et avec une deuxième borne couplée à ladite première borne POTS/RNIS (POTS/RNIS+) et ayant un deuxième bobinage (L22b ; L23b) avec une première borne couplée à la deuxième borne du deuxième bobinage (L21b) de ladite cellule de filtrage LC et avec une deuxième borne couplée à ladite deuxième borne POTS/RNIS (POTS/RNIS-), chaque cellule de filtrage elliptique comprenant en outre un deuxième condensateur (C22 ; C23) couplé entre la deuxième borne du premier bobinage (L22a ; L23a) de la deuxième bobine symétrique de ladite cellule de filtrage elliptique et la deuxième borne du deuxième bobinage (L22b ; L23b) de ladite deuxième bobine symétrique, un troisième condensateur (C24 ; C26) connecté sur le premier bobinage (L22a ; L23a) de ladite deuxième bobine symétrique et un quatrième condensateur (C25 ; C27) connecté sur le deuxième bobinage (L22b ; L23b) de ladite deuxième bobine symétrique,<br/>
<i><b>caractérisé en ce que</b></i> ledit séparateur comprend au moins un circuit RL constitué par le couplage parallèle d'une résistance (R22 ; R23) et d'une bobine (L25 ; L26) et<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> connecté en série avec le deuxième condensateur (C22 ; C23) d'une cellule de filtrage elliptique de ladite pluralité de cellules elliptiques.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Séparateur selon la revendication 1, <i><b>caractérisé en ce que</b></i> ledit séparateur comprend un autre circuit RL constitué par le couplage en parallèle d'une deuxième résistance (R21) et d'une deuxième bobine (L24) et connecté en série avec le premier condensateur (C21) de ladite cellule de filtrage LC entre la deuxième borne du premier bobinage (L21a) de ladite première bobine symétrique dudit filtre LC et la deuxième borne du deuxième bobinage (L21 b) de ladite première bobine symétrique dudit filtre LC.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Séparateur selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 et 2,<br/>
<i><b>caractérisé en ce que</b></i> ledit séparateur comprend la connexion en cascade de ladite cellule de filtrage LC (L21 a, L21 b, C21), une première cellule de filtrage elliptique (L22a, L22b, C22, C24, C25) comprenant un premier deuxième condensateur (C22) et une deuxième cellule de filtrage elliptique (L23a, L23b, C23, C26, C27) comprenant un deuxième deuxième condensateur (C23),<br/>
<i>et <b>en ce que</b></i> le deuxième deuxième condensateur (C23) de ladite deuxième cellule de filtrage elliptique est connecté en série avec un deuxième circuit RL constitué par le couplage en parallèle d'une deuxième résistance (R23) et d'une deuxième bobine (L26) entre la deuxième borne du premier bobinage (L23a) de la deuxième bobine symétrique de ladite deuxième cellule de filtrage elliptique et la deuxième borne du deuxième bobinage (L23b) de la deuxième bobine symétrique de ladite deuxième cellule de filtrage elliptique.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Séparateur selon la revendication 1, <i><b>caractérisé en ce que</b></i> ledit séparateur comprend en outre une première résistance d'amortissement connectée en parallèle avec le troisième condensateur (C24 ; C26) sur le premier bobinage (L22a ; L23a) de la deuxième bobine symétrique desdites cellules de filtrage elliptiques (L22a, L22b, C22, C24, C25 ; L23a, L23b, C23, C26, C27), et une deuxième résistance d'amortissement connectée en parallèle avec le quatrième condensateur (C25 ; C27) sur le deuxième bobinage (L22b ; L23b) de ladite deuxième bobine symétrique.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Séparateur selon la revendication 1, <i><b>caractérisé en ce que</b></i> ledit séparateur comprend en outre une troisième résistance d'amortissement connectée en série avec le troisième condensateur (C24 ; C26) sur le premier bobinage (L22a ; L23a)<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> de la deuxième bobine symétrique desdites cellules de filtrage elliptiques (L22a, L22b, C22, C24, C25 ; L23a, L23b, C23, C26, C27), et une quatrième résistance d'amortissement connectée en série avec le quatrième condensateur (C25 ; C27) sur le deuxième bobinage (L22b ; L23b) de ladite deuxième bobine symétrique.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16669073" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="165" he="227" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="150" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="155" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --><figure id="f0004" num="4"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="165" he="188" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
