<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2679367-A1" country="EP" doc-number="2679367" kind="A1" date="20140101" family-id="46720353" file-reference-id="318292" date-produced="20180823" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146550159" ucid="EP-2679367-A1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2679367</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-11817288-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154824082" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>11817288</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20110510</date><lang>JA</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP189754545" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>11817288.1</doc-number><date>20110510</date><lang>JA</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140446884" ucid="JP-2011040720-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>JP</country><doc-number>2011040720</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20110225</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140451795" ucid="JP-2011060741-W" linkage-type="W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>JP</country><doc-number>2011060741</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20110510</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL2001016942" load-source="docdb">B29C  33/02        20060101AFI20140115BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL2001016943" load-source="docdb">B29C  35/02        20060101ALI20140115BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL2001016944" load-source="docdb">B29D  30/06        20060101ALI20140115BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988120459" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B29C  33/02        20130101 FI20130726BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988125192" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B29D  30/0662      20130101 LI20131127BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988128024" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B29L2030/00        20130101 LA20131127BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988134717" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B29D2030/0674      20130101 LA20131127BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988135029" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B29C  35/02        20130101 LI20130726BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132182961" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">REIFENVULKANISATOR</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132182962" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">TIRE VULCANIZATION DEVICE</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132182963" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">DISPOSITIF DE VULCANISATION DE PNEUMATIQUE</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918172796" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>MITSUBISHI HEAVY IND LTD</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918146068" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>MITSUBISHI HEAVY INDUSTRIES, LTD.</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918985466" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Mitsubishi Heavy Industries, Ltd.</last-name><iid>101201472</iid><address><street>16-5, Konan 2-chome Minato-ku</street><city>Tokyo 108-8215</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918146766" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>SHINTANI KOJI</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918138234" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>SHINTANI, KOJI</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918978904" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>SHINTANI, KOJI</last-name><address><street>C/o MITSUBISHI HEAVY INDUSTRIES LTD. 16-5 Konan 2-chome Minato-ku</street><city>Tokyo 108-8215</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918993282" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Bongiovanni, Simone</last-name><suffix>et al</suffix><iid>101198266</iid><address><street>Studio Torta S.p.A. Via Viotti, 9</street><city>10121 Torino</city><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="JP-2011060741-W"><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>2011060741</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20110510</date><lang>JA</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2012114542-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2012114542</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20120830</date><lang>JA</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548891089" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS548854123" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS548891090" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS548907869" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS548902550" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS548809885" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS548854124" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS548891091" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548809886" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS548809887" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS548823704" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS548907914" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS548907915" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548891092" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548809888" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS548891093" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS548854125" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS548902551" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS548809889" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS548907916" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS548809890" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS548900217" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS548901779" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS548900218" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS548900219" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS548901780" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS548901781" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS548854126" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS548823705" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS548902552" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS548900220" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS548854127" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS548900221" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS548902553" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS548907917" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS548823706" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS548902554" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS548901786" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA128670826" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p id="pa01" num="0001">To provide a tire vulcanizer capable of solving problems of an electrical heating platen, which relate to the deformation at the time of tire vulcanization and to the replacement of the platen. The tire vulcanizer vulcanizes and molds a green tire placed in an outer mold by heating the green tire from the outer side and the inner side of the green tire, and is featured by including an electric platen (10) which is arranged to be in contact with each of the upper and lower sides of a container with the green tire placed therein, or to be embedded in each of the upper and lower portions of the container, so as to heat the green tire from the outside of the outer mold at the time of vulcanization, and which is formed into a doughnut-like disc shape and divided into a plurality of sections in the circumferential direction of the platen (10).<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="97" he="100" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA128500199" lang="EN" source="EPO" load-source="docdb"><p>To provide a tire vulcanizer capable of solving problems of an electrical heating platen, which relate to the deformation at the time of tire vulcanization and to the replacement of the platen. The tire vulcanizer vulcanizes and molds a green tire placed in an outer mold by heating the green tire from the outer side and the inner side of the green tire, and is featured by including an electric platen (10) which is arranged to be in contact with each of the upper and lower sides of a container with the green tire placed therein, or to be embedded in each of the upper and lower portions of the container, so as to heat the green tire from the outside of the outer mold at the time of vulcanization, and which is formed into a doughnut-like disc shape and divided into a plurality of sections in the circumferential direction of the platen (10).</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES63956256" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001">Technical Field</heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to a tire vulcanizer which vulcanizes and molds a green tire.</p><heading id="h0002">{Background Art}</heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">Conventionally, in a tire vulcanizer which vulcanizes and molds a green tire, an outer mold (mold), in which the green tire is placed, is heated, and the inner wall surface of the green tire is pressed toward the outer mold while being heated by a high-temperature and high-pressure heating medium being supplied to the inner space of the green tire (to the inside of the bladder). Then, the outer side and the inner side of the green tire are heated by the heated outer mold and the heating medium supplied to the inner space of the green tire, and thereby the green tire is vulcanized.<br/>
Note that the conventional tire vulcanizer is configured such that steam as a heating medium is supplied into and circulated through the inner space of the green tire, and such that a heated and pressurized medium, such as nitrogen gas and warm water, is sealed in the inner space.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003"><!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> As a prior art of the tire vulcanizer described above, in which a green tire is heated from the outside thereof, there is an apparatus using a heat medium, as disclosed, for example, in Patent Literatures 1 and 2. In the prior art, a platen (heat plate) is arranged on each of the upper and lower sides of an outer mold in which a green tire is placed, and steam as a heat medium is supplied to the inside of both the platens, so that heat is transferred to the green tire from the outside of the outer mold.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">On the other hand, as for a tire vulcanizer in recent years, instead of the above-described heating technique using the heat medium, a heating technique using an electric platen has been proposed from the viewpoint of energy saving, and the like.<br/>
As electric heating methods applied to the electric platen, there are known a heating method using a rod-shaped or planar electric heater embedded in the platen (see, for example, Patent Literature 3 described below), and an induction heating method using an electromagnetic coil (see, for example, Patent Literature 4 described below).</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">Further, the conventional platen described above is formed into a one-piece structure having a doughnut-like disc shape, for facilitating the formation of a heat medium flow<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> path, the attachment to the mold, and the like. However, Patent Literature 5 described below discloses a tire vulcanizing mold in which, in order to obtain a uniform degree of vulcanization over the whole of a tire, the platen is divided in the radial direction thereof, and the rates of temperature increase of heating sections are correspondingly changed.</p><heading id="h0003">Citation List</heading><heading id="h0004">Patent Literature</heading><p id="p0006" num="0006"><ul><li>{PTL 1}<br/>
Japanese Unexamined Patent Application, Publication No. <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="JP5200754A"><text>5-200754</text></patcit></li><li>{PTL 2}<br/>
Japanese Unexamined Patent Application, Publication No. <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="JP8238626A"><text>8-238626</text></patcit></li><li>{PTL 3}<br/>
Japanese Unexamined Patent Application, Publication No. <patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="JP2002036243A"><text>2002-36243</text></patcit></li><li>{PTL 4}<br/>
Japanese Unexamined Patent Application, Publication No. <patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="JP2008100513A"><text>2008-100513</text></patcit></li><li>{PTL 5}<br/>
Japanese Unexamined Patent Application, Publication No. <patcit id="pcit0005" dnum="JP8174554A"><text>8-174554</text></patcit></li></ul><!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p><heading id="h0005">Summary of Invention</heading><heading id="h0006">Technical Problem</heading><p id="p0007" num="0007">For example, as in an external view shown in <figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 10</figref>, a conventional platen 5 of an electric heating type has a doughnut-like disc shape in the center portion of which a circular through hole 6 is formed, and has a structure in which heat generating sections 7, such as rod-shaped heaters, are embedded. For this reason, in the case where a platen is changed to an electric platen from the viewpoint of energy saving, and the like, the following problems are caused because the platen 5 has the one-piece structure having the doughnut-like disc shape.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">The first problem is that, at the time of tire vulcanization, deformation (deflection) is easily generated in the circular platen. For this reason, the life of a heat generating section, such as an electric heater, embedded in the platen, and the life of an attaching member, and the like, are reduced under the influence of the stress generated due to the deformation of the platen. Also, the deformation of the platen means that the contact area between the outer mold and the heat generating section is reduced, and hence the heat transfer property (heating efficiency) between the outer mold and the heat generating section is reduced. Further, when the<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> heat transfer property between the outer mold and the heat generating section is reduced, the temperature of the heat generating section is increased to an unexpected high temperature, and thereby the thermal life of the heat generating section is reduced.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">The second problem relates to the replacement of the platen at the time of maintenance, and the like, and is that, in the work of replacing the platen having the one-piece structure, much time is required for the removal of and the attachment and adjustment of the platen. Further, when the platen is replaced due to a failure, or the like, the entire platen must be collectively replaced, which is disadvantageous from the viewpoint of cost.<br/>
The present invention has been made in view of the above described circumstances. An object of the present invention is to provide a tire vulcanizer capable of solving the problems of the electrical heating platen, which relate to the deformation at the time of tire vulcanization and to the replacement of the platen.</p><heading id="h0007">Solution to Problem</heading><p id="p0010" num="0010">The present invention adopts the following means in order to solve the above-described problems.<br/>
A tire vulcanizer according to the present invention,<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> which vulcanizes and molds a green tire placed in an outer mold by heating the green tire from the outside and the inside of the green tire, is featured by including an electric platen which is arranged to be in contact with each of the upper and lower sides of a container with the green tire placed therein, or to be embedded in each of the upper and lower portions of the container, so as to heat the green tire from the outside of the outer mold at the time of vulcanization, and which is formed into a doughnut-like disc shape and divided into a plurality of sections in the circumferential direction of the platen.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">The tire vulcanizer according to the present invention includes the electric platen which is arranged to be in contact with each of the upper and lower sides of the container with a green tire placed therein, or to be embedded in each of the upper and lower portions of the container, so as to heat the green tire from the outside of the outer mold at the time of vulcanization, and which is formed into the doughnut-like disc shape and divided into the plurality of sections in the circumferential direction of the platen. Therefore, the platen is hardly deformed at the time of tire vulcanization.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">It is preferred that, in the tire vulcanizer of the<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> above-described invention, the platen is divided into a plurality of sections in the radial direction of the platen and is formed into a doughnut-like disc shape by connecting the innermost sides of the divided sections in the circumferential direction. Thereby, the platen is more hardly deformed at the time of tire vulcanization. In this case, the divided platens are connected and formed into the doughnut-like disc shape at the innermost center portion of the platen, and hence a small diameter hole is formed at the center portion of the platen, so that the hole can be used for the centering at the time of attaching the platen.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">It is preferred that, in the tire vulcanizer of the above-described invention, the platen includes a concave-convex engaging section in which concave and convex sections of the mutually adjacent divided platens of the plurality of divided platens are engaged with each other to make the mutually adjacent divided platens connected together and positioned.<br/>
Further, in the tire vulcanizer of the above-described invention, the platen may include a fastening connecting section in which the mutually adjacent divided platens of the plurality of divided platens are connected together and positioned by a fastening member.<br/>
Further, in the tire vulcanizer of the above-described<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> invention, the platen may be configured to include a plate connecting section in which the mutually adjacent divided platens of the plurality of divided platens are connected together and positioned via a plate-shaped member.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">Alternatively, in the tire vulcanizer of the above-described invention, the platen may be divided into a plurality of divided platens of which the mutually adjacent divided platens are provided therebetween with two or more of the concave-convex engaging section, the fastening connecting section and the plate connecting section.<br/>
The mutually adjacent divided platens can be easily positioned and connected with each other by the concave-convex engaging section, the fastening connecting section, and the plate connecting section, and by a combination of the concave-convex engaging section, the fastening connecting section, and the plate connecting section.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">In the tire vulcanizer having the above-described configuration, the connection and positioning in the plate connecting section may be performed in such a manner that the concave-convex section provided on the upper surface or the lower surface of the platen is engaged with the concave-convex section provided on the lower surface or the upper surface of the plate-shaped member. Alternatively, in the plate<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> connecting section, the platen and the plate-shaped member are connected together and positioned via a fastening member.</p><heading id="h0008">Advantageous Effects of Invention</heading><p id="p0016" num="0016">According to the present invention described above, the electrical heating platen of the tire vulcanizer is configured to be divided into a plurality of sections in the circumferential direction, and hence the platen is hardly deformed by the load at the time of tire vulcanization, as a result of which the heating efficiency, the durability, and the reliability of the platen are improved. Further, the structure, in which the electrical heating platen is divided into a plurality of sections in the circumferential direction, facilitates the work of attaching and removing the platen and the work of replacing the platen, and hence is effective for improving the maintainability of the platen.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">Further, when the electrical heating platen is replaced, the replacement can be performed for each of the divided platens, and hence the cost required for replacing the components can be reduced.<br/>
Further, the structure, in which the electrical heating platen is divided into a plurality of sections, enables an optimum division shape to be selected in correspondence with the structure of the vulcanizer, the tire mold, and the<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> heating specification, and hence is effective for improving the degree of freedom of apparatus design. That is, since the electric heating method, in which a rod-shaped heater and a planar heater are combined together, can be easily used, and since the electric heating method and the heat-medium heating method are also easily combined together, the tire heating temperature can be made uniform and optimized. Thereby, the running cost for heating is reduced, and the accuracy of the heating temperature control is improved, as a result of which a tire vulcanizer capable of manufacturing a high quality tire is provided.</p><heading id="h0009">Brief Description of Drawings</heading><p id="p0018" num="0018"><ul><li>{<figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1A</figref>}<br/>
<figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1A</figref> is a plan view showing a structure of a platen (heat plate) as an embodiment of a tire vulcanizer according to the present invention.</li><li>{<figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1B</figref>}<br/>
<figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1B</figref> is a view showing the structure of the platen (heat plate) as the embodiment of the tire vulcanizer according to the present invention, and is a longitudinal sectional view (sectional view taken along line A-A) in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1A</figref>.</li><li>{<figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>}<br/>
<figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> is a longitudinal sectional view showing a<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> configuration example of a tire vulcanizer provided with the platen shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>.</li><li>{<figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>}<br/>
<figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> is a plan view showing a first modification of the platen shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>.</li><li>{<figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 4</figref>}<br/>
<figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 4</figref> is a plan view showing a second modification of the platen shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>.</li><li>{<figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5A</figref>}<br/>
<figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5A</figref> is a view showing a structural example of a concave-convex engaging section, and showing a structural example in which the upper and lower surfaces of the divided platens adjacent to each other are overlapped and engaged with each other at the end portions of the divided platens.</li><li>{<figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5B</figref>}<br/>
<figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5B</figref> is a view showing a structural example of a concave-convex engaging section, and showing a structural example in which the upper and lower surfaces of the divided platens adjacent to each other are overlapped and engaged with each other at the end portions of the divided platens.</li><li>{<figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5C</figref>}<br/>
<figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5C</figref> is a view showing a structural example of a concave-convex engaging section, and showing a structural example in which the end surfaces of the divided platens adjacent to each other are engaged with each other.<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></li><li>{<figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5D</figref>}<br/>
<figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5D</figref> is a view showing a structural example of a concave-convex engaging section, and showing a structural example in which the end surfaces of the divided platens adjacent to each other are engaged with each other.</li><li>{<figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 6A</figref>}<br/>
<figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 6A</figref> is a view showing a structural example of a fastening connecting section, and showing a structural example in which concave-convex surfaces formed at the end portions of the divided platens adjacent to each other are vertically overlapped and fastened together by a bolt.</li><li>{<figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 6B</figref>}<br/>
<figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 6B</figref> is a view showing a structural example of a fastening connecting section, and showing a structural example in which concave and convex portions formed at the end portions of the divided platens adjacent to each other are engaged and fastened together by a through-bolt.</li><li>{<figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 7</figref>}<br/>
<figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 7</figref> is a front view showing an appearance of a platen formed by connecting divided platens to each other via a plate-shaped member.</li><li>{<figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 8A</figref>}<br/>
<figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 8A</figref> is a view showing a structural example of a plate connecting section, and is a longitudinal sectional view showing an example of a plate connecting section.<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --></li><li>{<figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 8B</figref>}<br/>
<figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 8B</figref> is a view showing a structural example of a plate connecting section, and is a plan view showing an arrangement example of concave-convex sections of a divided platen.</li><li>{<figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 8C</figref>}<br/>
<figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 8C</figref> is a view showing a structural example of a plate connecting section, and is a plan view showing an arrangement example of a concave-convex section of a divided platen.</li><li>{<figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 9A</figref>}<br/>
<figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 9A</figref> is a view showing a structural example of a plate connecting section, and showing a structural example in which a divided platen and a plate-shaped member are fastened by a vertical bolt.</li><li>{<figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 9B</figref>}<br/>
<figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 9B</figref> is a view showing a structural example of a plate connecting section, and showing a structural example in which a divided platen and a plate-shaped member are fastened by a horizontal bolt.</li><li>{<figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 10A</figref>}<br/>
<figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 10A</figref> is a plan view showing an appearance of a platen used for a tire vulcanizer.</li><li>{<figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 10B</figref>}<br/>
<figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 10B</figref> is a view showing an appearance of the platen used for the tire vulcanizer, and is a front view of <figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 10A</figref>.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0010">Description of Embodiments</heading><!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --><p id="p0019" num="0019">In the following, an embodiment of a tire vulcanizer according to the present invention will be described with reference to the accompanying drawings.<br/>
A tire vulcanizer 1 shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> is an apparatus which heats and vulcanizes a green tire T in a container (mold) 2. The container 2 is configured by including an outer mold (mold) 3 in which the green tire T is placed, and a bladder 4 which forms the inner space of the tire.<br/>
Note that the outer mold 3 described above is divided into a plurality of members in order that the green tire T can be placed in the outer mold 3 and that the tire after vulcanization can be taken out from the outer mold 3.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">In the tire vulcanizer 1, the outer mold 3, in which the green tire T is placed, is heated, and also a high-temperature and high-pressure heating medium is supplied to the inside of the bladder 4 forming the inner space of the green tire T, so that the inner wall surface of the green tire T is pressed toward the outer mold 3 while being heated. As a result, the inner and outer sides of the green tire T are heated by the heated outer mold 3 and the heating medium supplied to the inside of the bladder 4, and thereby the green tire T is vulcanized and molded.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021"><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> In the case of the tire vulcanizer 1 shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>, the green tire T placed in the outer mold 3 is heated by separate platens (heat plates) 10 respectively arranged on the upper and lower sides of the container 2, but the tire vulcanizer 1 may also have a structure in which the platen 10 is incorporated in the upper portion or the lower portion of the container 2. The platen 10 is an electric platen formed by embedding a heat generating section 12, such as a rod-shaped heater and a planar heater, in a main body 11 having a doughnut-like disc shape. Note that, in the following description, the platen 10 arranged on the upper surface of the container 2 is exemplified. However, when the platen 10 is arranged on the lower surface of the container 2 or when the platen 10 is incorporated in the container 2, the basic structure of the platen is substantially the same as that of the platen arranged on the upper surface of the container 2, and only the upper and lower sides are reversed.<br/>
In the platen 10 having the doughnut-like disc shape shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1A</figref>, the main body 11 is formed to have a circular shape, and a concentric through hole 13 is provided at the center portion of the main body 11. Further, the main body 11 of the platen 10 is divided into four sections at angular intervals of 90 degrees in the circumferential direction.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022"><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> In the following description, each of the four sections formed by dividing the platen 10 in the circumferential direction is referred to as a divided platen 11A. That is, the four divided platens 11A, in each of which the independent heat generating section 12 is embedded, are connected to each other by concave-convex engaging sections 40 (see <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5</figref>), and the like, in other words, the divided platens 11A, each of which has a substantially one-quarter circular shape and in each of which the heat generating section 12 is embedded, are integrally connected to each other, whereby the platen 10 shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig 1A</figref> is formed into a doughnut-like disc shape, at the center portion of which the through hole 13 for centering is formed.<br/>
Further, reference numeral 14 in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1A</figref> denotes a flange section for connecting the platen 10 to the container 2, and the flange section is provided for each of the quadripartite divided platens 11A in the configuration example shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1A</figref>. The positioning accuracy of the divided platens 11A, which are integrally connected to each other to form the platen 10 having the through hole 13 used to center the installation position of the outer mold 3, is further improved by providing such flange sections 14.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">In the tire vulcanizer 1 configured in this way, the platen 10 formed by connecting the divided platens 11A is<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> arranged on each of the upper and lower sides of the container 2 in which the green tire T is placed. Therefore, at the time of vulcanization, the green tire T is heated, from the outside of the container 2 and of the outer mold 3, by the electric heat generating section 12 embedded in each of the divided platens 11A, and hence the platen 10 is hardly deformed even when receiving a load at the time of vulcanization. That is, the platen 10 is hardly deformed because of its structure divided in the circumferential direction, and hence a large stress is hardly generated in the platen 10.<br/>
Note that the number of division of the platen 10 in the circumferential direction is not limited to four described above, and the platen 10 may, of course, be bisected or trisected. Further, the platen 10 may also be divided into five sections or more according to the size, and the like, of the tire to be vulcanized.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">Meanwhile, the platen 10 of the embodiment described above is formed into the doughnut-like disc shape by connecting the divided platens 11A quadrisected only in the circumferential direction. However, as in a first modification shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>, and a second modification shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 4</figref>, the platen 10 may also be divided into a plurality of sections in the radial direction in addition to the circumferential direction.<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> -->In this case, it is preferred that the innermost section, that is, the center side section, in which the through hole 13 is formed, is formed into a doughnut shape continuous in the circumferential direction.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">In the following, a platen 20 according to the first modification shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> is specifically described. The platen 20 is configured such that an inner ring 22, in which the through hole 13 is formed, is left at the center portion of a main body 21 of the platen 20, and such that the outer circumferential side of the main body 21 is divided into four divided platens 21A in the circumferential direction. That is, the platen 20 shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> has a divided structure in which the main body 21 is radially divided into the inner ring 22 and the four divided platens 21A divided in the circumferential direction. As a result, the platen 20, which is divided in the radial direction as well as in the circumferential direction, is more hardly deformed at the time of tire vulcanization.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">Further, the inner ring 22, which is a divided platen having a doughnut-like disc-shape and formed at the innermost central portion of the platen 20, has the through hole 13 which is a small diameter hole formed at the center portion of the platen 20. Therefore, the through hole 13 can be used for<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> centering the platen 20 at the time when the platen 20 is attached to the outer mold 3. That is, higher centering accuracy can be obtained by providing the inner ring 22 which is not divided in the circumferential direction.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">Further, a platen 30 of a second modification shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 4</figref> is formed by also radially dividing the outer peripheral side of the platen 20 shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>. That is, the platen 30 shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 4</figref> has a divided structure in which a main body 31 is radially divided into an inner ring 32, an outer ring 33, and four divided platens 31A divided in the circumferential direction. Note that the division in the radial direction is not limited to the division into the inner ring 32 and the outer ring 33, and may be suitably changed, for example, as in such a case where the divided platen 31A is also radially divided into a plurality of sections.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">In this structure, in the case where the diameter of the platen 30 is larger than the container 2, the heat generating body of the outer ring 33 located on the outermost side of the platen 30 is not needed. Also, the kind of the heat generating body and the heating temperature can be suitably changed for each of the divided portions of the platens 30. Therefore, the design flexibility in the arrangement, selection, and the like, of the heat generating bodies can be<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> increased.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">Subsequently, there will be described connection structures for connecting and positioning the mutually adjacent divided rings of the divided platens 11A, 21A and 31A, the inner rings 22 and 32, and the outer ring 33, which are formed by the division in the circumferential and radial directions. That is, examples of connection structures shown in the sectional views taken along lines B-B, C-C and D-D in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 4</figref> will be described with reference to the accompanying drawings.<br/>
<figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5A to Fig. 5D</figref> show structural examples of concave-convex engaging sections. <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5A and Fig. 5B</figref> show structural examples in which the upper and lower surfaces at the end portions of the divided platens adjacent to each other are overlapped and engaged with each other. <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5C and Fig. 5D</figref> show structural examples in which the end surfaces of the divided platens adjacent to each other are engaged with each other.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">Here, in the case where <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5A</figref> is a sectional view taken along line D-D in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 4</figref> and shows the concave-convex engaging section 40, a concave section 41 and a convex section 42, which are engaged with each other in a manner of being vertically overlapped with each other, are respectively<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> provided on the upper and lower surfaces of the divided platens 31A and 31A. The concave and convex sections 41 and 42 are respectively formed on mutually facing stepped surfaces 43 which are respectively provided at the end portions of the divided platens 31A and 31A. In the state where the concave and convex sections 41 and 42 are engaged and connected with each other, each of the front and back surfaces of the platen 30 having a disc shape maintains flatness, and the divided platens 31A and 31A are prevented from being horizontally moved (positionally deviated).<br/>
As described above, each of the concave and convex sections 41 and 42 may be formed substantially at the center of each of stepped surfaces 43. Alternatively, as in a concave-convex engaging section 40A shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5B</figref>, the concave and convex sections 41 and 42 formed at the end portion of one of the divided platens 31A and 31A may be engaged with the concave and convex sections 41 and 42 formed at the end portion of the other of the divided platens 31A and 31A. In this way, the connection structure of the divided platens is not limited to the above-described structural examples, and the like.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">Further, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5C and Fig. 5D</figref>, the connection structure of the divided platens 31A and 31A adjacent to each other may also be configured as concave-convex engaging<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> sections 40B and 40C in which one or plurality of concave and convex sections 45 and 46 are provided on the end surfaces 44 of the divided platens 31A and 31A so as to be engaged with each other in the horizontal direction. In this case, the side surfaces of the concave and convex sections 45 and 46 are slid in the horizontal direction so as to make the concave and convex sections 45 and 46 engage each other, and hence the divided platens 31A and 31A are prevented from being moved in the vertical direction.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">Next, structural examples of fastening connecting sections shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 6A and Fig. 6B</figref> will be described.<br/>
A fastening connecting section 50 shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 6A</figref> has a structure in which stepped surfaces 51 and 52 are respectively formed at the end portions of the divided platens 31A and 31A adjacent to each other, and in which the stepped surfaces 51 and 52 are mechanically connected to each other by using a bolt 53 as a fastening member. Further, a fastening connecting section 50A shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 6B</figref> has a structure in which a concave-convex engaging section 54 is formed at the end portions of the divided platens 31A and 31A adjacent to each other, and in which the divided platens 31A and 31A are mechanically connected to each other by using a through-bolt 55, as a fastening member, passing through the concave-convex engaging section 54.<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> -->When such fastening connecting sections 50 and 50A are adopted, the divided platens 31A and 31A are mechanically connected to each other by the fastening member, and hence the divided platens 31A and 31A can be integrated with each other by being positioned and surely connected to each other.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">Finally, structural examples of plate connecting sections shown in <figref idrefs="f0005 f0006 f0007">Fig. 7 to Fig. 9</figref> will be described.<br/>
A platen 10A shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 7</figref> has a structure in which the divided platens 11A of the platen 10 shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1B</figref> are integrated with each other by being connected and positioned by a plate-shaped member 60. In this case, as the plate-shaped member 60, for example, a plate material having a continuous ring shape is used in correspondence with the doughnut-like disc shape of the platen 10A.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">The plate-shaped member 60 described above is, for example, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 8A</figref>, connected to the divided platen 11A by a concave-convex engaging section 62 in a plate connecting section 61. The concave-convex engaging section 62 has a structure in which the concave and convex sections that are engaged with each other are respectively provided on the contact surfaces of the plate-shaped member 60 and the divided platen 11A, so as to be engaged with each other. In this case, the concave-convex engaging section 62 may be configured<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --> such that the concave section of the concave-convex engaging section 62 is provided on the plate-shaped member 60, and such that the convex section of the concave-convex engaging section 62 is provided on the divided platen 11A, or vice versa.<br/>
Further, as for the position of the concave-convex engaging section 62, for example, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 8B</figref>, a pair of the concave-convex engaging sections 62 may be respectively provided near the both ends of the divided platen 11A, or, for example, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 8C</figref>, the concave-convex engaging section 62 may be provided at a position close to the center portion of the divided platen 11A.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">Further, the plate-shaped member 60 described above may be, for example, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 9A and Fig. 9B</figref>, positioned and connected with the divided platen 11A by using a fastening member, such as a bolt.<br/>
In a structural example of the plate connecting section 61A shown in <figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 9A</figref>, the divided platen 11A and the plate-shaped member 60 are connected with each other by a bolt 63 extending in the vertical direction. In a structural example of a plate connecting section 61B shown in <figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 9B</figref>, the divided platen 11A and the plate-shaped member 60 are connected with each other by a bolt 64 extending in the horizontal direction.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036"><!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --> In the tire vulcanizer 1 described above, each of the platens 10, 20 and 30 may be divided into the plurality of divided platens of which the mutually adjacent divided platens 11A, 21A, and 31A and each of the inner rings 22 and 32 and the outer ring 33 are provided therebetween with two or more of the concave-convex engaging section 40, the fastening connecting section 50 and the plate connecting section 61. That is, in the platen formed by integrally connecting the plurality of divided platens to each other, a connection structure can be provided by suitably combining the concave-convex engaging section 40, the fastening connecting section 50, and the plate connecting section 61, and hence the positioning and connection between the divided platens can be easily performed by optimizing the connection structure.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">In this way, in the tire vulcanizer 1 according to the present embodiment described above, the platens 10, 20 and 30 respectively having the divided shapes are formed in such a manner that the electrical heating platen having the integrated disk shape is divided into the plurality of divided platens in the circumferential direction, and hence the following operation effects can be obtained.
<ol><li>1) The platen is hardly deformed (deflected) at the time of tire vulcanization, and hence the lives of the heat generating section, the attaching members (for example, a<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> flange section, an upper and lower plates, and a fastening member, such as a bolt), and the like, are improved.</li><li>2) With the platen which is hardly deformed, the contact area between the platen and the heat generating section is hardly changed, and hence the heat transfer property is not lowered, as a result of which an excellent heating efficiency is obtained and also the thermal life of the heat generating section is improved.</li><li>3) When the platen is replaced, the platen can be easily removed and can be easily attached and adjusted, and hence the maintainability is improved.</li><li>4) The platen, a part of which can be replaced for each of the divided platens, is effective to reduce the cost.</li><li>5) An optimum division shape of the platen can be selected in correspondence with the structure of a tire vulcanizer, the mold structure of a container, and heating specifications.</li><li>6) In the platen, a combination of different kinds of electric heating methods, such as a method using an electric heater (including a combination of a rod-shaped heater and a planar heater) and an induction heating method, or a combination of the electric heating method and a heat-medium heating method can be easily used for each divided platen. Thereby, since the heating temperature of a tire can be made uniform and optimized, the running cost for heating can be<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --> reduced, and the control accuracy of heating temperature can be improved, as a result of which a tire with high quality can be manufactured.</li></ol></p><p id="p0038" num="0038">In this way, the tire vulcanizer 1 according to the embodiment described above can solve the problems of the electrical heating platen, which relate to the deformation at the time of tire vulcanization and to the replacement of the platen.<br/>
Note that the present invention is not limited to the above described embodiment, and can be suitably modified within the scope and spirit of the present invention.</p><heading id="h0011">Reference Signs List</heading><p id="p0039" num="0039"><dl id="dl0001" compact="compact"><dt>1</dt><dd>Tire vulcanizer</dd><dt>2</dt><dd>Container (mold)</dd><dt>3</dt><dd>Outer mold (mold)</dd><dt>4</dt><dd>Bladder</dd><dt>10, 20, 30</dt><dd>Platen</dd><dt>11A, 21A, 31A</dt><dd>Divided platen</dd><dt>12</dt><dd>Heat generating body</dd><dt>13</dt><dd>Through hole</dd><dt>14</dt><dd>Flange section</dd><dt>40</dt><dd>Concave-convex engaging section</dd><dt>50</dt><dd>Fastening connecting section<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --></dd><dt>60</dt><dd>Plate-shaped member</dd><dt>61</dt><dd>Plate connecting section</dd></dl></p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56977185" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --><claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A tire vulcanizer which vulcanizes and molds a green tire placed in an outer mold by heating the green tire from the outer side and the inner side of the green tire, the tire vulcanizer comprising<br/>
an electric platen which is arranged to be in contact with each of the upper and lower sides of a container with the green tire placed therein, or to be embedded in each of the upper and lower portions of the container, so as to heat the green tire from the outside of the outer mold at the time of vulcanization, and is formed into a doughnut-like disc shape and divided into a plurality of sections in the circumferential direction of the platen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The tire vulcanizer according to claim 1, wherein the platen is divided into a plurality of sections in the radial direction and is formed into a doughnut-like disc shape by mutually connecting the innermost sides of the divided sections in the circumferential direction.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The tire vulcanizer according to one of claim 1 and claim 2, wherein the platen includes a concave-convex engaging section in which concave and convex sections of the mutually adjacent divided platens of the plurality of divided platens<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --> are connected to each other and positioned by being engaged with each other.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The tire vulcanizer according to one of claim 1 and claim 2, wherein the platen includes a fastening connecting section in which the mutually adjacent divided platens of the plurality of divided platens are connected to each other and positioned by a fastening member.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The tire vulcanizer according to one of claim 1 and claim 2, wherein the platen includes a plate connecting section in which the mutually adjacent divided platens of the plurality of divided platens are connected to each other and positioned via a plate-shaped member.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The tire vulcanizer according to one of claim 1 and claim 2, wherein the platen is divided into a plurality of divided platens of which the mutually adjacent divided platens are provided therebetween with two or more of the concave-convex engaging section, the fastening connecting section and the plate connecting section.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The tire vulcanizer according to one of claim 5 and claim 6, wherein the connection and positioning in the plate connecting section are performed in such a manner that the<!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --> concave-convex section provided on the upper surface or the lower surface of the platen is engaged with the concave-convex section provided on the lower surface or the upper surface of the plate-shaped member.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The tire vulcanizer according to one of claim 5 and claim 6, wherein, in the plate connecting section, the divided platen and the plate-shaped member are connected to each other and positioned via a fastening member.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16667900" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1A,1B"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="147" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="157" he="197" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3,4"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="139" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --><figure id="f0004" num="5A,5B,5C,5D"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="113" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="36"> --><figure id="f0005" num="6A,6B,7"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="148" he="230" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="37"> --><figure id="f0006" num="8A,8B,8C"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="83" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="38"> --><figure id="f0007" num="9A,9B"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="100" he="205" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="39"> --><figure id="f0008" num="10A,10B"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="129" he="208" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><search-report-data><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="165" he="230" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="165" he="230" type="tif"/></search-report-data><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
