<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-1922550-B1" country="EP" doc-number="1922550" kind="B1" date="20140101" family-id="37829510" file-reference-id="299938" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146553578" ucid="EP-1922550-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>1922550</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-05795757-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154827501" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>05795757</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20050909</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140448104" ucid="US-2005032547-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>2005032547</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20050909</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140454742" ucid="US-22195905-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>22195905</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20050908</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130725</date></intention-to-grant-date><search-report-dispatch-date><date>20110629</date></search-report-dispatch-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988123217" load-source="ipcr">G01R  15/18        20060101AFI20130604BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988132261" load-source="ipcr">H01P   5/18        20060101ALI20130604BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988107671" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G01R  15/18        20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988133560" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01P   5/18        20130101 FI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132193218" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">VERFAHREN UND SYSTEM ZUM ÜBERWACHEN DES ENERGIEFLUSSES DURCH EINE ELEKTRISCHE STROMÜBERTRAGUNGSLEITUNG</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132193219" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">METHOD AND SYSTEM FOR MONITORING POWER FLOW THROUGH AN ELECTRIC POWER TRANSMISSION LINE</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132193220" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">PROCÉDÉ ET SYSTÈME DE SURVEILLANCE DU FLUX D'ÉNERGIE À TRAVERS UNE LIGNE DE TRANSMISSION D'ÉNERGIE ÉLECTRIQUE</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918137686" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>GENSCAPE INTANGIBLE HOLDING INC</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918145273" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>GENSCAPE INTANGIBLE HOLDING, INC.</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918150922" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>LAPINSKI STERLING</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918167264" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>LAPINSKI, STERLING</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918997230" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>LAPINSKI, STERLING</last-name><address><street>3018 Lightheart Road</street><city>Louisville, KY 40222</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918146747" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>ALPHENAAR DEIRDRE</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918147549" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>ALPHENAAR, DEIRDRE</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918997231" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>ALPHENAAR, DEIRDRE</last-name><address><street>604 Jarvis Lane</street><city>Louisville, KY 40207</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918154246" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>DEESE STEPHEN</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918151208" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>DEESE, STEPHEN</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918997232" load-source="patent-office" sequence="3" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>DEESE, STEPHEN</last-name><address><street>Southern Baptist Theological Seminary Box 8-0826, 2825 Lexington Road</street><city>Louisville, KY 40280</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918997234" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Genscape Intangible Holding, Inc.</last-name><iid>101417338</iid><address><street>445 East Market Street, Suite 200</street><city>Louisville, KY 40202</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918997233" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Findlay, Alice Rosemary</last-name><iid>101251662</iid><address><street>Reddie &amp; Grose LLP 16 Theobalds Road</street><city>London WC1X 8PL</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="US-2005032547-W"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2005032547</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20050909</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2007030121-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2007030121</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20070315</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548884268" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS548975287" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS548976846" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS548978853" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS548988228" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS548884269" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS548829226" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548975288" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS548988233" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS548864287" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS548976847" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS548976848" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548975289" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548975290" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS548884270" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS548978854" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS548975291" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS548976849" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS548988234" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS548829227" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS548884271" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS548829228" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS548829229" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS548884272" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS548884273" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS548975292" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS548884274" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS548884275" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS548829230" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS548988235" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS548978831" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63957280" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001"><b>BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</b></heading><heading id="h0002">A. Field of the Invention</heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">This invention relates to monitoring the power flowing through electric power transmission lines. More particularly, the invention relates to a method and system for selecting positions for a preferred placement of a plurality of magnetic field monitors where a change in the power flowing through the transmission line will result in a maximum change in the magnetic field at the positions.</p><heading id="h0003">B. Description of Related Art -</heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">Information about the power flowing through electric power transmission lines and electric power generation facility output is useful and valuable for companies engaged in the business of buying and selling electric power on the open market. Electric power producers do not currently release this information to other participants in the market.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">A typical overhead transmission line consists of three conductor bundles, separated from each other in a spatial configuration and running between transmission line towers. Each conductor bundle carries a different phase of the power transmitted through the line, and the total power flowing through the transmission line is the summation of the power flowing through each of the three conductor bundles. Conductor bundles typically consist of 2 to 4 conductors in a bundle. For convenience, conductor bundles will be referred to hereinafter as<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> "conductors," which shall be understood to refer to the medium of a transmission line that carries the phases of the power flowing through the transmission line. The conductors making up each transmission line carry alternating current (AC) at a specific frequency (60Hz in the United States, 50Hz in Europe). The currents flowing in a transmission line generate magnetic fields and the high voltages (typically ranging from 12kV to 1,000kV) generate electric fields. The net electric and magnetic fields that surround a transmission line are a superposition of the fields created by the currents and voltages associated with each individual conductor. Both the electric and magnetic fields are largest close to the conductors and fall off rapidly with distance from the conductors.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">Often, the transmission line towers will carry several transmission lines, which will be referred to herein as a "line set" or a "transmission line set". For convenience, the terms "line set" and "transmission line set" will be understood to also include configurations where only a single transmission line is present. The net electric and magnetic fields that surround the transmission line set are a superposition of the fields created by the individual conductors of each transmission line. Each transmission line may carry a power flow that differs in magnitude and direction from any other transmission line in the transmission line set. For example, a transmission line set may have a first transmission line carrying 100 megawatts (MW) in one direction, and a second transmission line carrying 300 MW in the opposite direction.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">The "conductor configuration" is the actual, geometric arrangement of the conductors in the transmission line set. Several exemplary configurations are shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1a - FIG. 1f</figref>, including: vertical parallel (<figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1a</figref>); horizontal parallel (<figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1b</figref>); triangular parallel (<figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1c</figref>); vertical single (<figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1d</figref>); horizontal single (<figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1e</figref>); and triangular single (<figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1f</figref>). The general spatial configuration of the transmission line set (e.g. vertical parallel, horizontal parallel, triangular parallel, etc.) will most likely be consistent along large spans of the transmission line set. However, the actual geometric arrangement of the lines will vary from transverse area to transverse area along the line as a result of variations in the tension and sag in the individual conductors. Additionally, individual conductor sag will also affect the distances of the individual lines from the ground continuously along the transmission line set.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">Transmission line sets are designed to operate at fixed voltage values and a maximum power / current capacity. These values can be obtained from available power line mapping resources (such as Platts Power Map, of Platts, Colorado).<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p><p id="p0007" num="0007">The relationships between the currents and voltages associated with the transmission line set and the resulting electric and magnetic fields are characterized by well-known mathematical models (primarily Maxwell's Law and the Biot-Savart Law). Thus, the electric and magnetic fields contain the information necessary to determine the currents and voltages (i.e. power) that produced them. <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US6771058B"><text>U.S. Patent Number 6,771,058</text></patcit>, describes an apparatus and method for the measurement and monitoring of electrical power flowing over a high-voltage electric power transmission line set, including a method of determinng the power flowing through a transmission line set from measured electric and magnetic field data.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">The amount of power flowing through a transmission line set is determined by the current times the voltage as shown in equation (1). <maths id="math0001" num="(1)"><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="italic">Power</mi><mfenced><mi mathvariant="italic">MW</mi></mfenced><mo>=</mo><msub><mi>V</mi><mi>L</mi></msub><mstyle displaystyle="false"><mstyle displaystyle="true"><munder><mo>∑</mo><mi>i</mi></munder></mstyle><msub><mi>I</mi><mi>i</mi></msub><mo>⁢</mo><mi>cos</mi><mspace width="1em"/><mi>φ</mi></mstyle></math><img id="ib0001" file="imgb0001.tif" wi="73" he="11" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> where <i>V<sub>L</sub></i> is the line voltage, <maths id="math0002" num=""><math display="inline"><mstyle displaystyle="false"><mstyle displaystyle="true"><munder><mo>∑</mo><mi>i</mi></munder></mstyle><msub><mi>I</mi><mi>i</mi></msub></mstyle></math><img id="ib0002" file="imgb0002.tif" wi="9" he="8" img-content="math" img-format="tif" inline="yes"/></maths> is the summation of the currents through each conductor, and φ is the difference between the phase of the line voltage and phase of the line current. Because the voltage of a transmission line set is fixed, the amount of power flowing through that line at any particular time can be measured by determining the current through the line. The current produces the aforementioned magnetic field, the measured magnitude of which, when analyzed in light of the conductor configuration and the distance of the measuring point from each of the conductors, determines the amount of power through the line.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">The magnetic field associated with an overhead transmission line set is generally considered in terms of the magnetic flux density vector, <i>B</i>, in Tesla surrounding the lines, which is directly proportional to the conductor currents <i>I<sub>i</sub></i> as shown in equation (2) and inversely proportional to the distance <i>r<sub>i</sub></i> from the center of the each conductor to the point of measurement. <maths id="math0003" num="(2)"><math display="block"><mi>B</mi><mo>∝</mo><mstyle displaystyle="false"><mstyle displaystyle="true"><munder><mo>∑</mo><mi>i</mi></munder></mstyle><mfrac><msub><mi>I</mi><mi>i</mi></msub><msub><mi>r</mi><mi>i</mi></msub></mfrac></mstyle></math><img id="ib0003" file="imgb0003.tif" wi="57" he="13" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> The magnetic flux density vector, <i>B</i>, lies along the XY plane perpendicular or transverse to the length axis (Z) of the conductors and points according to the "right-hand-rule" either clockwise or anti-clockwise dependent on the direction of current flow. This vector can be resolved into horizontal and vertical components <i>B<sub>x</sub></i> and <i>B<sub>y</sub></i>, respectively. As used herein, the term "magnetic<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> field" refers to the magnetic flux density vector, including but not limited to the magnitude and orientation of the magnetic field and its components.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">The phase relationship between the current and voltage on the line determines the power factor (or more generally, the direction of power flow). This phase relationship is translated to the phases of the resulting magnetic and electric fields, so the phase relationship of these fields at any measuring point can be used to determine the direction of flow, once similarly adjusted for the line geometry and other factors. Thus, it is possible to determine the amount and direction of power flowing through a transmission line set (the "power flow" of the transmission line set) by measuring the electric and magnetic fields associated with the line set and processing the information appropriately. (See: <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="US6771058B"><text>U.S. Patent Number 6,771,058</text></patcit>.)</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">In practice, errors in power determination arise due to imperfections in the measurement equipment and inaccuracy of various assumptions used in the mathematical models described in equations (1) and (2). The first group includes imperfect sensor alignment and orientation with respect to the magnetic and electric fields. An additional source of error involves less than perfect sensor calibration. Calibration errors stem from the assumptions made in the mathematical model. The distances between the conductors and the sensing equipment are assumed to be fixed. However, the amount of sag on the lines as a result of temperature induced linear expansion means these distances are variable. In applying equation (2) the measured magnetic field is modeled to be a result of equal current flowing in each conductor bundle associated with the line. In reality, small current imbalances exist between the conductor bundles. These imbalances cannot be measured directly, but will lead to distortion in the magnetic field measurements that are difficult to account for in the magnetic field model. In addition, the model does not take into consideration any external currents induced through the ground wire and other related tower structures. These currents will result in distortions in the measured magnetic field and are very difficult to include in the model. The extent of measurement and model inaccuracies vary with the amount and distribution of power flowing through a particular transmission line set and the complexity of the conductor configuration.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">Additionally, the resultant fields created by the conductor configuration and power flow of a transmission line set vary when the amount of power flowing through the transmission line set varies. Accurate monitoring of the power flow through the transmission line set requires accurate detection of changes in the resultant fields. For instance, a vertical parallel<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> conductor configuration, such as that shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1a</figref>, may produce a horizontal magnetic field sectional view for various power flows as shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>. In certain areas 202, 204 large changes in power flow result in only minimal changes in magnetic field. Combined with the intrinsic measurement errors discussed above, placing magnetic field monitors in these areas will likely result in difficulty in accurately detecting changes in power flow. However, in another area 206 changes in power flow result in large changes in magnetic field, such that intrinsic measurement errors are unlikely to affect accurately detecting changes in power flow. Therefore, it is preferable to place magnetic field sensors at positions where minimal changes in power flow through the line results in a maximum change in the magnetic field.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">Thus, there is a need for a method and system for monitoring the power flowing through an electric power transmission line set using magnetic field monitors placed at selected positions where a predetermined change in the power flow of the transmission line set results in a maximum change in the magnetic field at the positions. Additionally, there is a further need for a method for selecting the positions for the preferred placement for such magnetic field monitors.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014"><patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="EP1030183A"><text>EP 1030183</text></patcit> discloses a current sensor that is intended to be less expensive and easier to use as compared to prior current sensors. Accordingly, D1 describes a current sensor that includes at least two components sensitive to magnetic fields that are geometrically distributed around a conductor. Each component emits a signal representative of the current flowing in the conductor, and then, as part of the processing of the signals, the geometric position of each component relative to the conductor is taken into account.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015"><patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="WO0077535A"><text>WO 00/77535</text></patcit> discloses measuring the power flowing through transmission lines and evaluating, storing and transmitting the recorded data. Specific placement of the sensors is chosen depending on particular factors of the line. It further discloses directly measuring the relative position of the conductors to one another.</p><heading id="h0004"><b>SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</b></heading><p id="p0016" num="0016">According to one aspect of the invention, a method for monitoring the power flowing through an electric power transmission line set, comprising selecting positions for a preferred placement for a plurality of magnetic field monitors by (a) determining a conductor configuration and a power flow of the transmission line set at a location along the transmission line set, and (b) determining positions in a substantially planar area that is transverse to said transmission line set at said location where a predetermined change in said power flow results in a maximum change in the magnetic field at the positions; placing said magnetic field monitors at said selected positions for collecting magnetic field data; performing a computational analysis on said magnetic field data to determine a power flow through said transmission line set; and communicating said power flow to an end user;<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --><!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> wherein said sub-step of determining the conductor configuration and power flow of the transmission line set includes: obtaining horizontal and vertical distances between each conductor and a plurality of measuring points across the substantially planar area to determine the conductor configuration of the transmission line set; obtaining measured magnetic field values at said measuring points; generating, through computation performed on a digital computer, predicted magnetic field values at each measuring point for a range of line set power flows; and selecting the line set power flow where the predicted values have a best fit with the measured values.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">The positions where a change in the power flow of the line set result in a maximum change in magnetic field at the positions may be determined by obtaining the predicted magnetic field values at each measuring point for the determined power flow, obtaining predicted magnetic field values at each measuring point for a power flow where the determined powder flow has changed by a predetermined amount, determining the differences between the predicted values for the changed power flow and the predicted values for the determined power flow at each measuring point, and selecting the measuring points having the maximum differences as the positions where a change in the power flow results in a maximum change in the magnetic field at the positions.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">Alternatively, the positions may be determined by generating magnetic field difference curves for the vector components of the predicted values for the changed power flow and the predicted values for the determined power flow, and selecting the positions corresponding to the maxima of the difference curves for the preferred placement for the monitors.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">According to another aspect of the invention, a computer readable medium has computer executable instruction for performing the steps of the method for selecting positions for a preferred placement for a plurality of magnetic field monitors for monitoring the power flowing through an electric power transmission line set, described immediately above.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">According to yet another aspect of the invention, a system for monitoring the power flowing through an electric power transmission line set includes a plurality of magnetic field monitors placed at selected positions in a substantially planar area that is transverse to the transmission line set, and a central processing facility in communication with the plurality of magnetic field monitors for communicating the power flow to an end user. The positions for placement of the magnetic field monitors are selected by determining the conductor configuration and the power flow of the transmission line in the substantially planar area, and determining positions in the substantially planar area where a predetermined change in the power<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> flow of the line set results in a maximum change in the magnetic field at the positions, as described above.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">There is also disclosed a method for selecting positions for a preferred placement for a plurality of magnetic field monitors for monitoring the power flowing through an electric power transmission line set includes: determining a conductor configuration and a power flow of the transmission line set at a location along the transmission line set; and determining positions in a substantially planar area that is transverse to the transmission line set at the location where a predetermined change in the power flow of the line set results in a maximum change in the magnetic field at the positions, thereby indicating the preferred placement of the monitors. Advantageously, the method is performed through computational analyses performed on a digital computer.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">More specifically, determining the conductor configuration is accomplished by obtaining the horizontal and vertical distances between each conductor of the transmission line set and a plurality of measuring points across the substantially planar area. The power flow of the transmission line is obtained by obtaining magnetic field values at the measuring points, generating predicted magnetic field values at each measuring point for a range of line set power flows, and selecting the line set power flow where the predicted values have a best fit with the obtained values.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">The preceding description is provided as a non-limiting summary of the invention only. A better understanding of the invention will be had by reference to the following detail description, and to the appended drawings and claims.</p><heading id="h0005"><b>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</b></heading><p id="p0024" num="0024"><figref idrefs="f0001">FIGS. 1a - 1f</figref> are views of exemplary electric power transmission line sets and line sets having various conductor configurations.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025"><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> is a profile of predicted horizontal magnetic field values for a range of line current configuration for a particular planar area transverse to a representative vertical parallel transmission line set.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026"><figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> is a block diagram of an exemplary system for monitoring the power flow through an electric power transmission line set, according to an embodiment of the invention.<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --></p><p id="p0027" num="0027"><figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 4</figref> is a perspective view of an electric power transmission line set, showing a substantially planar area that is transverse to the transmission line set and placement of magnetic field monitors in the substantially planar area.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028"><figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 5</figref> is a sectional view of the substantially planar area of <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 4</figref>.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029"><figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 6</figref> is a logic flow diagram of a method for selecting a preferred placement of magnetic field monitors according to an embodiment of the invention.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030"><figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 7</figref> is a logic flow diagram showing the steps of determining the conductor configuration and power flow in more detail.<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></p><p id="p0031" num="0031"><figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 8</figref> is a view of a substantially planar area that is transverse to a transmission line set.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032"><figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 9</figref> is a logic flow diagram showing the steps of determining positions where a change in power flow through the line results in a maximum change in the magnetic field.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033"><figref idrefs="f0010">FIG. 10</figref> is a logic flow diagram showing a graphical method for determining positions where a change in power flow through the line results in a maximum change in magnetic field.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034"><figref idrefs="f0011">FIG. 11</figref> is a logic flow diagram showing the steps of a method for monitoring power flowing through an electric power transmission line set, according to an embodiment of the invention.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035"><figref idrefs="f0012">FIG. 12</figref> shows the measured horizontal magnetic field values, and predicted horizontal magnetic field values for a range of line current configurations for a particular planar area transverse to a representative vertical parallel transmission line set.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036"><figref idrefs="f0012">FIG. 13</figref> shows the measured vertical magnetic field values, and predicted vertical magnetic field values for a range of line current configurations for the planar area of the transmission line set of <figref idrefs="f0012">FIG. 12</figref>.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037"><figref idrefs="f0013">FIG. 14</figref> shows a horizontal magnetic field difference curve and a vertical magnetic field difference curve for a determined power flow and a power flow that has changed by a predetermined amount.</p><heading id="h0006"><b>DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF EXEMPLARY EMBODIMENTS</b></heading><p id="p0038" num="0038">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3</figref>, an exemplary system for monitoring the power flowing through an electric power transmission line set generally comprises a plurality of magnetic field monitors 302, 304, 306, 307 and a central processing facility 308 in communication with the plurality of magnetic field monitors 302, 304, 306, 307 through a communication network 310, such as the Internet or the like. Additionally, one or more end users 312, 314, 316, 318 are in communication with the central processing facility 308 through a communication network 320, such as the Internet or the like. Power flow information is gathered by the magnetic field monitors 302, 304, 306, 307 and transmitted to the end users 312, 314, 316, 318 through the central processing facility 308. The monitors 302, 304, 306, 307 can do all of the processing<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> required to determine the power flow, or they can transmit the magnetic field data to the central processing facility 308 for determination of the power flow.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 4</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 5</figref>, the magnetic field monitors 302, 304, 306 are placed at selected positions in a substantially planar area that is transverse to the transmission line set 324. The positions are selected so that a predetermined change in the power flow of the line set will result in a maximum change in the magnetic field at the positions. Placement of the monitors 302, 304, 306 in the substantially planar area 322 that is transverse to the transmission line set 324 enables the relationships between the currents and voltages associated with the conductors of the transmission line set and the resulting electric and magnetic fields to be characterized by well known mathematical models using the Biot-Savart law and other numerical analysis techniques.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">In an exemplary embodiment, each magnetic field monitor has two magnetometers for sensing the horizontal magnetic field value and the vertical magnetic field value at the monitor. Thus, each of the two magnetometers is placed such that its sensitive axis is aligned in either the horizontal or vertical direction. Further, such monitors may also have an electric field sensor. A detailed description of such monitors or monitoring devices, including the components and component interactions, can be found in <patcit id="pcit0005" dnum="US6771058B"><text>U.S. Patent Number 6,771,058</text></patcit>. However, one of skill in the art will understand that the system is not limited to specifically measuring horizontal and vertical magnetic field values, as other magnetic field vector components may be utilized in equivalent embodiments within the teaching of the invention.</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 6</figref>, an exemplary method for selecting positions for a preferred placement for a plurality of magnetic field monitors for monitoring the power flowing through an electric power transmission line set includes the step of S602 determining a conductor configuration and power flow of the transmission line set at a location along the transmission line set The possible magnetic fields in the planar area can be modeled using the conductor configuration of the transmission line set. The model data can then be compared to actual magnetic field data to determine an actual power flow of the line set Preferably, this modeling and comparison is accomplished through a computational analysis performed on a digital computer. Then, the selection process continues by S604 determining positions in a substantially planar area that is transverse to the transmission line set at the location where a predetermined<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> change in the power flow of the line set will result in a maximum change in the magnetic field at the positions. Preferably, this step is also accomplished through a computational analysis performed on a digital computer.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">The predetermined change in power flow of the line set may be a desired level of accuracy, such as 10 MW or 5 percent. This predetermined change in power flow is referred to herein as the "power resolution". Thus, for a vertical parallel transmission line set having a power flow of 50 MW / 200 MW, a monitoring system having a power resolution of 10 MW will detect a change resulting in a power flow of 60 MW / 210 MW.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 7</figref>, determining the conductor configuration and power flow of the transmission line set is accomplished through the steps of: S702 obtaining horizontal and vertical distances between each conductor and measuring points across the substantially planar area to determine the conductor configuration of the transmission line set in the planar area; S704 obtaining measured magnetic field values at said measuring points; S706 generating, through computation performed on a digital computer, predicted magnetic field values at each measuring point for a range of line set power flows; and S708 selecting the line set power flow where the predicted values have the best fit with the measured values.</p><p id="p0044" num="0044"><figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 8</figref> shows an exemplary planar area 322 that is transverse to a vertical parallel transmission line set 324. A plurality of measuring points 326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338 are established under the transmission line set 324 and across the substantially planar area 322 at a height, h, above the ground. A preferred height above the ground is four feet (the height of a standard permanent monitor placement). Also, a preferred spacing between the measuring points is one meter, and the measuring points extend for 30 meters on either side of the center of the transmission line set 324. For convenience, the measuring points 326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338 of <figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 8</figref> are shown in intervals of 10 meters.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045">Using a commercially available distance measuring device (such as an Impulse 100, by laser Technology, Inc. of Colorado), the horizontal distance and vertical distance between each measuring point and each conductor are collected. For instance, <figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 8</figref> shows a measuring point 326 located 30 meters from the center of the transmission line set 324, having a horizontal distance, d<sub>x</sub>, and a vertical distance, d<sub>y</sub>, between the measuring point 326 and the conductor 340. Of course, one of skill in the art will recognize that other means of obtaining the horizontal and vertical distances between each measuring point and each conductor may be utilized<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> within the scope of the invention described herein. The horizontal and vertical distances between all of the measuring points and all of the conductors establish specific geometric arrangement of each conductor in relation to the measuring points and to each other. This specific geometric arrangement is the conductor configuration.</p><p id="p0046" num="0046">Using a standard NIST (National Institute of Standards and Testing) calibrated gaussmeter (such as an Electromagnetic Field Radiation Tester, Model EMF-200A (range of 0.1 mG - 199.9 mG), manufactured by A.W. Sperry Instruments Inc., of Hauppauge, NY), magnetic field values are also collected at each measuring point. Preferably, horizontal and vertical vector components of the magnetic fields arc collected at each measuring point, but any magnetic field vector components that are needed could be collected (horizontal or vertical to line set, or 3-axis in any frame of reference, such as relative to the surface of the earth, etc.). Measurement of the values may be repeated and averaged. Further, measurement of both the distances and the magnetic field values may be repeated under different ambient conditions to establish conductor configuration and magnetic field profiles for the various ambient conditions. Still further, one of skill in the art will recognize that other means of obtaining the measured magnetic field vector component values may be utilized.</p><p id="p0047" num="0047">Using the conductor configuration and Biot-Savart modeling, predicted horizontal magnetic field values and predicted vertical magnetic field values are generated for a range of power flows of the transmission line set, or line set power flows. The individual conductors of a transmission line are assumed to carry the same current. The voltage of each transmission line is obtained by visual inspection cross-referenced with a power line mapping resource, as mentioned earlier. A power factor of 1.0 is assumed. A matrix of predicted magnetic field values is calculated using the conductor configuration for a range of power flows varied between zero and the maximum power rating of the transmission line set The line set power flow having predicted values that are a best fit with the measured values is then selected as the actual line set power flow.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048">The best fit determination is made by summing the absolute value of the differences between each measured magnetic field value and the corresponding predicted magnetic field value to determine a total error for each line set power flow, and selecting the line set power flow with the least total error.<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></p><p id="p0049" num="0049">Then, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 9</figref>, the preferred placement of monitors for power flow through the transmission line set is determined by: S902 obtaining predicted magnetic field values at each measuring point for the determined power flow of the transmission line set; S904 obtaining predicted magnetic field values at each measuring point for a power flow of the transmission line set where the determined power flow has changed by a predetermined power amount; S906 determining the differences between the predicted values for the changed power flow and the predicted values for the determined power flow for the magnetic field at each measuring point; and S908 selecting the measuring points having the maximum differences as the positions where a change in power flow through the line results in the maximum change in the magnetic field.</p><p id="p0050" num="0050">The predicted magnetic field values may have already been generated in calculating the matrix of predicted magnetic field values described above. The smallest increment of power change that one wishes to detect (i.e. the "power resolution") is selected as the predetermined power amount for the changed power flow. A preferred power resolution for a typical power flow monitoring system is 10 MW. The predicted horizontal and vertical magnetic field values for the changed power flow may also have already been generated in calculating the matrix of predicted magnetic field values described above. By determining the differences between the predicted values for the changed power flow and for the determined power flow, the measuring points having the maximum change in the magnetic field for the changed power flow are determined.</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0010">FIG. 10</figref>, a graphical method for determining the preferred placement of monitors includes the steps of: S1002 obtaining predicted horizontal magnetic field values and predicted vertical magnetic field values at each measuring point for the determined power flow of the transmission line set; S1004 obtaining predicted horizontal magnetic field values and predicted vertical magnetic field values at each measuring point for a power flow of the transmission line set where the determined power flow has changed by a predetermined power amount; S 1006 generating a horizontal magnetic field difference curve by taking the difference between the predicted horizontal magnetic field values for the changed power flow and the predicted horizontal magnetic field values for the determined power flow at each measuring point; S1008 generating a vertical magnetic field difference curve by taking the difference between the predicted vertical magnetic field values for the changed power flow and<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> the predicted vertical magnetic field values for the determined power flow at each measuring point; and S1010 selecting the maxima of the horizontal magnetic field difference curve and the vertical magnetic field difference curve.</p><p id="p0052" num="0052">Thus, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0011">FIG. 11</figref>, a method for monitoring power flow through an electric power transmission line set included the steps of: S1102 selecting positions for a preferred placement for a plurality of magnetic field monitors; S1104 placing magnetic field monitors at the selected positions for collecting magnetic field data; S1106 performing a computational analysis on the magnetic field data to determine a power flow through the transmission line set; and S1108 communicating said power flow to an end user.</p><p id="p0053" num="0053">Turning now to an example, <figref idrefs="f0012">FIG. 12</figref> shows the measured horizontal magnetic field values, and predicted horizontal magnetic field values for a range of power flows for a particular planar area transverse to a representative vertical parallel transmission line set. <figref idrefs="f0012">FIG. 13</figref> shows the measured vertical magnetic field values, and predicted vertical magnetic field values for a range of power flows for the transmission line set of <figref idrefs="f0012">FIG. 12</figref>. As shown graphically, the best fit of the predicted values to the measured values is a 50 MW / 200 MW power flow, with 50 MW flowing through the left transmission line, and 200 MW flowing through the right transmission line. A best fit analysis could also be performed through computation performed on a digital computer. As shown, there are areas 1202, 1204, 1302, 1304, 1306 where large changes in power flow result in only minimal change in the shape and magnitude of the predicted horizontal and vertical magnetic field values. Such areas are non-optimal for placing monitors to measure changes in power flowing through the transmission line set.</p><p id="p0054" num="0054">Thus, it is desirable to determine positions where a predetermined change in power flow through the line will result in a maximum change in the magnetic field. Continuing with the determined power flow of 50 MW / 200 MW of the example of <figref idrefs="f0012">FIGS. 12 and 13</figref>, <figref idrefs="f0013">FIG. 14</figref> shows a horizontal magnetic field difference curve generated by taking the difference between the predicted horizontal magnetic field values for an increased power flow of 10 MW in each transmission line (i.e. a 60 MW / 210 MW power flow) and the predicted horizontal magnetic field values for the determined power flow (i.e. 50 MW / 200 MW). Also shown is a vertical magnetic field difference curve generated by taking the difference between the predicted vertical magnetic field values for the 10 MW increased power flow and the predicted vertical magnetic field values for the determined power flow. The horizontal magnetic field difference<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> curve has maxima 1402 at the 0 meter position, and the vertical magnetic field difference curve has maxima 1404,1406 at -11 meters and 11 meters. The preferred positions for placement of magnetic field monitors are, therefore, at the measuring points located at -11 meters, 0, and 11 meters.</p><p id="p0055" num="0055">As an observation, it is noted that the preferred minimum number of magnetic field monitors will correspond to the three maxima of the horizontal and vertical magnetic field difference curves. However, additional accuracy may be obtained with the addition of other magnetic field monitors positioned in the substantially planar area, but at the expense of the additional monitors.</p><p id="p0056" num="0056">In the above description of the present invention, it should be recognized that the method for selecting a preferred placement of magnetic field monitors may be found as executable instructions contained on a computer readable medium. Additionally, the steps of determining a conductor configuration and a power flow of the transmission line set, and determining positions where a predetermined change in power flow results in a maximum change in the magnetic field at the positions, are practically accomplished through a computational analysis performed on a digital computer.</p><p id="p0057" num="0057">One of ordinary skill in the art will recognize that additional configurations and steps are possible. This detailed description, and particularly the specific details of the exemplary embodiments disclosed, is given primarily for clearness of understanding and no unnecessary limitations are to be understood therefrom, for modification will become obvious to those skilled in the art upon reading this disclosure</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56979329" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Verfahren zum Überwachen des durch eine Stromübertragungsleitung fließenden Stroms, das Folgendes beinhaltet:
<claim-text>Auswählen von Positionen für eine bevorzugte Platzierung für mehrere Magnetfeldmonitore (302, 304, 306, 307) durch (a) Ermitteln einer Leiterkonfiguration und eines Stromflusses des Übertragungsleitungssatzes (324) an einer Stelle entlang des Übertragungsleitungssatzes (324), und (b) Ermitteln von Positionen in einem im Wesentlichen planaren Bereich (322) transversal zu dem genannten Übertragungsleitungssatz (324) an dem genannten Ort, wo eine vorbestimmte Änderung des genannten Stromflusses in einer maximalen Änderung im Magnetfeld an den Positionen resultiert;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Platzieren der genannten Magnetfeldmonitore (302, 304, 306, 307) an den genannten Positionen zum Sammeln von Magnetfelddaten;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Durchführen einer Rechenanalyse an den genannten Magnetfelddaten, um einen Stromfluss durch den genannten Übertragungsleitungssatz (324) zu ermitteln; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Übermitteln des genannten Stromflusses zu einem Endbenutzer;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei der genannte Teilschritt des Ermittelns der Leiterkonfiguration und des Stromflusses des Übertragungsleitungssatzes (324) Folgendes beinhaltet:
<claim-text>Einholen von horizontalen und vertikalen Distanzen zwischen jedem Leiter (340) und mehreren Messpunkten (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) über den im Wesentlichen planaren Bereich (322), um die Leiterkonfiguration des Übertragungsleitungssatzes (324) zu ermitteln;<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>Einholen von gemessenen Magnetfeldwerten an den genannten Messpunkten (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338);</claim-text>
<claim-text>Erzeugen, durch auf einem digitalen Computer ausgeführte Berechnungen, von vorhergesagten Magnetfeldwerten an jedem Messpunkt (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) für eine Reihe von Leitungssatzstromflüssen; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Auswählen des Leitungssatzstromflusses, an dem die vorhergesagten Werte am besten mit den Messwerten übereinstimmen.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, wobei der Teilschritt des Auswählens des Leitungsstromflusses Folgendes beinhaltet:
<claim-text>Addieren des absoluten Wertes der Differenzen zwischen jedem gemessenen Magnetfeldwert und des entsprechenden vorhergesagten Magnetfeldwerts, um einen Gesamtfehler für jeden Leitungssatzstromfluss zu ermitteln; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Auswählen des Leitungssatzstromflusses mit dem geringsten Gesamtfehler als die beste Übereinstimmung mit den Messwerten.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, wobei der Teilschritt des Ermittelns von Positionen, wo eine Änderung des Stromflusses des Leitungssatzes in einer maximalen Änderung im Magnetfeld an den Positionen resultiert, Folgendes beinhaltet:
<claim-text>Einholen von vorhergesagten Magnetfeldwerten an jedem Messpunkt (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) für den ermittelten Stromfluss des Übertragungsleitungssatzes (324);</claim-text>
<claim-text>Einholen von vorhergesagten Magnetfeldwerten an jedem Messpunkt (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) für einen Stromfluss des Übertragungsleitungssatzes (324), wo sich<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --> der ermittelte Stromfluss um einen vorbestimmten Betrag geändert hat;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Ermitteln der Differenzen zwischen den vorhergesagten Werten für den geänderten Stromfluss und den vorhergesagten Werten für den ermittelten Stromfluss für das Magnetfeld an jedem Messpunkt (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338); und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Auswählen der Messpunkte (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) mit den maximalen Differenzen als die Positionen, wo eine Änderung im Stromfluss des Leitungssatzes (324) in einer maximalen Änderung im Magnetfeld an den Positionen resultiert.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>System zum Überwachen des durch einen Stromübertragungsleitungssatz fließenden Stroms, wobei das genannte System Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>mehrere Magnetfeldmonitore (302, 304, 306, 307), die an gewählten Positionen in einem im Wesentlichen planaren Bereich (322) transversal zu dem Übertragungsleitungssatz (324) platziert sind, wobei die genannten Positionen ausgewählt werden durch:
<claim-text>Ermitteln einer Leiterkonfiguration und eines Stromflusses des Übertragungsleitungssatzes in dem im Wesentlichen planaren Bereich durch: (a) Einholen von horizontalen und vertikalen Distanzen zwischen jedem Leiter (340) und mehreren Messpunkten (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) über den im Wesentlichen planaren Bereich (322), um die Leiterkonfiguration der Übertragungsleitung (324) zu ermitteln; (b) Einholen von gemessenen Magnetfeldwerten an den genannten Messpunkten (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338); (c) Erzeugen, durch eine von einem digitalen Computer durchgeführte Berechnung, von vorhergesagten Magnetfeldwerten an jedem Messpunkt (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) für eine Reihe von Leitungsstromflüssen; und<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> (d) Auswählen des Leitungssatzstromflusses, wo die vorhergesagten Werte am besten mit den Messwerten übereinstimmen; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Ermitteln von Positionen in dem im Wesentlichen planaren Bereich (322), wo eine vorbestimmte Änderung im Stromfluss des Leitungssatzes in einer maximalen Änderung im Magnetfeld an den Positionen resultiert; und</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Zentralverarbeitungseinrichtung (308) in Kommunikation mit den genannten mehreren Magnetfeldmonitoren (302, 304, 306, 307) zum Übermitteln der Stromflussermittlung zu einem Endbenutzer.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>System nach Anspruch 4, wobei die Positionen in dem im Wesentlichen planaren Bereich (322), wo eine Änderung im Stromfluss durch die Leitung in einer maximalen Änderung im Magnetfeld an den Positionen resultiert, ermittelt werden durch:
<claim-text>Einholen von vorhergesagten Magnetfeldwerten an jedem Messpunkt (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) für den ermittelten Stromfluss des Übertragungsleitungssatzes (324);</claim-text>
<claim-text>Einholen von vorhergesagten Magnetfeldwerten an jedem Messpunkt (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) für einen Stromfluss des Übertragungsleitungssatzes (324), wo sich der ermittelte Stromfluss um einen vorbestimmten Betrag geändert hat;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Ermitteln der Differenzen zwischen den vorhergesagten Werten für den geänderten Stromfluss und den vorhergesagten Werten für den ermittelten Stromfluss an jedem Messpunkt (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338); und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Auswählen der Messpunkte (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) mit den maximalen Differenzen als die Positionen, wo eine Änderung im Stromfluss des Leitungssatzes (324) in<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --> einer maximalen Änderung im Magnetfeld an den Positionen resultiert.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>System nach Anspruch 4, wobei die Positionen in dem im Wesentlichen planaren Bereich (322), wo eine Änderung im Stromfluss durch die Leitung in einer maximalen Änderung im Magnetfeld an den Positionen resultiert, ermittelt werden durch:
<claim-text>Einholen von vorhergesagten horizontalen Magnetfeldwerten und vorhergesagten vertikalen Magnetfeldwerten an jedem Messpunkt (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) für den ermittelten Stromfluss des Übertragungsleitungssatzes (324);</claim-text>
<claim-text>Einholen von vorhergesagten horizontalen Magnetfeldwerten und vorhergesagten vertikalen Magnetfeldwerten an jedem Messpunkt (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) für einen Stromfluss des Übertragungsleitungssatzes (324), wo sich der ermittelte Stromfluss um einen vorbestimmten Strombetrag geändert hat;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Erzeugen einer horizontalen Magnetfelddifferenzkurve durch Nehmen der Differenz zwischen den vorhergesagten horizontalen Magnetfeldwerten für den geänderten Stromfluss und den vorhergesagten horizontalen Magnetfeldwerten für den ermittelten Stromfluss an jedem Messpunkt;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Erzeugen einer vertikalen Magnetfelddifferenzkurve durch Nehmen der Differenz zwischen den vorhergesagten vertikalen Magnetfeldwerten für den geänderten Stromfluss und den vorhergesagten vertikalen Magnetfeldwerten für den ermittelten Stromfluss an jedem Messpunkt (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338);</claim-text>
<claim-text>Auswählen der Maxima der horizontalen Magnetfelddifferenzkurve und der vertikalen Magnetfelddifferenzkurve als die Positionen, wo eine<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --> Änderung im Stromfluss durch die Leitung in einer maximalen Änderung im Magnetfeld an den Positionen resultiert.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Computerlesbares Medium mit von einem Computer ausführbaren Befehlen zum Ausführen eines Verfahrens zum Auswählen von Positionen für eine bevorzugte Platzierung für mehrere Magnetfeldmonitore (302, 304, 306, 307) zum Überwachen von Stromfluss durch einen Stromübertragungsleitungssatz (324), wobei das genannte Verfahren Folgendes beinhaltet:
<claim-text>Ermitteln einer Leiterkonfiguration und eines Stromflusses des Übertragungsleitungssatzes (324) an einer Stelle entlang des Übertragungsleitungssatzes (324) durch:
<claim-text>Einholen von horizontalen und vertikalen Distanzen zwischen jedem Leiter (340) und mehreren Messpunkten (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) über einen im Wesentlichen planaren Bereich (322) transversal zu dem Übertragungsleitungssatz (324), um die detaillierte Leiterkonfiguration des Übertragungsleitungssatzes (324) an der Stelle entlang der Leitung zu ermitteln;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Einholen von Magnetfeldwerten an den genannten Messpunkten (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338);</claim-text>
<claim-text>Erzeugen von vorhergesagten Magnetfeldwerten an jedem Messpunkt (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) für eine Reihe von Leitungssatzstromflüssen; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Auswählen des Leitungssatzstromflusses, wo die vorhergesagten Werte am besten mit den Messwerten übereinstimmen; und</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>Ermitteln von Positionen in dem im Wesentlichen planaren Bereich (322) an der Stelle, an der eine vorbestimmte Änderung im Stromfluss durch den Leitungssatz (324) in einer maximalen Änderung im Magnetfeld an den<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --> Positionen resultiert, um dadurch die bevorzugte Platzierung der Monitore (302, 304, 306, 307) anzuzeigen.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Computerlesbares Medium nach Anspruch 7, wobei die vom Computer ausführbaren Befehle zum Ausführen des genannten Schrittes zum Ermitteln von Positionen, wo eine Änderung im Stromfluss des Leitungssatzes in einer maximalen Änderung im Magnetfeld an den Positionen resultiert, Folgendes beinhaltet:
<claim-text>Einholen von vorhergesagten Magnetfeldwerten an jedem Messpunkt (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) für den ermittelten Stromfluss des Übertragungsleitungssatzes (324);</claim-text>
<claim-text>Einholen von vorhergesagten Magnetfeldwerten an jedem Messpunkt (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) für einen Stromfluss des Übertragungsleitungssatzes (324), wo sich der ermittelte Stromfluss um einen vorbestimmten Strombetrag geändert hat;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Ermitteln der Differenzen zwischen den vorhergesagten Werten für den geänderten Stromfluss und den vorhergesagten Werten für den ermittelten Stromfluss für die horizontalen Magnetfeldwerte und die vertikalen Magnetfeldwerte an jedem Messpunkt (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338); und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Auswählen der Messpunkte (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) mit den maximalen Differenzen als die Positionen, wo eine Änderung im Stromfluss des Leitungssatzes (324) in einer maximalen Änderung im Magnetfeld an den Positionen resultiert.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Computerlesbares Medium nach Anspruch 7, wobei die von einem Computer ausführbaren Befehle zum Ausführen des genannten Schrittes des Ermittelns von Positionen, wo eine Änderung im Stromfluss des Leitungssatzes in einer<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --> maximalen Änderung im Magnetfeld an den Positionen resultiert, Folgendes beinhaltet:
<claim-text>Einholen von vorhergesagten horizontalen Magnetfeldwerten und vorhergesagten vertikalen Magnetfeldwerten an jedem Messpunkt (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) für den ermittelten Stromfluss des Übertragungsleitungssatzes (324);</claim-text>
<claim-text>Einholen von vorhergesagten horizontalen Magnetfeldwerten und vorhergesagten vertikalen Magnetfeldwerten an jedem Messpunkt (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) für einen Stromfluss des Übertragungsleitungssatzes (324), wo sich der ermittelte Stromfluss um einen vorbestimmten Strombetrag geändert hat;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Erzeugen einer horizontalen Magnetfelddifferenzkurve durch Nehmen der Differenz zwischen den vorhergesagten horizontalen Magnetfeldwerten für den geänderten Stromfluss und den vorhergesagten horizontalen Magnetfeldwerten für den ermittelten Stromfluss an jedem Messpunkt;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Erzeugen einer vertikalen Magnetfelddifferenzkurve durch Nehmen der Differenz zwischen den vorhergesagten vertikalen Magnetfeldwerten für den geänderten Stromfluss und den vorhergesagten vertikalen Magnetfeldwerten für den ermittelten Stromfluss an jedem Messpunkt (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338); und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Auswählen der Maxima der horizontalen Magnetfelddifferenzkurve und der vertikalen Magnetfelddifferenzkurve als die bevorzugte Platzierung für Magnetfeldmonitore (302, 304, 306, 307) zum Messen von Stromfluss durch einen Stromübertragungsleistungssatz.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56979330" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A method for monitoring the power flowing through an electric power transmission line set, comprising:
<claim-text>selecting positions for a preferred placement for a plurality of magnetic field monitors (302, 304, 306, 307) by (a) determining a conductor configuration and a power flow of the transmission line set (324) at a location along the transmission line set (324), and (b) determining positions in a substantially planar area (322) that is transverse to said transmission line set (324) at said location where a predetermined change in said power flow results in a maximum change in the magnetic field at the positions;</claim-text>
<claim-text>placing said magnetic field monitors (302, 304, 306, 307) at said selected positions for collecting magnetic field data;</claim-text>
<claim-text>performing a computational analysis on said magnetic field data to determine a power flow through said transmission line set (324); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>communicating said power flow to an end user;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said sub-step of determining the conductor configuration and power flow of the transmission line set (324) includes:
<claim-text>obtaining horizontal and vertical distances between each conductor (340) and a plurality of measuring points (326, 328, 330. 332, 334, 336, 338) across the substantially planar area (322) to determine the conductor configuration of the transmission line set (324);</claim-text>
<claim-text>obtaining measured magnetic field values at said measuring points (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338);</claim-text>
<claim-text>generating, through computation performed on a digital computer, predicted magnetic field values at each measuring point (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) for a range of line set power flows; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>selecting the line set power flow where the predicted values have a best fit with the measured values.</claim-text></claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The method of claim 1, wherein the sub-step of selecting the line set power flow includes:
<claim-text>summing the absolute value of the differences between each measured magnetic field value and the corresponding predicted magnetic field value to determine a total error for each line set power flow; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>selecting the line set power flow with the least total error as the best fit with the measured values.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The method of claim 1, wherein the sub-step of determining positions where a change in the power flow of the line set results in a maximum change in magnetic field at the positions includes:
<claim-text>obtaining predicted magnetic field values at each measuring point (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) for the determined power flow of the transmission line set (324);</claim-text>
<claim-text>obtaining predicted magnetic field values at each measuring point (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) for a power flow of the transmission line set (324) where the determined power flow has changed by a predetermined amount</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining the differences between the predicted values for the changed power flow and the predicted values for the determined power flow for the magnetic field at each measuring point (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>selecting the measuring points (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) having the maximum differences as the positions where a change in the power flow of the line set (324) results in a maximum change in the magnetic field at the positions.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>A system for monitoring the power flowing through an electric power transmission line set, said system comprising:
<claim-text>a plurality of magnetic field monitors (302, 304, 306, 307) placed at selected positions in a substantially planar area (322) that is transverse to the transmission line set (324), said positions selected by:
<claim-text>determining a conductor configuration and a power flow of the transmission line set in the substantially planar area by: (a) obtaining horizontal and vertical distances between each conductor (340) and a plurality of measuring points (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) across the substantially planar area (322) to determine the<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> conductor configuration of the transmission line set (324); (b) obtaining measured magnetic field values at said measuring points (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338); (c) generating, through computation performed on a digital computer, predicted magnetic field values at each measuring point (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) for a range of line set power flows: and (d) selecting the line set power flow where the predicted values have a best fit with the measured values; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining positions in the substantially planar area (322) where a predetermined change in the power flow of the line set results in a maximum change in the magnetic field at the positions; and</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>a central processing facility (308) in communication with said plurality of magnetic field monitors (302, 304, 306, 307) for communicating the power flow determination to an end user.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The system of claim 4, wherein the positions in the substantially planar area (322) where a change in power flow through the line results in a maximum change in magnetic field at the positions are determined by:
<claim-text>obtaining predicted magnetic field values at each measuring point (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) for the determined power flow of the transmission line set (324);</claim-text>
<claim-text>obtaining predicted magnetic field values at each measuring point (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) for a power flow of the transmission line set (324) where the determined power flow has changed by a predetermined amount;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining the differences between the predicted values for the changed power flow and the predicted values for the determined power flow at each measuring point (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>selecting the measuring points (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) having the maximum differences as the positions where a change in the power flow of the line set (324) results in a maximum change in the magnetic field at the positions.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The system of claim 4, wherein the positions in the substantially planar area (322) where a change in power flow through the line results in a maximum change in magnetic field at the positions are determined by:
<claim-text>obtaining predicted horizontal magnetic field values and predicted vertical magnetic field values at each measuring point (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) for the determined power flow of the transmission line set (324);</claim-text>
<claim-text>obtaining predicted horizontal magnetic field values and predicted vertical magnetic field values at each measuring point (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) for a power flow of the transmission line set (324) where the determined power flow has changed by a predetermined power amount;</claim-text>
<claim-text>generating a horizontal magnetic field difference curve by taking the difference between the predicted horizontal magnetic field values for the changed power flow and the predicted horizontal magnetic field values for the determined power flow at each measuring point;</claim-text>
<claim-text>generating a vertical magnetic field difference curve by taking the difference between the predicted vertical magnetic field values for the changed power flow and the predicted vertical magnetic field values for the determined power flow at each measuring point (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338);</claim-text>
<claim-text>selecting the maxima of the horizontal magnetic field difference curve and the vertical magnetic field difference curve as the positions where a change in power flow through the line results in a maximum change in the magnetic field at the positions.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>A computer readable medium having computer executable instructions for performing a method for selecting positions for a preferred placement for a plurality of magnetic field monitors (302, 304, 306, 307) for monitoring power flow through an electric power transmission line set (324), said method comprising:
<claim-text>determining a conductor configuration and a power flow of the transmission line set (324) at a location along the transmission line set (324) by:
<claim-text>obtaining horizontal and vertical distances between each conductor (340) and a plurality of measuring points (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) across a substantially planar area (322) that is transverse to the transmission line set (324) to determine the detailed conductor configuration of the transmission line set (324) at the location along the line;<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>obtaining magnetic field values at said measuring points (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338);</claim-text>
<claim-text>generating predicted magnetic field values at each measuring point (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) for a range of line set power flows; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>selecting the line set power flow where the predicted values have a best fit with the measured values; and</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>determining positions in the substantially planar area (322) at the location where a predetermined change in the power flow through the line set (324) results in a maximum change in the magnetic field at the positions, thereby indicating the preferred placement of the monitors (302, 304, 306, 307).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The computer readable medium of claim 7, wherein the computer executable instructions for performing said step of determining positions where a change in the power flow of the line set results in a maximum change in the magnetic field at the positions includes:
<claim-text>obtaining predicted magnetic field values at each measuring point (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) for the determined power flow of the transmission line set (324);</claim-text>
<claim-text>obtaining predicted magnetic field values at each measuring point (326, 328, 330. 332, 334, 336, 338) for a power flow of the transmission line set (324) where the determined power flow has changed by a predetermined power amount;</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining the differences between the predicted values for the changed power flow and the predicted values for the determined power flow for the horizontal magnetic field values and the vertical magnetic field values at each measuring point (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>selecting the measuring points (326, 328, 330. 332, 334, 336, 338) having the maximum differences as the positions where a change in the power flow of the line set results (324) in a maximum change in the magnetic field at the positions.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The computer readable medium of claim 7, wherein the computer executable instructions for performing said step of determining positions where a change in the power flow of the line set results in a maximum change in magnetic field at the positions includes:
<claim-text>obtaining predicted horizontal magnetic field values and predicted vertical magnetic field values at each measuring point (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) for the determined power flow of the transmission line set (324);</claim-text>
<claim-text>obtaining predicted horizontal magnetic field values and predicted vertical magnetic field values at each measuring point (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) for a power flow of the transmission line set (324) where the determined power flow has changed by a predetermined power amount;</claim-text>
<claim-text>generating a horizontal magnetic field difference curve by taking the difference between the predicted horizontal magnetic field values for the changed power flow and the predicted horizontal magnetic field values for the determined power flow at each measuring point;</claim-text>
<claim-text>generating a vertical magnetic field difference curve by taking the difference between the predicted vertical magnetic field values for the changed power flow and the predicted vertical magnetic field values for the determined power flow at each measuring point (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>selecting the maxima of the horizontal magnetic field difference curve and the vertical magnetic field difference curve as the preferred placement for magnetic field monitors (302, 304, 306, 307) for measuring power flow through an electric power transmission line set.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56979331" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Procédé de surveillance de la puissance s'écoulant à travers un ensemble de lignes de transmission de puissance électrique, comprenant :
<claim-text>la sélection de positions pour un placement préféré d'une pluralité de contrôleurs de champ magnétique (302, 304, 306, 307) en (a) déterminant une configuration de conducteurs et un flux de puissance de l'ensemble de lignes de transmission (324) à un emplacement le long de l'ensemble de lignes de transmission (324), et (b) déterminant des positions dans une zone sensiblement plane (322) transversale audit ensemble de lignes de transmission (324) audit emplacement où un changement prédéterminé dudit flux de puissance entraîne un changement maximum du champ magnétique aux positions ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>le placement desdits contrôleurs de champ magnétique (302, 304, 306, 307) auxdites positions sélectionnées pour collecter des données de champ magnétique ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'exécution d'une analyse de calcul sur lesdites données de champ magnétique pour déterminer un flux de puissance à travers ledit ensemble de lignes de transmission (324) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>la communication dudit flux de puissance à un utilisateur final ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel ladite sous-étape de détermination de la configuration de conducteurs et du flux de puissance de l'ensemble de lignes de transmission (324) comporte :
<claim-text>l'obtention de distances horizontales et verticales entre chaque conducteur (340) et une pluralité de points de mesure (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) sur toute la zone sensiblement plane (322) afin de déterminer la configuration de conducteurs de l'ensemble de lignes de transmission (324) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'obtention de valeurs de champ magnétique mesurées auxdits points de mesure (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>la génération, par un calcul exécuté sur un ordinateur numérique, de valeurs de champ magnétique prédites à chaque point de mesure (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) pour une plage de flux de puissance d'ensemble de lignes ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>la sélection du flux de puissance d'ensemble de lignes où les valeurs prédites présentent le meilleur ajustement avec les valeurs mesurées.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, dans lequel la sous-étape de sélection du flux de puissance d'ensemble de lignes comporte :
<claim-text>la sommation de la valeur absolue des différences entre chaque valeur de champ magnétique mesurée et la valeur de champ magnétique prédite correspondante pour déterminer une erreur totale pour chaque flux de puissance d'ensemble de lignes ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>la sélection du flux de puissance d'ensemble de lignes ayant la plus petite erreur totale comme celui ayant le meilleur ajustement avec les valeurs mesurées.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, dans lequel la sous-étape de détermination de positions où un changement du flux de puissance de l'ensemble de lignes entraîne un changement maximum du champ magnétique aux positions comporte :
<claim-text>l'obtention de valeurs de champ magnétique prédites à chaque point de mesure (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) pour le flux de puissance déterminé de l'ensemble de lignes de transmission (324) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'obtention de valeurs de champ magnétique prédites à chaque point de mesure (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) pour un flux de puissance de l'ensemble de lignes de transmission (324) où le flux de puissance prédéterminé a changé par une quantité prédéterminée ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>la détermination des différences entre les valeurs prédites du flux de puissance changé et les valeurs prédites du flux de puissance prédéterminé du champ magnétique à chaque point de mesure (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>la sélection des points de mesure (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) ayant les différences maximum comme positions où un changement du flux de puissance de l'ensemble de lignes (324) entraîne un changement maximum du champ magnétique aux positions.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Système de surveillance de la puissance s'écoulant à travers un ensemble de lignes de transmission de puissance électrique, ledit système comprenant :
<claim-text>une pluralité de contrôleurs de champ magnétique (302, 304, 306, 307) placés à des positions sélectionnées dans une zone sensiblement plane (322) qui est transversale audit ensemble de transmission de lignes (324), lesdites positions étant sélectionnées en :
<claim-text>déterminant une configuration de conducteurs et un flux de puissance de l'ensemble de lignes de transmission dans la zone sensiblement plane en : (a) obtenant des distances horizontale et verticale entre chaque conducteur (340) et une pluralité de points de mesure (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) sur toute la zone sensiblement plane (322) pour déterminer la configuration de conducteurs de l'ensemble de lignes de transmission (324) ; (b) obtenant des valeurs de champ magnétique mesurées auxdits points de mesure (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) ; (c) générant, par un calcul exécuté sur un ordinateur numérique, des valeurs de champ magnétique prédites à chaque point de mesure (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) pour une plage de flux de puissance d'ensemble de lignes ; et (d) sélectionnant le flux de puissance d'ensemble de lignes où les valeurs prédites présentent le meilleur ajustement avec les valeurs mesurées ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>déterminant des positions dans la zone sensiblement plane (322) où un<!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --> changement prédéterminé dudit flux de puissance de l'ensemble de lignes entraîne un changement maximum du champ magnétique aux positions ; et</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text>une installation de traitement centrale (308) en communication avec ladite pluralité de contrôleurs de champ magnétique (302, 304, 306, 307) pour communiquer la détermination du flux de puissance à un utilisateur final.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Système selon la revendication 4, dans lequel les positions dans la zone sensiblement plane (322) où un changement de flux de puissance à travers la ligne entraîne un changement maximum du champ magnétique aux positions sont déterminées en :
<claim-text>obtenant des valeurs de champ magnétique prédites à chaque point de mesure (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) pour le flux de puissance déterminé de l'ensemble de lignes de transmission (324) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>obtenant des valeurs de champ magnétique prédites à chaque point de mesure (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) pour un flux de puissance de l'ensemble de lignes de transmission (324) où le flux de puissance prédéterminé a changé par une quantité prédéterminée ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>déterminant les différences entre les valeurs prédites du flux de puissance changé et les valeurs prédites du flux de puissance prédéterminé à chaque point de mesure (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>sélectionnant les points de mesure (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) ayant les différences maximum comme positions où un changement du flux de puissance de l'ensemble de lignes (324) entraîne un changement maximum du champ magnétique aux positions.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Système selon la revendication 4, dans lequel les positions dans la zone sensiblement plane (322) où un changement du flux de puissance à travers la ligne entraîne un changement maximum du champ magnétique aux positions sont déterminées en :
<claim-text>obtenant des valeurs de champ magnétique horizontal prédites et des valeurs de champ magnétique vertical prédites à chaque point de mesure (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) pour le flux de puissance déterminé de l'ensemble de lignes de transmission (324) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>obtenant des valeurs de champ magnétique horizontal prédites et des valeurs de champ magnétique vertical prédites à chaque point de mesure (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) pour un flux de puissance de l'ensemble de lignes de transmission (324) où le flux de puissance prédéterminé a changé par une quantité de puissance prédéterminée ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>générant une courbe de différence de champ magnétique horizontal en utilisant la<!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --> différence entre les valeurs de champ magnétique horizontal prédites du flux de puissance changé et les valeurs de champ magnétique horizontal prédites du flux de puissance déterminé à chaque point de mesure ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>générant une courbe de différence de champ magnétique vertical en utilisant la différence entre les valeurs de champ magnétique vertical prédites du flux de puissance changé et les valeurs de champ magnétique vertical prédites du flux de puissance déterminé à chaque point de mesure (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>sélectionnant les maxima de la courbe de différence de champ magnétique horizontal et de la courbe de différence de champ magnétique vertical comme positions où un changement du flux de puissance à travers la ligne entraîne un changement maximum du champ magnétique aux positions.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Support lisible par ordinateur ayant des instructions exécutables par ordinateur pour exécuter un procédé de sélection de positions pour un placement préféré d'une pluralité de contrôleurs de champ magnétique (302, 304, 306, 307) pour surveiller un flux de puissance à travers un ensemble de lignes de transmission de puissance électrique, ledit procédé comprenant :
<claim-text>la détermination d'une configuration de conducteurs et d'un flux de puissance de l'ensemble de lignes de transmission (324) à un emplacement le long de l'ensemble de lignes de transmission (324) en</claim-text>
<claim-text>obtenant des distances horizontales et verticales entre chaque conducteur (340) et une pluralité de points de mesure (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) sur toute une zone sensiblement plane (322) transversale à l'ensemble de lignes de transmission (324) pour déterminer la configuration de conducteurs détaillée de l'ensemble de lignes de transmission (324) à l'emplacement le long de la ligne ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>obtenant des valeurs de champ magnétique auxdits points de mesure (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>générant des valeurs de champ magnétique prédites à chaque point de mesure (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) pour une plage de flux de puissance d'ensemble de lignes ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>sélectionnant le flux de puissance d'ensemble de lignes où les valeurs prédites présentent le meilleur ajustement avec les valeurs mesurées ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>déterminant des positions dans la zone sensiblement plane (322) à l'emplacement où un changement prédéterminé dudit flux de puissance de l'ensemble de lignes (324) entraîne un changement maximum du champ magnétique aux positions, indiquant ainsi le placement préféré des contrôleurs (302, 304, 306, 307).</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Support lisible par ordinateur selon la revendication 7, dans lequel les instructions exécutables par ordinateur pour exécuter ladite étape de détermination de positions où un changement dudit flux de puissance de l'ensemble de lignes entraîne un changement maximum du champ magnétique aux positions comporte :
<claim-text>l'obtention de valeurs de champ magnétique prédites à chaque point de mesure (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) pour le flux de puissance déterminé de l'ensemble de lignes de transmission (324) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'obtention de valeurs de champ magnétique prédites à chaque point de mesure (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) pour un flux de puissance de l'ensemble de lignes de transmission (324) où le flux de puissance prédéterminé a changé par une quantité de puissance prédéterminée ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>la détermination des différences entre les valeurs prédites du flux de puissance changé et les valeurs prédites du flux de puissance prédéterminé pour les valeurs de champ magnétique horizontal et les valeurs de champ magnétique vertical à chaque point de mesure (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>la sélection des points de mesure (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) ayant les différences maximum comme positions où un changement du flux de puissance de l'ensemble de lignes (324) entraîne un changement maximum du champ magnétique aux positions.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Support lisible par ordinateur selon la revendication 7, dans lequel les instructions exécutables par ordinateur pour exécuter ladite étape de détermination de positions où un changement dudit flux de puissance de l'ensemble de lignes entraîne un changement maximum du champ magnétique aux positions comporte :
<claim-text>l'obtention de valeurs de champ magnétique horizontal prédites et de valeurs de champ magnétique vertical prédites à chaque point de mesure (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) pour le flux de puissance déterminé de l'ensemble de lignes de transmission (324);</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'obtention de valeurs de champ magnétique horizontal prédites et de valeurs de champ magnétique vertical prédites à chaque point de mesure (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) pour un flux de puissance de l'ensemble de lignes de transmission (324) où le flux de puissance prédéterminé a changé par une quantité prédéterminée ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>la génération d'une courbe de différence de champ magnétique horizontal en utilisant la différence entre les valeurs de champ magnétique horizontal prédites du flux de puissance changé et les valeurs de champ magnétique horizontal prédites du flux de puissance déterminé à chaque point de mesure ;<!-- EPO <DP n="36"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>la génération d'une courbe de différence de champ magnétique vertical en utilisant la différence entre les valeurs de champ magnétique vertical prédites du flux de puissance changé et les valeurs de champ magnétique vertical prédites du flux de puissance déterminé à chaque point de mesure (326, 328, 330, 332, 334, 336, 338) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>la sélection des maxima de la courbe de différence de champ magnétique horizontal et de la courbe de différence de champ magnétique vertical comme le placement préféré des contrôleurs de champ magnétique (302, 304, 306, 307) pour mesurer un flux de puissance à travers un ensemble de lignes de transmission de puissance électrique.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16668837" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="37"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1a,1b,1c,1d,1e,1f"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="158" he="224" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="38"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="165" he="200" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="39"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="159" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="40"> --><figure id="f0004" num="4"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="151" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="41"> --><figure id="f0005" num="5"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="159" he="158" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="42"> --><figure id="f0006" num="6"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="117" he="161" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="43"> --><figure id="f0007" num="7"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="112" he="223" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="44"> --><figure id="f0008" num="8"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="156" he="202" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="45"> --><figure id="f0009" num="9"><img id="if0009" file="imgf0009.tif" wi="116" he="196" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="46"> --><figure id="f0010" num="10"><img id="if0010" file="imgf0010.tif" wi="118" he="228" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="47"> --><figure id="f0011" num="11"><img id="if0011" file="imgf0011.tif" wi="116" he="214" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="48"> --><figure id="f0012" num="12,13"><img id="if0012" file="imgf0012.tif" wi="150" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="49"> --><figure id="f0013" num="14"><img id="if0013" file="imgf0013.tif" wi="143" he="183" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
