<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2484472-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2484472" kind="B1" date="20140101" family-id="41228799" file-reference-id="306767" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146552948" ucid="EP-2484472-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2484472</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-12165045-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154826871" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12165045</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20090331</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP168030224" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12165045.1</doc-number><date>20090331</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140455188" ucid="EP-09250981-A" linkage-type="3" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>09250981</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20090331</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140445587" ucid="US-18661508-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>18661508</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20080806</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130717</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988114122" load-source="docdb">B23P  25/00        20060101ALI20120705BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988118677" load-source="docdb">B23D  43/04        20060101ALI20120705BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988119952" load-source="docdb">B23D  37/22        20060101ALI20120705BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988127195" load-source="docdb">B23D  37/04        20060101AFI20120705BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2073219735" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T  83/283       20150401 LA20150410BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2073221131" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T  83/293       20150401 LA20150410BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2073224590" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T  83/0414      20150401 LA20150410BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2102520596" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 407/16        20130101 LA20150123BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2102521757" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 409/400175    20130101 LA20150123BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2102522584" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B23D2043/025       20130101 LA20150124BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2102524007" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T  29/5176      20130101 LA20150123BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2102524641" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B23P  25/006       20130101 FI20150124BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2102524920" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B23D  37/22        20130101 LI20150124BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2102525921" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B23D  43/04        20130101 LI20150124BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2102529717" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T  29/5147      20130101 LA20150123BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2102532573" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T  29/49995     20130101 LA20150123BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2102533895" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T  29/49321     20130101 LA20150123BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2102534638" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T  29/49316     20130101 LA20150123BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2102534774" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 409/40105     20130101 LA20150123BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2102535312" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 409/405775    20130101 LA20150123BCEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132191328" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Maschinelle Bearbeitung und Schneidwerkzeug</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132191329" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Machining process and cutting tool</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132191330" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Procédé d'usinage et outil de découpe</invention-title></technical-data><related-documents><relation type="division"><child-doc ucid="EP-12165045-A"><document-id load-source="patent-office" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12165045</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20090331</date></document-id></child-doc><parent-doc ucid="EP-09250981.9"><document-id load-source="patent-office" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>09250981.9</doc-number><date>20090331</date></document-id></parent-doc></relation></related-documents><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918158410" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>UNITED TECHNOLOGIES CORP</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918152280" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>UNITED TECHNOLOGIES CORPORATION</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918170931" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>EL-WARDANY TAHANY IBRAHIM</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918170077" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>EL-WARDANY, TAHANY IBRAHIM</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918995895" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>EL-WARDANY, TAHANY IBRAHIM</last-name><address><street>14 C West Lane</street><city>Bloomfield, CT Connecticut 06002</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918134990" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>BURLATSKY SERGEI F</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918161096" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>BURLATSKY, SERGEI F.</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918995892" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>BURLATSKY, SERGEI F.</last-name><address><street>50 Fuller Drive</street><city>West Hartford, CT Connecticut 06117</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918135453" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>GUO CHANGSHENG</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918142604" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>GUO, CHANGSHENG</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918995894" load-source="patent-office" sequence="3" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>GUO, CHANGSHENG</last-name><address><street>132 Lisa Drive</street><city>South Windsor, CT Connecticut 06074</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918173875" load-source="docdb" sequence="4" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>SCHMIDT WAYDE R</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918135296" load-source="docdb" sequence="4" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>SCHMIDT, WAYDE R.</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918995893" load-source="patent-office" sequence="4" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>SCHMIDT, WAYDE R.</last-name><address><street>7 Amberg Drive</street><city>Pomfret Center, CT Connecticut 06259</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918995897" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>United Technologies Corporation</last-name><iid>100823961</iid><address><street>One Financial Plaza</street><city>Hartford, CT 06101</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918995896" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Leckey, David Herbert</last-name><iid>100034578</iid><address><street>Dehns St Bride's House 10 Salisbury Square</street><city>London EC4Y 8JD</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548880487" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548880488" load-source="docdb">GB</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63957007" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001"><b>BACKGROUND</b></heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">This disclosure relates to a cutting tool and a machining system.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002">A rotor of a typical gas turbine can have more than one hundred blades that are secured to rotating disks. The blade/disk attachment scheme includes providing a root on each blade that is secured to the disk. One type of root used to attach blades, commonly referred to as a "fir tree," includes a convoluted section that has a complementarily shaped slot in the disk periphery.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">Broaching is one common method used to manufacture fir tree slots. Broaching nickel-based super-alloys may induce undesired surface characteristics such as excessive material strain hardening and surface microstructure alteration, which typically results in an uneven surface due to deflection during machining. A white-etched layer (WEL) on the surface is one indication of undesired surface characteristics. Aside from the high cost of the broach tools and limited tool life, part scrap rate will increase due to the defected surface integrity.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">Several mechanical-based approaches are used to remove some of these undesired surface characteristics that remain after broaching. The efficiency of these approaches depends on the thickness of the WEL and depth of surface microstructure alteration. For example, the broached disk typically is moved to a second machining setup to perform post-processing operations to remove the undesired surface characteristics.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">Some known post-processing operations include performing thermal treatment on the broached part by heating and rapid cooling, induction heating, and more recently, laser heat-treating. Such thermal treatment has typically been employed to increase surface hardness subsequent to broaching.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">Although heating and rapid cooling increases surface hardness, this process also induces an internally stressed microstructure that makes the surface brittle. To relieve these internal stresses, a subsequent tempering process is required that typically entails heating the part to a temperature below the critical temperature for<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> several hours. Although tempering facilitates avoidance of a microstructure phase change, the surface hardness is also undesirably reduced.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">In induction heating, the part surface is placed within an induction coil. As electrical current in the induction coil is increased, the surface is heated above the critical temperature, thus also causing a microstructure phase change. When the surface is rapidly cooled, or quenched, a new microstructure phase is formed. Only a shallow depth beneath the surface is heated above the critical temperature and is rapidly quenched, while the remainder of the part remains unchanged. However, the rapid cooling also induces internal stresses that cause the surface to become brittle. Although a subsequent tempering process is required to relieve the internal stresses, tempering is time consuming. Additionally, the heat treated depth is controlled during induction hardening by producing a higher frequency current in the induction coil. However, common induction heating machines and surface area present limitations based on the highest frequency available.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">Hardened steel surfaces have been produced by machining using laser processing. For example, a method of laser heat-treating a flat part, such as a knife or blade, has been employed by focusing a laser beam perpendicular to the major flat surface of the part using a cylindrical lens. The width of the beam is adjusted according to the desired width of the part to be heated. The part is then moved through the laser or the laser may be moved along the part to heat the surface. There is no subsequent machining of the surface of presence of a WEL.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">It is desirable to provide a method of eliminating undesired surface characteristics during broaching without inducing further defects in the part.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">A cutting tool having the features of the preamble of claim 1 is disclosed in <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="CA1191428A"><text>CA-A-1191428</text></patcit>. Cutting apparatus employing laser heating is disclosed in <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="DE19613183C"><text>DE-C-19613183</text></patcit> and one which employs laser pretreatment of a surface disclosed in <patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="US4356376A"><text>US-A-4356376</text></patcit>.</p><heading id="h0002"><b>SUMMARY</b></heading><p id="p0011" num="0011">From a first aspect the invention provides a cutting tool as set forth in claim 1.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p><p id="p0012" num="0012">From a second aspect the invention provides a machining system as set forth in claim 5.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">These and other features of the disclosure can be best understood from the following specification and drawings, the following of which is a brief description.</p><heading id="h0003"><b>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</b></heading><p id="p0014" num="0014">The disclosure can be further understood by reference to the following detailed description when considered in connection with the accompanying drawings wherein:
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> is a highly schematic view of a machining system.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 2</figref> is an end view of a rotor disk having a fir tree slot.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 3</figref> is a partial cross-sectional view of the rotor disk shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 2</figref> with a tool cutting a locally heated area.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0004"><b>DETAILED DESCRIPTION</b></heading><p id="p0015" num="0015">A machining system 10 is generally depicted in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>. The system 10 includes a support 14 that retains an article 12, such as a rotor disk. An example rotor disk is shown in more detail in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 2</figref>. The rotor disk includes a slot 16 provided between lugs 18. The slot 16 is complementarily shaped to receive a fir-tree root of a rotor blade. Other slot shapes may be used to secure rotor blades to the rotor disk.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">Returning to <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>, a cutting tool 20 is movable relative to the article 12 to cut an area 42 of the article 12, best shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 3</figref>. In one example, the cutting tool 20 is a broach tool. For example, a broach tool includes a body 22 supporting multiple teeth 24 that are spaced from one another from a forward end 23 to a rearward end 25 to provide gaps 30 between the teeth 24, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figures 1 and 3</figref>. The teeth 24 extend along a longitudinal axis LA of the body 22. The forward end 23 typically includes teeth that more aggressively cut the slot 16 than the teeth on the rearward end 25. Typically, the teeth on the forward and rearward ends 23, 25 are separated by a portion 21, which may include a generally flat surface. Slots 16 are typically broached using multiple broaching tools that include,<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> for example, a rough broach, a semi-finish broach and a finish broach. In the example shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>, the cutting tool 20 is a finish broach tool.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">The cutting tool 20 is moved relative to the article 12 by an actuator 26. In the example of a broach tool, the teeth 24 progressively remove material from a surface 40 of the area 42 to form the slot 16, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figures 2 and 3</figref>. Immediately preceding predetermined teeth 24 cutting the surface 40, the system 10 heats the surface 40 of the area 42 using a heating member 28 (<figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>) so that an in-process heating of the surface 40 is provided during the broaching operation. In one example, the heating member 28 is arranged at the rearward end 25 adjacent to the cutting teeth 24 such that the surface 40 is heated prior to the last several teeth 24, thus facilitating providing a machined area substantially free from undesired surface characteristics. In one example, the surface 40 is machined in an environment 50 (<figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>) having a gas, such as helium or nitrogen, with a thermal conductivity greater than air. The environment 50 facilitates more controlled, precise heating of the surface 40.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">The surface 40 is heated above the critical temperature, to facilitate enabling the surface 40 to be machined without introducing surface stresses or altering the microstructure undesirably. While the surface 40 is still heated, the teeth 24 in the rearward end 25 remove surface anomalies 41 as part of the final surface cuts.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">In the example shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>, arrays 34 of lenses 32 are arranged in a gap 30 on the portion 21 between the teeth on the forward and rearward ends 23, 25. Lasers 36 are connected to the arrays 34 of lenses 32 by fibers 38. The finish broach tool is designed to accommodate the laser fiber optic beam delivery with the specified fiber core diameter. The body 22 of the broach tool is designed to allow for modular fiber replacement for easy maintenance. The desired number of fiber optic lenses depends upon, for example, the broaching insert pitch. In addition, the size, number and density of optic delivery fibers for the laser power is determined based upon the particular application. Possible alternates to fiber optics arrays include photonic crystals, Fresnel lenses, and diffraction gratings, for example. These lenses may utilize fewer individual laser feeds than fiber optics and may be able to do more thermal processing (for example, manifolding and banking). Various types of lasers are available for heat treating articles, including continuous wave CO<sub>2</sub> lasers,<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> excimer lasers, diode-pumped solid state lasers, femtosecond lasers, and continuous wave Nd:YAG.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">The laser 36 produces a beam 44 that is focused, via the lens 32 or the like, which generates an intense energy flux that rapidly heats the surface 40. Laser heat treatment allows the laser beam to be controlled to heat the surface of the metal article above the critical temperature to a depth of only a few microns. The surface 40 is heated to a depth of less than 20 microns (0.00079 inch), for example, 1-2 microns (0.00004 - 0.00008 inch). Controlling the depth of the heating to this shallow level allows for self-quenching. That is, no liquid or air quenching is required. Self-quenching is accomplished by conduction due to the mass and temperature disparity between the portion of the article not heated by the beam and the small depth of the surface that is heated above the critical temperature by the beam. The heat on the surface is quickly transferred to the unheated portion thereby quenching the heated surface. The laser power is adjusted to achieve the required temperature for heating the surface.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">Calculation of laser heating parameters (heated-layer thickness and laser power requirements) and the flow field developed at the gas-liquid boundary is accounted for based upon known flow equations. A laminar model for the flow conditions is taken into account. At any time the interface between the liquid layer and solid material is a straight line and is the melting isotherm. The heat transfer rate at the interface is determined to calculate the temperature rise across the liquid layer. The heat transfer to the solid material is also calculated, which will be less than the heat transferred from the hot gas boundary layer to the liquid metal by an amount equal to that absorbed by the first layer.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">Although example embodiments have been disclosed, a worker of ordinary skill in this art would recognize that certain modifications would come within the scope of the claims. For that reason, the following claims should be studied to determine their true scope and content.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56978510" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Schneidwerkzeug (20) aufweisend:
<claim-text>einen längs ausgedehnten Körper (22) mit mehreren längs beabstandeten Zähnen (24), die vom Körper (22) getragen sind, wobei jeder Zahn (24) eine Schneidekante bereitstellt; und <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> es aufweist:
<claim-text>ein vom Körper (22) getragenes Heizelement (28) zum Bereitstellen von Hitze neben einer der Schneidekanten, wobei das Heizelement (28) eine Linse (32) beinhaltet und in einem Spalt (30) zwischen wenigstens zwei nebeneinander liegenden Zähnen (24) liegt.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Schneidwerkzeug nach Anspruch 1, wobei eine Faser (38) mit der Linse verbunden ist, wobei die Faser (38) derart ausgestattet ist, dass sie der Linse (32) Laserlicht zuführt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Schneidwerkzeug nach einem der vorherigen Ansprüche, wobei das Werkzeug (20) ein Räumwerkzeug ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Schneidwerkzeug nach einem der vorherigen Ansprüche, wobei das Heizmittel (28) am hinteren Ende (25) des Werkzeugs (20) vorgesehen ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Maschinensystem aufweisend:
<claim-text>eine Halterung (14), die derart ausgebildet ist, dass sie einen Gegenstand (12) mit einem Bereich (40) hält; <b>gekennzeichnet durch</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>Räumwerkzeug (20), das mehrere Schneidezähne (24) aufweist und relativ zu der Halterung (14) über einen Aktuator (26) beweglich ist, um den Bereich (40) zu schneiden; und<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Heizelement (28) mit einer Linse (32), die auf dem Räumwerkzeug angebracht ist und die derart ausgebildet ist, dass sie den Bereich (40) des Gegenstands (12) lokal erhitzt, wobei das Heizelement (28) angebracht in einem Spalt (30) zwischen wenigstens zwei nebeneinander liegenden Zähnen (24) vorgesehen ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Maschinensystem nach Anspruch 5, wobei das Räumwerkzeug (20) einen Körper (22) beinhaltet, und der Schneidezahn (24) jeweils eine Schneidekante aufweist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Maschinensystem nach Anspruch 6, wobei der Körper (22) sich längs erstreckt, wobei mehrere Schneidezähne längs beabstandet und von dem Körper (22) getragen sind.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Maschinensystem nach Ansprüchen 5 bis 7, wobei die Heizlinse (32) neben einer der Schneidekanten angebracht ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Maschinensystem nach Anspruch 7, wobei eine Faser (38) mit der Linse (32) verbunden ist und die Faser (38) derart ausgebildet ist, dass sie Laserlicht der Linse (32) zuführt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Maschinensystem nach einem der Ansprüche 5 bis 9, wobei der Gegenstand (12) eine Rotorscheibe ist.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56978511" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A cutting tool (20) comprising:
<claim-text>a body (22) extending longitudinally with multiple longitudinally spaced teeth (24) supported on the body (22), each of the teeth (24) providing a cutting edge; and <b>characterised by</b> comprising</claim-text>
<claim-text>a heating member (28) supported by the body (22) that is configured to provide heat adjacent to one of the cutting edges, the heating member (28) including a lens (32) and being provided in a gap (30) between at least two adjacent teeth (24).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The cutting tool according to claim 1, wherein a fiber (38) is connected to the lens (32), the fiber (38) configured to provide laser light to the lens (32).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The cutting tool according to any preceding claim wherein the tool (20) is a broach tool .</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The cutting tool according to any preceding claim, wherein the heating means (28) is provided at a rearward end (25) of the tool (20).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>A machining system comprising:
<claim-text>a support (14) configured to retain an article (12) having an area (40); <b>characterised by</b> comprising</claim-text>
<claim-text>a broach tool (20) including multiple cutting teeth (24) and movable relative to the support (14) via an actuator (26) to cut the area (40); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a heating member (28) including a lens (32) mounted on the broach tool and configured to locally heat the area (40) of the article (12), the heating member (28) being provided in a gap (30) between at least two adjacent teeth (24).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The machining system according to claim 5, wherein the broach tool (20) includes a body (22), and the cutting teeth (24) each having a cutting edge.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The machining system according to claim 6, wherein the body (22) extends longitudinally with the multiple cutting teeth being longitudinally spaced and supported on the body (22).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The machining system according to any of claims 5 to 7, wherein the heating lens (32) is located adjacent to one of the cutting edges.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The machining system according to claim 7, wherein a fiber (38) is connected to the lens (32), the fiber (38) configured to provide laser light to the lens (32),</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The machining system according to any of claims 5 to 9, wherein the article (12) is a rotor disk.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56978512" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Outil de coupe (20) comprenant :
<claim-text>un corps (22) s'étendant longitudinalement avec de multiples dents (24) espacées longitudinalement et supportées sur le corps (22), chacune des dents (24) fournissant une arête de coupe, et <b>caractérisé en ce qu'</b>il comprend :</claim-text>
<claim-text>un élément chauffant (28) supporté par le corps (22) qui est configuré pour fournir de la chaleur à proximité de l'une des arêtes de coupe, l'élément chauffant (28) comprenant une lentille (32) et étant aménagé dans un intervalle (30) situé entre au moins deux dents adjacentes (24).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Outil de coupe selon la revendication 1, dans lequel une fibre (38) est raccordée à la lentille (32), la fibre (38) étant configurée pour fournir de la lumière laser à la lentille (32).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Outil de coupe selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans lequel l'outil (20) est un outil de brochage.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Outil de coupe selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans lequel le moyen chauffant (28) est prévu à une extrémité arrière (25) de l'outil (20).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Système d'usinage comprenant :
<claim-text>un support (14) configuré pour retenir un article (12) ayant une surface (40) ; <b>caractérisé en ce qu'</b>il comprend :</claim-text>
<claim-text>un outil de brochage (20) comprenant de multiples dents de coupe (24) qui sont mobiles par rapport au support (14) via un actionneur (26) pour découper la surface (40) ; et<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>un élément chauffant (28) comprenant une lentille (32) montée sur l'outil de brochage et configurée pour chauffer localement la surface (40) de l'article (12), l'élément chauffant (28) étant aménagé dans un intervalle (30) situé entre au moins deux dents adjacentes (24).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Système d'usinage selon la revendication 5, dans lequel l'outil de brochage (20) comprend un corps (22) et les dents de coupe (24) ayant chacune une arête de coupe.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Système d'usinage selon la revendication 6, dans lequel le corps (22) s'étend longitudinalement avec les multiples dents de coupe qui sont espacées longitudinalement et supportées sur le corps (22).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Système d'usinage selon l'une quelconque des revendications 5 à 7, dans lequel la lentille de chauffage (32) est située à proximité de l'une des arêtes de coupe.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Système d'usinage selon la revendication 7, dans lequel une fibre (38) est raccordée à une lentille (32), la fibre (38) étant configurée pour fournir de la lumière laser à la lentille (32).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Système d'usinage selon l'une quelconque des revendications 5 à 9, dans lequel l'article (12) est un disque de rotor.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16668598" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1,2,3"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="165" he="210" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
