<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-1710063-B1" country="EP" doc-number="1710063" kind="B1" date="20140101" family-id="34586682" file-reference-id="257016" date-produced="20180822" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146553807" ucid="EP-1710063-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>1710063</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-06251174-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154827730" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>06251174</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20060304</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140446812" ucid="GB-0506833-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>GB</country><doc-number>0506833</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20050405</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130814</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988124891" load-source="docdb">C04B  35/64        20060101ALI20130625BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988125566" load-source="docdb">F27B  17/00        20060101ALI20130625BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988126064" load-source="docdb">B28B  11/24        20060101AFI20130625BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988126128" load-source="docdb">F27D  99/00        20100101AFI20130306RMEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988906415" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B22F2998/00        20130101 LA20140103BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988911444" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">C04B2235/661       20130101 LA20140103BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988913198" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B28B  11/243       20130101 LI20140103BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988915790" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F27B  17/00        20130101 FI20140103BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988916855" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">C04B  35/64        20130101 LI20140103BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132193905" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Brennverfahren Keramischer Formlinge</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132193906" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Method of firing ceramic core bodies</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132193907" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Procédé de cuisson de corps en céramique</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918153805" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>ROLLS ROYCE PLC</last-name><address><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918152950" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>ROLLS-ROYCE PLC</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918171254" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>MCGOURLAY JAMIE CHARLES</last-name><address><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918165567" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>MCGOURLAY, JAMIE CHARLES</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918997966" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>MCGOURLAY, JAMIE CHARLES</last-name><address><street>89 Norton Park View Norton</street><city>Sheffield, South Yorkshire S8 8GU</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918143684" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>PRAJAPATI BHUPENDRA AMRATIAL</last-name><address><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918172870" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>PRAJAPATI, BHUPENDRA AMRATIAL</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918997967" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>PRAJAPATI, BHUPENDRA AMRATIAL</last-name><address><street>9 Cleveland Avenue Chaddesden</street><city>Derby DE21 6SA</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918997969" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>ROLLS-ROYCE PLC</last-name><iid>100210142</iid><address><street>65 Buckingham Gate</street><city>London, SW1E 6AT</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918997968" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Barcock, Ruth Anita</last-name><suffix>et al</suffix><iid>100039602</iid><address><street>Rolls-Royce plc Intellectual Property Department P.O. Box 31</street><city>Derby DE24 8BJ</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548982682" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548980542" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548982683" load-source="docdb">GB</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63957429" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to ceramic core bodies and more particularly to setting of such core bodies in their so called initially formed "green state".</p><p id="p0002" num="0002">Typical prior fire setting approaches (e.g. <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="RU2100318C1"><text>RU2100318C1</text></patcit> and <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="JP05339064A"><text>JP05339064A</text></patcit>) for ceramic core bodies used in combination with a conventional firing regime do not suitably accommodate for the large differences in the physical and chemical behaviour that can occur in modern highly complex geometric core bodies during the de-bond and sintering phases of the firing cycle. These geometries exhibit such features as large changes in core body cross-sections, support pedestals, rails, plenums and channel cores, so that in particular 'green' or initially formed cores are prone to additional distortion, cracking and surface degradation using conventional fire-setting processes. This ultimately results in cores of inferior visual, dimensional and material quality and leads to increased performance failure during core manufacture and cast core performance. <patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="RU2100318C1"><text>RU 2100 318-C1</text></patcit> and <patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="JP05339064A"><text>JP 05 339 064 A</text></patcit> teach a method of ceramic core firing, comprising the steps of :
<ol><li>i) placing a containment upon a base,</li><li>ii) locating a core in the containment upon the base,</li><li>iii) filling the containment with firing media, and</li><li>iv) firing the combination of the containment and the core in an oven.</li></ol></p><p id="p0003" num="0003">It will be appreciated with respect to relatively large components, or those of an intricate nature that the differentials between the firing media and the core body creates stresses due to the variable thermal performance of these materials with respect to each other. Furthermore, the act of packing firing media about the core to be fired may cause distortions. In order to achieve dimensionally consistent cores with less flaws, great care must be taken with respect to the firing media depth for consistency all over the core when fired.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">In accordance with the present invention there is provided a method of ceramic core firing characterised by<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> the steps of: i) placing a containment on a base, ii) locating a firing media within and about a containment, iii) locating a core in the containment upon the base, a level of firing media is located such that the core through a stem allows appropriate location of the core for presetting of the core to a sufficiently mechanically strong state such that it is freestanding, whereby the depth of the firing media about the core is regulated in terms of the gap to the walls of the containment and to ends of the containment, iv) pre-firing the combination of the base, the containment and the core in an oven to stabilise the core geometry, v) adjusting the core within the containment where appropriate and filling the remainder of the containment with further firing media, and vi) firing the combination of the containment and the core in an oven.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">Preferably, the method includes shaking the containment prior to firing.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">An embodiment of the present invention will now be described by way of example and with reference to the accompanying drawings in which;
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> depicts a schematic cross section of a typical core tube firing arrangement in accordance with the present invention during a pre-firing stage; and,</li><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2</figref> is a schematic cross-section of the arrangement in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> during a firing stage.</li></ul></p><p id="p0007" num="0007">As indicated above, in order to obtain acceptable cores, it is important to achieve as near consistent thermal environmental uniformity as possible during firing with respect to each core. In such circumstances, potential variations in firing media depth relative to a core according to different positions in a saggar or ceramic dish utilised to transfer the cores to a kiln for firing may be relevant. Particularly when the cores are in their initially formed or moulded 'green' state and<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> therefore have limited mechanical strength. It is important that the utilisation of the firing media does not itself distort the core.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">The present invention utilises a tube or containment about the core to be fired. Thus, the tube or containment is an open ended tube or box of specific height, depth, width and wall thickness and dimensional profile for particular operational requirements. Normally the tube is made from the same compound ceramic media as used in the saggar or ceramic dish to support the core for transportation to a kiln or oven for firing. Alternatively, the containment can be constructed from a ceramic fibre board. In either event the material has a primary component of alumina and is thus able to operate and be continuously reused over the temperature range required for normal ceramic core firing processes.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">As indicated above, environmental uniformity is important with respect to firing cores, and therefore the tube or containment dimensions are dictated by the size and geometry of the cores which will be contained in the tube or containment during the firing process. In such circumstances, certain tubes or containment sizes may be specific to certain core geometries.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">In use the tubes or containments are placed vertically, that is to say with either of the open ends of the tube or containment facing up inside a conventional saggar for core fire setting. Generally, a number of tubes or containments will be spaced apart on the same saggar dependent upon the size of the core to be placed in the tube and thus the size of the tube or containment required. The spacing will be of a specific distance and distribution with in particular saggars or ceramic dishes. Once the tubes or containments are located upon the saggar, these tubes or containments are then surrounded by a firing media<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> until an even and sufficient specific depth of firing media is achieved between any adjacent tube or containment and saggar wall. Subsequently a pre-measured volume of firing media is then placed inside each of the tubes or containments to produce a planting layer of specific depth in the bottom of each tube or containment. This pre-measured volume of firing media in a tube or containment enables the support of the core body once placed in the tube during subsequent tube filling and also regulates the distance of the core to the base saggar and its particular orientation so that it is spaced relative to the saggar.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">In accordance with the invention there is then a pre-firing stage during which the cores are sufficiently set, one core per tube or containment in a pre-defined orientation for positional adjustment. This pre-defined orientation and pre-firing stage sets the cores into the firing media at the bottom of the tube or containment to a point at which each core is relatively free standing in the tube. This pre-firing stage is illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>. In such circumstances the core is taken from its "green state" or initially moulded stage with limited mechanical stability to a situation where as indicated it is free standing and therefore has sufficient mechanical strength to be free standing within the tube or containment.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">By creation of a relatively stable and free standing core, it will be understood that through use of appropriate orientational tools such as an engineering rule it is possible to adjust the core such that all cores are repeatedly located within the respective tube or containment relative to the walls of that tube and also the saggar floor to an accuracy of + or - 3mm. In such circumstances there is relatively good core to core environmental uniformity between each core in its<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> respective tube or containment and between each containment or tube on the support saggar.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">As indicated above, <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> illustrates the pre-firing arrangement of the present invention. Thus, a core 1 is presented in a tube or containment 2 upon a saggar base 3. Around the tube or containment 2, firing media 4 is located to a sufficient depth to provide location of the tube or containment 2. Upon the saggar base 3 and within the tube or containment 2, a level 5 of firing media is located such that the core 1 through a stem 1a allows appropriate location of the core 1 for presetting of the core 1 to a sufficiently mechanically strong state such that it is freestanding. In this state, adjustment is made as indicated, and checked using a device such as engineering rule to ensure that the core 1 is located relative to the walls of the tube or containment 2 and the saggar base 3 to a repeatable accuracy of +/- 3mm for example relative to other cores.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">Once appropriately adjusted and presented within the tube or containment 2, the next stage is to fill the remainder of the tube or containment 2 with further firing media. The core 1, depending on its geometry and orientation, may require additional mechanical support during this process to ensure that it does not move during the pouring in of the firing media. Essentially the tubes or containments 2 are filled level with the top of the tube 2. Once all tubes have been filled with the firing media 4 the saggar 3 is shaken using a horizontal agitation of the saggar 3 before being placed on a firing truck ready for entry into the kiln. In such circumstances, due to the pre firing stage, the cores are all substantially located repeatedly relative to the walls of their respective tube or containment 2 and the base 3. In such circumstances,<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> any firing distortion effects are repeatable over all the cores 1 fired.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">By use of the tube or containment, a number of advantages over conventional fire setting regimes are achieved. The tubes or containments provide location for each core within relative to the saggar and within the tube and this automatically ensures the core is maintained at a more consistent firing position and orientation along with ensuring greater positional consistency from core to core. In short, use of the tubes or containments ensures there is local environmental thermal uniformity of the cores during the firing stage. Each core is maintained in its specific orientation within a repeatable specific volume of firing media surrounding it. By such greater specific control of the firing media surrounding the core, it will be understood that there is enhanced performance in terms of the firing media during the critical phases of firing, that is to say de-bond and sintering of the "green" ceramic core.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">By ensuring environmental thermal uniformity, greater consistency in fired cores can be achieved. By use of a tube or containment, there is control of the local thermal environment about the core during the ceramic firing process. Such greater local thermal control ensures that there is consistency with respect to relatively complex geometric cores which as described previously may suffer critical defect areas under the action of conventional ceramic fire and setting regimes in terms of local variation of the thermal regime experienced by the core. This reduces the potential for defect creation and propagation.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">In the above circumstances, overall there is a significant reduction in the dimension and visual defects associated with cores produced in accordance with the<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> present invention in comparison with conventional firing regimes using a conventional ceramic fire setting regime. With the present arrangement and method, highly complex geometric structures can be fired in normal firing kilns ensuring a generic process can be maintained without detrimental effect to fired core quality.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018"><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2</figref> illustrates the firing arrangement in accordance with the present invention during the main firing stage. Thus, in comparison with <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, it will be noted that the firing media 5a extends to the top of the tube or containment 2. The firing media 5a is shaken such that the top of the firing media 5a is substantially flat across the tube or containment 2. As indicated previously the core 1 is appropriately positioned to ensure that there is location of the core 1 to an accuracy of +/-3mm relative to the walls of the tube or containment 2 and the saggar base 3. In this condition the core 1 is fully fired to its final state.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">It will be appreciated that the actual temperatures, time periods and other factors utilised with respect to core firing will be substantially the same as previous regimes, thus these parameters will be operationally variable dependent upon the actual core to be fired.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">The present invention utilises a method of core firing. This method as indicated incorporates the use of a tube or containment 2 such that the core is initially placed within a tube or containment 2 on a saggar base 3. As described previously, initially the tube or containment 2 will be located on the saggar base 3 and then firing media 4, 5 packed within and thereabout to sufficient depth to ensure location of the tube on the saggar base 3 as well as provide a planting matrix for location of the "green" core 1 upon a stem 1a within the tube or containment 2.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></p><p id="p0021" num="0021">As indicated previously, normally a number of tubes or containments 2 will be located on the same ceramic dish or saggar base 3 transport utilised for delivery of the whole to a kiln for firing. Nevertheless, each tube will accommodate its own green state core 1 located in the firing media 5. In a pre firing state as indicated above, the core 1 will be pre-fired until it achieves an appropriate mechanical strength to be free standing and supported. In this pre-fired state adjustment will be made to ensure positional location of the core within its respective tube or containment 2 within the desired operational accuracy. As indicated previously, typically this accuracy is +/- 3mm.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">Once completely located or confirmed within the tube or containment 2, the core 1 can then be surrounded by further firing media. Where necessary the core may be supported or reinforced to prevent displacement upon fully of the containment with firing media 5 to a desired positional accuracy as described above through use of further reinforcement and support as the further firing media is introduced into the tube or containment 2.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">Once the further firing media is introduced into the tube, appropriate mechanisms are utilised in order to level off the firing media 5 at the top of the tube or containment 2. This may be through horizontal agitation shaking the excess firing media off to level. The arrangement is then fired in a kiln to achieve the desired core stabilisation for subsequent manufacturing processes.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">As indicated above, essentially uniformity of environmental conditions during firing is the objective. Thus, to further enhance such uniformity, the tubes or containments may be specifically shaped and manufactured to imitate the precise profiles and geometries of the underlying cores they will enclose. In such circumstances,<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> such specific profiling will regulate core to tube or containment wall section geometries and so the amount of surrounding firing media utilised and present that firing media to the core for greater consistency. Additionally, it will be appreciated that certain critical core geometries may need more firing media support, either by way of mass or density, than other cores or there may be improved regulation of heating during firing. Either of these approaches may be further achieved through use of tubes or containments that have been specifically shaped or moulded to form a particular specific shape and a wall section for fired core incapsulation.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">Coffin style closures including a base and a lid arrangement may also be used in the same way as firing tubes to facilitate better position and thermal profiles for cores during firing processes.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">Improvements and alternatives to the embodiments of the present invention described above will be envisaged by those skilled in the art. Thus, for example the tubes and containments can as illustrated be substantially cylindrical or may have a square cross section or otherwise shaped as required to provide uniformity of environmental conditions for a ceramic core located within the tube. Additionally, as illustrated, the tubes or containments may be substantially uniformly thick flat walled components or alternatively may be internally shaped for reciprocal profiling to an opposed core in order to provide consistency of firing medium gap between that core and a wall surface of the tube or containment. Externally of the tube or containment, fins or outward projections may be provided for inter-engagement with the firing medium to further facilitate secure location of the tube or containment relative to the firing medium or inner saggar<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> to maintain spacing between such tubes or containments as required for consistency.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56979776" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Verfahren zum Brennen eines keramischen Kerns (1), mit den Schritten:
<claim-text>i) Stellen eines Behältnisses (2) auf einen Sockel (3),</claim-text>
<claim-text>ii) Anordnen eines Brennmediums (4) innerhalb und um das Behältnis,</claim-text>
<claim-text>iii) Anordnen eines Kerns (1) in dem Behältnis (3) auf dem Sockel (3), wobei ein Pegel (5) des Brennmediums so angeordnet ist, dass der Kern (1) durch einen Schaft (1a) eine geeignete Positionierung des Kerns (1) ermöglicht zum Voraushärten des Kerns (1) auf einen ausreichend mechanisch festen Zustand, dass er freistehend ist, wodurch die Tiefe des Brennmediums um den Kern hinsichtlich des Spalts zu den Wänden des Behältnisses und zu den Enden des Behältnisses reguliert wird,</claim-text>
<claim-text>iv) Vorbrennen der Kombination aus dem Sockel (3), dem Behältnis (2) und dem Kern in einem Ofen zum Stabilisieren der Kerngeometrie,</claim-text>
<claim-text>v) Justieren des Kerns innerhalb des Behältnisses (2), wenn erforderlich, und Füllen des Rests des Behältnisses (2) mit weiterem Brennmedium (4), und</claim-text>
<claim-text>vi) Brennen der Kombination aus dem Behältnis und dem Kern in einem Ofen.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, welches das Schütteln des Behältnisses vor dem Brennen umfaßt.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56979777" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A method of ceramic core (1) firing comprising the steps of:
<claim-text>i) placing a containment (2) on a base (3),</claim-text>
<claim-text>ii) locating a firing media (4) within and about a containment,</claim-text>
<claim-text>iii) locating a core (1) in the containment (2) upon the base (3), a level (5) of firing media is located such that the core (1) through a stem (1a) allows appropriate location of the core (1) for presetting of the core (1) to a sufficiently mechanically strong state such that it is freestanding, whereby the depth of the firing media about the core is regulated in terms of the gap to the walls of the containment and to ends of the containment,</claim-text>
<claim-text>iv) pre-firing the combination of the base (3), the containment (2) and the core (1) in an oven to stabilise the core geometry,</claim-text>
<claim-text>v) adjusting the core within the containment (2) where appropriate and filling the remainder of the containment (2) with further firing media (4), and</claim-text>
<claim-text>vi) firing the combination of the containment and the core in an oven.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>A method as claimed in claim 1 comprising shaking the containment prior to firing.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56979778" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Procédé de cuisson de noyau en céramique (1) comprenant les étapes de :
<claim-text>i) placement d'une enceinte de confinement (2) sur une base (3),</claim-text>
<claim-text>ii) positionnement d'un support de cuisson (4) dans et autour d'une enceinte de confinement,</claim-text>
<claim-text>iii) positionnement d'un noyau (1) dans l'enceinte de confinement (2) sur la base (3), un niveau (5) de support de cuisson étant positionné de sorte que le noyau (1) par l'intermédiaire d'une tige (1a) permette un positionnement approprié du noyau (1) pour le préréglage du noyau (1) à un état suffisamment fort mécaniquement de sorte qu'il soit autoporté, moyennant quoi la profondeur du support de cuisson autour du noyau est régulée en termes d'intervalle jusqu'aux parois de l'enceinte de confinement et aux extrémités de l'enceinte de confinement,</claim-text>
<claim-text>iv) précuisson de la combinaison de la base (3), de l'enceinte de confinement (2) et du noyau (1) dans un four pour stabiliser la géométrie du noyau,</claim-text>
<claim-text>v) ajustement du noyau dans l'enceinte de confinement (2) le cas échéant et le remplissage du reste de l'enceinte de confinement (2) avec un autre support de cuisson (4), et</claim-text>
<claim-text>vi) cuisson de la combinaison de l'enceinte de confinement et du noyau dans un four.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 1, comprenant le secouement de l'enceinte de confinement avant la cuisson.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16668963" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1,2"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="121" he="206" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
