<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2630358-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2630358" kind="B1" date="20140101" family-id="44800999" file-reference-id="315075" date-produced="20180823" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146551790" ucid="EP-2630358-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2630358</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-11770078-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154825713" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>11770078</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20111004</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP168045677" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>11770078.1</doc-number><date>20111004</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140450357" ucid="EP-2011067287-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>2011067287</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20111004</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140454019" ucid="US-91004510-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>91004510</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20101022</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130906</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988109483" load-source="docdb">F02M  21/02        20060101AFI20120507BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988109564" load-source="docdb">F23K   5/00        20060101ALI20120507BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2073183724" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 137/4238      20150401 LA20150410BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2073185374" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 137/4358      20150401 LA20150410BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2073186036" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 137/7504      20150401 LA20150410BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2073186759" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 137/86389     20150401 LA20150410BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2073188077" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 137/0318      20150401 LA20150410BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988096260" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F23K   5/007       20130101 LI20130822BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988097987" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F23K2401/201       20130101 LA20130822BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988104948" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F02D  19/029       20130101 LI20130314BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988106764" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F02M  21/0293      20130101 FI20130313BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988120496" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F23K2900/05001     20130101 LA20130822BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988124271" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F02M  21/0212      20130101 LI20130313BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988133749" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y02T  10/32        20130101 LA20130822BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988135622" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F02D  19/025       20130101 LI20130313BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132187854" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">NACHWEIS UND AUTOMATISCHE REAKTION AUF KOHLENWASSERSTOFFGAS IN DER LUFT</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132187855" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">DETECTING AND AUTOMATICALLY RESPONDING TO AIRBORNE HYDROCARBON GAS</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132187856" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">DÉTECTION DE GAZ D'HYDROCARBURES ATMOSPHÉRIQUE ET RÉACTION AUTOMATIQUE À CELLE-CI</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918166612" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>IBM</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918133259" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>INTERNATIONAL BUSINESS MACHINES CORPORATION</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918147739" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>BAVISHI PANKAJ</last-name><address><country>IN</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918138030" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>BAVISHI, PANKAJ</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918994541" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>BAVISHI, PANKAJ</last-name><address><street>IBM India Pvt Ltd Mail Drop ETB1 3F B085 IT Park Phase2 Hinjewadi</street><city>Pune MH 412308</city><country>IN</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918994540" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>International Business Machines Corporation</last-name><iid>101239613</iid><address><street>New Orchard Road</street><city>Armonk, NY 10504</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918994539" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Gascoyne, Belinda Jane</last-name><iid>100042539</iid><address><street>IBM United Kingdom Limited Intellectual Property Department Hursley Park</street><city>Winchester, Hampshire SO21 2JN</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="EP-2011067287-W"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2011067287</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20111004</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2012052290-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2012052290</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20120426</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548841756" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS548938999" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS548841757" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS548870055" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS548949687" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS548937993" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS548939000" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS548941008" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548841758" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS548937998" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS548925231" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS548870056" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS548870057" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548941009" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548841759" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS548841760" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS548937999" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS548949688" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS548841761" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS548870058" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS548938000" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS548941014" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS548939001" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS548941015" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS548941016" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS548818581" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS548818582" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS548939002" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS548841762" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS548939003" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS548841763" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS548939004" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS548841764" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS548939005" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS548941017" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS548938001" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS548938006" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS548818583" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63956726" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001"><u>Field of the Invention</u></heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to controlling the flow of liquefied petroleum gas to a hydrocarbon gas-fueled device, and more particularly to detecting airborne hydrocarbon gas and automatically controlling the flow of hydrocarbon gas in response thereto.</p><heading id="h0002"><u>Background of the Invention</u></heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">Combustible hydrocarbon gas is often used as a fuel source to power devices (i.e. hydrocarbon gas-fueled devices). Liquefied petroleum gas ("LPG") refers to a category of hydrocarbon materials that are used as fuels in a gaseous form at atmospheric pressure but are stored in a pressurized, liquefied state within a pressure vessel. LPG is controllably released to atmosphere on-site to enter the gaseous state immediately prior to being consumed as a fuel in a hydrocarbon gas-fueled device. The term "LPG" may be used to refer to such a material both in its pressurized, liquefied state and its gaseous state. LPG commonly includes propane, butane, and mixtures thereof. Familiar applications for LPG include, for example, propane-burning grills, automobiles, and some domestic central heating systems.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">LPG is a relatively clean-burning fuel that produces low emissions compared with the burning of other fossil fuels, such as coal. Therefore, the storage and use of LPG is generally regarded as causing minimal pollution. Hydrocarbon gas-fueled devices and vessels for storing LPG are also generally well designed and include safety mechanisms that allow for safe storage and use of LPG. However, the combustible nature of LPG can still be hazardous when not properly handled or stored. For example, a leak of LPG from a system can pose the risk of fire or explosion.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="GB1485461A"><text>GB 1 485 461 A</text></patcit> discloses a system and a method according to the preamble of independent claims 1 and 14.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p><heading id="h0003"><u>Summary of the Invention</u></heading><p id="p0005" num="0005">Viewed from a first aspect, the present invention provides a system for controllably delivering hydrocarbon gas to a hydrocarbon gas-fueled device. The system includes a pressure vessel for containing a pressurized hydrocarbon gas. A valve is selectively movable between an open state and a closed state for controlling the flow of the hydrocarbon gas from the pressure vessel to a supply line in fluid communication with the pressure vessel. A liquid sealant is provided in a sealant container. The liquid sealant is configured for hardening if released from the sealant container. A hydrocarbon gas sensor is configured for detecting airborne hydrocarbon gas and generating a signal in response to detecting the airborne hydrocarbon gas. A controller is in communication with the hydrocarbon gas sensor and the valve. The controller includes a prime mover configured for automatically moving the valve to the closed state in response to the signal from the hydrocarbon gas sensor if the valve is in the open state. The controller is configured for releasing the liquid sealant to the supply line in response to the signal from the hydrocarbon gas sensor if the valve is in the closed state.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">Preferably in the hydrocarbon gas delivery system according to the first aspect, the valve comprises a mechanical valve actuator configured for manually moving the valve between the open and closed states by hand, and the prime mover is removably coupled to the mechanical valve actuator.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">Preferably in the hydrocarbon gas delivery system according to the first aspect, the mechanical valve actuator comprises a knob rotatable in a first direction for moving the valve to the open state and in a second direction for moving the valve to the closed state.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">Preferably, the hydrocarbon gas delivery system according to the first aspect further comprises a rigid adapter body holding the prime mover, the sensor, the sealant container and sealant, wherein the adapter body is configured for removably securing to the valve with the prime mover operably coupled to the mechanical valve actuator.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p><p id="p0009" num="0009">Preferably in the hydrocarbon gas delivery system according to the first aspect, the signal generated by the sensor includes a detected level of hydrocarbon gas, and the controller is configured to automatically move the valve to the closed state in response to the level reaching a first threshold while the valve is in the open state and to release the liquid sealant to the supply line in response to the level reaching a second threshold.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">Preferably in the hydrocarbon gas delivery system according to the first aspect, the second threshold is less than the first threshold.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">Preferably in the hydrocarbon gas delivery system according to the first aspect, each threshold includes a concentration threshold and a corresponding time threshold, whereby a corrective action is taken only if the concentration threshold is continuously sensed for the full duration of the corresponding time threshold</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">Preferably, the hydrocarbon gas delivery system according to the first aspect further comprises an electronic user interface on the rigid adapter body for communicating scheduling parameters from a user to the controller, wherein the controller configures a schedule for closing the valve according to the scheduling parameters.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">Preferably in the hydrocarbon gas delivery system according to the first aspect, the controller further comprises a timer, wherein the controller is configured for closing the valve according to a preprogrammed schedule.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">Preferably in the hydrocarbon gas delivery system according to the first aspect, the preprogrammed schedule is user-configurable.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">Preferably in the hydrocarbon gas delivery system according to the first aspect, the prime mover biases the valve to a default closed-valve state, and the timer is configured to provide a finite time period during which the default closed-valve state may be overridden, after which the prime mover automatically powers the valve back to the default closed-valve state.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p><p id="p0016" num="0016">Preferably in the hydrocarbon gas delivery system according to the first aspect, the liquid sealant is pressurized within the sealant container under sufficient pressure to move the liquid sealant into the supply line in response to releasing the liquid sealant from the sealant container.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">Preferably in the hydrocarbon gas delivery system according to the first aspect, the controller is configured for puncturing the sealant container to release the sealant to the supply line.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">Viewed from a second aspect, the invention provides a method of controllably delivering hydrocarbon gas. A valve is selectively opened and closed to control the flow of hydrocarbon gas from a pressure vessel to a supply line for a hydrocarbon gas-fueled device. Any escaped airborne hydrocarbon gas external to the pressure vessel is detected. An attempt is made to move the valve from an open state to a closed state in response to detecting escaped airborne hydrocarbon gas while the valve is in the open state. A liquid sealant is released to the supply line in response to detecting escaped gas after at least attempting to move the valve to the closed state.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">Preferably, the method of controllably delivering hydrocarbon gas comprises: selectively opening and closing a valve to control the flow of hydrocarbon gas from a pressure vessel to a supply line for a hydrocarbon gas-fueled device; detecting any airborne hydrocarbon gas; attempting to move the valve from an open state to a closed state in response to detecting airborne hydrocarbon gas while the valve is in the open state; and releasing a liquid sealant to the supply line in response to detecting escaped gas after at least attempting to move the valve to the closed state.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">Preferably, the method of controllably delivering hydrocarbon gas further comprises selectively closing the valve according to an electronically-stored schedule.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">Preferably, the method of controllably delivering hydrocarbon gas further comprises receiving user input including one or more scheduling parameters and configuring the electronically-stored schedule according to the user input.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></p><p id="p0022" num="0022">Preferably, in the method of controllably delivering hydrocarbon gas, the step of attempting to move the valve from an open state to a closed state comprises operating a prime mover to automatically urge a mechanical valve actuator.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">Preferably, in the method of controllably delivering hydrocarbon gas, the step of operating a prime mover to automatically urge a mechanical valve actuator comprises rotating a valve knob using an electric motor.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">Preferably, in the method of controllably delivering hydrocarbon gas, the step of releasing a liquid sealant to the supply line comprises automatically puncturing a pressurized sealant container containing the liquid sealant and guiding the released sealant into the supply line.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">Preferably, the method of controllably delivering hydrocarbon gas further comprises automatically attempting to move the valve to the closed state in response to detecting the escaped gas at a predetermined threshold value.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">In a preferred embodiment, if the signal from the sensor is received while the valve is in the open state, an attempt is made to close the valve. If the signal from the sensor is received when the valve is in the closed state (either because the valve was already in the closed state or because the controller previously attempted to close the valve) then the liquid sealant is released to the supply line as a backup measure.</p><heading id="h0004"><u>Brief Description of the Drawings</u></heading><p id="p0027" num="0027">A preferred embodiment of the invention will now be described in detail, by way of example only, with reference to the following drawings, in which:
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a schematic diagram of a hydrocarbon gas delivery system according to an embodiment of the invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. <b>2</b></figref> is an elevation view of the hydrocarbon gas delivery system according to a specific example embodiment; and<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> is a flowchart of a method of controllably delivering hydrocarbon gas, such as to a hydrocarbon gas-fueled device, according to an embodiment of the invention.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0005"><u>Detailed Description of the Preferred Embodiment</u></heading><p id="p0028" num="0028">Embodiments of the present invention include a system and method for safely delivering a hydrocarbon gas to a hydrocarbon gas-fueled device. Embodiments of the invention further include a safety system and method for taking one or more corrective actions in response to detecting airborne hydrocarbon gas. In at least one embodiment, a valve for controlling the supply of hydrocarbon gas to a device may be automatically closed in response to detecting a threshold level of airborne hydrocarbon gas. If airborne hydrocarbon gas continues to be detected after at least attempting to close the valve, then a liquid sealant may be automatically released from a sealant container and delivered to a hydrocarbon gas supply line to stop the flow of gas through the supply line to the device in an effort to prevent or reduce escaping hydrocarbon gas. Embodiments of the invention are discussed below in the context of a hydrocarbon gas delivery system for supplying a hydrocarbon gas to a hydrocarbon gas-fueled device, such as a hydrocarbon gas-fueled grill or burner. However, a system used with other devices, such as propane-powered vehicles or domestic central heating systems, are also within the scope of the invention.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029"><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. <b>1</b></figref> is a schematic diagram of a safety system <b>30</b> being used with a hydrocarbon gas delivery system <b>10</b> according to an embodiment of the invention. The hydrocarbon gas delivery system <b>10</b> includes a tank <b>12</b>, a supply line <b>18</b>, and a valve <b>20</b> to controllably deliver hydrocarbon gas <b>14</b> from the tank <b>12</b> to a hydrocarbon gas-fueled device <b>16.</b> The tank <b>12</b> is a pressure vessel for containing a pressurized hydrocarbon gas, such as liquefied petroleum gas (LPG), for use as a fuel. As used herein, the terms "hydrocarbon gas" and "liquefied petroleum gas" (LPG) refer to a hydrocarbon fuel whether it is in a pressurized, liquefied state while being stored, or in a depressurized, gaseous state just prior to being combusted in the hydrocarbon gas-fueled device <b>16</b>)<b>.</b> The hydrocarbon fuel in the tank <b>12</b> is likely to be present in equilibrium amounts of both liquid and gas. The gas in the top of the tank <b>12</b> is what is supplied through the supply line <b>18.</b> The gas experiences a pressure drop<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> across the supply valve <b>20</b> and may approach atmospheric pressure as the gas reaches the hydrocarbon gas-fueled device <b>16.</b></p><p id="p0030" num="0030">The hydrocarbon gas-fueled device <b>16</b> may be a cooking device, such as a hydrocarbon gas-burning grill or stove. In the example of a hydrocarbon gas-burning grill or stove, the tank <b>12</b> may be a refillable metal "LPG tank" for containing a liquefied hydrocarbon gas. The supply line <b>18</b> is in fluid communication with the tank <b>12</b> and the hydrocarbon gas-fueled device <b>16,</b> and provides a flow path for bringing the hydrocarbon gas <b>14</b> from the tank <b>12</b> to the hydrocarbon gas-fueled device <b>16.</b> The hydrocarbon gas <b>14</b> is consumed at the hydrocarbon gas-fueled device by combustion.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">The valve <b>20</b> is provided along the supply line <b>18</b> for controlling the flow of hydrocarbon gas <b>14</b> from the tank <b>12</b> to the hydrocarbon gas-fueled device <b>16.</b> The valve <b>20</b> may be any of a variety of valve types generally known in the art apart from the particular uses described herein. The hydrocarbon gas delivery system may include flow control elements such as piping or tubing used for supply line <b>18,</b> along with pressure fittings that couple the supply line <b>18</b> to the tank <b>12</b> at location <b>41,</b> to the valve <b>20</b> at locations <b>42</b> and <b>43,</b> and to the hydrocarbon gas-fueled device <b>16</b> at location <b>44.</b> The valve <b>20,</b> supply line <b>18,</b> and other flow control elements of the hydrocarbon gas delivery system <b>10</b> provide a generally sealed flow path from the tank <b>12</b> to the hydrocarbon gas-fueled device 16 through which the hydrocarbon gas <b>14</b> may flow.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">The valve <b>20</b> may be any of a variety of valve types known in the art suitable for controlling the flow of hydrocarbon gas. The valve <b>20</b> includes a mechanical valve actuator <b>22</b> for moving the valve between an open state and a closed state. For example, the mechanical actuator <b>22</b> may include a rotatable element that is rotated in one direction to open the valve and rotated in an opposite direction to close the valve <b>20.</b> In the open state, hydrocarbon gas <b>14</b> is allowed to flow through valve <b>20,</b> from the tank <b>12</b> to the hydrocarbon gas-fueled device 16. In the closed state, hydrocarbon gas <b>14</b> from the tank <b>12</b> is prevented by the valve <b>20</b> from flowing from the tank <b>12</b> to the hydrocarbon gas-fueled device <b>16.</b> The hydrocarbon gas-fueled device <b>16</b> may also include its own valves, orifices or the like to further control the flow of the gas.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></p><p id="p0033" num="0033">The schematically-drawn safety system <b>30</b> is configured for use with the hydrocarbon gas delivery system <b>10.</b> The safety system <b>30</b> includes an LPG sensor <b>32</b> for sensing airborne hydrocarbon gas, a prime mover <b>34</b> for moving the valve <b>20</b> between the open and closed states, an energy source <b>35</b> for powering the prime mover <b>34,</b> a liquid sealant <b>37</b> in an airtight liquid sealant container <b>36,</b> and controller <b>38.</b> The controller <b>38</b> may store instructions or control logic on a computer-usable storage medium such as an application-specific integrated circuit (ASIC) or other electronic circuit or chip. Those skilled in the art will appreciate that the various electrical components of the safety system <b>30</b> may include electrical power and/or signal connections, using electrical communication pathways including but not limited to wires, circuit board traces, and wiring harnesses. The safety system <b>30</b> is configured to interface with the hydrocarbon gas delivery system <b>10,</b> to monitor any airborne hydrocarbon gas external to the hydrocarbon gas delivery system <b>10</b> and to take action in response to detecting hydrocarbon gas from the hydrocarbon gas delivery system <b>10.</b> For example, the sensor <b>32</b> may generate a signal in response to detecting airborne hydrocarbon gas, which is indicative of a leak from the hydrocarbon gas delivery system <b>10.</b> As further described below, the controller <b>38</b> includes functionality for selectively operating the prime mover <b>34</b> to open or close the valve <b>20</b> and/or release the sealant 37 from the sealant container <b>36</b> in response to a signal from the LPG sensor <b>32.</b></p><p id="p0034" num="0034">The prime mover <b>34,</b> as that term is generally understood in the art, is a machine that uses thermal, electrical or potential energy to perform mechanical work. The prime mover <b>34</b> may also engage the tank <b>12</b> or supply line <b>18</b> to oppose torque applied to the valve <b>20.</b> The prime mover <b>34</b> is removably coupled to the valve 20. For example, in the present embodiment, the prime mover is operably coupled to the mechanical valve actuator <b>22</b> to move the valve between the open and closed positions. It is desirable for the prime mover <b>34</b> to be able to move the valve <b>20</b> alternately and repeatedly between the open and closed states, such as for the convenience of being able to power the valve <b>20</b> between the open and closed positions, in lieu of operating the mechanical actuator <b>22</b> by hand. However, it is sufficient for the prime mover <b>34</b> to at least be able to close the valve <b>20</b> (assuming the valve <b>20</b> is properly functioning and closeable) in response to the detection of a gas leak. In the illustrated example, the prime mover <b>34</b> is a motor, such as an electric motor, and the energy source <b>35</b> may be an electric battery. The electric battery may also supply electrical energy<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> to operate other components of the safety system <b>30,</b> such as the LPG sensor <b>32.</b> The motor can open or close the valve <b>20</b> by rotating the mechanical actuator <b>22.</b> Other non-limiting examples of prime movers include solenoids for alternately opening and closing the valve <b>20,</b> a pneumatically-operated member for alternately opening and closing the valve <b>20</b> in response to fluid pressure, or a spring-loaded member that may be triggered for closing the valve 20 using energy stored by the spring.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">The safety system <b>30</b> may be in a modular form adapted for use with an otherwise conventional hydrocarbon gas delivery system. In one example of a modular form, the prime mover <b>34</b> and energy source <b>35,</b> the LPG sensor <b>32,</b> and the sealant container <b>36</b> and liquid sealant <b>37</b> are all contained within a rigid adapter body <b>39.</b> The rigid adapter body <b>39</b> may be removably secured to the hydrocarbon gas delivery system <b>10,</b> such as by being mounted on the tank <b>12,</b> with the prime mover <b>34</b> being removably coupled to the mechanical actuator <b>22</b> of the valve <b>20.</b> In an alternative embodiment, the valve <b>20</b> may also be included with the safety system and housed within the rigid adapter body <b>39,</b> with the prime mover <b>34</b> permanently coupled to the mechanical actuator <b>22</b> of the valve <b>20.</b> In a modular embodiment, the safety system 30 may be separately manufactured and sold as an after-market add-on device for use with conventional hydrocarbon gas delivery system or components.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">During normal operation, hydrocarbon gas <b>14</b> may be supplied from the tank <b>12</b> to the hydrocarbon gas-fueled device <b>16.</b> The valve <b>20</b> may be opened to supply the hydrocarbon gas <b>14</b> to the hydrocarbon gas-fueled device <b>16.</b> The valve <b>20</b> may be opened manually, such as by a human user moving the mechanical actuator <b>22</b> by hand. Alternatively, opening and closing the valve <b>20</b> may be facilitated during normal operation, using the prime mover <b>34.</b> For example, a user interface (UI) <b>31</b> may include one or more buttons, switches, or other controls operable by a user to control the prime mover <b>34</b> for opening and closing the valve <b>20</b> in response to the user input. In this respect, opening and closing the valve is facilitated using the prime mover <b>34</b> to open and close the valve <b>20</b> without the user physically touching the valve <b>20.</b> When the valve <b>20</b> is open to supply hydrocarbon gas from the tank <b>12</b> to the hydrocarbon gas-fueled device <b>16,</b> the user may operate the hydrocarbon gas-fueled device in a conventional manner. For example, the hydrocarbon<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> gas-fueled device <b>16,</b> itself, may include controls for regulating the flow of hydrocarbon gas to individual burners or other elements of the hydrocarbon gas-fueled device <b>16.</b> The hydrocarbon gas-fueled device <b>16</b> may, for example, include a pilot flame fueled by the hydrocarbon gas or other ignition source (not shown).</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">If airborne hydrocarbon gas is detected in the vicinity of the hydrocarbon gas delivery system <b>10,</b> it is an indication of a leak in the system. One of the more likely causes of airborne hydrocarbon gas in the vicinity of the hydrocarbon gas delivery system <b>10</b> is if a pilot flame (not shown) goes out while the valve <b>20</b> is open and hydrocarbon gas <b>14</b> is being delivered from the tank <b>12</b> to the hydrocarbon gas-fueled device <b>16.</b> Although less likely, a leak can occur in the hydrocarbon gas delivery system 10 itself, such as due to accidents, misuse, or user-neglect. Potential leakage sites include, but are not limited to, an interface provided at location <b>41</b> between the supply line <b>18</b> and the tank <b>12,</b> an interface provided at location <b>42</b> between the valve <b>20</b> and a portion of the supply line <b>18</b> upstream of the valve <b>20,</b> at an interface at location <b>43</b> between the valve <b>20</b> and a portion of the supply line <b>18</b> downstream of the valve <b>20,</b> or at an interface at location <b>44</b> between the supply line 18 and the hydrocarbon gas-fueled device <b>16.</b> A damaged supply line <b>18</b> or damaged valve <b>20</b> may also allow hydrocarbon gas to leak from the hydrocarbon gas delivery system <b>10.</b> The LPG sensor <b>32</b> is preferably maintained in a powered-on state at all times, since various potential causes of escaping hydrocarbon gas exist whether the valve <b>20</b> is open or closed and whether or not the hydrocarbon gas-fueled device <b>16</b> is currently being operated by a user. In a continuously powered-on state, the sensor <b>32</b> may continuously monitor for airborne hydrocarbon gas regardless of whether the valve <b>20</b> is open or closed and regardless of whether a user is currently using the hydrocarbon gas-fueled device <b>16.</b></p><p id="p0038" num="0038">The LPG sensor <b>32</b> monitors the air to detect airborne hydrocarbon gas. The safety system <b>30</b> may perform one or more corrective actions in response to detecting the airborne gas. As governed by the controller <b>38,</b> a first example of a corrective action that may be taken by the safety system <b>30</b> in response to the sensor <b>32</b> detecting airborne hydrocarbon gas is for the prime mover <b>34</b> to automatically close the valve <b>20</b> (or at least attempt to close the valve <b>20</b>)<b>.</b> This corrective action may be performed by the prime mover <b>34</b> as instructed by the controller <b>38</b> in response to the signal from the LPG sensor <b>32.</b> This corrective action is<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> thereby performed automatically by the safety system <b>30,</b> and does not require user intervention or user input. Successfully closing the valve <b>20</b> would be effective at stopping the flow of non-combusted hydrocarbon gas anywhere downstream of the valve <b>20.</b> For example, a leak at the interface at location <b>43</b> between the downstream portion of the supply line <b>18</b> and the valve <b>20</b> or an unlighted pilot flame at the hydrocarbon gas-fueled device <b>16</b> are two examples of escaping hydrocarbon gas downstream of the valve <b>20</b> for which closing the valve <b>20</b> would be effective at preventing the further escape of non-combusted hydrocarbon gas 14 into the air.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">In other cases, attempting to close the valve <b>20</b> may not be effective at preventing the escape of non-combusted hydrocarbon gas <b>14</b> into the air. For example, if hydrocarbon gas is escaping from the hydrocarbon gas delivery system <b>10</b> at a location upstream of the valve <b>20,</b> such as at the interface <b>41</b> between the supply line <b>18</b> and the tank <b>12,</b> closing the valve <b>20</b> will not stop the escaping hydrocarbon gas. In another scenario, the valve <b>20</b> may be failed or stuck, or a mechanical interface between the prime mover <b>34</b> and the valve <b>20</b> may be damaged to prevent the prime mover <b>34</b> from correctly operating the valve <b>20.</b> In such cases, the prime mover <b>34</b> may be unable to close the valve <b>20.</b> As a failsafe measure, therefore, a second example of a corrective action that may be taken by the safety system <b>30</b> as governed by the controller <b>38</b> is to release the liquid sealant <b>37</b> to the flow passage from the tank <b>12</b> to the hydrocarbon gas-fueled device <b>16.</b> The liquid sealant may comprise a glue or epoxy that remains in a liquefied state indefinitely while in the sealant container <b>37,</b> but which subsequently cures or otherwise hardens in a relatively short time period after being released from the sealant container. Non-limiting examples of liquid sealant include Seal-Tite® sealants available from Seal-Tite International and Vacseal® High Vacuum Leak Sealant available from Space Environment Laboratories. In the illustrated example, the liquid sealant <b>37</b> is released to the portion of the supply line <b>18</b> upstream of the valve <b>20</b> through a separate port in the supply line. Assuming the liquid sealant <b>37</b> successfully closes the flow passage within the supply line, this would stop or substantially reduce any further flow of hydrocarbon gas from the tank <b>12.</b> For example, the sealant <b>37</b> may be pressurized at a pressure of greater than the gas pressure in the supply line <b>18</b> to generate positive flow from the released sealant <b>37</b> to the supply line. Other methods of delivering a liquid to the supply line <b>18</b> are also within the scope of the invention.<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></p><p id="p0040" num="0040">When attempting to stop or reduce escaping hydrocarbon gas, it is desirable to deliver the liquid sealant <b>37</b> to a location upstream of the valve <b>20.</b> By delivering the liquid sealant to a location upstream of the valve <b>20,</b> a leak anywhere downstream of the location where the liquid sealant is applied may be remedied. Delivering the liquid sealant upstream of the valve <b>20</b> may also allow the liquid sealant to be urged into the valve <b>20</b> by gas pressure in the flow passage. In a scenario in which the valve has become damaged or otherwise cannot be completely closed, the valve <b>20</b> may at least be partially closed and provide a gas-flow restriction to the supply line <b>18</b> upstream of the valve <b>20.</b> Thus, it may be easier to seal off an internal gas flow passage within the valve <b>20,</b> itself, than to seal off the portion of the supply line <b>18</b> upstream of the valve <b>20,</b> using the liquid sealant <b>37.</b> Additionally, or in the alternative, liquid sealant <b>37</b> may be applied to a location downstream of the valve <b>20.</b></p><p id="p0041" num="0041">The liquid sealant <b>37</b> may be stored in the sealant container <b>36</b> and subsequently released to a desired location of the hydrocarbon gas delivery system <b>10</b> in a variety of ways. In one, non-limiting example, the liquid sealant is stored under pressure within the sealant container <b>36.</b> An aerosol or propellant may be included within the sealant container <b>36</b> along with the liquid sealant <b>37.</b> A sealant flow path <b>49</b> may be provided from the sealant container <b>36</b> to the desired location of the hydrocarbon gas delivery system <b>10.</b> When the liquid sealant <b>37</b> is to be released, the sealant container <b>36</b> may be opened at the location of the sealant flow path <b>49</b> to release the liquid sealant 37 to the sealant flow path <b>49.</b> For example, the sealant container <b>36</b> may be punctured in a controlled manner, such as by driving a plunger <b>45</b> through a wall of the sealant container <b>36.</b> In another example, the sealant container may have a closure (not shown) that may be opened in a controlled manner when it is desired to release the liquid sealant <b>37</b> from the sealant container <b>36.</b> The prime mover <b>34</b> or a separate prime mover may be configured to release the liquid sealant when so signaled by the controller <b>38.</b> For example, the prime mover <b>34</b> may be mechanically coupled to a closure for selectively opening the sealant container 37 or to a plunger 45 for puncturing the sealant container <b>37.</b></p><p id="p0042" num="0042">Another, optional safety and convenience feature of the safety system <b>30</b> is a timer <b>33</b> for controlling the state of the valve <b>20</b> according to an electronic schedule. The electronic schedule may be included with the control logic that is executed by the controller <b>38.</b> The<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> electronic schedule may be user-configurable, allowing a user to input one or more scheduling parameters via the user interface <b>31.</b> For example, the safety system <b>30</b> may be configured to automatically close the valve <b>20</b> late at night, or during other user-programmable or factory-programmable time periods when the hydrocarbon gas-fueled device <b>16</b> is unlikely to be used. This function may include an override feature allowing a user to override any default scheduling, if the user desires to use the hydrocarbon gas-fueled device 16 during scheduled downtime.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">Alternatively, the prime mover <b>34</b> may close the valve <b>20</b> by default to reduce the likelihood of hydrocarbon gas from escaping from the hydrocarbon gas delivery system <b>10.</b> The timer <b>33</b> may be operated by a user to provide a finite time period during which the default closed-valve condition may be overridden. For example, if the hydrocarbon gas-fueled device <b>16</b> is a grill, the user may set the timer <b>33</b> for a desired time period, such as two hours, during which the safety system <b>30</b> may allow the valve to remain in the opened state. After expiration of the predefined time interval, the prime mover <b>34,</b> under the control of the controller <b>38,</b> may automatically power the valve 20 to the closed state.</p><p id="p0044" num="0044"><figref idrefs="f0002"><b>FIG.</b> 2</figref> is an elevation view of the hydrocarbon gas delivery system <b>10</b> according to a specific example embodiment. In this embodiment, the tank <b>12</b> is made of metal or other material having sufficient strength to withstand the internal pressure of LPG in the tank <b>12.</b> The tank <b>12</b> has a wall <b>50</b> having a wall thickness "t." A port <b>52</b> through the wall <b>50</b> is threaded. The rigid adapter body <b>39</b> includes a threaded pressure fitting <b>48</b> that threadedly mates with the threaded port <b>52,</b> to provide a sealed interface between the adapter body <b>39</b> and the tank <b>12.</b> More specifically, the sealed interface may be between a valve <b>20</b> contained within the adapter body <b>39</b> and the tank <b>12,</b> as hydrocarbon gas from the tank flows through the pressure fitting <b>48</b> to the valve <b>20</b> and typically not through the portion of the adapter body <b>39</b> external to the valve <b>20</b>. The threaded pressure fitting <b>48</b> and threaded port <b>52</b> may be manufactured, for example, according to a National Pipe Thread (NPT) standard.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045">The rigid adapter body <b>39</b> houses the LPG sensor <b>32,</b> the prime mover <b>34,</b> the energy source <b>35,</b> the sealant container <b>36,</b> and the sealant <b>37</b> in the sealed sealant container. The prime<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> mover <b>34</b> is embodied as an electric motor. The energy source <b>35</b> is embodied as an electric battery <b>35</b> electrically coupled to the motor <b>34</b> and to the LPG sensor <b>32.</b> The valve <b>20</b> is included within the adapter body <b>39</b> in this embodiment, and includes an externally-accessible knob <b>46.</b> The knob <b>46</b> may be rotated by hand in one direction (e.g. counterclockwise) to open the valve <b>20,</b> and in an opposite (e.g. clockwise) direction to close the valve <b>20.</b> The motor <b>34</b> may also power the valve <b>20</b> to the open or closed state. For example, the motor <b>34</b> and the knob <b>46</b> may be mechanically coupled to a common shaft <b>47</b> as part of a mechanical actuator used to open and close the valve <b>20.</b></p><p id="p0046" num="0046">A conventional pressure regulator <b>60</b> is optionally provided along the flow path from the tank <b>12</b> to the hydrocarbon gas-fueled device <b>16.</b> The pressure regulator <b>60</b> is secured to the adapter body <b>39</b> and is sealingly coupled to the valve <b>20</b> downstream of the valve <b>20.</b> The pressure regulator may be mechanically coupled to the adapter body <b>39</b> using any of a variety of mechanical fasteners known in the art. The pressure regulator <b>60</b> may be sealingly coupled to the valve <b>20</b> using, for example, a threaded connection (not shown). A polymeric hose <b>54,</b> which may be a component of the supply line <b>18</b> (see <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. <b>1</b></figref>), is used to couple the pressure regulator <b>60</b> to the hydrocarbon gased device <b>16,</b> as shown. The pressure regulator <b>60</b> includes its own flow control mechanism, which may include another valve, for independently controlling the flow of hydrocarbon gas through the pressure regulator <b>60.</b> During normal operation, a user may control the flow of hydrocarbon gas from the tank <b>12</b> to the hydrocarbon gas-fueled device <b>16</b> using the pressure regulator. For example, the user may use the pressure regulator <b>60</b> to open the flow of hydrocarbon gas, or to regulate the rate of flow of hydrocarbon gas, such as to adjust the intensity of a cooking flame at the hydrocarbon gas-fueled device <b>16.</b> The user may use the pressure regulator <b>60</b> to completely shut off the flow of hydrocarbon gas from the tank <b>12</b> to the hydrocarbon gas-fueled device <b>16</b> when the hydrocarbon gas-fueled device <b>16</b> is not in use. The valve <b>20</b> in the safety system <b>30</b> may then be separately controlled, as described above, to attempt to close the valve <b>20</b> in response to a signal from the LPG sensor <b>32.</b></p><p id="p0047" num="0047"><figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. <b>3</b></figref> is a flowchart of a method of controllably delivering hydrocarbon gas, such as to a hydrocarbon gas-fueled device, according to an embodiment of the invention. The flowchart may relate, for example, to the operation of the hydrocarbon gas delivery systems of <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGS. <b>1</b></figref><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> and <figref idrefs="f0002"><b>2</b></figref>, or more generally to other hydrocarbon gas delivery systems. Therefore, the method steps are described in the context of a hydrocarbon gas delivery system including an LPG tank and a hydrocarbon gas-fueled device to be supplied with hydrocarbon gas from the LPG tank.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048">Step <b>100</b> involves monitoring for airborne LPG in the vicinity of the hydrocarbon gas delivery system. For example, the airborne LPG may be caused by LPG leaking from the hydrocarbon gas delivery system or from non-combusted LPG entering the air due to an extinguished pilot flame of a hydrocarbon gas-fueled device. An electronic LPG sensor may be used to detect any airborne LPG. The sensor generates a signal in response to the detection of airborne LPG. The sensor generates a signal that at least generally indicates whether airborne LPG is or is not detected. The signal generated by the sensor may, more specifically, indicate a level of LPG detected, such as may be expressed as a concentration of LPG in the air.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">Conditional step <b>102</b> involves a determination of whether airborne LPG is present, as determined by the LPG sensor. This determination may be a simple determination of whether airborne LPG is, or is not, detected. This determination may alternatively involve a quantitative determination using one or more threshold value. For example, a sensed level of airborne LPG may be compared against a predetermined threshold level of LPG. A sensed level of airborne LPG that is less than the threshold value may generate a "NO" value, indicating that an appreciable level of airborne LPG is not detected. The hydrocarbon gas delivery system may continue to be operated normally according to step <b>104</b> if an appreciable level of airborne LPG is not detected. Conversely, a sensed level of airborne LPG that equals or exceeds the threshold value may generate a "YES" value at conditional step <b>102</b>, indicating that an appreciable level of airborne LPG has been detected.</p><p id="p0050" num="0050">Detecting an appreciable level of airborne LPG in conditional step <b>102</b> (resulting in a "YES" value) leads to conditional step <b>106</b>, which determines whether the valve used to control the flow of hydrocarbon gas from the tank is closed. If the valve is closed, the presence of airborne hydrocarbon gas in an appreciable amount indicates a leak. The valve may be assumed to be closed, for example, if a mechanical actuator used to close the valve is known<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> to be in a fully closed position. Thus, if the valve is already closed at conditional step <b>106</b>, then liquid sealant is released to a supply line of the hydrocarbon gas delivery system according to step <b>110</b>. The liquid sealant, once released, is intended to close the flow of hydrocarbon gas and/or seal a leak in the hydrocarbon gas delivery system. The released liquid sealant hardens at some point after it has been released.</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">If the valve is not yet closed at conditional step <b>106</b>, then conditional step <b>108</b> determines whether an attempt to close the valve has previously been performed. For example, a prime mover may have attempted to close the valve, but a stuck valve actuator or a faulty coupling between the prime move and the valve actuator may have prevented the full closure of the valve. Thus, if the valve is not closed according to conditional step <b>106</b>, but a previous (unsuccessful) attempt was made to close the valve according to conditional step <b>108,</b> then liquid sealant is released according to step <b>110</b> (described above). Alternatively, if the valve is not closed according to conditional step <b>106,</b> but no previous attempt was made to close the valve according to conditional step <b>108,</b> then an attempt is then made to close the valve according to step <b>112.</b> After attempting to close the valve in step <b>112,</b> the method may return to conditional step <b>102</b> of determining whether an appreciable amount of airborne hydrocarbon gas is detected.</p><p id="p0052" num="0052">Different threshold values for the detected level of airborne hydrocarbon gas may be used to trigger different corrective actions. For example, a first threshold value may be used for triggering the closure of the valve, and a second threshold value may be used for subsequently triggering the release of liquid sealant. In some cases, the first threshold value may equal the second threshold value. However, in other circumstances it is desirable for the second threshold value to be less than the first threshold value. For example, if airborne hydrocarbon gas continues to be detected after closing (or at least attempting to close) the valve, this indicates a possible leak in the hydrocarbon gas delivery system. Thus, the second threshold, used for triggering the release of liquid sealant, may be smaller in value than the first threshold, used for triggering closure of the valve. Although not required, any of the threshold values may be set below a critical value (e.g. a particular airborne concentration) at which hydrocarbon gas is known to combust or explode. For example, the<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> critical value may be the lower limit of a flammable range, which is the range of concentration of a gas or vapor that will burn (or explode) if an ignition source is introduced.</p><p id="p0053" num="0053">The threshold(s) may include one or more additional parameters in addition to a concentration. For example, each threshold may include both a concentration threshold and a corresponding time threshold, whereby a corrective action is taken only if a concentration threshold is continuously sensed for the full duration of a time threshold.</p><p id="p0054" num="0054">As will be appreciated by one skilled in the art, aspects of the present invention may be embodied as a system, method or computer program product. Accordingly, aspects of the present invention may take the form of an entirely hardware embodiment, an entirely software embodiment (including firmware, resident software, micro-code, etc.) or an embodiment combining software and hardware aspects that may all generally be referred to herein as a "circuit," "module" or "system." Furthermore, aspects of the present invention may take the form of a computer program product embodied in one or more computer readable medium(s) having computer readable program code embodied thereon.</p><p id="p0055" num="0055">Any combination of one or more computer readable medium(s) may be utilized. The computer readable medium may be a computer readable signal medium or a computer readable storage medium. A computer readable storage medium may be, for example, but not limited to, an electronic, magnetic, optical, electromagnetic, infrared, or semiconductor system, apparatus, or device, or any suitable combination of the foregoing. More specific examples (a non-exhaustive list) of the computer readable storage medium would include the following: an electrical connection having one or more wires, a portable computer diskette, a hard disk, a random access memory (RAM), a read-only memory (ROM), an erasable programmable read-only memory (EPROM or Flash memory), an optical fiber, a portable compact disc read-only memory (CD-ROM), an optical storage device, a magnetic storage device, or any suitable combination of the foregoing. In the context of this document, a computer readable storage medium may be any tangible medium that can contain, or store a program for use by or in connection with an instruction execution system, apparatus, or device.<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --></p><p id="p0056" num="0056">A computer readable signal medium may include a propagated data signal with computer readable program code embodied therein, for example, in baseband or as part of a carrier wave. Such a propagated signal may take any of a variety of forms, including, but not limited to, electro-magnetic, optical, or any suitable combination thereof. A computer readable signal medium may be any computer readable medium that is not a computer readable storage medium and that can communicate, propagate, or transport a program for use by or in connection with an instruction execution system, apparatus, or device.</p><p id="p0057" num="0057">Program code embodied on a computer readable medium may be transmitted using any appropriate medium, including but not limited to wireless, wireline, optical fiber cable, RF, etc., or any suitable combination of the foregoing.</p><p id="p0058" num="0058">Computer program code for carrying out operations for aspects of the present invention may be written in any combination of one or more programming languages, including an object oriented programming language such as Java, Smalltalk, C++ or the like and conventional procedural programming languages, such as the "C" programming language or similar programming languages. The program code may execute entirely on the user's computer, partly on the user's computer, as a stand-alone software package, partly on the user's computer and partly on a remote computer or entirely on the remote computer or server. In the latter scenario, the remote computer may be connected to the user's computer through any type of network, including a local area network (LAN) or a wide area network (WAN), or the connection may be made to an external computer (for example, through the Internet using an Internet Service Provider).</p><p id="p0059" num="0059">Aspects of the present invention are described above with reference to flowchart illustrations and/or block diagrams of methods, apparatus (systems) and computer program products according to embodiments of the invention. It will be understood that each block of the flowchart illustrations and/or block diagrams, and combinations of blocks in the flowchart illustrations and/or block diagrams, can be implemented by computer program instructions. These computer program instructions may be provided to a processor of a general purpose computer, special purpose computer, or other programmable data processing apparatus to produce a machine, such that the instructions, which execute via the processor of the<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> computer or other programmable data processing apparatus, create means for implementing the functions/acts specified in the flowchart and/or block diagram block or blocks.</p><p id="p0060" num="0060">These computer program instructions may also be stored in a computer readable medium that can direct a computer, other programmable data processing apparatus, or other devices to function in a particular manner, such that the instructions stored in the computer readable medium produce an article of manufacture including instructions which implement the function/act specified in the flowchart and/or block diagram block or blocks.</p><p id="p0061" num="0061">The computer program instructions may also be loaded onto a computer, other programmable data processing apparatus, or other devices to cause a series of operational steps to be performed on the computer, other programmable apparatus or other devices to produce a computer implemented process such that the instructions which execute on the computer or other programmable apparatus provide processes for implementing the functions/acts specified in the flowchart and/or block diagram block or blocks.</p><p id="p0062" num="0062">The flowchart and block diagrams in the Figures illustrate the architecture, functionality, and operation of possible implementations of systems, methods and computer program products according to various embodiments of the present invention. In this regard, each block in the flowchart or block diagrams may represent a module, segment, or portion of code, which comprises one or more executable instructions for implementing the specified logical function(s). It should also be noted that, in some alternative implementations, the functions noted in the block may occur out of the order noted in the figures. For example, two blocks shown in succession may, in fact, be executed substantially concurrently, or the blocks may sometimes be executed in the reverse order, depending upon the functionality involved. It will also be noted that each block of the block diagrams and/or flowchart illustration, and combinations of blocks in the block diagrams and/or flowchart illustration, can be implemented by special purpose hardware-based systems that perform the specified functions or acts, or combinations of special purpose hardware and computer instructions.</p><p id="p0063" num="0063">The terminology used herein is for the purpose of describing particular embodiments only and is not intended to be limiting of the invention. As used herein, the singular forms "a",<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> "an" and "the" are intended to include the plural forms as well, unless the context clearly indicates otherwise. It will be further understood that the terms "comprises" and/or "comprising," when used in this specification, specify the presence of stated features, integers, steps, operations, elements, components and/or groups, but do not preclude the presence or addition of one or more other features, integers, steps, operations, elements, components, and/or groups thereof. The terms "preferably," "preferred," "prefer," "optionally," "may," and similar terms are used to indicate that an item, condition or step being referred to is an optional (not required) feature of the invention.</p><p id="p0064" num="0064">The corresponding structures, materials, acts, and equivalents of all means or steps plus function elements in the claims below are intended to include any structure, material, or act for performing the function in combination with other claimed elements as specifically claimed. The description of the present invention has been presented for purposes of illustration and description, but it is not intended to be exhaustive or limited to the invention as defined by the claims. Many modifications and variations will be apparent to those of ordinary skill in the art without departing from the scope of the invention as defined by the claims. The embodiment was chosen and described in order to best explain the principles of the invention and the practical application, and to enable others of ordinary skill in the art to understand the invention for various embodiments with various modifications as are suited to the particular use contemplated.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56977667" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>System (10) zum steuerbaren Zuführen eines Kohlenwasserstoffgases zu einer mit Kohlenwasserstoff betriebenen Einheit (16), das System aufweisend:
<claim-text>einen Druckbehälter (12) zum Enthalten eines unter Druck stehenden Kohlenwasserstoffgases (14);</claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Ventil (20), welches selektiv zwischen einem offenen Zustand und einem geschlossenen Zustand bewegbar ist, zum Steuern des Stroms des Kohlenwasserstoffgases aus dem Druckbehälter zu einer Versorgungsleitung (18) in Fluidkommunikation mit dem Druckbehälter (12);</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Kohlenwasserstoffgas-Sensor (32) zum Erkennen von Kohlenwasserstoffgas in der Luft und zum Erzeugen eines Signals in Reaktion darauf; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Steuerung (38) in Kommunikation mit dem Kohlenwasserstoffgas-Sensor (32) und dem Ventil (20), wobei die Steuerung (38) einen Primärantrieb (34) aufweist, der so zu betreiben ist, dass das Ventil (20) in Reaktion auf das Signal von dem Kohlenwasserstoffgas-Sensor (32) automatisch in den geschlossenen Zustand bewegt wird, wenn sich das Ventil (20) in dem offenen Zustand befindet, <b>gekennzeichnet durch</b>:
<claim-text>ein flüssiges Dichtungsmittel (37) in einem Dichtungsmittelbehälter (36), wobei das flüssige Dichtungsmittel (37) eine Zusammensetzung aufweist, die<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --> zum Aushärten einsetzbar ist, wenn sie aus dem Dichtungsmittelbehälter (36) freigesetzt wird; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei die Steuerung (38) so zu betreiben ist, dass das flüssige Dichtungsmittel (37) in Reaktion auf das Signal von dem Kohlenwasserstoffgas-Sensor (32) zu der Versorgungsleitung (18) freigesetzt wird, wenn sich das Ventil (20) in dem geschlossenen Zustand befindet.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Kohlenwasserstoffgas-Zuführsystem nach Anspruch 1, wobei das Ventil (20) ein mechanisches Ventilstellelement (22) aufweist, welches so zu bedienen ist, dass das Ventil (20) manuell per Hand zwischen dem offenen und geschlossenen Zustand bewegt wird, und wobei der Primärantrieb (34) lösbar mit dem mechanischen Ventilstellelement (22) verbunden ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Kohlenwasserstoffgas-Zuführsystem nach Anspruch 1 oder 2, ferner aufweisend:
<claim-text>ein starres Passgehäuse (39), welches den Primärantrieb (34), den Sensor (32), den Dichtungsmittelbehälter (36) und das Dichtungsmittel (37) enthält, wobei das Passgehäuse so einzusetzen ist, dass es lösbar an dem Ventil (20) zu befestigen ist, wobei der Primärantrieb (34) operativ mit dem mechanischen Ventilstellelement (22) verbunden ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Kohlenwasserstoffgas-Zuführsystem nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei das von dem Sensor (32) erzeugte Signal einen erkannten Kohlenwasserstoffgas-Pegel umfasst und wobei die Steuerung (38) so zu<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> betreiben ist, dass das Ventil (20) in Reaktion darauf, dass der Pegel einen ersten Schwellenwert erreicht, während sich das Ventil in dem offenen Zustand befindet, automatisch in den geschlossenen Zustand bewegt wird, und dass das flüssige Dichtungsmittel (37) in Reaktion darauf, dass der Pegel einen zweiten Schwellenwert erreicht, zu der Versorgungsleitung freigesetzt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Kohlenwasserstoffgas-Zuführsystem nach Anspruch 4, wobei der zweite Schwellenwert niedriger als der erste Schwellenwert ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Kohlenwasserstoffgas-Zuführsystem nach Anspruch 4 oder 5, wobei jeder Schwellenwert einen Konzentrations-Schwellenwert und einen entsprechenden Zeit-Schwellenwert umfasst, wobei eine Korrekturhandlung nur erfolgt, wenn der Konzentrations-Schwellenwert für die vollständige Dauer des entsprechenden Zeit-Schwellenwerts durchgängig nachgewiesen wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Kohlenwasserstoffgas-Zuführsystem nach einem der Ansprüche 3 bis 6, ferner aufweisend:
<claim-text>eine elektronische Benutzerschnittstelle (31) auf dem starren Passgehäuse (39) zum Übermitteln von Ablaufplanparametern von einem Benutzer an die Steuerung (38), wobei die Steuerung so zu betreiben ist, dass ein Ablaufplan zum Schließen des Ventils (20) gemäß den Ablaufplanparametern konfiguriert wird.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Kohlenwasserstoffgas-Zuführsystem nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei die Steuerung ferner aufweist:
<claim-text>eine zeitliche Ablaufsteuerung, wobei die Steuerung (38) dafür konfiguriert ist, das Ventil (20) gemäß einem vorprogrammierten Ablaufplan zu schließen.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Kohlenwasserstoffgas-Zuführsystem nach Anspruch 8, wobei der vorprogrammierte Ablaufplan durch einen Benutzer konfigurierbar ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Kohlenwasserstoffgas-Zuführsystem nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei der Primärantrieb (34) das Ventil (20) in einen Standardzustand eines geschlossenen Ventils vorspannt und die zeitliche Ablaufsteuerung so zu betreiben ist, dass eine endliche Zeitperiode bereitgestellt wird, während welcher der Standardzustand des geschlossenen Ventils überschaltbar ist und nach welcher der Primärantrieb (34) das Ventil (20) automatisch zurück in den Standardzustand des geschlossenen Ventils bringt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Kohlenwasserstoffgas-Zuführsystem nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei das flüssige Dichtungsmittel (37) innerhalb des Dichtungsmittelbehälters (36) unter ausreichendem Druck steht, um das flüssige Dichtungsmittel (37) in Reaktion auf das Freisetzen des flüssigen Dichtungsmittels (37) aus dem Dichtungsmittelbehälter (36) in die Versorgungsleitung (18) zu bewegen.<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Verfahren zum steuerbaren Zuführen von Kohlenwasserstoffgas (14), das Verfahren aufweisend:
<claim-text>selektives Öffnen und Schließen eines Ventils (20), um den Strom von Kohlenwasserstoffgas aus einem Druckbehälter (12) zu einer Versorgungsleitung (18) für eine durch Kohlenwasserstoff betriebene Einheit (16) zu steuern;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Erkennen (102) jedes Kohlenwasserstoffgases in der Luft;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Bewegen des Ventils (20) von einem offenen Zustand in einen geschlossenen Zustand in Reaktion auf das Erkennen von Kohlenwasserstoffgas in der Luft, während sich das Ventil (20) in dem offenen Zustand befindet; <b>gekennzeichnet durch</b>:
<claim-text>Freisetzen eines flüssigen Dichtungsmittels (37) zu der Versorgungsleitung (18) in Reaktion auf das Erkennen von entwichenem Gas, nachdem zumindest versucht worden ist, das Ventil (20) in den geschlossenen Zustand zu bewegen.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 12, ferner aufweisend:
<claim-text>selektives Schließen des Ventils (20) gemäß einem elektronisch gespeicherten Ablaufplan.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 12 oder 13, wobei der Schritt des Bewegens des Ventils (20) von einem offenen Zustand in einen geschlossenen Zustand ein Betreiben eines Primärantriebs (34) aufweist, so dass ein mechanisches Ventilstellelement (22) automatisch angetrieben wird.<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 12 bis 14, welches ferner aufweist, in Reaktion auf das Erkennen des entwichenen Gases bei einem vorgegebenen Schwellenwert zu versuchen, das Ventil (20) in den geschlossenen Zustand zu bewegen.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56977668" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A system (10) for controllably delivering hydrocarbon gas to a hydrocarbon gas-fueled device (16), the system comprising:
<claim-text>a pressure vessel (12) for containing a pressurized hydrocarbon gas (14);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a valve (20) selectively movable between an open state and a closed state for controlling the flow of the hydrocarbon gas from the pressure vessel to a supply line (18) in fluid communication with the pressure vessel (12),</claim-text>
<claim-text>a hydrocarbon gas sensor (32) for detecting airborne hydrocarbon gas and generating a signal in response; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a controller (38) in communication with the hydrocarbon gas sensor (32) and the valve (20), the controller (38) comprising a prime mover (34) operable for automatically moving the valve (20) to the closed state in response to the signal from the hydrocarbon gas sensor (32) if the valve (20) is in the open state; <b>characterised by</b>:
<claim-text>a liquid sealant (37) in a sealant container (36), the liquid sealant (37) comprising a composition operable for hardening if released from the sealant container (36), and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the controller (38) operable for releasing the liquid sealant (37) to the supply line (18) in response to the signal from the hydrocarbon gas sensor (32) if the valve (20) is in the closed state.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The hydrocarbon gas delivery system of claim 1, wherein the valve (20) comprises a mechanical valve actuator (22) operable for manually moving the valve (20) between the open and closed states by hand, and wherein the prime mover (34) is removably coupled to the mechanical valve actuator (22).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The hydrocarbon gas delivery system of claim 1 or 2, further comprising:
<claim-text>a rigid adapter body (39) holding the prime mover (34), the sensor (32), the sealant container (36) and sealant (37), wherein the adapter body is operable for removably securing to the valve (20) with the prime mover (34) operably coupled to the mechanical valve actuator (22).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The hydrocarbon gas delivery system of any preceding claim, wherein the signal generated by the sensor (32) includes a detected level of hydrocarbon gas, and wherein the controller (38) is operable for automatically moving the valve (20) to the closed state in response to the<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> level reaching a first threshold value while the valve is in the open state and for releasing the liquid sealant (37) to the supply line in response to the level reaching a second threshold value.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The hydrocarbon gas delivery system of claim 4, wherein the second threshold value is less than the first threshold value.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The hydrocarbon gas delivery system of claim 4 or 5, wherein each threshold value includes a concentration threshold value and a corresponding time threshold value, whereby a corrective action is taken only if the concentration threshold value is continuously sensed for the full duration of the corresponding time threshold value.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The hydrocarbon gas delivery system of any of claims 3 to 6, further comprising:
<claim-text>an electronic user interface (31) on the rigid adapter body (39) for communicating scheduling parameters from a user to the controller (38), wherein the controller is operable for configuring a schedule for closing the valve (20) according to the scheduling parameters.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The hydrocarbon gas delivery system of any preceding claim, wherein the controller further comprises:
<claim-text>a timer, wherein the controller (38) is configured for closing the valve (20) according to a preprogrammed schedule.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The hydrocarbon gas delivery system of claim 8, wherein the preprogrammed schedule is user-configurable.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The hydrocarbon gas delivery system of any preceding claim, wherein the prime mover (34) biases the valve (20) to a default closed-valve state, and the timer is operable for providing a finite time period during which the default closed-valve state may be overridden, after which the prime mover (34) automatically powers the valve (20) back to the default closed-valve state.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>The hydrocarbon gas delivery system of any preceding claim, wherein the liquid sealant (37) is pressurized within the sealant container (36) under sufficient pressure to move the liquid sealant (37) into the supply line (18) in response to releasing the liquid sealant (37) from the sealant container (36).<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>A method of controllably delivering hydrocarbon gas (14), the method comprising:
<claim-text>selectively opening and closing a valve (20) to control the flow of hydrocarbon gas from a pressure vessel (12) to a supply line (18) for a hydrocarbon gas-fueled device (16);</claim-text>
<claim-text>detecting (102) any airborne hydrocarbon gas;</claim-text>
<claim-text>moving the valve (20) from an pen state to a closed state in response to detecting airborne hydrocarbon gas while the valve (20) is in the open state; <b>characterised by</b>:
<claim-text>releasing a liquid sealant (37) to the supply line (18) in response to detecting escaped gas after at least attempting to move the valve (20) to the closed state.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>The method of claim 12, further comprising:
<claim-text>selectively closing the valve (20) according to an electronically-stored schedule.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>The method of any of claims 12 or 13, wherein the step of moving the valve (20) from an open state to a closed state comprises operating a prime mover (34) for automatically urging a mechanical valve actuator (22).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>The method of any of claims 12 to 14, further comprising automatically attempting to move the valve (20) to the closed state in response to detecting the escaped gas at a predetermined threshold value.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56977669" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Système (10) destiné à l'alimentation contrôlée d'hydrocarbures sous forme gazeuse à une unité (16) alimentée par des hydrocarbures gazeux, le système comprenant :
<claim-text>une enceinte sous pression (12) destinée à contenir un hydrocarbure gazeux pressurisé (14) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une vanne (20), manoeuvrable sélectivement entre une position ouverte et une position fermée, pour contrôler l'écoulement de l'hydrocarbure gazeux de l'enceinte sous pression vers une conduite d'approvisionnement (18) en communication fluide avec l'enceinte sous pression (12) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un détecteur d'hydrocarbure gazeux (32) pour détecter l'hydrocarbure gazeux atmosphérique et générer un signal en réponse ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un régulateur (38) en communication avec le détecteur d'hydrocarbure gazeux (32) et la vanne (20), le régulateur (38) comprenant un moteur d'entraînement (34) utilisable pour la manoeuvre automatique de la vanne (20) vers la position fermée en réponse au signal du détecteur d'hydrocarbure gazeux (32) lorsque la vanne (20) est en position ouverte ; <b>caractérisé par</b> :
<claim-text>un enduit d'étanchéité liquide (37) dans un conteneur d'enduit d'étanchéité (36), l'enduit d'étanchéité liquide (37) comprenant une composition destinée à durcir<!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --> si elle est libérée du conteneur d'enduit d'étanchéité (36) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>le régulateur (38) destiné à libérer l'enduit d'étanchéité liquide (37) dans la conduite d'approvisionnement (18) en réponse au signal du détecteur d'hydrocarbure gazeux (32) lorsque la vanne (20) est en position fermée.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Système de d'alimentation d'hydrocarbure gazeux selon la revendication 1, dans lequel la vanne (20) comprend un actionneur mécanique (22) de vanne fonctionnant par mouvement manuel de la vanne (20) entre la position ouverte et la position fermée, et dans lequel le moteur d'entraînement (34) est couplé de manière amovible à l'actionneur mécanique (22) de la vanne.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Système d'alimentation d'hydrocarbure gazeux selon les revendications 1 ou 2, comprenant en outre :
<claim-text>un corps d'adaptateur rigide (39) maintenant le moteur d'entraînement (34), le capteur (32), le conteneur d'enduit d'étanchéité (36) et l'enduit (37), dans lequel le corps de l'adaptateur est utilisable pour fixer de manière amovible la vanne (20) avec le moteur d'entraînement (34) couplé en fonctionnement à l'actionneur mécanique (22) de la vanne.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Système d'alimentation d'hydrocarbure gazeux selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans lequel le signal généré par le capteur (32) inclut une quantité détectée d'hydrocarbure gazeux, et dans lequel le régulateur (38) est utilisable pour manoeuvrer<!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --> automatiquement la vanne (20) vers la position fermée en réponse lorsque le niveau atteint une première valeur de seuil pendant que la vanne est en position ouverte et pour la libération de l'enduit d'étanchéité liquide (37) dans la conduite d'approvisionnement en réponse lorsque le niveau atteint une seconde valeur de seuil.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Système d'alimentation d'hydrocarbure gazeux selon la revendication 4, dans lequel la seconde valeur de seuil est inférieure à la première valeur de seuil.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Système d'alimentation d'hydrocarbure gazeux selon les revendications 4 ou 5, dans lequel chaque valeur de seuil inclut une valeur de seuil en concentration et une valeur de seuil correspondante en temps, par laquelle une action corrective est prise seulement si la valeur de seuil en concentration est captée de manière continue pendant la durée complète de la valeur de seuil correspondante en temps.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Système d'alimentation d'hydrocarbure gazeux selon l'une quelconque des revendications 3 à 6, comprenant en outre :
<claim-text>une interface d'utilisateur électronique (31) sur le corps de l'adaptateur rigide (39) pour communiquer les paramètres de planification d'un utilisateur au régulateur (38), dans lequel le régulateur est utilisé pour configurer la planification de la fermeture de la vanne (20) en fonction des paramètres de planification.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Système d'alimentation d'hydrocarbure gazeux selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans lequel le régulateur comprend en outre :
<claim-text>un minuteur, dans lequel le régulateur (38) est configuré pour fermer la vanne (20) selon un planning préprogrammé.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Système d'alimentation d'hydrocarbure gazeux selon la revendication 8, dans lequel le planning préprogrammé est configurable par l'utilisateur.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Système d'alimentation d'hydrocarbure gazeux selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans lequel le moteur d'entraînement (34) ramène la vanne (20) vers une position par défaut de vanne fermée, et le minuteur est utilisable pour procurer une période de temps limitée pendant laquelle la position fermée par défaut de la vanne peut être abrogée, après quoi le moteur d'entraînement (34) fait revenir automatiquement la vanne (20) à la position de la vanne fermée par défaut.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Système d'alimentation d'hydrocarbure gazeux selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans lequel l'enduit d'étanchéité liquide (37) est mis sous pression dans le conteneur d'enduit (36) à une pression suffisante pour envoyer l'enduit d'étanchéité liquide (37) dans la conduite d'approvisionnement (18) en réponse à la libération de l'enduit d'étanchéité liquide (37) à partir du conteneur d'enduit (36).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Procédé pour l'alimentation de manière contrôlée d'un hydrocarbure gazeux (14), le procédé comprenant :<!-- EPO <DP n="34"> -->
<claim-text>l'ouverture et la fermeture sélective d'une vanne (20) pour contrôler le flux d'hydrocarbure gazeux d'une enceinte sous pression (12) vers une conduite d'approvisionnement (18) pour une unité (16) alimentée par des hydrocarbures gazeux ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>la détection (102) de n'importe quel hydrocarbure gazeux atmosphérique ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>la manoeuvre de la vanne (20) d'une position ouverte vers une position fermée en réponse à la détection d'hydrocarbure gazeux atmosphérique pendant que la vanne (20) est en position ouverte ; <b>caractérisé par</b> :
<claim-text>la libération d'un enduit d'étanchéité liquide (37) dans la conduite d'approvisionnement (18) en réponse à une fuite de gaz détectée après au moins avoir tenté de mettre la vanne (20) en position fermée.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 12, comprenant en outre :
<claim-text>la fermeture sélective de la vanne (20) selon un planning gardé en mémoire électroniquement.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications 12 ou 13, dans lequel l'étape de la manoeuvre de la vanne (20) d'une position ouverte vers une position fermée comprend l'action d'un moteur d'entraînement (34) pour pousser automatiquement un actionneur mécanique (22) de la vanne.<!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications 12 à 14, comprenant en outre la tentative automatique de manoeuvrer la vanne (20) en position fermée en réponse à la détection d'une fuite de gaz à une valeur de seuil prédéterminée.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16668346" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="36"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="165" he="229" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="37"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="118" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="38"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="158" he="223" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
