<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2680301-A1" country="EP" doc-number="2680301" kind="A1" date="20140101" family-id="46720643" file-reference-id="246385" date-produced="20180824" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146549303" ucid="EP-2680301-A1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2680301</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-12749782-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154823226" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12749782</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120207</date><lang>JA</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP181745959" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12749782.4</doc-number><date>20120207</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140452563" ucid="JP-2011038764-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>JP</country><doc-number>2011038764</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20110224</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140454674" ucid="JP-2012052655-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>JP</country><doc-number>2012052655</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20120207</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1946289578" load-source="docdb">H01L  21/60        20060101AFI20160418BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1946289579" load-source="docdb">H01C   7/04        20060101ALI20160418BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1946289580" load-source="docdb">H01C   1/14        20060101ALI20160418BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2001300832" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01L  35/02        20130101 FI20151112BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2027179356" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01C   1/14        20130101 LI20150825BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2027180565" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01L2924/00013     20130101 LA20150825BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2027181894" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01L2924/0002      20130101 LA20150825BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2027182034" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01C   1/014       20130101 LI20150825BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2027182890" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01C   1/1413      20130101 LA20150825BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2027184160" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01C   1/144       20130101 LI20150825BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2027185409" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01L  24/16        20130101 LI20150825BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2027188023" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01C   1/1406      20130101 LA20150825BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2027189207" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01C   7/008       20130101 LI20150825BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132180393" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">MONTAGESTRUKTUR FÜR ELEKTRONISCHE BAUTEILE</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132180394" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">ELECTRONIC-COMPONENT-MOUNTING STRUCTURE</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132180395" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">STRUCTURE DE MONTAGE DE COMPOSANT ÉLECTRONIQUE</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918170673" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>MURATA MANUFACTURING CO</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918136808" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>MURATA MANUFACTURING CO., LTD.</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918991230" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Murata Manufacturing Co., Ltd.</last-name><iid>101325781</iid><address><street>10-1 Higashikotari 1-chome</street><city>Nagaokakyo-shi, Kyoto 617-8555</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918134077" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>MIURA TADAMASA</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918168186" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>MIURA, TADAMASA</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918984769" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>MIURA, TADAMASA</last-name><address><street>c/o Murata Manufacturing Co. Ltd. 10-1 Higashikotari 1-chome</street><city>Nagaokakyo-shi Kyoto 617-8555</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918978678" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Zinkler, Franz</last-name><suffix>et al</suffix><iid>100046196</iid><address><street>Schoppe, Zimmermann, Stöckeler &amp; Zinkler Patentanwälte Postfach 246</street><city>82043 Pullach bei München</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="JP-2012052655-W"><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>2012052655</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20120207</date><lang>JA</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2012114857-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2012114857</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20120830</date><lang>JA</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548859736" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS548857924" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS548859737" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS548854702" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS548840117" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS548882246" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS548857925" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS548859738" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548882247" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS548882920" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS548804077" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS548854703" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS548854704" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548859739" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548882921" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS548859740" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS548857926" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS548840118" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS548859741" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS548854705" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS548882922" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS548802857" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS548857927" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS548802858" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS548802859" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS548857737" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS548857738" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS548804082" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS548854706" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS548857739" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS548840119" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS548804083" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS548840120" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS548857740" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS548840121" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS548854707" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS548857741" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS548882923" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA128669973" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p id="pa01" num="0001">According to the present invention, there are provided an electronic-component mounting structure and an electronic-component mounting method, in each of which solder mounting can be performed, and solder rise is not likely to occur.</p><p id="pa02" num="0002">The electronic-component mounting structure includes an electronic component which has a metal substrate, a semiconductor ceramic layer formed on the metal substrate, a pair of split electrodes formed on the semiconductor ceramic layer, and plating films formed on the split electrodes and the metal substrate; and a mounting body on which lands to be connected to the respective split electrodes of the electronic component are formed. The position of a peripheral end portion of each land to be connected to the corresponding split electrode is located inside than the position of a peripheral end portion of the split electrode. In addition, a plane area of the land is smaller than that of the split electrode.<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="155" he="81" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA128499346" lang="EN" source="EPO" load-source="docdb"><p>According to the present invention, there are provided an electronic-component mounting structure and an electronic-component mounting method, in each of which solder mounting can be performed, and solder rise is not likely to occur.  The electronic-component mounting structure includes an electronic component which has a metal substrate, a semiconductor ceramic layer formed on the metal substrate, a pair of split electrodes formed on the semiconductor ceramic layer, and plating films formed on the split electrodes and the metal substrate; and a mounting body on which lands to be connected to the respective split electrodes of the electronic component are formed. The position of a peripheral end portion of each land to be connected to the corresponding split electrode is located inside than the position of a peripheral end portion of the split electrode. In addition, a plane area of the land is smaller than that of the split electrode.</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES63955403" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001">Technical Field</heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to a mounting structure in which an electronic component including a metal substrate, a semiconductor ceramic layer, and split electrodes is mounted on a mounting body.</p><heading id="h0002">Background Art</heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">Heretofore, as an NTC thermistor or a PTC thermistor, which is used as a temperature sensor in a protective circuit, a thermistor disclosed in Patent Document 1 has been known. The thermistor disclosed in Patent Document 1 is formed of a flat metal substrate also functioning as an electrode, a temperature-sensitive resistive film formed on one primary surface of the metal substrate, and one electrode film formed on the temperature-sensitive resistive film.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">However, the above-described thermistor has a structure in which the flat metal substrate is used as one electrode, and the electrode film formed as the topmost layer is used as the other electrode. Hence, when this thermistor is<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> mounted on a substrate or the like, an electrical connection to the electrode film has to be performed by wire bonding, and hence mounting to an extremely small space has been impossible. For example, when the thermistor as described above is used as a temperature sensor of an IC component mounted on a printed circuit board, a small space, such as 150 to 200 µm, is formed between the printed circuit board and the IC component, and the thermistor is preferably mounted in this space. However, it is practically difficult to perform mounting in this small space by wire bonding.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">Accordingly, the invention disclosed in PCT application (<patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="JP2010064089W"><text>PCT/JP2010/64089</text></patcit>) was made by the present inventor. In particular, in this application, there are provided a metal substrate, a thin thermistor layer formed on the metal substrate, and a pair of split electrodes formed on the thin thermistor layer. According to the structure as described above, solder mounting can be performed on a printed circuit board by a reflow method or the like. When solder mounting is performed, in general, in order to improve solder wettability, plating films are formed on the split electrodes. In the structure as described above, when a split-electrode side is mounted on lands formed on the printed circuit board, solder rise from the lands to a surface of the metal substrate occurs, and the problem in<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> that the split electrodes are electrically connected to the metal substrate with the solder may occur. As a result, a short-circuit defect is disadvantageously generated.</p><heading id="h0003">Citation List</heading><heading id="h0004">Patent Document</heading><p id="p0005" num="0005"><ul><li>Patent Document 1: Japanese Unexamined Patent Application Publication No. <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="JP61245502A"><text>61-245502</text></patcit></li></ul></p><heading id="h0005">Summary of Invention</heading><heading id="h0006">Technical Problem</heading><p id="p0006" num="0006">Accordingly, an object of the present invention is to provide an electronic-component mounting structure in which solder mounting can be performed, and solder rise to a metal substrate is not likely to occur.</p><heading id="h0007">Solution to Problem</heading><p id="p0007" num="0007">A first aspect of the present invention provides an electronic-component mounting structure comprising: an electronic component which includes a metal substrate, a semiconductor ceramic layer formed on the metal substrate, a pair of split electrodes formed on the semiconductor ceramic layer, and plating films formed on the split electrodes and the metal substrate; and a mounting body on which lands to be connected to the respective split electrodes of the<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> electronic component are formed. In the electronic-component mounting structure described above, the position of a peripheral end portion of each land to be connected to the corresponding split electrode is located inside than the position of a peripheral end portion of the split electrode.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">As described above, since the position of the peripheral end portion of the land is located inside the electronic component than the position of the peripheral end portion of the split electrode, solder applied to the land is not likely to reach a peripheral side of the metal substrate, and solder rise to the plating film formed on a surface of the metal substrate can be prevented.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">In addition, a plane area of the land is preferably smaller than a plane area of the split electrode (second aspect of the present invention).</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">Since the plane area of the land is smaller than the plane area of the split electrode, the solder applied to the land is not more likely to reach the peripheral side of the metal substrate, and hence the solder rise to the metal substrate can be further prevented.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">In addition, the thickness of the metal substrate of<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> the electronic component is preferably 10 to 80 µm, and the thickness of the ceramic layer is preferably 1 to 10 µm (third aspect of the present invention).</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">In the electronic component as described above, since the reduction in height thereof can be realized, mounting can be performed even in an extremely small space, such as 200 µm or less, and in addition, since the thin ceramic layer and the thin metal substrate are integrally formed together, flexible properties can be obtained. Hence, even if a stress is applied to the electronic component, cracks are not likely to be generated in a ceramic layer portion, and even if irregularities and steps are present in a mounting space, mounting can be carried out. In the case of the electronic component having flexibility as described above, if the electronic component receives a stress when mounted on a mounting body, the position of the peripheral side of the metal substrate is liable to be shifted in a thickness direction, and the position of the peripheral end portion of the metal substrate and the position of the land are liable to be closer to each other. As a result, the solder rise to the surface of the metal substrate is liable to occur. However, when a first or a second structure of the present invention is used, the solder rise can be sufficiently prevented. That is, in particular, the present<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> invention can be effectively applied to a flexible electronic component which satisfies the above conditions.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">The metal substrate of the electronic component preferably has a sheet shape formed from a metal powder paste, and the ceramic layer preferably has a sheet shape formed from a ceramic slurry (fourth aspect of the present invention).</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">In addition, the sheet-shaped metal substrate and the sheet-shaped ceramic layer are preferably obtained by firing while integrally laminated together (fifth aspect of the present invention).</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">In the structure as described above, there can be provided an electronic component in which flexibility can be reliably obtained, and in addition, cracks and the like are not likely to be generated in the ceramic layer.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">In addition, a protective layer formed from an insulating material is preferably formed on a surface of the ceramic layer on which at least the split electrodes are formed (sixth aspect of the present invention).</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">When the above structure is formed, the plating film<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> formed on the split electrode can be reliably insulated from the metal substrate. Accordingly, the solder applied to the land does not reach the peripheral side of the metal substrate, and the solder rise to the surface of the metal substrate can be reliably prevented.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">In addition, the plating film is preferably formed on a surface of the metal substrate (seventh aspect of the present invention).</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">When the plating film is formed by electric field plating, it is preferable since the manufacturing process is easy, and a dense plating film can be obtained. However, when the plating films are formed on the split electrodes by electric field plating, the plating film is also formed on the metal substrate formed from a metal. In this case, since the same plating film is formed on both the split electrode and the metal substrate, the solder rise to a surface of the plating film on the metal substrate is more liable to occur. However, according to the first or the second structure of the present invention, the solder rise can be sufficiently prevented. That is, in particular, the present invention is effectively applied to an electronic component which satisfies the above condition in which the plating film is formed on the surface of the metal substrate.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></p><heading id="h0008">Advantageous Effects of Invention</heading><p id="p0020" num="0020">According to the present invention, solder mounting can be performed, and in addition, since the solder rise to the surface of the metal substrate is not likely to occur, a short-circuit defect is not likely to be generated. Brief Description of Drawings</p><p id="p0021" num="0021"><ul><li>[<figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1] Fig. 1</figref> is a cross-sectional view showing a mounting structure of a flexible thermistor according to a first embodiment of the present invention.</li><li>[<figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2] Fig. 2(a)</figref> is a plan view of a flexible thermistor 1A according to the first embodiment, and <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2(b)</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the flexible thermistor 1A according to the first embodiment.</li><li>[<figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 3] Fig. 3</figref> shows an equivalent circuit of the flexible thermistor 1A according to the first embodiment.</li><li>[<figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 4] Fig. 4</figref> shows a pathway of a current passing through the flexible thermistor 1A according to the first embodiment.</li><li>[<figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 5] Fig. 5</figref> includes views each showing an example of a method for manufacturing the flexible thermistor 1A according to the first embodiment.</li><li>[<figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 6] Fig. 6</figref> is a cross-sectional view of a mounting structure of a flexible thermistor according to a second<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> embodiment of the present invention.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0009">Description of Embodiments</heading><heading id="h0010">(First Example)</heading><p id="p0022" num="0022"><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is a cross-sectional view showing an electronic-component mounting structure according to a first embodiment of the present invention. The mounting structure will be described using a flexible thermistor 1A as one example of the electronic component.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">A mounting structure of the flexible thermistor 1A according to the present invention includes a flexible thermistor 1A having a metal substrate 11, a semiconductor ceramic layer 15 formed on the metal substrate 11, and a pair of split electrodes 21 and 22 formed on the semiconductor ceramic layer 15; and a printed circuit board 30 functioning as a mounting body on which lands 31 and 32 to be connected to the respective split electrodes 21 and 22 of the flexible thermistor 1A are formed. A Ni plating film 23 and an Sn plating film 24 are formed in this order on the surface of each of the split electrodes 21 and 22. In addition, on surfaces of the metal substrate 11, a Ni plating film 23' and an Sn plating film 24' are formed. The reason for this is that when the Ni plating film 23 and the Sn plating film 24 are formed on the surface of each split<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> electrode by electric field plating, the plating films are also inevitably formed on the metal substrate 11. In addition, when electric field plating is not used, the Ni plating film 23' and the Sn plating film 24' may not be always formed. In this case, although a protective layer 16 is formed on the surface of the semiconductor ceramic layer 15, this protective layer 16 may not be always formed.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">In the present invention, the positions of peripheral end portions of the lands 31 and 32 are located inside than the positions of peripheral end portions of the split electrodes 21 and 22, respectively. By the structure as described above, the positions of the peripheral end portions of the lands 31 and 32 to which solders 33 are to be applied are each farther than the position of a peripheral end portion of the metal substrate 11. Hence, even when solder is applied on the Ni plating film 23 and the Sn plating film 24, which are formed on each of the split electrodes 21 and 22, since the positions of the peripheral end portions of the lands 31 and 32 are each far from the position of the peripheral end portion of the metal substrate 11, the solder 33 is prevented from rising to the metal substrate 11 or the Ni plating film 23' and the Sn plating film 24', each of which is formed along the peripheral end portion of the metal substrate 11.<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --></p><p id="p0025" num="0025">In this case, the peripheral end portion of the metal substrate 11 indicates peripheral ends of side surfaces and end surfaces of the metal substrate 11. In addition, the peripheral end portion of each of the split electrodes 21 and 22 indicates a peripheral end portion which is located in a planar direction thereof and at a position adjacent to the peripheral end portion of the metal substrate 11. In addition, the peripheral end portion of each of the lands 31 and 32 indicates a peripheral end portion which is located in a planar direction parallel to the printed circuit board 30 and at a position adjacent to the peripheral end portion of the metal substrate 11. In the present invention, the positions of the peripheral end portions of the lands 31 and 32 are located inside than the positions of the peripheral end portions of the split electrodes 21 and 22, respectively, that is, are located inside than the peripheral end portion of the metal substrate 11. Furthermore, when the plane areas of the lands 31 and 32 are smaller than the plane areas of the split electrodes 21 and 22, respectively, the distance between the metal substrate 11 and each of the lands 31 and 32 can be increased, and hence the solder 33 can be made to stay at the positions of the Ni plating film 23 and the Sn plating film 24, which are provided on each of the split electrodes 21 and 22. Hence, the solder 33 can be<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> prevented from rising.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">In addition, in general, the lands 31 and 32 provided on the printed circuit board 30 are frequently designed so as to have larger plane areas than those of the split electrodes 21 and 22, respectively, which are to be connected to the lands 31 and 32. The reason for this is to absorb displacement which occurs when the electronic component is mounted and to increase the degree of freedom in mounting. On the other hand, the solder 33 is liable to rise when the metal substrate 11 is located close to the mounting body or when the peripheral end portion of each of the lands 31 and 32 becomes closer to the peripheral end portion of the metal substrate 11 due to the formation of the Ni plating film 23' and the Sn plating film 24' on the surfaces of the metal substrate 11. Hence, in the present invention, it is found that when the peripheral end portions of the lands 31 and 32 to be connected to the split electrodes 21 and 22, respectively, are provided so as to be located inside than the peripheral end portions of the split electrodes 21 and 22, the solder 33 is not likely to rise to the metal substrate 11, and this is the novel finding.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">Hereinafter, a flexible thermistor preferably used as the electronic component of the present invention and a<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> method for manufacturing the same will be described in more detail.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028"><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2(A)</figref> is a schematic plan view of a flexible thermistor 1B, and <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2(B)</figref> is a front view thereof. The flexible thermistor 1B is a more simplified component of the flexible thermistor 1A. This flexible thermistor 1B includes a metal substrate 11, a semiconductor ceramic layer 15 formed on this metal substrate 11, and a pair of split electrodes 21 and 22 formed on this semiconductor ceramic layer 15. The metal substrate 11 is obtained by firing a sheet-shaped body formed from a metal powder paste, the semiconductor ceramic layer 15 is obtained by firing a sheet-shaped body formed from a ceramic slurry, and the split electrodes 21 and 22 are each obtained by firing an electrode material paste. The sheet-shaped body formed from a metal powder paste, the sheet-shaped body formed from a ceramic slurry, and an electrode paste are integrally fired. In addition, at least the metal substrate 11 and the semiconductor ceramic layer 15 may be obtained by integral firing.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">The thickness of the metal substrate 11 is approximately 10 to 80 µm, the thickness of the semiconductor ceramic layer 15 is approximately 1 to 10 µm,<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> the thickness of each of the split electrodes 21 and 22 is approximately 0.1 to 10 µm, and the total thickness of the flexible thermistor 1A is approximately 10 to 100 µm.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">As the semiconductor ceramic layer 15, a ceramic material having an NTC characteristic and containing appropriate amounts of Mn, Ni, Fe, Ti, Co, Al, Zn, and the like in an arbitrary combination may be used. In this example, although oxides of elements selected from the above transition metal elements are used and mixed together, a carbonate, a hydroxide, and/or the like of an element selected from the above elements may also be used as a starting raw material. For the metal substrate 11 and the split electrodes 21 and 22, a single noble metal, such as Ag, Pd, Pt, or Au, a single base metal, such as Cu, Ni, Al, W, or Ti, or an alloy containing at least one of the above metals may be used.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">As a method for forming the metal substrate 11 and the semiconductor ceramic layer 15 to have a sheet shape, although a doctor blade method is generally used, a screen printing method, a gravure printing method, or an ink jet method may also be used. The split electrodes 21 and 22 may be formed, for example, by a screen printing method, a sputtering method, or a deposition method.<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --></p><p id="p0032" num="0032"><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 3</figref> is an equivalent circuit of the flexible thermistor 1B. The split electrodes 21 and 22 are used as an input and an output terminal, and resistances R1 and R2 are formed by the semiconductor ceramic layer 15 and are also electrically connected in series to each other through the metal substrate 11. That is, the resistances R1 and R2 formed by the semiconductor ceramic layer 15 provided in thickness direction between the metal substrate 11 and the split electrodes 21 and 22 form a thermistor circuit.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033"><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 4</figref> is a view showing a pathway of a current flowing through the flexible thermistor 1B described above. Since the split electrodes 21 and 22 are formed on the surface of the semiconductor ceramic layer 15, as shown by the arrows in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 4</figref>, the current passes along a pathway between two parts of the semiconductor ceramic layer 15, which are in contact with the split electrodes 21 and 22, via the metal substrate 11. Flexure of the flexible thermistor 1A is liable to occur, and when mounting is performed by a mounter, cracks are also liable to be generated in a central portion of the semiconductor ceramic layer 15. However, even if cracks are generated in the central portion of the semiconductor ceramic layer 15, the central portion is not the current pathway, and hence electrical characteristics as<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> the flexible thermistor 1A are not adversely influenced.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034"><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 5</figref> includes views showing one example of a method for manufacturing the flexible thermistor 1A.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">First, as a raw material of the semiconductor ceramic layer 15, oxides of Mn-Ni-Fe-Ti and/or the like are weighed to have a predetermined mixing ratio (in order to obtain a resistivity of 10<sup>4</sup> Ω·cm) and are then sufficiently wet-pulverized using a ball mill with a pulverizing medium formed from zirconia and/or the like, and subsequently, calcination is performed at a predetermined temperature to obtain a ceramic powder.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">After an organic binder is added to the ceramic powder, and a wet mixing treatment is then performed to form a slurry, the slurry thus obtained is formed into a ceramic green sheet on a PET-made carrier film 31 so as to obtain a semiconductor ceramic layer 15 having a thickness of 1 to 15 µm by firing. A metal-substrate paste containing Ag-Pd as a primary component is formed into a metal substrate sheet on this ceramic green sheet so as to obtain a metal substrate 11 having a thickness of 5 to 100 µm by firing (see <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 5(b)</figref>). Subsequently, the film 31, the sheet 15, and the sheet 11 are cut into a size of a mother sheet from which a<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> plurality of components is to be formed, and the sheets 15 and 11 are then peeled away from the film 31 (see <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 5(c)</figref>). Next, on the ceramic green sheet, an Ag-Pd paste to be formed into the split electrodes 21 and 22 is applied by screen printing to form a laminate (see <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 5(d)</figref>).</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">Next, the mother sheet in the form of a laminate is cut into thermistor units (<figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 5(e)</figref>). After one unit thus obtained is received in a thermistor zirconia-made container and is then processed by a debinding treatment, firing is performed at a predetermined temperature (such as 900°C to 1,300°C).<br/>
By the steps as described above, the flexible thermistor 1A including the metal substrate 11, the semiconductor ceramic layer 15, and the split electrodes 21 and 22 is obtained.</p><heading id="h0011">(Example 1)</heading><p id="p0038" num="0038">In Example 1, a flexible thermistor formed by the following method was evaluated.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">First, after MnO<sub>3</sub>, NiO, Fe<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub>, and TiO<sub>2</sub> were weighed to have a resistivity of 10<sup>4</sup> Ω·cm and were then sufficiently wet-pulverized by a ball mill using a pulverizing medium formed from zirconia and/or the like, calcination was performed at 700°C to obtain a ceramic calcined powder formed of an oxide of Mn-Ni-Fe-Ti.<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --></p><p id="p0040" num="0040">Next, an organic binder, a dispersant, and water were added to this calcined powder and were mixed together using zirconia balls for several hours to form a slurry, and the slurry thus obtained was processed by a doctor blade method into a ceramic green sheet so as to have a thickness of 5 µm after firing.</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">A metal-substrate paste containing Ag-Pd as a primary component was applied on the ceramic green sheet thus obtained to form a metal substrate sheet as a mother sheet so as to have a thickness of 30 µm after firing. Subsequently, an Ag-Pd paste was screen-printed on the ceramic green sheet to form split electrodes.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">Next, after each mother sheet on which the split electrodes were formed was cut into thermistor units, and the thermistor units were each received in a zirconia-made sheath and then processed by a debinding treatment, firing was performed at 1,100°C. As a result, a flexible thermistor including the metal substrate, a thermistor layer, and the split electrodes was obtained.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">Next, a Ni plating film and an Sn plating film were formed by electrolytic plating on the thermistor obtained by<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> firing. As a result, the Ni plating film and the Sn plating film were formed in this order on the surface of the metal substrate and the surfaces of the split electrodes.</p><p id="p0044" num="0044">A split electrode side of the flexible thermistor thus obtained was arranged on Au-plated Cu-metal lands which were formed on a glass epoxy substrate, and using a lead-free solder containing Sn-Ag-Cu as a primary component, solder mounting was performed in a reflow furnace at a peak temperature of 260°C.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045">The external dimensions of the obtained flexible thermistor were 1.0 mm×0.5 mm×0.040 mm. In addition, the dimensions of the formed split electrode, the dimensions of the land, a distance a from the peripheral end portion of the metal substrate to the peripheral end portion of the split electrode, a distance b from the peripheral end portion of the split electrode to the peripheral end portion of the land, and a distance c from the peripheral end portion of the metal substrate to the peripheral end portion of the land are shown in Table 1.</p><p id="p0046" num="0046">In addition, a direct-current resistance of a solder-mounted flexible thermistor was measure by a direct-current four-terminal method in a liquid bath at a temperature of<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> 25°C, and an incidence rate of short-circuit defects was evaluated. The number of evaluated thermistors was 1,000, and the incidence rate of short-circuit defects was calculated by (the number of short-circuited thermistors/1,000)×100 (%).</p><p id="p0047" num="0047"><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --><tables id="tabl0001" num="0001"><table frame="all"><title>[Table 1]</title><tgroup cols="7"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="10mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="27mm"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="27mm"/><colspec colnum="4" colname="col4" colwidth="27mm"/><colspec colnum="5" colname="col5" colwidth="27mm"/><colspec colnum="6" colname="col6" colwidth="27mm"/><colspec colnum="7" colname="col7" colwidth="24mm"/><thead><row><entry namest="col1" nameend="col7" align="left" valign="middle">EXTERNAL DIMENSIONS OF THERMISTOR 1.0 mm × 0.5 mm × 0.04 mm</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle"/><entry align="center" valign="middle">DIMENSIONS OF SPLIT ELECTRODE µm</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">DIMENSIONS OF LAND µm</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">DISTANCE BETWEEN PERIPHERAL END PORTION OF METAL SUBSTRATE AND PERIPHERAL END PORTION OF SPLIT ELECTRODE a</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">DISTANCE BETWEEN PERIPHERAL END PORTION OF SPLIT ELECTRODE AND PERIPHERAL END PORTION OF LAND b</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">DISTANCE BETWEEN PERIPHERAL END PORTION OF METAL SUBSTRATE AND PERIPHERAL END PORTION OF LAND c = a + b</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">INCIDENCE RATE OF SHORT- CIRCUIT DEFECTS (%)</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">*1</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">300 × 350</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">300 × 365</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">50</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">-10</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">40</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">10.1</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">*2</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">300 × 350</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">300 × 350</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">50</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">0</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">50</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">0.08</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">3</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">300 × 350</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">300 × 340</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">50</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">10</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">60</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">0</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">4</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">300 × 350</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">300 × 330</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">50</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">20</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">70</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">0</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">5</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">300 × 350</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">300 × 320</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">50</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">30</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">80</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">0</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></tables><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --></p><p id="p0048" num="0048">As apparent from the above, it was found that in Sample 1 or 2 in which the position of the peripheral end portion of the land was located outside the peripheral end portion of the metal substrate than the position of the peripheral end portion of the split electrode or was located at the same position as that thereof, short-circuit defects were generated. On the other hand, it was found that in Samples 3 to 5 in which the position of the peripheral end portion of the land was located inside the peripheral end portion of the metal substrate than the position of the peripheral end portion of the split electrode, the incidence rate of short circuit defects was 0%. The reason for this is that the distance from the peripheral end portion of the metal substrate to the peripheral end portion of the land can be sufficiently secured.</p><heading id="h0012">(Second Example)</heading><p id="p0049" num="0049"><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 6</figref> is a cross-sectional view showing a mounting structure of an electronic component 2A according to a second embodiment of the present invention. In the flexible thermistor 2A, a protective layer 16' of an insulating material was formed on the entire surface of a metal substrate 11 except for parts thereof on which split electrodes 21 and 22 were formed. Accordingly, a Ni plating film 23 and an Sn plating film 24 formed on each of the split electrodes 21 and 22 could be reliably insulated from<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> the metal substrate 11. Hence, solders 33 applied to lands 31 and 32 did not reach a peripheral side of the metal substrate 11 and could be reliably prevented from rising to the metal substrate 11.</p><heading id="h0013">Reference Signs List</heading><p id="p0050" num="0050"><dl id="dl0001" compact="compact"><dt>1A</dt><dd>flexible thermistor</dd><dt>11</dt><dd>metal substrate</dd><dt>15</dt><dd>thermistor layer</dd><dt>16</dt><dd>protective layer</dd><dt>21, 22</dt><dd>split electrode</dd><dt>23</dt><dd>Ni plating film</dd><dt>23</dt><dd>Sn plating film</dd><dt>30</dt><dd>printed circuit board</dd><dt>31, 32</dt><dd>land</dd><dt>33</dt><dd>solder</dd></dl></p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56976320" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --><claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>An electronic-component mounting structure comprising: an electronic component which includes a metal substrate, a semiconductor ceramic layer formed on the metal substrate, a pair of split electrodes formed on the semiconductor ceramic layer, and plating films formed on the split electrodes and the metal substrate; and a mounting body on which lands to be connected to the respective split electrodes of the electronic component are formed,<br/>
wherein the position of a peripheral end portion of each land to be connected to the corresponding split electrode is located inside than the position of a peripheral end portion of the split electrode.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The electronic-component mounting structure according to Claim 1, wherein a plane area of each land is smaller than that of the corresponding split electrode.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The electronic-component mounting structure according to Claim 1 or 2, wherein the thickness of the metal substrate of the electronic component is 10 to 80 µm, and the thickness of the ceramic layer is 1 to 10 µm.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The electronic-component mounting structure according<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --> to one of Claims 1 to 3, wherein the metal substrate of the electronic component has a sheet shape formed from a metal powder paste, and the ceramic layer has a sheet shape formed from a ceramic slurry.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The electronic-component mounting structure according to one of Claims 1 to 4, wherein the sheet-shaped metal substrate and the sheet-shaped ceramic layer are obtained by firing while integrally laminated together.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The electronic-component mounting structure according to one of Claims 1 to 5, further comprising a protective layer formed from an insulating material on a surface of the ceramic layer on which at least the split electrodes are formed.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The electronic-component mounting structure according to one of Claims 1 to 6, wherein the plating film is formed on a surface of the metal substrate.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16667101" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1,2(A),2(B)"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="149" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --><figure id="f0002" num="3,4"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="165" he="202" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --><figure id="f0003" num="5(A),5(B),5(C),5(D),5(E),6"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="153" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><search-report-data><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="162" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="162" he="233" type="tif"/></search-report-data><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
