<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-1188555-B1" country="EP" doc-number="1188555" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="11445816" file-reference-id="276394" date-produced="20180823" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146589258" ucid="EP-1188555-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>1188555</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-01121985-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154851450" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>01121985</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20010913</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140557488" ucid="IT-MI20002028-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>IT</country><doc-number>MI20002028</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20000918</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130916</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989328067" load-source="docdb">B32B  27/32        20060101ALI20040223BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989328068" load-source="docdb">B32B   1/08        20060101AFI20040223BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989328069" load-source="docdb">B32B  27/28        20060101ALI20040223BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989328070" load-source="docdb">B32B  27/34        20060101ALI20040223BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989328071" load-source="docdb">C08F 210/02        20060101ALI20040223BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989328072" load-source="docdb">C08F 214/24        20060101ALI20040223BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989328073" load-source="docdb">C08F 214/26        20060101ALI20040223BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989328074" load-source="docdb">C08J   3/24        20060101ALI20040223BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989328075" load-source="docdb">C08K   5/00        20060101ALI20040223BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989328076" load-source="docdb">C08K  13/02        20060101ALI20040223BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989328077" load-source="docdb">F16L  11/04        20060101ALI20040223BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989628106" load-source="docdb">C08K   5/14        20060101ALI20051220RMJP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989647456" load-source="docdb">B32B  27/30        20060101AFI20051220RMJP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989649235" load-source="docdb">C08L  27/22        20060101ALI20051220RMJP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2077553865" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 428/31511     20150401 LA20150409BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2077557524" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 428/31938     20150401 LA20150409BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2077559589" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 428/31855     20150401 LA20150409BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2077563295" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 428/31721     20150401 LA20150409BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2077563614" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 428/3154      20150401 LA20150409BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2077564240" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 428/31786     20150401 LA20150409BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2077567698" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 428/31931     20150401 LA20150409BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2077574327" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 428/31504     20150401 LA20150409BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2077575362" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 428/31551     20150401 LA20150409BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2077576101" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 428/31971     20150401 LA20150409BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2077576149" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 428/31507     20150401 LA20150409BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2077577707" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 428/31935     20150401 LA20150409BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2108578678" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 428/1393      20130101 LA20150115BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2108593205" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F16L2011/047       20130101 LA20150119BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2108598734" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B32B   1/08        20130101 LI20150119BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2108601315" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B32B  27/28        20130101 FI20150119BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132372407" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Fluorkunststoffe und hydrierte Polymere enthaltender Mehrschichtverbundstoff</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132372408" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">A multilayer composite comprising fluoropolymer and hydrogenated polymers</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132372409" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Composite multicouche contenant des fluoropolymères et des polymères hydrogènes</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919517007" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>SOLVAY SPECIALTY POLYMERS IT</last-name><address><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919523171" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>SOLVAY SPECIALTY POLYMERS ITALY S.P.A.</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919524042" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>ABUSLEME JULIO A</last-name><address><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919535178" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>ABUSLEME, JULIO A.</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919027090" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>ABUSLEME, JULIO A.</last-name><address><street>Via Bergamo 5</street><city>21047 Saronno (VA)</city><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919538019" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>MANZONI CLAUDIA</last-name><address><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919514237" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>MANZONI, CLAUDIA</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919027091" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>MANZONI, CLAUDIA</last-name><address><street>Via del Lino 3</street><city>40100 Bologna</city><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919027093" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Solvay Specialty Polymers Italy S.p.A.</last-name><iid>101296459</iid><address><street>Via Turati 12</street><city>20121 Milano</city><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919027092" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Benvenuti, Federica</last-name><suffix>et al</suffix><iid>101035266</iid><address><street>Solvay S.A. Département de la Propriété Intellectuelle Rue de Ransbeek, 310</street><city>1120 Bruxelles</city><country>BE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549876425" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549900306" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549807500" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549885614" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549900307" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549885615" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549791901" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549926726" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549926727" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549900308" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549885616" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549807501" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549926728" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549885617" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549876430" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549891445" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549876431" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549891446" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549885622" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549794504" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63961668" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to multilayer compositions comprising thermoprocessable fluoropolymers and hydrogenated polymers having improved adhesion among the single layers.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002">In particular the invention relates to multilayer compositions based on thermoprocessable fluoropolymers and hydrogenated polymers, wherein the thermoprocessable fluoropolymers are copolymers of ethylene (E) with tetrafluoroethylene (TFE) and/or chlorotrifluoroethylene (CTFE). Said multilayer compositions show improved adhesion among the single layers and high chemical resistance.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">The use of hydrogenated polymers in the car industry for preparing fuel hoses and fuel lines is known in the prior art. Examples of hydrogenated polymers are polyamides, polyvinylchloride (PVC), nitrile rubbers (NBR). The drawbacks of the manufactured articles obtained from said polymers are the low chemical resistance and high permeability to gasolines and oils, in particular SF oils. A high permeability to this fluids, in particular gasolines, implies a high emission of dangerous substances to the environment. The laws of most countries are more and more restrictive on these emissions due<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> to their environmental impact. Therefore, manufactured articles having a lower permeability and an improved chemical resistance are required.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">Fluorinated polymers are known, which, in comparison with hydrogenated polymers, have an improved chemical resistance to gasolines and to particularly aggressive oils used in the car industry. The drawback of fluorinated polymers is the high cost which limits the use thereof.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">To make economically possible the use of fluorinated polymers it has been tried to laminate hydrogenated polymers with fluorinated polymers, for example in the preparation of fuel hoses (hydrogenated rubbers/fluorinated polymers) and fuel lines (polyamides/fluorinated polymers). However the adhesion between fluorinated polymers and hydrogenated polymers is very poor. The research is directed to find solutions such as to make it possible these laminates. This is true in particular for the thermoprocessable fluorinated copolymers of ethylene (E) with tetrafluoroethylene (TFE) and/or chlorotrifluoroethylene (CTFE), for example Halar commercialized by Ausimont. Tests carried out by the Applicant, see the comparative Examples, have shown that the hydrogenated polymer/fluorinated polymer bilayer gives a poor adhesion or, in most cases, no adhesion among the layers of the manufactured article.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p><p id="p0006" num="0006"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="JP5008353A"><text>JP 05 008353</text></patcit> discloses multilayers comprising:
<ul><li>a inner layer of a fluoro-containing resin, such as PVDF, PCTFE, ECTFE or ETFE or its graft copolymer or their blend;</li><li>an intermediate layer crosslinked by irradiating radiation beams;</li><li>an outer layer of polyamide.</li></ul></p><p id="p0007" num="0007">The outer polyamide layer and/or the inner fluoropolymer layer are optionally admixed with a crosslinking aid, for example diacrylates, triallyl-isocyanurate (TAIC).</p><p id="p0008" num="0008"><patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="EP1038914A"><text>EP 1 038 914</text></patcit> which represents prior art under the provisious of Article 54(3) EPC discloses a bilayer between
<ul><li>a layer of a terpolymer of ethylene (E), chlorotrifluoroethylene (CTFE) (and/or tetrafluorethylene TFE) and acrylic monomers (a) containing a crosslinking agent</li><li>a layer of a hydrogenated polymer.</li></ul><!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p><p id="p0009" num="0009">The need was therefore felt to make multilayer polymer manufactured articles having a high adhesion among the single layers, which contemporaneously show a high chemical resistance typical of fluorinated polymers and good mechanical properties when the hydrogenated polymers are thermoprocessable. ,</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">An object of the present invention is therefore a multilayer composition comprising:
<ol><li>A) a first layer based on copolymers of ethylene (E) with tetrafluoroethylene (TFE) and/or chlorotrifluoroethylene (CTFE), preferably CTFE;</li><li>B) a second intermediate layer based on thermoprocessable copolymers of ethylene (E) with tetrafluoroethylene (TFE) and/or chlorotrifluoroethylene (CTFE) modified with acrylic monomers of formula:<br/>
<br/>
        CH<sub>2</sub>=CH=CO-O-R<sub>2</sub>     (a)<br/>
<br/>
R<sub>2</sub> is a C<sub>1</sub>-C<sub>20</sub> hydrogenated radical from 1 to 20 carbon atoms, linear and/or branched alkyl radical or cycloalkyl radical, or R<sub>2</sub> is H. The R<sub>2</sub> radical can optionally contain: heteroatoms preferably Cl, O, N; one or more functional groups preferably selected from OH, COOH, epoxide, ester and ether;</li><li>C) a third layer based on hydrogenated polymers;</li></ol>
said multilayer composition containing in layer B) and/or in<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> layer C) one or more crosslinking agents of fluorinated polymers.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">The copolymers of layer A) contain:
<ul><li>from 30 to 60% by moles, preferably from 40 to 50% of ethylene;</li><li>from 40 to 70% by moles, preferably from 50 to 60% of a fluorinated monomer selected from tetrafluoroethylene, chloro-trifluoroethylene, or mixtures thereof;</li><li>optionally from 0.1 to 5% by moles referred to the sum of the previous monomers of a fluorinated monomer selected from perfluoroalkylvinylethers, preferably perfluoropropylvinylether (PPVE), perfluorodioxoles, hexafluoroisobutene.</li></ul></p><p id="p0012" num="0012">The thermoprocessable copolymers of layer B) are formed by:
<ul><li>from 10 to 70% by moles, preferably from 35 to 55% of ethylene;</li><li>from 30 to 90% by moles, preferably from 45 to 65%, of a fluorinated monomer selected from tetrafluoroethylene, chlorotrifluoroethylene, or mixtures thereof, preferably CTFE;</li><li>from 0.1 to 30% by moles, preferably from 1 to 15% by moles of the acrylic comonomer (a) referred to the sum of the previous monomers.</li></ul></p><p id="p0013" num="0013">The acrylic monomers of formula (a) are preferably n-butylacrylate.<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></p><p id="p0014" num="0014">Optionally layer B) comprises also the thermoprocessable copolymers of layer A) in an amount from 0 to 95% by weight, preferably from 70 to 95% by weight with respect to the copolymers of layer B), with the proviso that layer B) contains an amount of acrylic monomers of formula (a) of at least 0.1% by moles. It has been found by the Applicant that when in layer B) a blend of the copolymers of A) and B) is used and the final amount of the comonomer of formula a) in the blend is lower than 0.5% by moles, then the multilayer can be made without using layer A), yet substantially maintaining the multilayer properties.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">The hydrogenated polymers of layer C) are of both thermoprocessable and elastomeric type, preferably thermoprocessable. Among thermoprocessable polymers, hydro-cellulose polymers, polyamides as NYLON 6, NYLON 66, NYLON 11, NYLON 12, polyamide copolymers, policarbonates, polyesters, such as for example polyethylenterephthalate, polyolefins such as for example high and low density polyethylene, olefine copolymers, polyimides, polystyrene, polyurethanes, polyvinylchloride (PVC), polysulphones, ethylene/vinylacetate copolymers, polyacrylobutadienestyrene (ABS), can be mentioned.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">As hydrogenated elastomers we can mention acrylic rubbers, nitrile rubbers (NBR), ethylene-propylene rubbers<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> (EPM), ethylene-propylene-diene rubbers (EPDM), NVC rubbers (nitrile NBR rubbers mixed with PVC), epichloro-hydrin rubbers (CO and ECO).</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">The preferred thermoprocessable hydrogenated polymers are polyesters, polyolefins, polyamides.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">The preferred hydrogenated elastomers are epichlorohydrin and nitrile rubbers (NBR).</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">The crosslinking agents used in the multilayer composition of the invention can be of both radical and ionic type and they are those well known and conventionally used in the crosslinking of fluorinated polymers.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">As radical crosslinking agents we can mention triallylisocyanurate (TAIC), triallylcyanurate (TAC), diallylisophthalate (<patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="USP4039631A"><text>USP 4,039,631</text></patcit>), diallylterephthalate (<patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="USP4039631A"><text>USP 4,039,631</text></patcit>), esters of phenyl indan (<patcit id="pcit0005" dnum="USP3763222A"><text>USP 3,763,222</text></patcit>), triallylester of the aryl polycarboxylic acid (<patcit id="pcit0006" dnum="USP3840619A"><text>USP 3,840,619</text></patcit>), bis-olefins such as for example 1,6 divinylperfluorohexane (see <patcit id="pcit0007" dnum="USP5612419A"><text>USP 5,612,419</text></patcit>) and others (see <patcit id="pcit0008" dnum="USP4121001A"><text>USP 4,121,001</text></patcit>). Among the radical crosslinking agents, triallylisocyanurate is preferred. Preferably the radical crosslinking agent is used in combination with a peroxide, for example Luperco® 101 XL (2,5-dimethyl-2,5-di(terbutylperoxy)hexane 45% by weight based on inert support), dicumylperoxide and terbutylhydroperoxide. In this case when the peroxide is present in layer C), the crosslinking<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> agent is present in layer B), or viceversa.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">As ionic crosslinking agents, we can mention those of amine type, for example hexamethylendiaminecarbamate, N,N'-dicinnamylidene-1,6 hexanediamine, maleimides derivatives, such for example m-phenylenbismaleimide, C<sub>4</sub>-C<sub>20</sub> aliphatic diamines, or polyhydroxyl aromatic compounds, for example bisphenols, A, AF and S, preferably in combination with a crosslinking accelerator, for example ammonium or phosphonium salts, preferably tetralkyl salts, for example tetrabutyl or phosphoranamines salts. In this case when the polyhydroxyl aromatic compounds are present in layer C), the accelerator is present in layer B), or viceversa. Preferably the accelerator is in layer C). The molar ratio between the accelerator and the polyhydroxyl aromatic compounds generally ranges between 1:5 and 1:1.<br/>
Among the ionically active crosslinking agents, both aliphatic and aromatic protected diamines are preferred. Preferably amines are used in layer C).</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">The crosslinking agent amount can range from 0.1 to 20.0% by weight, preferably from 0.5 to 10.0% by weight, more preferably from 1.0 to 5.0% by weight with respect to the polymer.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">The multilayer compositions of the invention can furthermore contain one or more optional ingredients such as fillers<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> (for example polytetrafluoroethylene (PTFE), silicates), "smoke retarders", lubricants, pigments, "fire retardants", "intumescent agents", plasticizers (for example MORFLEX<sup>®</sup> 560), metal oxides (ZnO, MgO), inorganic bases (Ca(OH)<sub>2</sub>), thermal stabilizers such as for example Irganox<sup>®</sup> 1010.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">The maximum total amount of said optional components is in the range 0 and 30% by weight.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">The multilayer composition of the present invention can be obtained by co-extrusion of layers A), B) and C). An alternative method is the compression of the single layers at the softening temperature of the components. Preferably the co-extrusion method is used.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">From the multilayer compositions of the invention manufactured articles are obtained, for example fuel lines obtained by co-extrusion of polyamide (layer C) and of layers A) and B) of the invention, fuel hoses obtained for example by extrusion of a hydrogenated rubber (layer C) on a tube formed by co-extruded layers A) and B).</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">The multilayer manufactured articles A/B/C obtainable from the compositions of the invention show the following combination of properties:
<ul><li>high chemical resistance when in contact layer A) of the multilayer with aggressive fluids;</li><li>good mechanical properties;<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></li><li>very good adhesion among the single layers, wherefore the manufactured articles are completely integrated.</li></ul></p><p id="p0028" num="0028">Some embodiment examples of the present invention are hereinafter reported, the purpose of which is merely illustrative but not limitative of the scope of the invention itself.</p><heading id="h0001">EXAMPLES</heading><heading id="h0002"><u>EXAMPLE 1</u></heading><heading id="h0003"><u>Preparation of the copolymer of layer A</u></heading><heading id="h0004"><u>(E/CTFE 49/51 by moles %)</u></heading><p id="p0029" num="0029">5.3 l of demineralized water, 1.7 l of methyl alcohol, 52 ml of methylcyclopentane and 2 Kg of chlorotrifluoroethylene were fed into an enamelled autoclave equipped with baffles and stirrer working at 450 rpm in Hastelloy C. The autoclave was then heated to the reaction temperature of 15°C and ethylene was fed up to a pressure of 12.6 absolute bar.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">In the autoclave the radical initiator was then introduced with a flow-rate of 40 ml/h for the whole polymerization under the form of a trichloroacetylperoxide (TCAP) solution in isooctane, maintained at -17°C, having a titre equal to 0.12 g TCAP/ml.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">The pressure was maintained constant during the whole polymerization, by continuously feeding of ethylene to the reactor up to a consumption of 200 g; in total 200 ml of<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> initiator solution were introduced.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">The product discharged from the autoclave was dried at 120°C for about 16 hours. The amount of the obtained dry product was 1507 g.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">The obtained polymer was compounded with optional components such as MARK-260® in an amount of 0.45% by weight and Aclyn-316® in an amount of 0.15% by weight both mainly used as thermal stabilizers. Then the compounded product is pelletized in a single screw Brabender extruder in Hastelloy C-276 having a 18 mm diameter and a length equivalent to 25 times the diameter, with a melt temperature of 270°C. Plaques having a 1.5 mm thickness are obtained by compression moulding from the granules.</p><heading id="h0005"><u>Preparation of the copolymer of layer B</u></heading><heading id="h0006"><u>(E/CTFE/n-BuA 40/55/5 by moles %)</u></heading><p id="p0034" num="0034">5.3 l of demineralized water, 1.7 l of methyl alcohol, 20 ml of methylcyclopentane, 10 g of n-butylacrylate and 2 Kg of chlorotrifluoroethylene were fed into an enamelled autoclave equipped with baffles and stirrer working at 450 rpm in Hastelloy C. The autoclave was then heated to the reaction temperature of 15°C and ethylene was fed up to a pressure of 8.2 absolute bar. In the autoclave the radical initiator was then continuously fed for the whole polymerization under the form of a trichloroacetylperoxide (TCAP) solution in isooctane,<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> maintained at -17°C, having a titre equal to 0.1 g TCAP/ml. Furthermore, 10 g of n-butylacrylate were introduced at consumption of 20, 40, 60, 80, 100, 120, 140, 160 and 180 g of ethylene, for a total of 100 g of n-butylacrylate introduced, comprising the initially fed amount.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">The pressure was maintained constant for the whole polymerization, by continuously feeding of ethylene to the reactor up to a consumption of 200 g; in total 399 ml of initiator solution were introduced. The whole polymerization lasted 555 minutes.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">The product discharged from the autoclave was dried at 120°C for about 16 hours. The amount of the obtained dry product was 1200 g.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">The obtained polymer was compounded with optional components such as MARK-260<sup>®</sup> in an amount of 0.45% by weight and Aclyn-316<sup>®</sup> in an amount of 0.15% by weight both mainly used as thermal stabilizers. Then the compounded product is pelletized in a single screw Brabender extruder in Hastelloy C-276 having a 18 mm diameter and a length equivalent to 25 times the diameter, with a melt temperature of 240°C. Plaques having a 1.5 mm thickness are obtained by compression moulding from the granules.</p><heading id="h0007"><u>Preparation of the polymer of layer C</u></heading><p id="p0038" num="0038">1 Kg of Nylon 12 under the form of granules was<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> compounded with 4% by weight of hexamethylendiamine monocarbamate. Then it was pelletized in a single screw Brabender extruder in Hastelloy C-276 having a 18 mm diameter and a length equivalent to 25 times the diameter, with a melt temperature of 225°C. Plaques having a 1.5 mm thickness are obtained by compression moulding from the granules.</p><heading id="h0008"><u>Preparation of Multilayer A/B/C</u></heading><p id="p0039" num="0039">The previously obtained plates of the single layers have been overlapped in the A/B/C order, and kept under pressure at a temperature of 270°C for 10 minutes.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">By applying mechanical stress one tries to separate layer A from layer C of the multilayer A/B/C.</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">One cannot measure the force of delamination between the layers A and C, since there is an adhesion between the layers such to prevent the separation thereof. By increasing the applied force for separating the layers, one succeeds in breaking the manufactured article without obtaining the delamination. This shows that the multilayer of the invention has a high adhesion among the single layers.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">The chemical resistance of the multilayer A/B/C is given by the high chemical resistance of layer A, which is put into contact with toluene at different temperatures. The variation by weight of the polymer forming layer A is evaluated:<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> -->
<tables id="tabl0001" num="0001"><table frame="none"><tgroup cols="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="23mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="31mm"/><thead><row><entry valign="top">Temperature</entry><entry align="center" valign="top">Variation by weight</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry>30°C</entry><entry align="center">3.5%</entry></row><row><entry>50°C</entry><entry align="center">4.0%</entry></row><row><entry>75°C</entry><entry align="center">5.0%</entry></row><row><entry>100°C</entry><entry align="center">7.2%</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></tables></p><p id="p0043" num="0043">These data show a limited variation by weight also at high temperatures, wherefore the chemical resistance of the multilayer is high and imparted by layer A.</p><heading id="h0009"><u>EXAMPLE 2</u></heading><heading id="h0010"><u>Preparation of the copolymer of layer A</u></heading><heading id="h0011"><u>(E/CTFE/PPVE 48.9/50.0/1.1 by moles %)</u></heading><p id="p0044" num="0044">45.6 l of demineralized water were fed to a 30 gallons Pfaudler type enamelled autoclave, equipped with stirrer working at 350 rpm. The autoclave was pressurized with nitrogen and subsequently evacuated. 13.6 kg of methanol, 100 ml of chloroform, 4.0 kg of perfluoropropylvinylether (PPVE) and 22.7 kg of chlorotrifluoroethylene (CTFE) were then introduced. The reactor was brought to 5°C and then pressurized with ethylene up to an internal pressure of 13.4 absolute bar was reached. In the autoclave the radical initiator was then gradually introduced formed by a trichloroacetylperoxide (TCAP) solution in CFC-113, maintaianed at -17°C, having a concentration equal to 0.09 g/ml. In total 59.6 g of TCAP were fed. The working pressure was approximately maintained<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> constant during the reaction by continuously feeding of ethylene. After 235 minutes, the reaction was stopped. 10.4 kg of dry polymer were obtained.</p><heading id="h0012"><u>Preparation of the Polymer of layer B</u></heading><p id="p0045" num="0045">The same copolymer of Example 1 is used.</p><heading id="h0013"><u>Preparation of the polymer of layer C</u></heading><p id="p0046" num="0046">The same hydrogenated polymer of Example 1 is used.</p><heading id="h0014"><u>Preparation of Multilayer A/B/C</u></heading><p id="p0047" num="0047">The previously obtained plates of the single layers have been overlapped in the A/B/C order, and kept under pressure at a temperature of 270°C for 10 minutes.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048">By applying mechanical stress one tries to separate layer A from layer C of the multilayer A/B/C.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">One cannot measure the force of delamination between the layers A and C, since there is an adhesion between the layers such to prevent the separation thereof. This shows that the multilayer of the invention has a high adhesion among the single layers.</p><p id="p0050" num="0050">The chemical resistance of multilayer A/B/C is given by the high chemical resistance of layer A, which is put into contact with toluene at different temperatures. The variation by weight of the polymer forming layer A is evaluated:
<tables id="tabl0002" num="0002"><table frame="none"><tgroup cols="2" colsep="0" rowsep="0"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="23mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="31mm"/><thead><row><entry valign="top">Temperature</entry><entry align="center" valign="top">Variation by weight</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry>30C</entry><entry align="right">4.5%</entry></row><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --><row><entry>50°C</entry><entry align="right">5.5%</entry></row><row><entry>75°C</entry><entry align="right">7.6%</entry></row><row><entry>100°C</entry><entry align="right">11.8%</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></tables></p><p id="p0051" num="0051">These data show a limited variation by weight also at high temperatures, wherefore the chemical resistance of the multilayer is high and imparted by layer A.</p><heading id="h0015"><u>EXAMPLE 3</u></heading><heading id="h0016"><u>Preparation of the polymer of layer A</u></heading><p id="p0052" num="0052">The same copolymer of Example 1 is used.</p><heading id="h0017"><u>Preparation of the polymer of layer B</u></heading><p id="p0053" num="0053">100 g in granules of the copolymer of layer B of Example 1 are mixed with 900 g in granules of the copolymer of layer A of Example 1. Then the blend is pelletized in a single screw Brabender extruder in Hastelloy C-276 having a 18 mm diameter and a length equivalent to 25 times the diameter, with a melt temperature of 270°C. Plaques having a 1.5 mm thickness are obtained by compression moulding from the granules.</p><heading id="h0018"><u>Preparation of the polymer of layer C</u></heading><p id="p0054" num="0054">The same hydrogenated polymer of Example 1 is used.</p><heading id="h0019"><u>Preparation of Multilayer A/B/C</u></heading><p id="p0055" num="0055">The previously obtained plaques of the single layers have been overlapped in the A/B/C order, and kept under pressure at a temperature of 270°C for 10 minutes.</p><p id="p0056" num="0056">By applying mechanical stress one tries to separate layer<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> A from layer C of multilayer A/B/C.</p><p id="p0057" num="0057">One cannot measure the force of delamination between the layers A and C, since there is an adhesion between the layers such to prevent the separation thereof. This shows that the multilayer of the invention has a high adhesion among the single layers.</p><heading id="h0020"><u>EXAMPLE 4 (comparative)</u></heading><p id="p0058" num="0058">A bilayer composition A/C is prepared by using the plaques A and C obtained in Example 1. The plates are overlapped and kept under pressure at a temperature of 270°C for 10 minutes.</p><p id="p0059" num="0059">The composition A/C does not show any adhesion among its components.</p><p id="p0060" num="0060">This Example shows that in absence of the intermediate layer B) it is not possible to obtain a manufactured article formed by A) and C) having the properties of high chemical resistance (given by layer A) and of good mechanical properties (given by layer C).</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56987744" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Mehrschichtige Zusammensetzung, umfassend :
<claim-text>A) eine erste Schicht auf Basis von Copolymeren von Ethylen (E) mit Tetrafluorethylen (TFE) und/oder Chlortrifluorethylen (CTFE), vorzugsweise CTFE;</claim-text>
<claim-text>B) eine zweite intermediäre Schicht, umfassend thermisch verarbeitbare Copolymere von Ethylen (E) mit Tetrafluorethylen (TFE) und/oder Chlortrifluorethylen (CTFE), modifiziert mit Acrylmonomeren der Formel :<br/>
<br/>
        CH<sub>2</sub>=CH-CO-O-R<sub>2</sub>     (a)<br/>
<br/>
wobei R<sub>2</sub> für einen hydrierten C<sub>1</sub>-C<sub>20</sub>-Rest mit 1 bis 20 Kohlenstoffatomen, linearen und/oder verzweigten Alkyl- oder Cycloalkylrest steht oder R<sub>2</sub> für H steht, wobei der Rest R<sub>2</sub> gegebenenfalls Heteroatome, vorzugsweise Cl, O, N; eine oder mehrere funktionelle Gruppen, die aus OH, COOH, Epoxid, Ester und Ether ausgewählt sind, enthält;</claim-text>
<claim-text>C) eine dritte Schicht auf Basis von hydrierten Polymeren;<br/>
wobei die mehrschichtige Zusammensetzung in Schicht B) und/oder in Schicht C) ein oder mehrere Vernetzungsmittel enthält.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Mehrschichtige Zusammensetzung nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Copolymere von Schicht A)
<claim-text>- 30 bis 60 Mol- %, vorzugsweise 40 bis 50 Mol- % Ethylen;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- 40 bis 70 Mol- %, vorzugsweise 50 bis 60 Mol- % eines fluorierten Monomers, das aus Tetrafluorethylen und/oder Chlortrifluorethylen ausgewählt ist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- gegebenenfalls 0,1 bis 5 Mol- %, bezogen auf die Summe der vorhergehenden Monomere, eines fluorierten Monomers, das aus Perfluoralkylvinylethern, vorzugsweise Perfluorpropylvinylether, Perfluordioxolen, Hexafluorisobuten ausgewählt ist;</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Mehrschichtige Zusammensetzung nach den Ansprüchen 1-2, wobei die thermisch verarbeitbaren Copolymere von Schicht B) aus
<claim-text>- 10 bis 70 Mol- %, vorzugsweise 35 bis 55 Mol- % Ethylen;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- 30 bis 90 Mol- %, vorzugsweise 45 bis 65 Mol- %, eines fluorierten Monomers, das aus Tetrafluorethylen, Chlortrifluorethylen ausgewählt ist, vorzugsweise CTFE;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- 0,1 bis 30 Mol- %, vorzugsweise 1 bis 15 Mol- %, des Comonomers (a), bezogen auf die Summe der vorhergehenden Monomere;<br/>
gebildet sind.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Mehrschichtige Zusammensetzung nach den Ansprüchen 1-3, wobei Schicht B) auch die thermisch verarbeitbaren Copolymere von Schicht A) in einer Menge von 0 bis 95 Gew.- %, vorzugsweise 70 bis 95 Gew.- %, bezogen auf die Copolymere von Schicht B), umfasst, mit der Maßgabe, dass Schicht B) eine Menge von Acrylmonomeren der Formel (a) von mindestens 0,1 Mol- % enthält.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Mehrschichtige Zusammensetzung nach den Ansprüchen 1-4, wobei die hydriertem Polymere von Schicht C) sowohl vom thermisch verarbeitbaren als auch vom elastomeren Typ, vorzugsweise thermisch verarbeitbar, sind.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Mehrschichtige Zusammensetzung nach Anspruch 5, wobei es sich bei den thermisch verarbeitbaren hydrierten Polymeren um Hydrocellulosepolymere, Polyamide, Polyamid-Copolymere, Polycarbonate, Polyester, Polyolefine, Polyimide, Polystyrol, Polyurethane, Polyvinylchlorid (PVC), Polysulfone, Ethylen/Vinylacetat-Copolymere, Polyacrylbutadienstyrol (ABS) handelt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Mehrschichtige Zusammensetzung nach Anspruch 5, wobei es sich bei den hydrierten Elastomeren um Acrylkautschuke, Nitrilkautschuke (NBR), Ethylen-Propylen-Kautschuke (EPM), Ethylen-Propylen-Dien-Kautschuke (EPDM), Nitrilkautschuke im Gemisch mit PVC (NVC), Epichlorhydrinkautschuke (CO und ECO) handelt.<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Mehrschichtige Zusammensetzung nach den Ansprüchen 1-7, wobei die Vernetzungsmittel sowohl vom radikalischen als auch vom ionischen Typ sind.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Mehrschichtige Zusammensetzung nach Anspruch 8, wobei es sich bei den radikalischen Vernetzungsmitteln um Tricallylisocyanurat (TAIC), Triallyl-cyanurat (TAC), Diallylisophthalat, Diallylterephthalat, Ester von Phenylindan, Triallylester der Arylpolycarbonsäure, Bisolefine handelt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Mehrschichtige Zusammensetzung nach den Ansprüchen 8-9, wobei das radikalische Vernetzungsmittel in Kombination mit einem Peroxid verwendet wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Mehrschichtige Zusammensetzung nach den Ansprüchen 8-10, wobei dann, wenn das Peroxid in Schicht C) vorliegt, das Vernetzungsmittel in Schicht B) vorliegt, oder umgekehrt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Mehrschichtige Zusammensetzung nach Anspruch 8, wobei die ionischen Vernetzungsmittel vom Amin-Typ, Maleinimidderivate, aliphatische C<sub>4</sub>-C<sub>20</sub>-Diamine, polyhydroxylaromatische Verbindungen, vorzugsweise in Kombination mit einem Vernetzungsbeschleuniger, der aus Ammonium- oder Phosphoniumsalzen, Phosphoranaminsalzen ausgewählt ist, sind.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Mehrschichtige Zusammensetzung nach Anspruch 12, wobei es sich bei den ionischen Vernetzungsmitteln um sowohl aliphatische als auch aromatische geschützte Diamine handelt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Mehrschichtige Zusammensetzung nach den Ansprüchen 12-13, wobei Amine in Schicht C) verwendet werden.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Mehrschichtige Zusammensetzung nach den Ansprüchen 8-14, wobei die Menge von Vernetzungsmitteln im Bereich von 0,1 bis 20,0 Gew.- % aber vorzugsweise 0,5 bis 10,0 Gew.- %, bezogen auf das Polymer, liegt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0016" num="0016"><claim-text>Mehrschichtige Zusammensetzung nach den Ansprüchen 1-15, die durch Coextrusion von Schichten A), B) und C) erhältlich ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0017" num="0017"><claim-text>Erzeugnisse, die aus den mehrschichtigen Zusammensetzungen der Ansprüche 1-16 erhältlich sind.<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0018" num="0018"><claim-text>Erzeugnisse nach Anspruch 17 in Form von Kraftstoffleitungen und Kraftstoffschläuchen.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56987745" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A multilayer composition comprising:
<claim-text>A) a first layer based on copolymers of ethylene (E) with tetrafluoroethylene (TFE) and/or chlorotrifluoroethylene (CTFE), preferably CTFE;</claim-text>
<claim-text>B) a second intermediate layer comprising thermoprocessable copolymers of ethylene (E) with tetrafluoroethylene (TFE) and/or chlorotrifluoroethylene (CTFE) modified with acrylic monomers of formula:<br/>
<br/>
        CH<sub>2</sub>=CH-CO-O-R<sub>2</sub>     (a)<br/>
<br/>
R<sub>2</sub> is a C<sub>1</sub>-C<sub>20</sub> hydrogenated radical from 1 to 20 carbon atoms, linear and/or branched, alkyl or cycloalkyl radical, or R<sub>2</sub> is H; the R<sub>2</sub> radical optionally containing heteroatoms preferably Cl, O, N; one or more functional groups selected from OH, COOH, epoxide, ester and ether;</claim-text>
<claim-text>C) a third layer based on hydrogenated polymers;<br/>
said multilayer composition containing in layer B) and/or in layer C) one or more crosslinking agents.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>A multilayer composition according to claim 1, wherein the copolymers of layer A) contain:
<claim-text>- from 30 to 60% by moles, preferably from 40 to 50% of ethylene;<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>- from 40 to 70% by moles, preferably from 50 to 60% of a fluorinated monomer selected from tetrafluoroethylene and/or chlorotrifluoroethylene;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- optionally from 0.1 to 5% by moles referred to the sum of the previous monomers of a fluorinated monomer selected from: perfluoroalkylvinylethers, preferably perfluoropropylvinylether, perfluorodioxoles, hexafluoroisobutene.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>A multilayer composition according to claims 1-2, wherein the thermoprocessable copolymers of layer B) are formed by:
<claim-text>- from 10 to 70% by moles, preferably from 35 to 55% of ethylene;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- from 30 to 90% by moles, preferably from 45 to 65%, of a fluorinated monomer selected from tetrafluoroethylene, chlorotrifluoroethylene, preferably CTFE;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- from 0.1 to 30% by moles, preferably from 1 to 15% by moles of the comonomer (a) referred to the sum of the previous monomers.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>A multilayer composition according to claims 1-3, wherein layer B) comprises also the thermoprocessable copolymers of layer A) in an amount from 0 to 95% by weight, preferably from 70 to 95% by weight with respect to the copolymers of layer B), with the proviso that layer B)<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> contains an amount of acrylic monomers of formula (a) at least 0.1% by moles.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>A multilayer composition according to claims 1-4, wherein the hydrogenated polymers of layer C) are of both the thermoprocessable and elastomeric type, preferably thermoprocessable.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>A multilayer composition according to claim 5, wherein the thermoprocessable hydrogenated polymers are hydro-cellulose polymers, polyamides, polyamide copolymers, policarbonates, polyesters, polyolefins, polyimides, polystyrene, polyurethanes, polyvinylchloride (PVC), polysulphones, ethylene/vinylacetate copolymers, polyacrylobutadienestyrene (ABS).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>A multilayer composition according to claim 5, wherein the hydrogenated elastomers are acrylic rubbers, nitrile rubbers (NBR), ethylene-propylene rubbers (EPM), ethylene-propylene-diene rubbers (EPDM), nitrile rubbers mixed with PVC (NVC), epichlorohydrin rubbers (CO and ECO).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>A multilayer composition according to claims 1-7, wherein the crosslinking agents are of both radical and ionic type.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>A multilayer composition according to claim 8, wherein the radical crosslinking agents are triallylisocyanurate (TAIC), triallylcyanurate (TAC), diallylisophthalate,<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> diallylterephthalate, esters of phenyl indan, triallylester of the aryl polycarboxylic acid, bis-olefins.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>A multilayer composition according to claims 8-9, wherein the radical crosslinking agent is used in combination with a peroxide.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>A multilayer composition according to claims 8-10, wherein when the peroxide is present in layer C), the crosslinking agent is present in layer B), or viceversa.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>A multilayer composition according to claim 8, wherein the ionic crosslinking agents are of amine type, maleimides derivatives, C<sub>4</sub>-C<sub>20</sub> aliphatic diamines, polyhydroxyl aromatic compounds preferably in combination with a crosslinking accelerator selected from ammonium or phosphonium salts, phosphoranamine salts.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>A multilayer composition according to claim 12, wherein the ionic crosslinking agents are both aliphatic and aromatic protected diamines.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>A multilayer composition according to claims 12-13, wherein amines are used in layer C).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>A multilayer composition according to claims 8-14, wherein the amount of crosslinking agents ranges from 0.1 to 20.0% by weight, preferably from 0.5 to 10.0% by weight with respect to the polymer.<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0016" num="0016"><claim-text>A multilayer composition according to claims 1-15 obtainable by co-extrusion of layers A), B) and C).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0017" num="0017"><claim-text>Manufactured articles obtainable from the multilayer compositions of claims 1-16.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0018" num="0018"><claim-text>Manufactured articles according to claim 17 under the form of fuel lines and fuel hoses.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56987746" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Composition multicouche comprenant :
<claim-text>A) une première couche à base de copolymères d'éthylène (E) avec du tétrafluoroéthylène (TFE) et/ou du chlorotrifluoroéthylène (CTFE), préférablement du CTFE ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>B) une deuxième couche intermédiaire comprenant des copolymères thermotransformables d'éthylène (E) avec du tétrafluoroéthylène (TFE) et/ou du chlorotrifluoroéthylène (CTFE) modifiés avec des monomères acryliques ayant la formule :<br/>
<br/>
        CH<sub>2</sub>=CH-CO-0-R<sub>2</sub>     (a)<br/>
<br/>
dans laquelle<br/>
R<sub>2</sub> est un radical hydrogéné C<sub>1</sub>-C<sub>20</sub> comportant de 1 à 20 atomes de carbone, un radical alkyle ou cycloalkyle linéaire et/ou ramifié, ou R<sub>2</sub> est un atome d'hydrogène, le radical R<sub>2</sub> pouvant éventuellement contenir des hétéroatomes, préférablement de chlore, d'oxygène ou d'azote ; un ou plusieurs groupes fonctionnels sélectionnés parmi un groupe OH, COOH, époxyde, ester et éther ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>C) une troisième couche à base de polymères hydrogénés ;<br/>
ladite composition multicouche contenant dans la couche B) et/ou dans la couche C) un ou plusieurs agents de réticulation.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Composition multicouche selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle les copolymères de la couche A) contiennent :
<claim-text>- de 30 % mol à 60 % mol, préférablement de 40 %mol à 50 % mol d'éthylène ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- de 40 % mol à 70 % mol, préférablement de 50 % mol à 60 % mol d'un monomère fluoré sélectionné parmi le tétrafluoroéthylène et/ou le chlorotrifluoroéthylène ;<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>- éventuellement de 0,1 % mol à 5 % mol, relativement à la somme des monomères précédents, d'un monomère fluoré sélectionné parmi : les éthers perfluoroalkylvinyliques, préférablement l'éther perfluoropropylvinylique, les perfluorodioxoles, et l'hexafluoroisobutène.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Composition multicouche selon les revendications 1-2, dans laquelle les copolymères thermotransformables de la couche B) se composent de :
<claim-text>- de 10 % mol à 70 % mol, préférablement de 35 % mol à 55 % mol d'éthylène ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- de 30 % mol à 90 % mol, préférablement de 45 % mol à 65 % mol d'un monomère fluoré sélectionné parmi le tétrafluoroéthylène, le chlorotrifluoroéthylène, préférablement le CTFE ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- de 0,1 % mol à 30 % mol, préférablement de 1 % mol à 15 % mol du comonomère (a) relativement à la somme des monomères précédents.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Composition multicouche selon les revendications 1-3, dans laquelle la couche B) comprend aussi les copolymères thermotransformables de la couche A) dans une quantité de 0 % pds à 95 % pds, préférablement de 70 % pds à 95 % pds relativement aux copolymères de la couche B), sous réserve que la couche B) contienne une quantité de monomères acryliques selon la formule (a) d'au moins 0,1 % mol.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Composition multicouche selon les revendications 1-4, dans laquelle les polymères hydrogénés de la couche C) sont à la fois de type thermotransformable et de type élastomère, préférablement thermotransformables.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Composition multicouche selon la revendication 5, dans laquelle les polymères hydrogénés thermotransformables sont des polymères d'hydrocellulose, des polyamides, des copolymères de polyamides, des polycarbonates, des polyesters, des polyoléfines, des polyimides, des polystyrènes, des polyuréthanes, du polychlorure de vinyle (PVC), des polysulfones, des copolymères d'éthylène/acétate de vinyle, du polyacrylobutadiène-styrène (ABS).<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Composition multicouche selon la revendication 5, dans laquelle les élastomères hydrogénés sont des caoutchoucs acryliques, des caoutchoucs nitriles (NBR), des caoutchoucs d'éthylène-propylène (EPM), des caoutchoucs d'éthylène-propylène-diène (EPDM), des caoutchoucs nitriles mélangés avec du PVC (NVC), des caoutchoucs d'épichlorhydrine (CO et ECO).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Composition multicouche selon les revendications 1-7, dans laquelle les agents de réticulation sont de type radical ainsi que de type ionique.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Composition multicouche selon la revendication 8, dans laquelle les agents de réticulation de type radical sont l'isocyanurate de triallyle (TAIC), le cyanurate de triallyle (TAC), l'isophtalate de diallyle, le téréphtalate de diallyle, des esters de phénylindane, l'ester triallylique de l'acide aryl-polycarboxylique, ou des bis-oléfines.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Composition multicouche selon les revendications 8-9, dans laquelle l'agent de réticulation de type radical est utilisé en combinaison avec un peroxyde.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Composition multicouche selon les revendications 8-10, dans laquelle, quand le peroxyde est présent dans la couche C), l'agent de réticulation est présent dans la couche B), ou inversement.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Composition multicouche selon la revendication 8, dans laquelle les agents de réticulation ioniques sont de type amine, des dérivés de maléimides, des diamines aliphatiques C<sub>4</sub>-C<sub>20</sub>, des composés aromatiques polyhydroxyles préférablement en combinaison avec un accélérateur de réticulation sélectionné parmi les sels d'ammonium, les sels de phosphonium, ou les sels de phosphoranamine.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Composition multicouche selon la revendication 12, dans laquelle les agents de réticulation ioniques sont des diamines protégées à la fois par des groupes aliphatiques et par des groupes aromatiques.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Composition multicouche selon les revendications 12-13, dans laquelle les amines sont utilisées dans la couche C).<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Composition multicouche selon les revendications 8-14, dans laquelle la quantité d'agents de réticulation est de 0,1 %pds à 20,0 %pds, préférablement de 0,5 %pds à 10,0 %pds relativement au polymère.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0016" num="0016"><claim-text>Composition multicouche selon les revendications 1-15, pouvant être obtenue par co-extrusion des couches A), B) et C).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0017" num="0017"><claim-text>Articles manufacturés pouvant être obtenus à partir des compositions multicouche selon les revendications 1-16.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0018" num="0018"><claim-text>Articles manufacturés selon la revendication 17, sous forme de canalisations de carburant et de tuyaux de carburant.</claim-text></claim></claims><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
