<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-1800328-B1" country="EP" doc-number="1800328" kind="B1" date="20140101" family-id="36119180" file-reference-id="287175" date-produced="20180822" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146553740" ucid="EP-1800328-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>1800328</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-05766771-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154827663" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>05766771</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20050719</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140452324" ucid="SG-200405927-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>SG</country><doc-number>200405927</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20040927</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140452323" ucid="SG-2005000240-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>SG</country><doc-number>2005000240</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20050719</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130715</date></intention-to-grant-date><search-report-dispatch-date><date>20090825</date></search-report-dispatch-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988098580" load-source="docdb">H01L  21/00        20060101AFI20060412BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988124434" load-source="docdb">B25J  15/06        20060101ALI20060412BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988132719" load-source="docdb">B25B  11/02        20060101ALI20060412BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988133945" load-source="docdb">H01L  21/68        20060101ALI20060412BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2108111148" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 279/11        20130101 LA20150120BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2108113092" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01L  21/67333     20130101 FI20150122BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2108136866" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B25B  11/005       20130101 LI20150122BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2108141260" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01L  21/67336     20130101 LI20150122BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132193704" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">VAKUUM-HALTEVORRICHTUNG FÜR EINHEITEN INTEGRIERTER SCHALTUNGEN</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132193705" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">VACUUM HOLDER FOR INTEGRATED CIRCUIT UNITS</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132193706" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">SUPPORT A ASPIRATION POUR UNITES DE CIRCUITS INTEGRES</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918138168" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>ROKKO SYSTEMS PTE LTD</last-name><address><country>SG</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918142563" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>ROKKO SYSTEMS PTE LTD</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918157219" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>YANG HAE CHOON</last-name><address><country>SG</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918132239" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>YANG, HAE CHOON</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918997739" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>YANG, Hae Choon c/o Rokko Systems Pte Ltd</last-name><address><street>18 Kaki Bukit Road 3 02-01 Entrepreneur Business</street><city>Centre Singapore 415978</city><country>SG</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918997741" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Rokko Systems Pte Ltd</last-name><iid>100778197</iid><address><street>18 Kaki Bulik Road 3 02-01 Entrepreneur Business Centre</street><city>Singapore 415978</city><country>SG</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918997740" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Howe, Steven</last-name><iid>100038368</iid><address><street>Marks &amp; Clerk LLP 90 Long Acre</street><city>London WC2E 9RA</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="SG-2005000240-W"><document-id><country>SG</country><doc-number>2005000240</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20050719</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2006036126-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2006036126</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20060406</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548980018" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS548981675" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS548829976" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS548885094" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS548978985" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS548980019" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS548981676" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548978986" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS548978987" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS548989824" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS548829977" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS548829978" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548981677" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548978988" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS548980020" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS548885095" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS548978989" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS548829979" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS548978990" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS548984612" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS548980021" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS548984613" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS548985406" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS548981682" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS548985407" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS548885096" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS548981683" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS548985408" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS548885097" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS548829980" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS548978991" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63957381" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001"><u>Field of the Invention</u></heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to a sawing and sorting system. The system interacts with, or includes, a dicing machine which saws ("dices") a substrate with many integrated circuits formed onto it to form individual integrated circuits. The invention further relates to apparatus for use in such a sawing and sorting system.</p><heading id="h0002"><u>Background of Invention</u></heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">Conventionally a plurality of integrated circuits are formed simultaneously on a semiconductor substrate, and the substrate is then diced to form individual integrated circuits. Apparatus is know for feeding substrates into such a dicing machine, and for sorting the diced integrated circuits.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">One type of integrated circuit which is becoming increasingly popular is one having an array of multiple electrical contacts (typically solder balls, known as a ball grid array (BGA) packages, and pads in non-leaded packages, known as a Quad Flatpack Non-Leaded (QFN) packages) in an array on one of its major faces. The dicing of a substrate having a ball grid array on one of its surfaces is typically performed with the surface of the substrate carrying the balls facing upwards. It is known to perform a limited number of sorting operations on the singulated integrated circuit units to detect abnormal (faulty) units. At each stage of the process following singulation of the integrated circuit units, the manipulation of the units requires a firm engagement of the units. In some circumstances this is achieved a vacuum seal whereby the unit is held within a matrix by suction. In one arrangement a metal "manifold" having an internal hollow portion which is applied a vacuum will have a surface divided into an array of recesses with an aperture for each recess through which the vacuum will draw the units.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">The units themselves are delicate and can suffer damage through the manipulation process and particularly, when draw near to the respective metal recesses of the surface. For this reason, a layer or coating of a soft material such as rubber is placed on the surface such that the unit contacts the soft layer rather than the metal surface.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p><p id="p0005" num="0005">Because of the fine tolerances required for holding the small units it is a particularly complex task to bond the layer to the metal surface. One difficulty in this duplication process is the different tolerances required of the metal surface as compared to the soft material. Therefore, the element having the metal surface with the layer and the vacuum manifold are generally expensive items should themselves need to be treated with care.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">As a result of the manufacturing process, it is inevitable that the soft material layer will either wear or suffer damage. To prevent damage to the units, It is therefore necessary to replace the soft material layer. However, because of the aforementioned difficulties replacing the soft metal layer will also require replacement of the entire element.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US6196532B"><text>US6196532</text></patcit> discloses a support device for supporting a semiconductor item, the device comprising: a support member having a metal surface, said surfaces having a plurality of recesses; a material layer, overlaying the recesses of the metal surface and a vacuum means in communication with said recesses such that the vacuum means supports parts of the item; wherein the material layer is formed of a plurality of independent inserts, each insert engageable with at least one recess.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008"><patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="US5953590A"><text>US5953590</text></patcit> discloses a semiconductor wafer having a set of integrated circuit units which are partly finished at stages of manufacture.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">The invention is the support device of Claim 1, and the repair method of Claim 9.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">The present invention can reduce the cost of replacement imposed by wear or damage.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">Therefore, the invention provides for replaceable inserts which will fit into the metal surface and so on damage to the deformable i.e. soft material formed by the plurality of inserts instead of replacing the entire element including the undamaged metal surface, it is only necessary to replace those particular inserts that have suffered wear or damage.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p><p id="p0012" num="0012">A further advantage of the present invention beyonds the cost saving of replacing the entire element is the manufacturing cost. As discussed creating a layered element of dissimilar materials being the soft material such as rubber and the metal surface is a difficult and potentially expensive exercise. Further, avoiding delamination of the layer in use is a further problem to be overcome. In one embodiment of the present invention, this is overcome through a mechanical engagement between the insert and the metal surface. Alternatively, the inserts may be chemically bonded to the metal surface. Thus, manufacturing of the element as a whole avoids the layering process required of the prior art and instead applies simply on either a mechanical of chemical bonding of the insert to the surface which may require little expertise or cost.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">In a preferred embodiment, mechanically engageable inserts may have a barbed portion which may engage with an internal shape of a portion of the recess, such that, on application of a force to the insert, the insert is "press fit" into the recess through a corresponding engagement of the insert barbed portion and internal shaped portion of the recess.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">In an alternative embodiment, the insert may be bonded to the metal surface, which may be sufficient to hold the insert, but permitting selective removal of the insert through heat, force or a combination of both. Such a bond may be through a "hot melt" material which may be applied in a hot liquid form and sets at room temperature.<br/>
In one embodiment, each recess may be engaged with a single recess. Alternatively, or in certain circumstances, as well as, a single insert may overlay several recesses, and either engage with each recess, or sufficient recesses to maintain engagement. In a purely illustrative, and non-limiting, example, one insert may overlay eight recesses, and engage with only four peripherally located recesses.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">Further to the manufacturing advantages because of the dissimilar inherent tolerances of a soft material and metal having the layer covering many of the recesses, any inconsistency in the tolerances between individual recesses and the layer will be multiplied by the number of recesses present in the metal surface. In the present<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> invention, however, any inconsistency in tolerance will apply to individual recesses or in a preferred embodiment, a small number of recesses for a multiple recess insert and thus, limiting any multiplication of the inconsistency.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">Further advantages to the present invention relates to a balance between downtime of the equipment and the cost of spare parts. To limit the lost production time through replacing an element, a fabricator may keep in stock several replacement elements of the prior art. Such spare equipment may include a Twin Chuck Table, Net lifter, Frame lifter and Idle lifter, each of which may require the use of the support device of the prior art. To this end, being expensive items, the fabricator will need to bear the cost of the non-productive spare equipment. Alternatively, the present invention may require maintaining a stock of inserts only, applicable for use with each of the above equipment. Being relatively inexpensive items the fabricator may maintain this stock at a lower cost without compromising lost production time.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">In a further benefit the time taken to replace the element of the prior art will be substantial, as this may require the refit of a new element, alignment of vacuum seals etc.. This is compared to fitting the required inserts to the metal surface which may be a fraction of the downtime and maintenance cost compared to the prior art.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">In a preferred embodiment, the inserts may be entirely made of the soft material, said material including, but not limited to polyurethane, natural rubber and silicone. It will be apparent to the skilled person that other available relevant materials may also perform the protective function of the invention, and so the invention is not limited to the above materials, but will include each of said relevant materials.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">In a more preferred embodiment, the insert may comprise more than one material. A material may be selected based on the particular function of differing portions of the insert. For instance, the engagement means of the insert may be of a different material to contact surface of the insert. The contact surface is that portion which contacts and protects the units, and so is well suited to the soft material. However, an engagement portion, corresponding to the engagement means may be of a stiffer material to facilitate<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> mechanical engagement. As an illustrative, non-limiting, example, a suitable material may include polypropylene, HDPE, ABS etc.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">Further, if the engagement means includes a chemical engagement, the engagement portion of the insert may include a material that suits the type of chemical engagement.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">In a further embodiment, the selection of multiple materials for the insert may also take into account the compatibility of the various selections so as to both serve their respective functions, and also facilitate efficient and effective manufacture.</p><heading id="h0003"><u>Brief Description of Drawings</u></heading><p id="p0022" num="0022">It will be convenient to further describe the present invention with respect to the accompanying drawings which illustrate possible arrangements of the invention. Other arrangements of the invention are possible, and consequently the particularity of the accompanying drawings is not to be understood as superseding the generality of the preceding description of the invention.
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1a</figref> is a plan view of a support device according to the present invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1b</figref> is a side elevation view of the support device of <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1a</figref>;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2a</figref> is a detail view of the soft material layer of the support device according to the present invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2b</figref> is a side elevation view of the soft material layer of <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2a</figref>.</li></ul></p><p id="p0023" num="0023"><figref idrefs="f0001">Figures 1a and 1b</figref> show a support device 10 such as a vacuum pad for use with Twin Chuck Table, Net lifter, Frame lifter and Idle lifter. Said devices are used to manipulate and support units, such as integrated circuit chips singulated from a wafer.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">The support device 10 includes a support member 15 which acts as a housing for a metal surface 20, a "manifold" chamber 35 for a applying a vacuum and an overlay 30. The metal surface includes an array 25 of recesses 27 which correspond to the inserts 40 to which the support device 10 allocates and supports the units. Because of the metal<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> surface representing a hazard to the units, the overlay 30 cushions the effect of the units coming in contact with the support device 10. In the prior art, this overlay is formed of a sheet of rubber. The present invention, however, provides a layer of individual inserts which, together form a layer, but individually, correspond to one or a small number of the recesses 27.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">In this embodiment, each insert 40 corresponds to a single recess 27, and thus forms a mosaic of inserts which form the layer 30.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026"><figref idrefs="f0002">Figures 2a and 2b</figref> show a close up view of the arrangement of inserts 40 and recesses 27. The inserts form, in this embodiment, a tessellated layer of soft material, corresponding to the array of recesses. Each insert 40 includes a barbed portion 50 and an engagement portion 55. To engagement the insert with the recess 27, a force is applied to the top of the insert 60, pressing the barb 50 into the recess, and passed a throat 37 of the recess, the throat 37 is of a smaller corresponding size to the recess 27 itself, with the throat being of a size to require the barb 50 to deform so as to pass through. Once the barb 50 is clear of the throat, the throat then engages in a relaxed fit with the engagement portion 55 of the insert. Thus, in this embodiment, the insert is engaged with the recess through a press fit 52, with the insert, on engagement, sitting in an unstressed condition. In a preferred embodiment, the insert may sit "snuggly" with a shoulder portion 57 of the insert contacting the interface 58 between the recess 27 and the throat 37, with this contact acting as a "stop" to both position the insert 40, and prevent over application of force.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">When supported by the support device 10, the unit 65 is held in place by a vacuum. The vacuum in this embodiment, is generated by a negative pressure with the manifold chamber 35, with this chamber being in fluid communication with the unit 65 through a conduit 45 passing through the insert 40. Thus, in this embodiment, the conduit may be a centrally located conduit 45, passing through the center of the insert 40, so as to maintain the corresponding unit in a central position in contact with the overlay portion of the insert.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56979632" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Stützvorrichtung (10) zum Stützen eines Satzes von vereinzelten integrierten Schaltkreiseinheiten (65), wobei die Vorrichtung Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>ein Stützelement (15), das eine Metalloberfläche hat, wobei die Oberfläche eine Gruppierung von Aussparungen (27) hat,</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine erste Materialschicht (30), welche über den Aussparungen der Metalloberfläche liegt, um so die Einheiten (65) an einem Kontakt mit der Metalloberfläche zu hindern, und wobei das erste Material eines oder eine Kombination von Naturkautschuk, Polyurethan und Silikon ist,</claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Vakuummittel (35) in Verbindung mit dem Aussparungen (27) derart, dass das Vakuummittel jede Einheit innerhalb einer jeweiligen Aussparung stützt, wobei</claim-text>
<claim-text>die erste Materialschicht aus mehreren unabhängigen Einsätzen (40) geformt ist, wobei jeder Einsatz eine Stützfläche (60) hat, die einer Fläche jeder vereinzelten Schaltkreiseinheit (65) entspricht, wobei jeder Einsatz mit wenigstens einer Aussparung in Eingriff gebracht werden kann, unter Verwendung von Eingriffsmitteln (50 55) zum In-Eingriff-Bringen jedes Einsatzes (40) mit wenigstens einer Aussparung (27).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Stützvorrichtung (10) nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Eingriffsmittel (50, 55) eines oder beides von einem mechanischen Eingriff und einem chemischen Verbindungseingriff einschließt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Stützvorrichtung (10) nach Anspruch 2, wobei der mechanische Eingriff (50, 55) eine Presspassung zwischen dem Einsatz und wenigstens einer Aussparung einschließt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Stützvorrichtung (10) nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei jeder Einsatz (40) mit einer einzigen Aussparung (27) in Eingriff gebracht werden kann.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Stützvorrichtung (10) nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 4, wobei der Einsatz (40) mit wenigstens zwei Aussparungen (27) in Eingriff gebracht werden kann.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Stützvorrichtung (10) nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei die Einsätze (40) ein zweites Material einschließen, das mit dem ersten Material verbunden ist, um die Eingriffsmittel zu ermöglichen, wobei das zweite Material eines oder eine Kombination von Polypropylen, HDPE und ABS ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Stützvorrichtung (10) nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei das Vakuummittel (35) eine Vakuumpumpe in Verbindung mit dem Stützelement (15) einschließt, um einen Unterdruck innerhalb einer inneren Kammer des Stützelements zu erzeugen derart, dass jede Aussparung (27) und jeder Abschnitt des Einsatzes, der jeder Aussparung entspricht, eine Öffnung einschließt, durch die der Unterdruck wirkt, um so eine Einheit (65), die der Aussparung entspricht, einzuziehen und mit derselben ineinanderzugreifen.<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Einsatz (40) zur Verwendung mit einer Stützvorrichtung (10), wobei die Stützvorrichtung zum Stützen eines Satzes von vereinzelten integrierten Schaltkreiseinheiten (65) dient, wobei die Vorrichtung Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>ein Stützelement (15), das die Metalloberfläche hat, wobei die Oberfläche eine Gruppierung von Aussparungen (27) hat,</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine erste Materialschicht (30), welche über den Aussparungen der Metalloberfläche liegt, um so die Einheiten (65) an einem Kontakt mit der Metalloberfläche zu hindern, und wobei das erste Material eines oder eine Kombination von Naturkautschuk, Polyurethan und Silikon ist,</claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Vakuummittel (35) in Verbindung mit dem Aussparungen (27) derart, dass das Vakuummittel jede Einheit innerhalb einer jeweiligen Aussparung stützt, wobei</claim-text>
<claim-text>die erste Materialschicht aus mehreren unabhängigen Einsätzen (40) geformt ist, wobei jeder Einsatz eine Stützfläche (60) hat, die einer Fläche jeder vereinzelten integrierten Schaltkreiseinheit (65) entspricht, wobei jeder Einsatz mit wenigstens einer Aussparung (27) in Eingriff gebracht werden kann.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Verfahren zum Reparieren einer Stützvorrichtung (10), wobei die Stützvorrichtung zum Stützen eines Satzes von vereinzelten integrierten Schaltkreiseinheiten (65) verwendet wird, wobei das Verfahren die folgenden Schritte umfasst:
<claim-text>das Entfernen eines beschädigten oder verschlissenen Einsatzes (40) aus einer Aussparung eines Stützelements (15) der Stützvorrichtung (10), wobei das Stützelement (15) eine Metalloberfläche mit einer Gruppierung der Aussparungen (27) hat,</claim-text>
<claim-text>das Auswählen eines Ersatzeinsatzes (40) für einen erneuten Eingriff mit der Aussparung (27),</claim-text>
<claim-text>das In-Eingriff-Bringen des Einsatzes (40) mit der Aussparung (27), um so zu ermöglichen, dass ein Vakuummittel (35) in Verbindung mit den Aussparungen eine Einheit innerhalb der jeweiligen Aussparungen stützt, wobei der Ersatzeinsatz (40) eine erste Materialschicht (30) auf der Metalloberfläche vervollständigt, wobei das erste Material eines oder eine Kombination von Naturkautschuk, Polyurethan und Silikon ist, wobei die Schicht mehrere unabhängige Einsätze umfasst, wobei jeder Einsatz eine Stützfläche (60) hat, die einer Fläche jeder vereinzelten integrierten Schaltkreiseinheit (65) entspricht.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56979633" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A support device (10) for supporting a set of singulated integrated circuit units (65), the device comprising:
<claim-text>a support member (15) having a metal surface, said surface having an array of recesses (27);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first material layer (30), overlaying the recesses of the metal surface so as to prevent the units (65) from contact with the metal surface; and, the first material being one or a combination of natural rubber, polyurethane and silicone;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a vacuum means (35) in communication with said recesses (27), such that the vacuum means supports each unit within a respective recess, wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first material layer is formed of a plurality of independent inserts (40), each insert having an area of support (60) corresponding to an area of each singulated integrated circuit unit (65), each insert engageable with at least one recess using engagement means (50, 55) for engaging each insert (40) with the at least one recess (27).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The support device (10) according to claim 1, wherein the engagement means (50, 55) includes one or both of mechanical engagement and chemical bonding engagement.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The support device (210) according to claim 2 wherein the mechanical engagement (50, 55) includes a press fitting between the insert and at least one recess.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The support device (10) according to any one of the preceding claims wherein each insert (40) is engageable with a single recess (27).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The support device (10) according to any one of claims 1 to 4 wherein the insert (40) is engageable with at least two recesses (27).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The support device (10) according to any one of the preceding claims wherein the inserts (40) include a second material bonded to the first material for facilitating the engagement means, the second material being one or a combination of polypropylene, HDPE and ABS.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The support device (10) according to any one of the preceding claims wherein the vacuum means (35) includes a vacuum pump in communication with the support member (15) for creating a negative pressure within an internal chamber of the support member, such that each recess (27), and each portion of the insert corresponding to each recess, includes an aperture through which the negative pressure acts so as to draw in and engage with a unit (65) corresponding to the recess.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>An insert (40) for use with a support device (10), said support device for supporting a set of singulated integrated circuit units (65), the device comprising:
<claim-text>a support member (15) having the metal surface, said surface having an array of recesses (27);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first material layer (30), overlaying the recesses of the metal surface so as to prevent the units (65) from contact with the metal surface, the first material being one or a combination of natural rubber, polyurethane and silicone; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a vacuum means (35) in communication with said recesses (27), such that the vacuum means supports each unit within a respective recess, wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first material layer is formed of a plurality of the independent inserts (40), each insert having an area of support (60) corresponding to an area of each singulated integrated circuit unit (65), each insert engageable with at least one recess (27).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>A method of repairing a support device (10), said support device used to support a set of singulated integrated circuit units (65), the method comprising the steps of:
<claim-text>removing a damaged or worn insert (40) from a recess of a support member (15) of the support device (10), said support member (15) having a metal surface with an array of said recesses (27);</claim-text>
<claim-text>selecting a replacement insert (40) for re-engagement with the recess (27);</claim-text>
<claim-text>engaging the insert (40) with the recess (27), so as to permit a vacuum means (35) in communication with said recesses to support a unit within the respective recess, wherein the replacement insert (40) completes a first material layer (30) on the metal surface, the first material being one or a combination of natural rubber, polyurethane and silicone, said layer comprising a plurality of independent inserts, each insert having an area of support (60) corresponding to an area of each singulated integrated circuit unit (65).</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56979634" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Dispositif de support (10), destiné à supporter un groupe d'unités de circuit intégré individualisées (85), le dispositif comprenant :
<claim-text>un élément de support (15), comportant une surface métallique, ladite surface comportant un ensemble d'évidements (27) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une couche d'un premier matériau (30), superposée aux évidements de la surface métallique, de sorte à empêcher un contact entre les unités (65) et la surface métallique ; le premier matériau étant constitué par une substance, le caoutchouc naturel, le polyuréthane, la silicone ou une combinaison de ces substances ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un moyen à vide (35), en communication avec lesdits évidements (27), de sorte que le moyen à vide supporte chaque unité dans un évidement respectif ; dans lequel</claim-text>
<claim-text>la couche du premier matériau est formée à partir de plusieurs inserts indépendants (40), chaque insert comportant une surface de support (60) correspondant à une surface de chaque unité de circuit intégré individualisée (65), chaque insert pouvant être engagé dans au moins un évidement par l'intermédiaire d'un moyen d'engagement (50, 55) pour engager chaque insert (40) dans au moins un évidement (27).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Dispositif de support (10) selon la revendication 1, dans lequel le moyen d'engagement (50, 55) englobe un engagement mécanique ou un engagement par liaison chimique ou ces deux types d'engagement.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Dispositif de support (10) selon la revendication 2, dans lequel l'engagement mécanique (50, 55) englobe un ajustement serré entre l'insert et au moins un évidement.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Dispositif de support (10) selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans lequel chaque insert (40) peut être engagé dans un seul évidement (27).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Dispositif de support (10) selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 4, dans lequel l'insert (40) peut être engagé dans au moins deux évidements (27).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Dispositif de support (10) selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans lequel les inserts (40) englobent un deuxième matériau relié au premier matériau pour faciliter l'action du moyen d'engagement, le deuxième matériau étant constitué par une substance, le polypropylène, le polyéthylène haute densité, un ABS ou une combinaison de ces substances.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Dispositif de support (10) selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans lequel le moyen à vide (35) englobe une pompe à vide, en communication avec l'élément de support (15), pour établir une pression négative dans une chambre interne de l'élément de support, de sorte que chaque évidement (27) et chaque partie de l'insert correspondant à chaque évidement englobent une ouverture à travers laquelle la pression négative agit, de sorte à aspirer une unité (65) correspondant à l'évidement et à entraîner son engagement.<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Insert (40), destiné à être utilisé avec un dispositif de support (10), ledit dispositif de support servant à supporter un groupe d'unités de circuit intégré individualisées (65), le dispositif comprenant :
<claim-text>un élément de support (15), comportant la surface métallique, ladite surface comportant un ensemble d'évidements (27) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une couche d'un premier matériau (30), superposée aux évidements de la surface métallique, de sorte à empêcher un contact entre les unités (65) et la surface métallique, le premier matériau étant constitué par une substance, le caoutchouc naturel, le polyuréthane, la silicone ou par une combinaison de ces substances ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un moyen à vide (35), en communication avec lesdits évidements (27), le moyen à vide supportant ainsi chaque unité dans un évidement respectif ; dans lequel</claim-text>
<claim-text>la couche du premier matériau est formée à partir de plusieurs inserts indépendants (40), chaque insert comportant une surface de support (60) correspondant à une surface de chaque unité de circuit intégré individualisée (65), chaque insert pouvant être engagé dans au moins un évidement (27).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Procédé de réparation d'un dispositif de support (10), ledit dispositif de support servant à supporter un groupe d'unités de circuit intégré individualisées (65), le procédé comprenant les étapes ci-dessous :
<claim-text>retrait d'un insert endommagé ou usé (40) d'un évidement d'un élément de support (15) du dispositif de support (10), ledit élément de support (15) comportant une surface métallique présentant un ensemble desdits évidements (27) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>sélection d'un insert de remplacement (40) en vue d'un nouvel engagement dans l'évidement (27) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>engagement de l'insert (40) dans l'évidement (27), de sorte à permettre à un moyen à vide (35), en communication avec lesdits évidements, de supporter une unité dans l'évidement respectif, l'insert de remplacement (40) complétant une couche d'un premier matériau (30) sur la surface métallique, le premier matériau étant un matériau constitué par une substance, le caoutchouc naturel, le polyuréthane, la silicone ou une combinaison de ces substances, ladite couche comprenant plusieurs inserts indépendants, chaque insert comportant une surface de support (60) correspondant à une surface de chaque unité de circuit intégré individualisée (65).</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16668922" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1a,1b"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="120" he="178" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2a,2b"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="159" he="191" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
