<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2085981-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2085981" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="39343951" file-reference-id="299952" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146588306" ucid="EP-2085981-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2085981</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-07827977-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154850498" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>07827977</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20071101</date><lang>JA</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140547061" ucid="JP-2006299354-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>JP</country><doc-number>2006299354</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20061102</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140554509" ucid="JP-2007001198-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>JP</country><doc-number>2007001198</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20071101</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130808</date></intention-to-grant-date><search-report-dispatch-date><date>20120323</date></search-report-dispatch-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989325244" load-source="ipcr">H01F   5/04        20060101AFI20130620BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989325245" load-source="ipcr">H01F  41/10        20060101ALI20130620BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989325246" load-source="ipcr">H01R   4/02        20060101ALI20130620BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989623486" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01R   4/023       20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989625380" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01F  41/10        20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989626906" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01F   5/04        20130101 FI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989634934" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01R   4/625       20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989637188" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01R   4/187       20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989640264" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01F2027/065       20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132369551" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">ANSCHLUSS UND SPULENANORDNUNG DAMIT</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132369552" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">TERMINAL AND COIL DEVICE USING THE SAME</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132369553" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">BORNE ET DISPOSITIF DE BOBINE L'UTILISANT</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919531125" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>TABUCHI DENKI KK</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919543824" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>TABUCHI ELECTRIC CO., LTD.</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919512949" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>TAMURA AKIMASA</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919506220" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>TAMURA, AKIMASA</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919022488" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>TAMURA, AKIMASA</last-name><address><street>c/o Tabuchi Electric Co., Ltd. 2-21, Miyahara 4-chome Yodogawa-ku Osaka-shi</street><city>Osaka 532-0003</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919530665" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>TAKAHASHI HITOSHI</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919508547" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>TAKAHASHI, HITOSHI</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919022486" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>TAKAHASHI, HITOSHI</last-name><address><street>c/o Tabuchi Electric Co., Ltd. 2-21, Miyahara 4-chome Yodogawa-ku Osaka-shi</street><city>Osaka 532-0003</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919511011" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>WARASHINA KEISUKE</last-name><address><country>TH</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919517914" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>WARASHINA, KEISUKE</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919022487" load-source="patent-office" sequence="3" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>WARASHINA, KEISUKE</last-name><address><street>c/o Thai Tabuchi Electric Co., Ltd. 88 Moo 5 Bangna-Trad Highway Tambol Bangsamuk Amphur Bangpakong</street><city>Chachoengsao 24180</city><country>TH</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919022490" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Tabuchi Electric Co., Ltd.</last-name><iid>101041263</iid><address><street>2-21, Miyahara 4-chome Yodogawa-ku</street><city>Osaka-shi, Osaka 532-0003</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919022489" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Jenkins, Peter David</last-name><iid>100026614</iid><address><street>Page White &amp; Farrer Bedford House John Street</street><city>London WC1N 2BF</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="JP-2007001198-W"><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>2007001198</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20071101</date><lang>JA</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2008053599-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2008053599</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20080508</date><lang>JA</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549923518" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549784521" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549869070" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549872141" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549801605" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549923519" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549784522" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549801606" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549801607" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549891700" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549869071" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549869072" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549784523" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549801608" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549923520" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549872146" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549784524" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549869073" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549801633" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549783705" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549923521" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549783706" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549783707" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549878021" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549923522" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549801634" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549783708" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549923523" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549923524" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549783713" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549784529" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549878026" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63960731" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading><heading id="h0002">(Field of the Invention)</heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to an electric terminal member and also to a coil assembly utilizing such terminal member.</p><heading id="h0003">(Description of the Prior Art)</heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">Electric wires largely employed in practice are generally made of copper. However, aluminum has a good electroconductivity and inexpensive as compared with copper and, accordingly, if aluminum is used for electric wires and/or coil windings, some advantages can be appreciated.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">Even though the electric wires or coil windings are made of aluminum, it is not infrequently required for those electric wires or coil windings to be electrically welded or soldered to existing electric terminal members or wires made of copper. However, by the reasons which will be described subsequently, soldering of the aluminum wires or coil windings to the copper based terminal member or wires has generally considered difficult to achieve.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">In the first place, when a soldering material of a copper-zinc system is used in connecting an aluminum wire electrically with a copper wire, electric erosion tends to occur in the aluminum wire due to the potential difference which will develop when the circuit including the aluminum wire connected with the copper wire is in use. Also, if a soldering material of a zinc-tin system is used for the same purpose, an oxide layer tends to be formed on the surface of the aluminum, which leads to a rejection of the soldering material used. Although a method has been contemplated, in which soldering is performed under a vacuum atmosphere in order to avoid formation of the oxide layer referred to above, this method is so costly as to render it remote from the practical utilization.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">Another method has been suggested, in which in order for a soldered connection to be achieved between the aluminum conductor and the copper wire,<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> a copper plated layer is continuously formed by means of a copper electroplating process on an outer surface of the zinc layer, which has been formed on the surface of the aluminum conductor by means of a zinc substitution process. See, for example, the Japanese Laid-open Patent Publication No. <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="JP2001271198A"><text>2001-271198, published October 2, 2001</text></patcit>, which discloses a copper coated aluminum wire. It has, however, been found that this technique requires the use of a complicated electroplating process.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">In addition, where in order to remove the oxide layer on the aluminum surface, a flux is applied to the aluminum surface prior to soldering by dipping, immersion of aluminum into a soldering bath causes an abrupt increase of the temperature, resulting in scattering of the applied flux. This leads to such a problem that no soldering can be achieved successfully.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007"><patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="US4581820A"><text>US4581820</text></patcit>, on which the pre-characterising portion of claim 1 is based, discloses an electrical connector system comprising a terminal for electrically connecting wires. <patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="US20030190846A"><text>US2003/0190846</text></patcit> discloses a folding blade electrical terminal.</p><heading id="h0004">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading><p id="p0008" num="0008">It is an object of the present invention to provide a coil assembly utilizing an electric terminal member that is easy to manufacture and effective to achieve a firm soldering with aluminum.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">In order to accomplish the foregoing and other objects, the present invention provides a coil assembly as defined in claim 1.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">According to the present invention, the flux applying surface of the wire connecting portion is defined on a rear side opposite to the wire holding surface of the same wire connecting portion and, on the other hand, the retaining hole defined in the<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> wire connecting portion has one end open on the first surface of the wire connecting portion, that is, the flux applying surface thereof. Accordingly, the flux, when applied to the flux applying surface, flows in part into the retaining hole and is therefore retained within the retaining hole, so that the flux will not scatter by the effect of an abrupt increase of temperature when the wire holding surface is subsequently immersed or dipped into the soldering bath.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">In view of the above, that part of the flux retained within the retaining hole in the wire connecting portion, after having been heated gradually by thermal conduction to melt or liquefy, contacts the lead line through the retaining hole and, accordingly, an outer surface of an end portion of the lead line, that is connected with the wire connecting portion of the terminal member, can be sufficiently activated enough to accomplish a firm soldering of that end portion of the lead line to the wire connecting portion of the terminal member.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">Also, in the terminal member of the coil assembly of present invention, the connector portion and the wire connecting portion are spaced apart from each other a distance corresponding to the length of the bridge portion and, accordingly, even when the wire connecting portion is immersed or dipped into the soldering bath, the connector portion can be protected from being deposited with soldering material. In addition, with the terminal member of the coil assembly in accordance with the present invention, there is no need to create a vacuum condition for the soldering to be accomplished thereunder nor to employ a wire plating process and, accordingly, manufacture can be facilitated.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">In one preferred embodiment of the present invention, the wire connecting portion of the terminal member may have a crimping pawl for holding the lead line<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> assuredly relative to the wire holding surface. The use of the crimping pawl is particularly advantageous in that the lead line can be assuredly held by the wire holding surface enough to prevent the lead line from being separated from the wire holding surface during the soldering taking place, thus facilitating the soldering work.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">In another preferred embodiment of the present invention, the use of the retaining hole in a plural number is desirable. The use of the plural retaining holes in the wire connecting portion is effective to avoid an undesirable effusion or spillage of the applied flux completely from the flux applying surface even when the terminal member is tilted. Accordingly, the soldering can be accomplished assuredly.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">The present invention is effective to provide an inexpensive and lightweight coil assembly utilizing the aluminum winding.</p><heading id="h0005">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading><p id="p0016" num="0016">In any event, the present invention will become more clearly understood from the following description of preferred embodiments thereof, when taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings. However, the embodiments and the drawings are given only for the purpose of illustration and explanation, and are not to be taken as limiting the scope of the present invention in any way whatsoever, which scope is to be determined by the appended claims. In the accompanying drawings, like reference numerals are used to denote like parts throughout the several views, and:
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is perspective view of a coil assembly in accordance with a preferred embodiment of the present invention;<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> is a perspective view, on a somewhat enlarged scale, showing one of the terminal members of the coil assembly of the present invention as viewed from bottom; and</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> is a schematic side view, on a somewhat enlarged scale, showing the terminal member shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0006">DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</heading><p id="p0017" num="0017">A preferred embodiment of the present invention will now be described in detail with particular reference to the accompanying drawings.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018"><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> illustrates in a perspective view a coil assembly 20 in accordance with the preferred embodiment of the present invention. The coil assembly 20 is of a kind that is utilized in an electric appliance such as, for example, an electric reactor and includes a coil 22 formed by winding an aluminum thin wire and a pair of terminal members 2 connected respectively with opposite ends of the aluminum thin wire used to form the coil 22. An electrically insulating sheet 17 such as a paper is interposed between the coil 22 and each of the terminal members 2, and lead lines 22a of the coil 22, drawn respectively from the opposite ends of the aluminum wire, are connected with respective wire holding surfaces 16, which form lower surfaces of the terminal members 2, as will be described in detail later.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">As best shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> in a perspective representation with one of the terminal members 2 shown as viewed from bottom, each of the terminal members 2 includes a generally elongated rectangular connector portion 4, a generally rectangular wire connecting portion 6 extending parallel to the connector portion 4 and a generally rectangular bridge portion 8 having its<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> opposite ends rigidly connected with, or otherwise formed integrally with, respective one ends of the connector portion 4 and wire connecting portion 6 so as to lie perpendicular to any one of the connector and wire connecting portions 4 and 6. The connector portion 4 and the wire connecting portion 6 are held parallel to each other and extend substantially orthogonal to the bridge portion 8, and have free ends at the respective other ends thereof. The free end of the connector portion 4 is used for connection with an extra electric appliance or component part through, for example, a circuit wire or a connector of that appliance or component part.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">The wire connecting portion 6, shown as positioned below the connector portion 4, has a pair of crimping pawls 10 formed integrally therewith so as to extend downwardly therefrom, as viewed in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, in a direction away from the connector portion 4 and also has two round retaining holes 12 both extending completely across the thickness of the connector portion 4. For the purpose of the present invention, the use of at least one retaining hole 12 is sufficient, but the use of the plural retaining holes 12 such as shown is desirable.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">Where the plural retaining holes 12 are employed such as in the embodiment now under discussion, those plural retaining holes 12 are preferably disposed in an area of the wire connecting portion 6 spaced a distance away from the bridge portion 8 and in alignment with the longitudinal axis of the wire connecting portion 6.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">Each of the terminal members 2 is prepared from a single elongated plate made of a copper alloy such as, for example, brass by the use of any known bending technique. Hence, the respective terminal member 2 is of one-piece construction including the connector portion 4, the wire connecting portion 6, the crimping pawls 10, and the bridge portion 8.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">As best shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>, showing the terminal member 2 as viewed from bottom, a lead line 22a drawn from a corresponding end of the coil winding is introduced onto a wire holding surface 16 of the wire connecting portion 6,<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> which is a surface thereof remote from the connector portion 4 (i.e., a lower surface when viewed in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, but an upper surface when viewed in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>), and is then fixed in position with the crimping pawls 10 bent inwardly relative to each other as indicated by the phantom lines in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>. In this way, the lead line 22a is immovably connected with the wire connecting portion 6 and is subsequently soldered thereto in a manner as will be described subsequently.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">It is to be noted that although the only one pair of the crimping pawls 10 have been shown and described as employed in the foregoing embodiment, another pair of similar crimping pawls may be employed as indicated by the phantom lines 10A in addition to the pair of the crimping pawls 10. In this case, the additional paired crimping pawls 10A are formed integrally with the wire connecting portion 6 in a manner similar to the paired crimping pawls 10, but positioned on one side of the paired crimping pawls 10 remote from the bridge portion 8 in a direction of extension of the lead sire 22a. In any event, the number of pairs of crimping pawls that can be employed may not be always limited to one, but two or more pairs thereof may be employed.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">Referring now to <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> showing one of the terminal members 2 on a somewhat enlarged scale, the manner of soldering by the use of a soldering machine will be described. The respective lead lines 22a, then clamped to the wire connecting portion 6 of each terminal member 2 in the manner described above, are soldered to such wire connecting portion 6 by means of a dip soldering technique. Before the dip soldering is effected, the coil 22 has to be mounted on a surface of the connector portion 4 of each terminal member 2 opposite to the wire connecting portion 6 with the electrically insulating sheet 17 sandwiched between the coil 22 and the connector portion 4, followed by firm positioning of the coil 22 relative to the connector portions 4 of the terminal members 2 by the use of any suitable fixing means such as, for example, a length of tape that is turned therearound.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></p><p id="p0026" num="0026">Thereafter, a flux best shown by 24 in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> is deposited on the flux applying surfaces 18 of the wire connecting portions 6 of the respective terminal members 2. As is well known to those skilled in the art, the flux 24 is utilized to activate the respective surfaces of the lead lines 22a drawn from the opposite ends of the coil winding forming the coil 22, so that a firm soldering of those lead lines 22a with the terminal members 2 can be achieved. This flux 24 is also deposited around the lead lines 22a, and the lead lines 22a are then clamped to the respective wire connecting portions 6 in contact with the wire holding surfaces 16 thereof by means of the paired crimping pawls 10.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">The assembly of the coil 22 connected with the terminal members 2 in the manner described above is mounted on a manipulator in a manner with the respective free ends of the connector portions 4 gripped by a manipulator hand 26 of the soldering machine, and the manipulator hand 26 is then moved downwardly, as viewed in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>, to allow the terminal members 2 to be immersed a first predetermined depth into a soldering bath 30. The first predetermined depth referred to above is so chosen that the surface of a soldering material in a melt phase relatively comes to a level L1 where substantially only the lead lines 22a, supported on the wire holding surfaces 16 of the wire connecting portions 6 of the terminal members 2, can be immersed in the soldering bath, but the fluxes 24 applied to the flux applying surfaces 18 has not yet immersed into the soldering bath 30 nor wetted with the soldering material within the soldering bath 30.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">In the condition, in which the assembly of the coil 22 with the terminal members 2 is immersed the first predetermined depth into the soldering bath 30 to allow the surface of the soldering material within the soldering bath 30 to come to the level L1 relative to the terminal members 2 with substantially only the lead lines 22a immersed completely within the soldering bath 30, the lead lines 22a are abruptly heated to, for example, 300°C in the instance now under discussion and, therefore, most of the fluxes 24 deposited on the lead lines 22a<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> are scattered. On the other hand, the fluxes 24 deposited on the flux applying surfaces 18 are not abruptly heated since they are clear off the surface level of the soldering material within the soldering bath 30, but are gradually heated by the effect of a thermal conduction from the lead lines 22a and the terminal members 2 and, therefore, an undesirable scattering of the fluxed 24 on the flux applying surfaces 18 can be suppressed.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">Further the manipulator hand 26 is moved downwardly to a portion where the surface of the soldering material within the soldering bath 30 relatively comes to a level L2 and halted. At this position the wire connecting portions 6 of the respective terminal members 2 are completely immersed within the soldering bath together with the lead lines 22a described above, but none of the connector portions 4 is immersed within the soldering bath 30. In other words, the assembly of the coil 22 with the terminal members 2 is immersed a second predetermined depth into the soldering bath 30 to such an extent that the surface of the soldering material within the soldering bath 30 comes to the level L2 relative to the terminal members 2. This second predetermined depth is, as a matter of course, greater than the first predetermined depth.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">In the condition of the assembly of the coil 22 with the terminal members 2 having been immersed the second predetermined depth into the soldering bath 30, the fluxes 24 heated to an optimum temperature acts on the lead lines 22a through the retaining hole 12 and as a result, the respective surfaces of the lead lines 22a are activated to facilitate soldering thereof to the respective wire connecting portions 6. The soldering completes when the terminal members 2 are immersed the second predetermined depth below the surface level L2 for 12 to 13 seconds.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">It is to be noted that the optimum temperature in the soldering bath 30 referred to above in the illustrated embodiment is preferably within the range of 250 to 500°C and, more preferably, within the range of 300 to 450°C.<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></p><p id="p0032" num="0032">According to the present invention hereinabove fully described, the flux 24 applied to the flux applying surface 18 in each of the terminal members 2 is retained in part within the retaining holes 12 and will not therefore scatter at once when heated to the elevated temperature, but will liquefy enough to flow through the holding holes 12 to contact the surface of the corresponding lead line 22a to thereby activate the surface of the lead line 22a sufficiently. Also, the provision of the plural holding holes 12 is particularly advantageous in that when the terminal member 2 tilts, the flux 24 can be effectively prevented from flowing downwards from the terminal member 2.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">The feature that the connector portion 4 and the wire connecting portion 6 are spaced a distance corresponding to the length of the bridge portion 8, connecting the connector portion 4 and the wire connecting portion 6 together, is particularly advantageous in that even when the wire connecting portion 6 is completely immersed within the soldering bath 30, it is possible to avoid a deposition of the soldering material on the connector portion 4 and/or the coil 22. Also, there is no need to create a vacuum atmosphere nor need to perform a plating process on the connecting wire or any other cable, resulting in facilitation of the soldering.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">Although the present invention has been fully described in connection with the preferred embodiments thereof with reference to the accompanying drawings which are used only for the purpose of illustration, those skilled in the art will readily conceive numerous changes and modifications within the framework of obviousness upon the reading of the specification herein presented of the present invention.<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --></p><p id="p0035" num="0035">Accordingly, such changes and modifications are, unless they depart from the scope of the present invention as delivered from the claims annexed hereto, to be construed as included therein.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56984930" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Spulenanordnung (20), umfassend ein elektrisches Endelement (2) zur Verbindung mit einem elektrischen Draht, und eine Spule (22) mit einer Aluminiumwicklung und einer Zuleitung (22a), die aus der Aluminiumwicklung gezogen ist; wobei der elektrische Endverbinder (2) Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>einen Verbindungsabschnitt (4);</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Drahtverbindungsabschnitt (6), der vom Verbindungsabschnitt (4) beabstandet ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Brückenabschnitt (8), der sich zwischen einem Ende des Verbindungsabschnitts (4) und einem Ende des Drahtverbindungsabschnitts (6) in einer Richtung erstreckt, die quer zu jedem des Verbindungs- und des Drahtverbindungsabschnitts (4, 6) liegt, und zur Verbindung des Verbindungsabschnitts (4) mit dem Drahtverbindungsabschnitt (6) dient, wobei der Drahtverbindungsabschnitt (6) des Endelements (2) mit der Zuleitung (22a) verbunden ist,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei die Spulenanordnung (20) <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet ist, dass</b> der Drahtverbindungsabschnitt (6) ein Rückhalteloch (12) aufweist, das darin derart definiert ist, dass es sich vollständig durch die Dicke des Drahtverbindungsabschnitts (6) erstreckt und auch eine Stromanlagefläche (18) aufweist, um einen Strom zu tragen, der darauf angelegt werden soll, und eine Drahthaltefläche (16) gegenüber der Stromanlagefläche (18), um die Zuleitung (22a), die damit verbunden ist, zu tragen, wobei die Stromanlagefläche (18) auf den Verbindungsabschnitt (4) gerichtet ist, während die Drahthaltefläche (16) in eine Richtung weg vom Verbindungsabschnitt (4) zeigt und der Drahtverbindungsabschnitt (6) parallel zum Verbindungsabschnitt (4) liegt.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Spulenanordnung (20) nach Anspruch 1, wobei der Drahtverbindungsabschnitt (6) eine Quetschklinke (10) aufweist, um die Zuleitung (22a) an die Drahthaltefläche (16) zu klemmen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Spulenanordnung (20) nach Anspruch 1, wobei das Rückhalteloch<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> (12) in einer mehrfachen Ausführung verwendet wird.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56984931" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A coil assembly (20) comprising an electric terminal member (2) for connection with an electric wire, and a coil (22) having an aluminum winding and a lead line (22a) drawn from the aluminum winding; the electric terminal connector (2) comprising:
<claim-text>a connector portion (4);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a wire connecting portion (6) spaced apart from the connector portion (4); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a bridge portion (8) extending between one end of the connector portion (4) and one end of the wire connecting portion (6) in a direction transverse to any one of the connector and wire connecting portions (4,6), and for connecting the connector portion (4) with the wire connecting portion (6), the terminal member (2) having the wire connecting portion (6) connected with the lead line (22a);</claim-text>
<claim-text>the coil assembly (20) being <b>characterized by</b> the wire connecting portion (6) having a retaining hole (12) defined therein so as to extend completely through the thickness of the wire connecting portion (6) and also having a flux applying surface (18) for supporting a flux to be applied thereto and a wire holding surface (16) opposite to the flux applying surface (18) for supporting the lead line (22a) connected thereto, the flux applying surface (18) facing towards the connector portion (4) whereas the wire holding surface (16) faces in a direction away from the connector portion (4), and the wire connecting portion (6) lying parallel to the connector portion (4).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The coil assembly (20) as claimed in Claim 1, in which the wire connecting portion (6) has a crimping pawl (10) for clamping the lead line (22a) to the wire holding surface (16).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The coil assembly (20) as claimed in Claim 1, in which the retaining hole (12) is employed in a plural number.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56984932" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Ensemble de bobine (20) comprenant un élément de borne électrique (2) pour une connexion à un fil électrique, et une bobine (22) comportant un enroulement en aluminium et une ligne conductrice (22a) tirée de l'enroulement en aluminium ; le connecteur de borne électrique (2) comprenant:
<claim-text>une partie de connecteur (4) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une partie de connexion de fil (6) espacée de la partie de connecteur (4); et</claim-text>
<claim-text>une partie de pont (8) s'étendant entre une extrémité de la partie de connecteur (4) et une extrémité de la partie de connexion de fil (6) dans une direction transversale à l'une quelconque des parties de connecteur et de connexion de fil (4, 6), et pour connecter la partie de connecteur (4) à la partie de connexion de fil (6), l'élément de borne (2) ayant la partie de connexion de fil (6) connectée à la ligne conductrice (22a) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'ensemble de bobine (20) étant <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> la partie de connexion de fil (6) comporte un trou de retenue (12) défini dans celle-ci de manière à s'étendre complètement à travers l'épaisseur de la partie de connexion de fil (6) et comporte également une surface d'application de flux (18) pour supporter un flux à appliquer à celle-ci et une surface de maintien de fil (16) opposée à la surface d'application de flux (18) pour supporter la ligne conductrice (22a) connectée à celle-ci, la surface d'application de flux (18) étant orientée vers la partie de connecteur (4) tandis que la surface de maintien de fil (16) est orientée dans une direction à l'opposé de la partie de connecteur (4), et la partie de connexion de fil (6) étant parallèle à la partie de connecteur (4).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Ensemble de bobine (20) selon la revendication 1, dans lequel la partie de connexion de fil (6) comporte une languette de sertissage (10) pour serrer la ligne conductrice (22a) sur la surface de maintien de fil (16).<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Ensemble de bobine (20) selon la revendication 1, dans lequel il y a plusieurs trous de retenue (12).</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16672003" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="146" he="170" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="143" he="172" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="155" he="186" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
