<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2371564-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2371564" kind="B1" date="20140101" family-id="44280967" file-reference-id="315065" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146552827" ucid="EP-2371564-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2371564</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-11159994-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154826750" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>11159994</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20110328</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140450988" ucid="JP-2010081328-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>JP</country><doc-number>2010081328</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20100331</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130813</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988127397" load-source="docdb">B41J  13/00        20060101ALI20120301BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988137075" load-source="docdb">B41J  11/00        20060101AFI20120301BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2087989263" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B41J  13/0045      20130101 LI20150305BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2087989568" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B41J  11/006       20130101 FI20150305BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132190965" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Aufzeichnungsvorrichtung</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132190966" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Recording apparatus</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132190967" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Appareil d'enregistrement</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918164947" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>BROTHER IND LTD</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918142533" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>BROTHER KOGYO KABUSHIKI KAISHA</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918160868" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>SAKANO YUJI</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918132756" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>SAKANO, YUJI</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918995596" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>SAKANO, YUJI</last-name><address><street>c/o BROTHER KOGYO KABUSHIKI KAISHA, Intellectual Property Department 1-1-1, Kawagishi, Mizuho-ku</street><city>Nagoya-shi, Aichi 467-8562</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918995597" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Brother Kogyo Kabushiki Kaisha</last-name><iid>100092003</iid><address><street>15-1 Naeshiro-cho, Mizuho-ku</street><city>Nagoya-shi, Aichi-ken 467-8561</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918995598" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Kuhnen &amp; Wacker</last-name><iid>101158360</iid><address><street>Patent- und Rechtsanwaltsbüro Prinz-Ludwig-Strasse 40A</street><city>85354 Freising</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548879546" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS548851086" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS548879547" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS548958361" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS548959247" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS548879548" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS548967538" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS548825318" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548879549" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS548879550" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS548961962" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS548958362" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS548958363" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548825319" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548879551" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS548825320" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS548967539" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS548959248" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS548879552" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS548958364" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS548879553" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS548825321" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS548851087" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS548958365" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS548958366" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS548851088" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS548851089" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS548851090" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS548959249" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS548851091" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS548961963" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS548970161" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS548961964" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS548851092" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS548825322" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS548959258" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS548959259" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS548879554" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63956953" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION</heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present application claims the priority from Japanese Patent Application No. <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="JP2010081328A"><text>2010-081328 filed March 31, 2010</text></patcit>.</p><heading id="h0002">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading><heading id="h0003">1. Field of the Invention</heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">The present invention relates to a recording apparatus including a recording unit that records an image on a recording medium and a conveying unit that conveys the recording medium to the recording unit.</p><heading id="h0004">2. Description of the Related Art</heading><p id="p0003" num="0003">A known recording apparatus having a duplex printing function accommodates a recording unit, a conveying unit, a return path unit, a paper cassette, etc, in a casing. In single-sided printing, paper stacked in the paper cassette is conveyed to the recording unit by the conveying unit, and an image is printed on one side of the paper by the recording unit. In duplex printing, paper on which an image is recorded by the recording unit is returned from the upstream side of the recording unit to the conveying unit through the return path and is conveyed again to the<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> recording unit, and an image is recorded also on the other side. If a paper jam occurs in a region between the recording unit and the conveying unit, the jammed paper was removed by hand. However, the manual work was not easy because the region is not wide enough for the hand to be inserted.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">Thus, various technologies for simplifying jam handling have been proposed. For example, Japanese Unexamined Patent Application Publication No. <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="JP10333384A"><text>10-333384</text></patcit> (Paragraph [0028]) discloses a technology for ensuring a workspace for jam handling between the recording unit and the conveying unit by inclining the conveying unit in the casing. However, this technology needs a space in the casing for inclining the conveying unit, which poses the problem of increasing the size of the casing.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">Thus, as disclosed in Japanese Unexamined Patent Application Publication No. <patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="JP10091053A"><text>10-91053</text></patcit> (<figref idrefs="f0008">Figs. 8</figref> and 10), the conveying unit is drawn out of the casing together with paper placed on the holding surface thereof.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">Since the technology described above needs no space in the casing for the conveying unit to be inclined, an increase in the size of the casing may be prevented. However, when the conveying unit is drawn out of the casing, paper placed on the holding surface is sometimes caught in the recording unit or the like to be left in the casing,<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> thus posing the problem of difficulty in removing the paper.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">The document <patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="JP2009241355A"><text>JP 2009 241355 A</text></patcit> discloses a recording apparatus comprising: a recording unit, a conveying unit disposed below the recording unit and configured to convey the recording medium to a position at which recording is performed by the recording unit, a return path unit configured to return the recording medium from the upstream side of the recording unit to the conveying unit to record an image again on the recording medium; side walls of the apparatus casing comprise a drawing port through which the conveying unit is out and an opening facing in a direction perpendicular to the drawing direction thereof.</p><heading id="h0005">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading><p id="p0008" num="0008">The present invention is made in view of the background art described above. Accordingly, it is an object of the present invention to provide a recording apparatus in which a jammed recording medium may be removed while an increase in the size of the casing is prevented, and in which even if a recording medium is left in the casing, the recording medium may easily be removed.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">According to one embodiment described herein, a recording apparatus includes a recording unit configured to record an image on a recording medium. The recording apparatus includes a conveying unit disposed below the recording unit and configured to convey the recording medium to a position at which recording is performed by the recording unit. The recording apparatus includes a return path unit configured to return the recording medium from the upstream side of the recording unit to the conveying unit to record an image again on the recording medium. The recording apparatus includes a casing which accommodates the recording unit, the conveying unit, and the return path unit. The return path unit is disposed below the conveying unit and includes a horizontal conveying path including an upper portion and a lower portion. Side walls of the casing<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> include a drawing port through which the conveying unit and at least the upper portion of the horizontal conveying path are drawn out, and an opening facing in a direction perpendicular to the drawing direction thereof. The inner edge of the lower end of the opening is positioned the same or lower in height than the uppermost portion of the horizontal conveying path in the return path unit.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">With this configuration, since a jammed recording medium is taken out of the casing together with the conveying unit etc., the recording medium may easily be removed at the outside of the casing. Furthermore, the opening is formed to face in the direction perpendicular to the drawing direction of the conveying unit etc.<br/>
Accordingly, even if a recording medium is left in the casing when the conveying unit etc. are drawn out, the recording medium may easily be removed by inserting a hand into the casing through the opening.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">Since at least the upper portion of the horizontal conveying path is drawn out together with the conveying unit, and since the inner edge of the lower end of the opening is positioned the same or lower in height than the uppermost portion of the horizontal conveying path, a wide space into which the hand is inserted may be provided in the casing, thus allowing the recording medium left in the casing to be effectively removed.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></p><p id="p0012" num="0012">Thus, a jammed recording medium may easily be removed while preventing an increase in the size of the casing. Furthermore, even if the recording medium is left in the casing, the recording medium may easily be removed by inserting a hand into the casing through the opening.</p><heading id="h0006">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading><p id="p0013" num="0013"><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is a perspective view illustrating the configuration of a recording apparatus according to an embodiment.
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> is a cross-sectional view taken along line II-II in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> is a cross-sectional view taken along line III-III in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4A</figref> is a front view illustrating a state in which the whole of a horizontal conveying path is drawn out together with a conveying unit.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4B</figref> is a front view illustrating a state in which only the upper portion of the horizontal conveying path is drawn out together with the conveying unit.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 5A</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a state in which a cover provided on an opening is locked.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 5B</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a state in which the cover is unlocked.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 6</figref> is a block diagram illustrating the<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> configuration of the recording apparatus according to the embodiment.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 7</figref> is a flowchart illustrating the jam handling operation of the recording apparatus according to the embodiment.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 8A</figref> is a cross-sectional view illustrating the process of opening a drawing port.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 8B</figref> is a cross-sectional view illustrating the process of drawing out the whole horizontal conveying path together with the conveying unit.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 8C</figref> is a front view illustrating the process of removing paper through the opening.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0009">Fig. 9</figref> is a cross-sectional view illustrating, of the jam handling method of the recording apparatus according to the embodiment, the process of drawing only the upper portion of the horizontal conveying path together with the conveying unit.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0007">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENTS</heading><p id="p0014" num="0014">Recording apparatuses according to embodiments of the present invention will be described hereinbelow with reference to the drawings. Although the following embodiments use paper P as a "recording medium", a plastic sheet and so on may be used instead of the paper P.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p><heading id="h0008">[Overall Configuration of Recording Apparatus]</heading><p id="p0015" num="0015">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0001 f0002 f0003">Figs. 1 to 3</figref>, the recording apparatus 10 includes a casing 12. The casing 12 accommodates a recording head unit 14 that records an image on paper P; a conveying unit 16 that conveys the paper P to a position at which recording is performed in the recording head unit 14; a return path unit 18 that returns the paper P on which the image is recorded by the recording head unit 14 to the conveying unit 16 from the upstream side of the recording head unit 14; and a paper cassette 20 that accommodates the paper P, in this order from the top to the bottom.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>, the casing 12 further accommodates a paper feeding unit 22 that supplies the paper P from the paper cassette 20 to the conveying unit 16; a paper output unit 24 that discharges the paper P from the conveying unit 16 onto the upper surface (top plate 30f) of the casing 12; a nip unit 26; and a control unit 28 that performs various controls on jam handling.</p><heading id="h0009">[Configuration of Casing]</heading><p id="p0017" num="0017">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0001 f0002 f0003">Figs. 1 to 3</figref>, the casing 12 has a substantially rectangular parallelepiped main body 30 and a substantially rectangular parallelepiped protruding portion 32 protruding upward from the upper surface of the main body 30.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></p><p id="p0018" num="0018">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, the main body 30 includes a bottom plate 30a that is substantially rectangular in plan view, four side walls 30b to 30e erecting from the peripheral edge of the bottom plate 30a, and a top plate 30f. The top plate 30f that constitutes the upper surface of the casing 12 functions as a paper output tray that receives the paper P discharged from the paper output unit 24.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>, the side wall 30d that constitutes the left side of the casing 12 has a first drawing port 34 for drawing the conveying unit 16 and at least the upper portion 90a of a horizontal conveying path 90, to be described later, to the outside. The lower inner edge of the first drawing port 34 is fitted with a first cover 36 that opens and closes the first drawing port 34 using a first hinge 38. Referring to <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>, the side wall 30b that constitutes the front face of the casing 12 has an opening 40 through which a hand is inserted into the casing 12 and a second drawing port 42 through which the paper cassette 20 is to be drawn out, which are arranged vertically. The lower inner edge of the opening 40 is fitted with a second cover 44 that opens and closes the opening 40 using a second hinge 46. The lower inner edge of the second drawing port 42 is fitted with a third cover 48 that opens and closes the second drawing port 42 using a third hinge 50. The opening 40 and the second drawing port<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> 42 may be formed as one continuous opening.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0002">Figs. 2</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0003">3</figref>, the main body 30 has therein a plate-like receiving member 52 that receives the paper P that has fallen from the conveying unit 16, ink that has dropped from the recording head unit 14, and so on. A region above the receiving member 52 functions as an upper region U1 that accommodates the recording head unit 14, the conveying unit 16, and the return path unit 18. A region below the receiving member 52 functions as a lower region U2 that accommodates the paper cassette 20. The upper region U1 is provided with a guide rail 54 that guides the conveying unit 16 and at least the upper portion 90a of the horizontal conveying path 90 in parallel to a paper-P conveying direction (hereinafter referred to as a "conveying direction X"). Furthermore, referring to <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>, the inner surface of the second cover 44 has a substantially L-shaped first locking portion 56 that locks the second cover 44 in a closed state. Referring to <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>, a cover sensor 58 that senses whether the first cover 36 has opened is disposed in the vicinity of the first drawing port 34 in the casing 12.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>, the protruding portion 32 has a side wall 32a that erects from the edge of the top plate 30f functioning as the paper output tray. The side wall 32a has a long-hole paper output port 59, extending in parallel to the top plate 30f, for outputting the paper P conveyed in<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> the paper output unit 24 onto the upper surface (top plate 30f) of the casing 12.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">In the foregoing description, of directions parallel to the conveying direction X, a direction in which the conveying unit 16 is drawn out is referred to as a "drawing direction Y".</p><heading id="h0010">[Recording Head Unit]</heading><p id="p0023" num="0023">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0001">Figs. 1</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0003">3</figref>, the recording head unit 14 is a unit that records an image on the paper P on the basis of image data given from an image input unit (not shown), such as a personal computer, and includes a plurality of (in this embodiment, four) ink cartridges 60a to 60d (see <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>) that accommodate different colors (in this embodiment, four colors of cyan, yellow, magenta, and black) of ink; a plurality of (in this embodiment, four) inkjet recording heads 62a to 62d that eject the ink supplied from the ink cartridges 60a to 60d toward the paper P; and ink tubes (not shown) through which the ink in the ink cartridges 60a to 60d is supplied to the inkjet recording heads 62a to 62d, respectively.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, the individual inkjet recording heads 62a to 62d are line recording heads extending in a direction perpendicular to the conveying direction X. Referring to <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>, the inkjet recording<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> heads 62a to 62d have ejecting surfaces 64a to 64d each having a plurality of ink ejection ports (not shown), respectively. The inkjet recording heads 62a to 62d are arranged in parallel to the conveying direction X to form "columns" in such a manner that the ejecting surfaces 64a to 64d are horizontal.</p><heading id="h0011">[Conveying Unit]</heading><p id="p0025" num="0025">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>, the conveying unit 16 includes two rollers 70a and 70b arranged in parallel to each other at a certain interval therebetween in a direction parallel to the conveying direction X; a conveying belt 72 stretched in a ring shape between the two rollers 70a and 70b; a holder 74 (see <figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 5A and 5B</figref>) that holds them; a paper feed path 76 that guides the paper P accommodated in the paper cassette 20 to the conveying belt 72; a pair of conveying rollers 78a and 78b; a pair of belt upstream rollers 80a and 80b; and a belt pinch roller 82.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">The rollers 70a and 70b are columnar members that rotatably support the conveying belt 72. An output shaft of a motor (not shown) disposed in the casing 12 is detachably connected to at least one of the rotation shafts of the rollers 70a and 70b via a coupling. Specifically, when the conveying unit 16 is positioned at a position in the casing 12 at which a recording operation is executed (hereinafter<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> referred to as a "recording position E"), at least one of the rotation shafts of the rollers 70a and 70b is connected to the output shaft of the motor, and when the conveying unit 16 is drawn out of the casing 12, the rotation shaft is disconnected from the output shaft of the motor.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">The conveying belt 72 is an endless belt having a holding surface 72a that holds the paper P. In the casing 12, the holding surface 72a facing upward is disposed horizontally to oppose the ejecting surfaces 64a to 64d. Accordingly, when the conveying belt 72 is rotated by the motor, the paper P placed on the holding surface 72a is conveyed horizontally in sequence to positions opposing the ejecting surfaces 64a to 64d (that is, positions at which recording is performed).</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4A</figref>, the holder 74 is a support member that supports the rollers 70a and 70b and the conveying belt 72 while holding the mutual positional relationship thereof and includes a box-shaped holder main body 84 having an opening (not shown) at the top. The paper feed path 76, the pair of conveying rollers 78a and 78b, and the lower belt upstream roller 80b are mounted to the holder main body 84.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0002">Figs. 2</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0004">4A</figref>, two guide rollers 86a and 86b to be fitted in a long hole 54a formed in the guide rail 54 are disposed, with a certain distance therebetween<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> in a direction perpendicular to the drawing direction Y, at one side 84a and the other side 84b of the holder main body 84 in the direction parallel to the drawing direction Y. Furthermore, referring to <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>, a substantially L-shaped second locking portion 88, which is locked to the first locking portion 56 when the conveying unit 16 is positioned at the recording position E in the casing 12, is disposed at the side 84a of the holder main body 84.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0002">Figs. 2</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0003">3</figref>, the conveying direction X and the drawing direction Y in this embodiment are parallel to the horizontal surface, and the direction in which the long hole 54a extends is also parallel to the horizontal surface. Accordingly, since the two guide rollers 86a and 86b are fitted in the long hole 54a of the guide rail 54, the recording head unit 14 can be moved along the long hole 54a while holding the ejecting surfaces 64a to 64d horizontally.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 5A</figref>, when the conveying unit 16 is positioned at the recording position E, a locking piece 56b extending upward from a leg 56a of the first locking portion 56 and a locking piece 88b extending downward from a leg 88a of the second locking portion 88 can come into engagement, thereby inhibiting the opening action of the second cover 44 (see <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>) that closes the opening 40. On the other hand, referring to <figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 5B</figref>, when the conveying<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> unit 16 is drawn from the recording position E, the engagement of the locking piece 56b and the locking piece 88b is released to allow the opening action of the second cover 44 (see <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>). In other words, in this embodiment, the first locking portion 56 and the second locking portion 88 function as the "locking unit" that locks the second cover 44 in a closed state, and the mechanism that draws out the conveying unit 16 (including the guide rail 54) functions as an "unlocking mechanism" that releases the locking state.</p><heading id="h0012">[Return Path Unit]</heading><p id="p0032" num="0032">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>, the return path unit 18 is a unit for returning the paper P on which an image is recorded by the recording head unit 14 from the upstream side of the recording head unit 14 to the conveying unit 16 to record an image again on the paper P. The return path unit 18 is disposed below the conveying unit 16. The return path unit 18 includes the horizontal conveying path 90 that conveys the paper P in the horizontal direction; a connecting path 94 that connects a paper output path 92 of the paper output unit 24 and the horizontal conveying path 90; reversing rollers 96a and 96b provided at the junction of the paper output path 92 and the connecting path 94; a support unit 98 (see. <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4A and 4B</figref>) that supports the horizontal conveying<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> path 90; and a fixing portion 100 that fixes the horizontal conveying path 90.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4A</figref>, the horizontal conveying path 90 is defined by the upper portion 90a and a lower portion 90b. The upper portion 90a has an upper wall 102a that constitutes the upper surface of a horizontal path 102 through which the paper P is passed and a plurality of (in this embodiment, three) upper conveying rollers 104a, 106a, and 108a disposed with a certain distance therebetween in a direction parallel to the conveying direction X so as to be in contact with the upper surface of the paper P positioned in the horizontal path 102. On the other hand, the lower portion 90b has a lower wall 102b that constitutes the lower surface of the horizontal path 102 and lower conveying rollers 104b, 106b, and 108b disposed so as to oppose the upper conveying rollers 104a, 106a, and 108a, respectively, and to be in contact with the lower surface of the paper P positioned in the horizontal path 102.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">The upper wall 102a of the upper portion 90a is formed so as to continue to the paper feed path 76 and to be separable from the connecting path 94. On the other hand, the lower wall 102b of the lower portion 90b is formed so as to be separable from both the paper feed path 76 and the connecting path 94. Accordingly, this embodiment allows a choice between a form, referring to <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4A</figref>, in which both<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> the upper portion 90a and the lower portion 90b are drawn out of the casing 12 together with the conveying unit 16 (hereinafter referred to as a "first form" and a form, referring to <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4B</figref>, in which only the upper portion 90a is drawn out of the casing 12 together with the conveying unit 16 (hereinafter referred to as a "second form").</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0004">Figs. 4A and 4B</figref>, the support unit 98 is integrally disposed at the holder 74 of the conveying unit 16. In the "first form", the support unit 98 supports both the upper portion 90a and the lower portion 90b and, in the "second form", supports only the upper portion 90. The support unit 98 has a first support portion 98a that fixedly supports the upper portion 90a and a second support portion 98b that detachably supports the lower portion 90b.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>, the fixing portion 100 is integrally disposed at the receiving member 52. In the "first form", the fixing portion 100 releases the fixed state of the lower portion 90b and, in the "second form", fixes the lower portion 90b in the casing 12. The fixing portion 100 has a support mechanism (not shown) that detachably supports the lower portion 90b. The support unit 98 and the fixing portion 100 of this embodiment are configured to be driven by a solenoid or the like and are electrically connected to the control unit 28 through an electrical wire.<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></p><p id="p0037" num="0037">In the state in which the conveying unit 16 and the return path unit 18 are accommodated in the casing 12, referring to <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>, the inner edge of the lower end of the opening 40 is positioned lower than the uppermost portion of the horizontal conveying path 90 of the return path unit 18, and the inner edge of the upper end of the opening 40 is positioned higher than the lowermost portion of the conveying unit 16. In this embodiment, since the upper portion 90a of the horizontal conveying path 90 has the upper conveying rollers 104a, 106a, and 108a, and the conveying unit 16 has the ring-shaped conveying belt 72, the inner edge of the lower end of the opening 40 is positioned the same or lower in height than the uppermost portions of the upper conveying rollers 104a, 106a, and 108a, and the inner edge of the upper end of the opening 40 is positioned higher than the holding surface 72a, facing downward, of the conveying belt 72. This widens the inner space of the casing 12 into which the hand is to be inserted, thus allowing the paper P left in the casing 12 to be easily taken out of the opening 40. Furthermore, in this embodiment, the inner edge of the upper end of the opening 40 is positioned lower than the ejecting surfaces 64a to 64d, thus preventing a hand from touching the ejecting surfaces 64a to 64d.<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --></p><heading id="h0013">[Paper Cassette]</heading><p id="p0038" num="0038">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>, the paper cassette 20 includes a box-shaped cassette main body 110 having an opening 110a in the upper surface; a paper receiving portion 112 that is disposed at the bottom of the cassette main body 110 and that is lifted up by a coil spring or the like (not shown); a positioning portion 114 that is secured in the cassette main body 110 and that is in contact with the side edge of the paper P adjacent to the opening 40 to define the position of the paper P; and a guide 116 that is disposed so as to be adjustable in the direction perpendicular to the conveying direction X and that guides the side edge of the paper P opposite the opening 40. Accordingly, in the paper cassette 20, the side edge of the paper P adjacent to the opening 40 is positioned at a predetermined reference position F by the positioning portion 114 irrespective of the size of the paper P. When the paper P is supplied to the conveying unit 16 through the paper feeding unit 22, the paper P is positioned along the side edge of the holding surface 72a adjacent to the opening 40.</p><heading id="h0014">[Configurations of Paper Feeding Unit and Paper Output Unit]</heading><p id="p0039" num="0039">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>, the paper feeding unit 22 supplies the paper P accommodated in the paper cassette 20 to the paper feed path 76 of the conveying unit 16. The paper feeding<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> unit 22 includes a pickup roller 120, a paper feed roller 122, and a separation roller 124. When the conveying unit 16 is positioned at the recording position E in the casing 12, an upstream end 76a of the paper feed path 76 is positioned downstream of the paper feed roller 122 and the separation roller 124, thus allowing the paper P to be conveyed to the conveying unit 16. On the other hand, the paper output unit 24 includes a paper output path 92 and paper eject rollers 130a and 130b. A downstream end of the paper output path 92 is communicated with the paper output port 59.</p><heading id="h0015">[Nip Unit]</heading><p id="p0040" num="0040">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>, the nip unit 26 nips the paper P between the belt upstream rollers 80a and 80b and between the belt pinch roller 82 and the conveying belt 72. The nip unit 26 includes a main body 140 that holds the belt upstream roller 80a and the belt pinch roller 82; a rotation shaft 142 that rotatably supports the main body 140; and a solenoid 144 that rotates the main body 140. An output portion 144a of the solenoid 144 is connected to an end 140a of the main body 140.</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">When the nip unit 26 is driven, the end 140a of the main body 140 is raised together with the output portion 144a of the solenoid 144 to rotate the main body 140 about<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> the rotation shaft 142. Thus, the belt upstream roller 80a and the belt pinch roller 82 held by the main body 140 are moved downward to nip the paper P.</p><heading id="h0016">[Control Unit etc.]</heading><p id="p0042" num="0042">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 6</figref>, the control unit 28 executes various controls on jam handling; specifically, the control unit 28 includes a central processing unit (CPU) that executes various arithmetic operations and storage units (ROM and RAM) that store various kinds of data. The control unit 28 is connected to first jam sensors 150a to 150c, second jam sensors 152a to 152d, the cover sensor 58, a display device 154, a light-emitting unit 156, the nip unit 26, the support unit 98, and the fixing portion 100.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>, the first jam sensors 150a to 150c detect the occurrence of a jam in the conveying unit 16. Specifically, the first sensors 150a to 150c are paper sensors opposed to the holding surface 72a facing upward.<br/>
On the other hand, the second jam sensors 152a to 152d detect the occurrence of a jam in the horizontal conveying path 90. Specifically, the second jam sensors 152a to 152d are paper sensors opposed to the horizontal path 102.</p><p id="p0044" num="0044">The individual first jam sensors 150a to 150c and second jam sensors 152a to 152d are configured to be able to detect the presence or absence of the paper P in their<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> detection regions. Accordingly, if the time from the time at which one jam sensor detects the paper P until the time at which the jam sensor no longer detects the paper P is excessively long, the control unit 28 can determine that a jam has occurred in the detection region of the jam sensor. If the time from the time at which one upstream jam sensor detects the paper P until the time at which a downstream jam sensor detects the paper P is excessively long, the control unit 28 can determine that a jam has occurred in the detection regions of the jam sensors. A method for detecting the occurrence of a jam is not particularly limited and may be selected from known arts.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045">The control unit 28 outputs a "first signal" indicating that "both the upper portion 90a and the lower portion 90b should be drawn out together with the conveying unit 1", when the the first jam sensors 150a to 150c detect "a jam in the "conveying unit 16". The control unit 28 outputs a "second signal" indicating that "only the upper portion 90a should be drawn out together with the conveying unit 16", when the second jam sensors 152a to 152d detect "a jam in the horizontal conveying path 90". The display device 154, the light-emitting unit 156, the support unit 98, and the fixing portion 100 are controlled on the basis of the "first signal" and the "second signal" output from the control unit 28.<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --></p><p id="p0046" num="0046">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, the display device 154 includes a display panel 154a disposed on the upper surface of the casing 12. The display device 154 is configured, when the "first signal" is input, to output an image indicating that "both the upper portion 90a and the lower portion 90b should be drawn out together with the conveying unit 16" to the display panel 154a, and when the "second signal" is input, to output an image indicating that "only the upper portion 90a should be drawn out together with the conveying unit 16" to the display panel 154a.</p><p id="p0047" num="0047">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, the light-emitting unit 156 includes lamps 156a and 156b that are disposed on the upper surface of the casing 12 and that emit different colors of light. The light-emitting unit 156 is configured, when the "first signal" is input, to output light (for example, red light) indicating that "both the upper portion 90a and the lower portion 90b should be drawn out together with the conveying unit 16" from the lamp 156a, and when the "second signal" is input, to output light (for example, blue light) indicating that "only the upper portion 90a should be drawn out together with the conveying unit 16" from the lamp 156b.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0004">Figs. 4A and 4B</figref>, the support unit 98 is configured, when the "first signal" is input, to support both the upper portion 90a and the lower portion 90b, and when the "second signal" is input, to support only the upper<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> portion 90a.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0008">Figs. 8A to 8C</figref>, the fixing portion 100 is configured, when the "first signal" is input, to release the fixed state of the lower portion 90b, and when the "second signal" is input, to fix the lower portion 90b.</p><heading id="h0017">[Recording Operation]</heading><p id="p0050" num="0050">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>, when an image is to be recorded on one side of the paper P using the recording apparatus 10, the conveying unit 16 is positioned at the recording position E, the paper P is accommodated in the paper cassette 20, and the position of the paper P is defined by the positioning portion 114 (see <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>).</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">When a recording operation is started, the paper P accommodated in the paper cassette 20 is fed to the holding surface 72a of the conveying unit 16 through the paper feed path 76 and is conveyed to positions opposing the ejecting surfaces 64a to 64d by the conveying belt 72. Since ink is ejected from the plurality of ink ejection ports (not shown), an image is recorded on the surface of the paper P. The paper P on which the image is recorded is discharged onto the top plate 30f through the paper output path 92. Furthermore, when an image is to be recorded also on the other side of the paper P, the paper P on which the image is recorded by the recording head unit 14 is conveyed from the<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --> paper output path 92 to the connecting path 94 of the return path unit 18 by rotating the reversing rollers 96a and 96b in the opposite direction and is returned from the upstream side of the recording head unit 14 to the conveying unit 16 through the horizontal conveying path 90.</p><heading id="h0018">[Jam Handling Operation]</heading><p id="p0052" num="0052">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 7</figref>, when the jam detecting operation of the control unit 28 is started, first, in step S1, the jam detecting operation of the first jam sensors 150a to 150c, the second jam sensors 152a to 152d, and the control unit 28 is executed. In step S3, it is determined whether the second jam sensors 152a to 152d etc. have detected "a jam in the horizontal conveying path 90". If it is determined to be "YES", then the "second signal" is output from the control unit 28 in step S5. In contrast, if it is determined to be "NO", then it is determined in step S7 whether the first jam sensors 150a to 150c etc. have detected "a jam in the conveying unit 16". If it is determined to be "YES", then the "first signal" is output from the control unit 28 in step S9.</p><p id="p0053" num="0053">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 8A</figref>, when it is seen using the display device 154 and the light-emitting unit 156 that the "first signal" was output in step S9, the user first brings down the first cover 36 that closes the first drawing port<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --> 34 to open the first drawing port 34. Then, it is detected by the cover sensor 58 that the first cover 36 is opened, and together with it, current supply to the nip unit 26 is stopped by the control unit 28, such that the nip unit 26 releases the nip of the paper P. At that time, the support unit 98 and the fixing portion 100 are driven in response to the "first signal", such that both the upper portion 90a and the lower portion 90b are supported by the support unit 98, and the fixed state of the lower portion 90b is released by the fixing portion 100.</p><p id="p0054" num="0054">Subsequently, referring to <figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 8B</figref>, the conveying unit 16 and the horizontal conveying path 90 (the upper portion 90a and the lower portion 90b) are drawn out of the casing 12 through the first drawing port 34. If the paper P is placed on the holding surface 72a of the conveying unit 16, the paper P is removed at the outside of the casing 12. Referring to <figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 8C</figref>, if the paper P placed on the holding surface 72a falls into the casing 12 when the conveying unit 16 etc. are drawn out, the second cover 44 is brought down to open the opening 40, and the paper P is removed by inserting a hand into the casing 12 through the opening 40.</p><p id="p0055" num="0055">On the other hand, when the "second signal" is output in step S5, the support unit 98 and the fixing portion 100 are driven in response to the "second signal", such that only the upper portion 90a of the horizontal<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> conveying path 90 is supported by the support unit, and the lower portion 90b is fixed by the fixing portion 100. Accordingly, referring to <figref idrefs="f0009">Fig. 9</figref>, the conveying unit 16 is thereafter drawn out of the casing 12, the lower portion 90b is left in the casing 12, thus allowing the paper P placed on the lower portion 90b to be easily removed through the opening 40.</p><p id="p0056" num="0056">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0008">Figs. 8B</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0009">9</figref>, in this embodiment, the drawing direction Y is parallel to the conveying direction X, such that the conveying unit 16 and at least the upper portion 90a of the horizontal conveying path 90 are drawn out parallel to the direction of the "columns" of the inkjet recording heads 62a to 62d. Accordingly, when jam handling is performed through the opening 40, all of the inkjet recording heads 62a to 62d and regions T positioned therebetween can be viewed through the opening 40. This allows the paper P jammed in the regions T to be easily removed through the opening 40 also owing to the wide space in the casing 12 into which the hand can be inserted.</p><p id="p0057" num="0057">Furthermore, referring to <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>, when the paper P is positioned at the opening 40 side in the paper cassette 20, and when the paper P is supplied to the conveying unit 16, the paper P is positioned along the edge of the holding surface 72a adjacent to the opening 40. Therefore, the paper P that is jammed in the conveying unit 16 and the<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --> horizontal conveying path 90 is positioned near the opening 40. Accordingly, even if the paper P is left in the casing 12, the paper P can be easily removed through the opening 40.</p><p id="p0058" num="0058">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0008">Figs. 8B</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0009">9</figref>, since the paper P left in the casing 12 can be received by the receiving member 52 or the lower portion 90b positioned above the paper cassette 20, the paper P stained with ink does not come into contact with the paper P accommodated in the paper cassette 20, thus preventing the paper P in the paper cassette 20 from being stained.</p><p id="p0059" num="0059">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 5A</figref>, since the first locking portion 56 and the second locking portion 88 lock the second cover 44 in a closed state, the second cover 44 can be prevented from being opened while the conveying unit 16 is performing a conveying operation.</p><p id="p0060" num="0060">Furthermore, referring to <figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 7</figref>, the detection of "a jam in the horizontal conveying path 90" by the second jam sensors 152a to 152d etc. is performed before the detection of "a jam in the conveying unit 16" by the first jam sensors 150a to 150c etc.; therefore, if jams have occurred both in the conveying unit 16 and the horizontal conveying path 90, the upper portion 90a of the horizontal conveying path 90 can be drawn out together with the conveying unit 16 in response to the "second signal", thus allowing the paper P to be removed from both the conveying<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --> unit 16 and the horizontal conveying path 90.</p><heading id="h0019">[Other Embodiments]</heading><p id="p0061" num="0061">Although the embodiment described above is configured such that the conveying unit 16 and the upper portion 90a of the horizontal conveying path 90 are integrally formed and are drawn out at the same time, they may be separably formed and may be separately drawn out. The upper portion 90a and the lower portion 90b of the horizontal conveying path 90 may be integrally formed so as not to be separated. Also in those cases, at least the upper portion 90a of the horizontal conveying path 90 can be drawn out of the casing 12 together with the conveying unit 16 or separately, which increases the space in the casing 12 into which the hand is to be inserted, thus allowing the paper P left in the casing 12 to be easily removed through the opening 40.</p><p id="p0062" num="0062">Furthermore, the "drawing direction Y" in which the conveying unit 16 and at least the upper portion 90a of the horizontal conveying path 90 are drawn out should be a direction perpendicular to a direction in which the opening 40 faces. If the direction of the opening 40 is the "conveying direction X", the "drawing direction Y" may be a direction perpendicular to the "conveying direction X".</p><p id="p0063" num="0063">In the embodiment described above, the present invention is applied to the line inkjet printer; instead,<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --> the present invention may also be applied to serial inkjet printers, laser printers, facsimile machines, copying machines, etc. The method for conveying a recording medium is not limited to the "belt system" but may be a "roller system".</p><p id="p0064" num="0064">Furthermore, the "return path unit" is not limited to the path unit for printing both sides of the paper P; for example, it may be a path unit for printing on the same side of the paper P a plurality of times.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56978348" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Aufzeichnungsvorrichtung mit<br/>
einer Aufzeichnungseinheit (14), die ausgebildet ist, um ein Bild auf einem Aufzeichnungsmedium (P) aufzuzeichnen;<br/>
einer unterhalb der Aufzeichnungseinheit (14) angeordneten Fördereinheit (16), die ausgebildet ist, um das Aufzeichnungsmedium (P) zu einer Position zu befördern, bei der von der Aufzeichnungseinheit (14) eine Aufzeichnung durchgeführt wird;<br/>
einer Rückführstreckeneinheit (18), die ausgebildet ist, , um das Aufzeichnungsmedium (P) von der Eingangsseite der Aufzeichnungseinheit (14) zur Fördereinheit (16) zurückzuführen, um erneut ein Bild auf dem Aufzeichnungsmedium (P) aufzuzeichnen; und<br/>
einem Gehäuse (12), das die Aufzeichnungseinheit (14), die Fördereinheit (16) und die Rückführstreckeneinheit (18) aufnimmt,<br/>
wobei die Rückfiihrstreckeneinheit (18) unterhalb der Fördereinheit (16) angeordnet ist und eine horizontale Förderstrecke mit einem oberen Abschnitt (90a) und einem unteren Abschnitt (90b) umfasst;<br/>
wobei Seitenwände des Gehäuses (12) eine Herausziehöffnung umfassen, durch die die Fördereinheit (16) und mindestens der obere Abschnitt (90a) der horizontalen Förderstrecke herausgezogen werden, und eine Öffnung (40), die in eine zu der Herausziehrichtung senkrechte Richtung weist; und<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="35"> -->wobei die Innenkante des unteren Endes der Öffnung (40) auf der gleichen Höhe oder niedriger angeordnet ist als der oberste Abschnitt der horizontalen Förderstrecke in der Rückfiihrstreckeneinheit.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Aufzeichnungsvorrichtung nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Fördereinheit und mindestens der obere Abschnitt der horizontalen Förderstrecke einstückig ausgebildet sind.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Aufzeichnungsvorrichtung nach Anspruch 1 oder 2, wobei der obere Abschnitt und der untere Abschnitt voneinander trennbar ausgebildet sind; und<br/>
wobei die Aufzeichnungsvorrichtung ferner eine Befestigungseinheit umfasst, die den unteren Abschnitt im Gehäuse befestigt, wenn die Fördereinheit und der obere Abschnitt durch die Herausziehöffnung herausgezogen werden.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Aufzeichnungsvorrichtung nach Anspruch 3, ferner mit<br/>
einer ersten Stauerfassungseinheit, die ausgebildet ist, um das Auftreten eines Staus in der Fördereinheit zu erfassen;<br/>
einer zweiten Stauerfassungseinheit, die ausgebildet ist, um das Auftreten eines Staus in der horizontalen Förderstrecke zu erfassen; und<br/>
einer Ausgabeinheit,<br/>
wobei, wenn die erste Stauerfassungseinheit einen Stau erfasst, die Ausgabeeinheit ein erstes Signal ausgibt, das anzeigt, dass sowohl der obere Abschnitt als auch der untere Abschnitt zusammen mit der Fördereinheit herausgezogen werden sollten, und wobei, wenn die zweite Stauerfassungseinheit einen Stau erfasst, die Ausgabeeinheit ein zweites Signal ausgibt, das anzeigt, dass nur der obere Abschnitt zusammen mit der Fördereinheit herausgezogen werden sollte.<!-- EPO <DP n="36"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Aufzeichnungsvorrichtung nach Anspruch 1 oder 2, wobei der obere Abschnitt und der untere Abschnitt einstückig ausgebildet sind.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Aufzeichnungsvorrichtung nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 5,<br/>
wobei die Aufzeichnungseinheit eine Mehrzahl von Tintenstrahl-Aufzeichnungsköpfen umfasst;<br/>
wobei die Mehrzahl von Tintenstrahl-Aufzeichnungsköpfen parallel zu den Förderrichtungen des Aufzeichnungsmediums angeordnet sind; und<br/>
wobei die Fördereinheit und mindestens der obere Abschnitt der horizontalen Förderstrecke parallel zu der Förderrichtung des Aufzeichnungsmediums herausgezogen werden.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Aufzeichnungsmedium nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 6, wobei die Innenkante des oberen Endes der Öffnung höher angeordnets ist als der unterste Abschnitt der Fördereinheit.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Aufzeichnungsvorrichtung nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 7, ferner mit<br/>
einem Deckel, der zum Öffnen und Schließen der Öffnung ausgebildet ist;<br/>
einer Verriegelungseinheit, die zum Verriegeln des Deckels in einem geschlossenen Zustand ausgebildet ist; und<br/>
einem Entriegelungsmechanismus, der ausgebildet ist, um den Verriegelungszustand der Verriegelungseinheit zu lösen, wenn die Fördereinheit durch die Herausziehöffnung herausgezogen wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Aufzeichnungsvorrichtung nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 8, ferner mit<!-- EPO <DP n="37"> --> einer unterhalb der Rückfi.ihrstreckeneinheit angeordneten Aufzeichnungs-medium-Aufnahmeeinheit, die zur Aufnahme des Aufzeichnungsmediums ausgebildet ist,<br/>
wobei die Aufzeichnungsmedium-Aufnahmeeinheit umfasst: einen Positionierabschnitt, der mit einem an die Öffnung angrenzenden Seitenrand des Aufzeichnungsmediums in Berührung steht, um die Position des Aufzeichnungsmediums zu definieren, und eine Führung, die einen der Öffnung gegenüberliegenden Seitenrand des Aufzeichnungsmediums in Abhängigkeit von der Größe des Aufzeichnungsmediums führt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Aufzeichnungsvorrichtung nach Anspruch 9, ferner mit einem Aufnahmeelement, das zwischen der Rückführstreckeneinheit und der Aufzeichnungsmedium-Aufnahmeeinheit angeordnet und ausgebildet ist, um ein aus der Fördereinheit gefallenes Aufzeichnungsmedium aufzunehmen.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56978349" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A recording apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a recording unit (14) configured to record an image on a recording medium (P);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a conveying unit (16) disposed below the recording unit (14) and configured to convey the recording medium (P) to a position at which recording is performed by the recording unit (14);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a return path unit (18) configured to return the recording medium (P) from the upstream side of the recording unit (14) to the conveying unit (16) to record an image again on the recording medium (P); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a casing (12) which accommodates the recording unit (14), the conveying unit (16), and the return path unit (18),</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the return path unit (18) is disposed below the conveying unit (16) and comprises a horizontal conveying path comprising an upper portion (90a) and a lower portion (90b);</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein side walls of the casing (12) comprise a drawing port through which the conveying unit (16) and at least the upper portion (90a) of the horizontal conveying path are drawn out, and an opening (40) facing in a direction perpendicular to the drawing direction thereof; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the inner edge of the lower end of the opening (40) is positioned the same or lower in height than the uppermost portion of the horizontal conveying path in the return path<!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --> unit.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The recording apparatus according to Claim 1,<br/>
wherein the conveying unit and at least the upper portion of the horizontal conveying path are integrally formed.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The recording apparatus according to Claim 1 or 2,<br/>
wherein the upper portion and the lower portion are separably configured; and<br/>
wherein the recording apparatus further comprises a fixing unit that fixes the lower portion in the casing when the conveying unit and the upper portion are drawn out through the drawing port.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The recording apparatus according to Claim 3, further comprising:
<claim-text>a first jam detecting unit configured to detect the occurrence of a jam in the conveying unit;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second jam detecting unit configured to detect the occurrence of a jam in the horizontal conveying path; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an output unit,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein when the first jam detecting unit detects a jam, the output unit outputs a first signal indicating that both the upper portion and the lower portion should be drawn out together with the conveying unit, and when the second jam<!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --> detecting unit detects a jam, the output unit outputs a second signal indicating that only the upper portion should be drawn out together with the conveying unit.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The recording apparatus according to Claim 1 or 2, wherein the upper portion and the lower portion are integrally formed.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The recording apparatus according to one of Claims 1 to 5,<br/>
wherein the recording unit comprises a plurality of inkjet recording heads;<br/>
wherein the plurality of inkjet recording heads are arranged parallel to the recording-medium conveying directions; and<br/>
wherein the conveying unit and at least the upper portion of the horizontal conveying path are drawn out parallel to the recording-medium conveying direction.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The recording apparatus according to one of Claims 1 to 6, wherein the inner edge of the upper end of the opening is positioned higher than the lowermost portion of the conveying unit.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The recording apparatus according to one of Claims<!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --> 1 to 7, further comprising:
<claim-text>a cover configured to open and close the opening;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a locking unit configured to lock the cover in a closed state; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an unlocking mechanism configured to release the locking state of the locking unit when the conveying unit is drawn out through the drawing port.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The recording apparatus according to one of Claims 1 to 8, further comprising:
<claim-text>a recording-medium accommodating unit disposed below the return path unit and configured to accommodate the recording medium,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the recording-medium accommodating unit comprises a positioning portion which is in contact with a side edge of the recording medium adjacent to the opening to define the position of the recording medium; and a guide which guides a side edge of the recording medium opposite the opening depending on the size of the recording medium.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The recording apparatus according to Claim 9, further comprising a receiving member disposed between the return path unit and the recording-medium accommodating unit, and configured to receive a recording medium which has fallen from the conveying unit.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56978350" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="38"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Dispositif d'enregistrement comprenant :
<claim-text>une unité d'enregistrement (14) configurée de manière à enregistrer une image sur un support d'enregistrement (P) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une unité de transfert (16) disposée au-dessous de l'unité d'enregistrement (14) et configurée de manière à transférer le support d'enregistrement (P) vers un emplacement auquel l'enregistrement est réalisé par l'unité d'enregistrement (14) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une unité formant trajet de retour (18) configurée de manière à renvoyer le support d'enregistrement (P) à partir du côté amont de l'unité d'enregistrement (14) vers l'unité de transfert (16) afin d'enregistrer de nouveau une image sur le support d'enregistrement (P), et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un boîtier (12) qui contient l'unité d'enregistrement (14), l'unité de transfert (16), et l'unité formant trajet de retour (18),</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel l'unité formant trajet de retour (18) est disposée au-dessous de l'unité de transfert (16) et comprend un trajet de transfert horizontal comprenant une partie supérieure (90a) et une partie inférieure (90b) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel les parois latérales du boîtier (12) comprennent un orifice d'extraction à travers lequel l'unité de transfert (16) et au moins la partie supérieure (90a) du trajet de transfert horizontal sont extraites, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>une ouverture (40) orientée dans une direction perpendiculaire à la direction d'extraction de celui-ci ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel le bord interne de l'extrémité inférieure de l'ouverture (40) est positionné à une hauteur inférieure ou égale à la partie supérieure du trajet de transfert horizontal sur l'unité formant trajet de retour.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Dispositif d'enregistrement selon la revendication 1, dans lequel l'unité de transfert et au moins la partie supérieure du trajet de transfert horizontal sont formées de manière unitaire.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Dispositif d'enregistrement selon la revendication 1 ou 2, dans lequel la partie supérieure et la partie inférieure sont configurées de manière à pouvoir être séparées ; et<br/>
dans lequel le dispositif d'enregistrement comprend en outre une unité de fixation qui fixe la partie inférieure sur le boîtier lorsque l'unité de transfert et la partie supérieure sont extraites à travers l'orifice d'extraction.<!-- EPO <DP n="39"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Dispositif d'enregistrement selon la revendication 3, comprenant en outre :
<claim-text>une première unité de détection de bourrage configurée de manière à détecter l'occurrence d'un bourrage sur l'unité de transfert ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une seconde unité de détection de bourrage configurée de manière à détecter l'occurrence d'un bourrage sur le trajet de transfert horizontal ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>une unité de sortie,</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel lorsque la première unité de détection de bourrage détecte un bourrage, l'unité de sortie délivre un premier signal indiquant que, à la fois la partie supérieure et la partie inférieure doivent être extraites ensemble avec l'unité de transfert, et lorsque la seconde unité de détection de bourrage détecte un bourrage, l'unité de sortie délivre un second signal indiquant que seule la partie supérieure doit être extraite ensemble avec l'unité de transfert.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Dispositif d'enregistrement selon la revendication 1 ou 2, dans lequel la partie supérieure et la partie inférieure sont formées de manière unitaire.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Dispositif d'enregistrement selon l'une des revendications 1 à 5,<br/>
dans lequel l'unité d'enregistrement comprend une pluralité de têtes d'enregistrement à jet d'encre ;<br/>
dans lequel les têtes de la pluralité de têtes d'enregistrement à jet d'encre sont agencées parallèlement aux directions de transfert de support d'enregistrement ; et<br/>
dans lequel l'unité de transfert et au moins la partie supérieure du trajet de transfert horizontal sont extraites parallèlement à la direction de transfert de support d'enregistrement.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Dispositif d'enregistrement selon l'une des revendications 1 à 6, dans lequel le bord interne de l'extrémité supérieure de l'ouverture est positionné plus haut que la partie inférieure de l'unité de transfert.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Dispositif d'enregistrement selon l'une des revendications 1 à 7, comprenant en outre :
<claim-text>un couvercle configuré de manière à ouvrir et à fermer l'ouverture ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une unité de verrouillage configurée de manière à verrouiller le couvercle dans un état fermé ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un mécanisme de déverrouillage configuré de manière à libérer l'état de verrouillage de l'unité de verrouillage lorsque l'unité de transfert est extraite à travers l'orifice d'extraction.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="40"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Dispositif d'enregistrement selon l'une des revendications 1 à 8, comprenant en outre :
<claim-text>une unité de logement de support d'enregistrement disposée au-dessous de l'unité formant trajet de retour et configurée de manière à contenir le support d'enregistrement,</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel l'unité de logement de support d'enregistrement comprend une partie de positionnement qui est en contact avec un bord latéral du support d'enregistrement adj acent à l'ouverture afin de définir la position du support d'enregistrement ; et un guide qui guide le bord latéral du support d'enregistrement opposé à l'ouverture en fonction de la taille du support d'enregistrement.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Dispositif d'enregistrement selon la revendication 9, comprenant en outre un élément de réception disposé entre l'unité formant trajet de retour et l'unité de logement de support d'enregistrement, et configuré de manière à recevoir un support d'enregistrement qui est tombé de l'unité de transfert.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16668554" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="41"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="158" he="155" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="42"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="149" he="135" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="43"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="150" he="129" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="44"> --><figure id="f0004" num="4A,4B"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="141" he="115" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="45"> --><figure id="f0005" num="5A,5B"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="143" he="196" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="46"> --><figure id="f0006" num="6"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="164" he="134" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="47"> --><figure id="f0007" num="7"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="149" he="199" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="48"> --><figure id="f0008" num="8A,8B,8C"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="151" he="230" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="49"> --><figure id="f0009" num="9"><img id="if0009" file="imgf0009.tif" wi="141" he="113" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
