<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2682888-A1" country="EP" doc-number="2682888" kind="A1" date="20140108" family-id="46758129" file-reference-id="298574" date-produced="20180824" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146584864" ucid="EP-2682888-A1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2682888</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-12751889-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154847056" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12751889</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120302</date><lang>JA</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP170521197" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12751889.2</doc-number><date>20120302</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140549119" ucid="JP-2011045911-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>JP</country><doc-number>2011045911</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20110303</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140553571" ucid="JP-2012055459-W" linkage-type="W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>JP</country><doc-number>2012055459</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20120302</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classification-ipc><edition>7</edition><main-classification>G06F  21/24</main-classification></classification-ipc><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989321217" load-source="patent-office">G06F  21/24        00000000AFI20120919BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1713568837" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G16H  10/60        20180101 LA20180103BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1976550037" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G06F  21/604       20130101 LA20160204BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1976553534" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04L  63/102       20130101 LA20160204BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1976554682" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G06F  21/6245      20130101 LI20160204BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2092281139" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04L  63/20        20130101 FI20150213BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132359225" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">RICHTLINIENBESTIMMUNGSVERFAHREN, RICHTLINIENBESTIMMUNGSSERVER UND PROGRAMM DAFÜR</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132359226" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">POLICY ARBITRATION METHOD, POLICY ARBITRATION SERVER, AND PROGRAM</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132359227" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">MÉTHODE D'ARBITRAGE DE POLITIQUE, SERVEUR D'ARBITRAGE DE POLITIQUE ET PROGRAMME</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919509154" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>NEC CORP</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919513043" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>NEC CORPORATION</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919010447" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Nec Corporation</last-name><iid>101193625</iid><address><street>7-1, Shiba 5-chome Minato-ku</street><city>Tokyo 108-8001</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919528370" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>FURUKAWA RYO</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919544042" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>FURUKAWA, RYO</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919015590" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>FURUKAWA, RYO</last-name><address><street>c/o NEC Corporation 7-1, Shiba 5-chome</street><city>Minato-ku, Tokyo 108-8001</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919011186" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Vossius &amp; Partner</last-name><iid>100751388</iid><address><street>Siebertstrasse 4</street><city>81675 München</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="JP-2012055459-W"><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>2012055459</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20120302</date><lang>JA</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2012118205-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2012118205</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20120907</date><lang>JA</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549741770" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS549812472" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549741771" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549907346" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549738316" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549739322" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549812473" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549739979" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549741772" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549739323" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549813639" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549907347" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549907348" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549739980" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549741777" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549741778" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549739324" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549738317" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549741779" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549907349" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549739325" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549739981" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549812478" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549739982" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549739983" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549739621" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS549739622" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549812479" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549741780" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549812480" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549741785" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549812481" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549741786" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS549812486" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549739984" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549739326" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549739327" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS549739623" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA128673036" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p id="pa01" num="0001">There is provided a method whereby it is made possible to efficiently obtain agreement from a holder of privacy information relating to the use of the privacy information. Based on a user policy describing at least one rule for handling privacy information set by a holder of privacy information and a set of service policies including at least one service policy which is a rule for handling privacy information predetermined by a user of privacy information, a ranking of the service policy is generated based on the degree of divergence between the user policy and the service policy. The holder of privacy information refers to the service policy ranking and selects a service policy he can agree to.<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="142" he="104" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA128737181" lang="EN" source="EPO" load-source="docdb"><p>There is provided a method whereby it is made possible to efficiently obtain agreement from a holder of privacy information relating to the use of the privacy information. Based on a user policy describing at least one rule for handling privacy information set by a holder of privacy information and a set of service policies including at least one service policy which is a rule for handling privacy information predetermined by a user of privacy information, a ranking of the service policy is generated based on the degree of divergence between the user policy and the service policy. The holder of privacy information refers to the service policy ranking and selects a service policy he can agree to.</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES63959024" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001">[Technical Field]</heading><heading id="h0002">(Reference to Related Application)</heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">This application is based upon and claims the benefit of the priority of Japanese Patent Application No. <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="JP2011045911A"><text>2011-045911 filed on March 03, 2011</text></patcit>, the disclosure of which is incorporated herein in its entirety by reference thereto.<br/>
The present invention relates to a policy arbitration method, a policy arbitration server, and a program, and particularly to a policy arbitration method, a policy arbitration server, and a program that resolve a conflict between a privacy information holder's policy regarding how his privacy information is handled and a policy of a user of the privacy information regarding how the privacy information is used.</p><heading id="h0003">[Background]</heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">In recent years, services that obtain attribute information (age, sex, address, etc.) and activity information (location information, purchase information, etc.) of a privacy information holder to utilize the information for delivering advertisements of interest to the privacy information holder have attracted attention.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">In such a service, since the attribute information and the activity information are privacy information, the privacy of a privacy information holder will be violated if a privacy information user, who provides the service, unilaterally acquires and utilizes the privacy information. Therefore, a privacy information holder needs to be able to control how a privacy information user handles privacy information (disclosure requirements, data protection requirements,<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> etc.).</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">As a method for performing such control, Non-Patent Literature (NPL) 1 describes a policy-based control method using P3P (Platform for Privacy Preferences).</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">In P3P, privacy information collected by a privacy information user (service provider) and the way this information is handled are set as a policy file (referred to as "service policy" hereinafter) written in XML (Extensible Markup Language), and by investigating whether or not conditions of data disclosure match between a policy file (referred to as "user policy" hereinafter) describing a data disclosure policy set in advance by a privacy information holder and the aforementioned service policy, a data disclosure decision can be automatically/semi-automatically made.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">P3P has a problem that a privacy information user cannot use the data and a privacy information holder cannot receive a service when a conflict arises between the user policy and the service policy and data disclosure agreement cannot be reached (for instance, when there is a conflict between the two policies regarding the conditions of data disclosure). Therefore, policy agreement must be reached between the privacy information holder and the privacy information user. Such a method for reaching policy agreement between two parties is called policy arbitration method.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">Patent Literature (PTL) 1 describes an example of the policy arbitration method. The policy arbitration method in Patent Literature 1 is constituted by privacy information holder terminals connected to each other via a network, a privacy information user terminal, and a server.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">According to Patent Literature 1, each of the privacy information holder terminals registers a privacy policy defining<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> standards for using privacy information to the server, the privacy information user terminal registers a user policy defining a range of requirements for privacy information disclosure to the server, the server determines whether or not there is a conflict between the policies, and the server notifies the privacy information holder terminal of the user policy when there is a conflict, requesting consent for privacy information disclosure. When there is no conflict and when consent is made, the privacy information user terminal is able to use the privacy information.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">Further, Non-Patent Literature 2 describes another example of a policy arbitration method. The policy arbitration method in Non-Patent Literature 2 is constituted by privacy information holder terminals and privacy information user terminals connected by a network.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">According to Non-Patent Literature 2, a privacy information user terminal transmits a user policy to a privacy information holder terminal, and the privacy information holder terminal compares the user policy to a privacy policy and transmits attribute information of the privacy information holder if there is no conflict. Further, when there is a conflict, a user transmits use/preservation conditions to the privacy information user terminal from the privacy information holder terminal, and the privacy information user terminal creates a new user policy meeting these conditions and transmits the new policy to the privacy information holder terminal. In other words, policy arbitration is performed by repeating the transmission of the user policy, the comparison, the transmission of conditions, and the creation of a new policy until agreement between the two parties is reached.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">Patent Literatures 2 to 4 are other relevant documents.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p><heading id="h0004">[Citation List]</heading><heading id="h0005">[Patent Literature]</heading><p id="p0012" num="0012"><ul><li>[PTL 1]<br/>
Japanese Patent Kokai Publication No. <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="JP2004192353A"><text>JP2004-192353A</text></patcit></li><li>[PTL 2]<br/>
Japanese Patent Kokai Publication No. <patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="JP2003132160A"><text>JP2003-132160A</text></patcit></li><li>[PTL 3]<br/>
Japanese Patent Kokai Publication No. <patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="JP2006344156A"><text>JP2006-344156A</text></patcit></li><li>[PTL 4]<br/>
Japanese Patent Kokai Publication No. <patcit id="pcit0005" dnum="JP2008117026A"><text>JP2008-117026A</text></patcit></li></ul></p><heading id="h0006">[Non Patent Literature]</heading><p id="p0013" num="0013"><ul><li>[NPL 1]<br/>
<nplcit id="ncit0001" npl-type="s" url="&lt;URL: http://www.w3.org/P3P/&gt;"><text>Platform for Privacy Preferences (P3P) Project, [online], [searched on February 23, 2011], the Internet &lt;URL: http://www.w3.org/P3P/&gt;</text></nplcit>.</li><li>[NPL 2]<br/>
<nplcit id="ncit0002" npl-type="s" url="http://www.w3.org/2006/07/privacy-ws/papers/22-hatakeyama-negotiati on-attributes/&gt;"><text>Hatakeyama, M., Gomi, H., "Privacy Policy Negotiation Framework for Attribute Exchange", W3C Workshop on Languages for Privacy Policy Negotiation and Semantics - Driven Enforcement, 2006, [online], [searched on February 23, 2011], the Internet &lt;URL: http://www.w3.org/2006/07/privacy-ws/papers/22-hatakeyama-negotiati on-attributes/&gt;</text></nplcit>.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0007">[Summary]</heading><heading id="h0008">[Technical Problem]</heading><p id="p0014" num="0014">The following analysis is given by the present invention. The policy arbitration method described in Patent Literature 1 is able to perform policy arbitration with only one interaction, however, even when there is a conflict between the user policy and the service policy, the privacy information holder has no choice but to agree to the service policy in order to receive the service. As a result, there is no option in terms of changing the quality of the service offered according to the degree of the privacy information provided such as a case where a better service will be offered if a certain piece of data is<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> additionally provided, and policy agreement cannot be flexibly reached.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">Meanwhile, in the policy arbitration method described in Non-Patent Literature 2, a privacy information holder and privacy information user can flexibly reach policy agreement by performing a plurality of interactions between the privacy information holder and the privacy information user. However, it is inefficient for the privacy information user to perform a plurality of interactions for a single privacy information holder.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">The present invention has been invented to solve the above problems, and it is an object thereof to provide a policy arbitration method capable of flexibly facilitating policy agreement between a privacy information holder and privacy information user while reducing the number of interactions.</p><heading id="h0009">[Solution to Problem]</heading><p id="p0017" num="0017">According to a first aspect of the present invention, there is provided a policy arbitration method. The policy arbitration method comprises: entering a user policy in which a privacy information holder describes at least one rule that is a pair of a data type of privacy information possessed by the privacy information holder and the way to handle the data type; generating, using the user policy and a service policy set that includes at least one service policy in which a privacy information user describes at least one rule that is a pair of a data type of the privacy information and the way to handle the data type, a ranking of the service policy according to the degree of divergence between the user policy and the service policy; displaying the service policy ranking on a privacy information holder terminal; and having the privacy information holder select one service policy from the service policy ranking. The present method is tied to a particular machine, which is a computer that handles privacy information of a privacy information holder.<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></p><p id="p0018" num="0018">According to a second aspect of the present invention, there is provided an arbitration server. The arbitration server comprises: user policy receiving means for receiving from a user a user policy describing at least one rule that is a pair of a data type of privacy information possessed by the user and the way to handle the data type; ranking generation means for generating, using the user policy and a service policy set that includes at least one service policy describing at least one rule that is a pair of a data type of the privacy information and the way to handle the data type, a ranking of the service policy based on the degree of divergence between the user policy and the service policy; and agreed policy receiving means for receiving from the user who has referred to the service policy ranking selection of a service policy to be applied to the privacy information of the user.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">According to a third aspect of the present invention, there is provided a program. The program causes an arbitration server to execute: receiving from a user a user policy describing at least one rule that is a pair of a data type of privacy information possessed by the user and the way to handle the data type; generating, using the user policy and a service policy set that includes at least one service policy describing at least one rule that is a pair of a data type of the privacy information and the way to handle the data type, a ranking of the service policy based on the degree of divergence between the user policy and the service policy; and receiving from the user who has referred to the service policy ranking selection of a service policy to be applied to the privacy information of the user. Further, this program can be stored in a computer-readable recording-medium. In other words, the present invention can be realized as a computer program product as well.</p><heading id="h0010">[Advantageous Effects of Invention]</heading><p id="p0020" num="0020">According to the present invention, it becomes possible to<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> flexibly facilitate policy agreement between a privacy information holder and privacy information user while reducing the number of interactions.</p><heading id="h0011">[Brief Description of the Drawings]</heading><p id="p0021" num="0021"><ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is a drawing for explaining a summary of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> is a flowchart for explaining a summary of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> is a flowchart showing details of step S4 in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4</figref> is a block diagram showing a configuration of a first exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 5</figref> is a block diagram showing a detailed configuration of ranking generation means in <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4</figref>.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 6</figref> is an example of a user policy used to describe an operation of the first exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 7</figref> is an example of a service policy used to describe an operation of the first exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 8</figref> is a drawing showing a storage format of service policies in service policy storage means in <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4</figref>.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0009">Fig. 9</figref> is a flowchart showing an operation of the first exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0010">Fig. 10</figref> is an example of a user policy input screen displayed by user policy input means in <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4</figref>.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0011">Fig. 11</figref> is a flowchart showing an operation of policy distance calculation means in <figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 5</figref>.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0012">Fig. 12</figref> is a drawing showing the results of calculation by the policy distance calculation means in <figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 5</figref>.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0013">Fig. 13</figref> is an example of service policy rankings generated by the ranking generation means in <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4</figref>.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0014">Fig. 14</figref> is an example of a service policy ranking display screen displayed by ranking display means in <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4</figref>.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0015">Fig. 15</figref> is a drawing showing a storage format of agreed policies in agreed policy storage means in <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4</figref>.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></li><li><figref idrefs="f0016">Fig. 16</figref> is a block diagram showing a detailed configuration of ranking generation means of an arbitration server of a second exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0017">Fig. 17</figref> is a drawing showing a storage format of service policies in service policy storage means of the arbitration server of the second exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0018">Fig. 18</figref> is a flowchart showing an operation of the ranking generation means of the arbitration server of the second exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0019">Fig. 19</figref> is an example of service policy rankings generated by the ranking generation means of the arbitration server of the second exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0020">Fig. 20</figref> is an example of a service policy ranking display screen displayed by ranking display means of the arbitration server of the second exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0021">Fig. 21</figref> is a block diagram showing a detailed configuration of policy distance calculation means of an arbitration server of a third exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0022">Fig. 22</figref> is an example of a user policy used to describe an operation of the third exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0023">Fig. 23</figref> is a drawing showing a storage format of service policies in service policy storage means of the arbitration server of the third exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0024">Fig. 24</figref> is a flowchart showing an operation of the policy distance calculation means of the arbitration server of the third exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0025">Fig. 25</figref> is a flowchart showing an operation of policy mapping means of the arbitration server of the third exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0026">Fig. 26</figref> is an example of information stored in action information storage means used to describe an operation of the third exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0027">Fig. 27</figref> is a drawing showing a state after the service policies have been mapped by the policy mapping means of the arbitration server of<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> the third exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0028">Fig. 28</figref> is a flowchart showing an operation of vector distance calculation means of the arbitration server of the third exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0029">Fig. 29</figref> is a drawing showing the results of calculating the distance to the service policies performed by the vector distance calculation means of the arbitration server of the third exemplary embodiment of the present invention.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0012">[Description of Embodiments]</heading><p id="p0022" num="0022">First, a summary of an exemplary embodiment of the present invention will be described with reference to the drawings. Note that the drawing reference signs used in the summary are given to elements as an example for convenience to facilitate understanding and not to limit the present invention to the illustrated aspects.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, The present invention, in an exemplary embodiment thereof, can be realized by an arbitration server 200 comprising user policy receiving means 210 for receiving a user policy supplied by a privacy information holder (simply referred to as "user" hereinafter); service policy storage means 220 for storing at least one service policy describing at least one rule which is a set of a data type and an action desired by a privacy information user; ranking generation means 230 for generating a service policy ranking of the service policy in the order of the degree of divergence (smallest to largest) between the supplied user policy and at least one service policy; agreed policy receiving means 240 for receiving a service policy (also referred to as "agreed policy" hereinafter) selected by the user as an accepted policy from the service policies; and agreed policy storage means 250 for storing the agreed policy.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">Further, the user policy and the service policy describes a data type (value identifying the property of data such as name, age, etc.) and an action for each data type (how to handle privacy information<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> such as whether or not the disclosure of the data is allowed, whether or not the information should be acquired, a privacy protection process is performed, etc.).</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">The arbitration server operates as shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>. First, a privacy information holder enters a user policy using his own terminal (referred to as "user terminal" hereinafter) (step S1).</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">Next, the user policy receiving means 210 of the arbitration server 200 receives the user policy (step S2).</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">Next, the ranking generation means 230 acquires a set of service policies from the service policy storage means 220 (step S3).</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">Next, the ranking generation means 230 receives the user policy and the set of service policies, generates rankings of the service policies based on the degree of divergence between the user policy and the service policies, and transmits the service policy rankings to the user terminal (step S4).</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">The generated service policy rankings are displayed on the user terminal (step S5). The user selects a service policy from the service policy rankings displayed, and transmits the selected policy to the arbitration server 200 as an agreed policy (step S6).</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">Finally, the agreed policy receiving means 240 receives the agreed policy and stores it in the agreed policy storage means 250 (step S7).</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">Further, in the step S6, the user may be able to choose not to receive the service if he cannot select any agreed policy from the service policy rankings or there is no service policy he wants to select.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032"><!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> The process of generating service policy rankings in the step S4 will be described with reference to <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">First, the user policy received in the step S2 and the set of service policies acquired in the step S3 are entered into the ranking generation means 230 (step B1).</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">Next, the ranking generation means 230 repeats step B3 for all the service policies (step B2).</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">The ranking generation means 230 calculates a distance expressing the degree of divergence between the user policy and each service policy (the step B3). For instance, this distance can be derived by expressing the difference in the handling of data between the user policy and a service policy as a numerical value for each data type and summing the differences in the handling of the data for all the data attributes. Further, in the calculation of the distance, a weighting may be appropriately performed for each data type.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">Finally, the service policies are sorted in the order of smallest to largest distance and outputted as the service policy rankings (step B4).</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">As described, service policy rankings generated based on the distance between a user policy entered by a user and service policies determined by a privacy information user are provided to the user, enabling the user to select an agreed policy he can accept. As a result, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, an agreed policy desirable for both the privacy information holder and the privacy information user can be generated by having the two parties perform only one interaction.</p><heading id="h0013">(First Exemplary Embodiment)</heading><p id="p0038" num="0038">Next, a first exemplary embodiment of the present invention will be described in detail with reference to the drawings. <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4</figref> is a block<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> diagram showing a configuration of the first exemplary embodiment of the present invention. With reference to <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4</figref>, a configuration including a privacy information holder terminal 100 and the arbitration server 200 is shown.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">The privacy information holder terminal 100 comprises user policy input means 110 for entering a user policy, ranking display means 120 for displaying rankings of service policies, and agreed policy selection means 130 for selecting an agreed policy from service policy rankings.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">The arbitration server 200 comprises the service policy storage means 220 for storing a service policy ID identifying a service policy and a service policy, the user policy receiving means 210 for receiving a user policy entered by a privacy information holder, the ranking generation means 230 for generating service policy rankings based on the distance between the user policy and the service policies stored in the service policy storage means 220, the agreed policy receiving means 240 for receiving an agreed policy selected by the privacy information holder, and the agreed policy storage means 250 for storing a user ID of the privacy information holder and the agreed policy.</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">Further, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 5</figref>, the ranking generation means 230 includes policy distance calculation means 232 for calculating the distance between policies, which is the degree of divergence between the user policy and a service policy, and ranking calculation means 231 for ranking the service policies based on the distance between the policies.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">In the exemplary embodiments below, the user policy is assumed to be written in XML in such a manner that binary values ("Provide" and "Do not provide") are set using ACTION tags as the content of a rule defining how each data type (datatype) such as Name and Address<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> is handled, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 6</figref>.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">Further, the service policy is also assumed to be written in XML in such a manner that binary values ("Acquire" and "Do not acquire") are set using ACTION tags as the content of a rule defining how each data type (datatype) such as Name and Address is handled, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 7</figref>.</p><p id="p0044" num="0044">Further, in the present exemplary embodiment, a conflict between the user policy and the service policy, described above, occurs when "not provided" is written in the rule of a data type while "acquire" is written in the rule of the corresponding data type of the service policy.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045">Further, each part (processing means) of the arbitration server 200 shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">Figs. 4</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0005">5</figref> can be realized by a computer program having a computer that constitutes the arbitration server 200 execute each processing described below using the hardware thereof.</p><p id="p0046" num="0046">Next, an operation of the present exemplary embodiment will be described in detail with reference to the drawings. First, a privacy information holder is assumed to have been already authenticated as the privacy information holder of User ID = "1." Further, the service policy storage means 220 is assumed to store service policy IDs and service policies in a table shown in <figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 8</figref>. The service policy IDs in <figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 8</figref> are the identifiers of service policies.</p><p id="p0047" num="0047"><figref idrefs="f0009">Fig. 9</figref> is a flowchart showing an operation of the first exemplary embodiment of the present invention. With reference to <figref idrefs="f0009">Fig. 9</figref>, first, the user policy receiving means 110 receives the entry of a user policy such as the one shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 6</figref> from the privacy information holder, and transmits it to the arbitration server 200 (step A1). <figref idrefs="f0010">Fig. 10</figref> is an example of a user policy input screen displayed on the privacy information holder terminal 100 by the user policy input<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> means 110.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048">Next, the user policy receiving means 210 of the arbitration server 200 receives the user policy from the privacy information holder terminal 110 (step A2).</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">Upon receiving the user policy, the ranking generation means 230 of the arbitration server 200 acquires a set of service policies from the service policy storage means 220 (step A3). In the present exemplary embodiment, five pairs of the service policy IDs ("1," "2," "3," "4," and "5") and the service policies written in XML are assumed to be acquired, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 8</figref>.</p><p id="p0050" num="0050">Next, the ranking generation means 230 generates service policy rankings (step A4).</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">With reference to the flowchart in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> again, an operation in which the ranking generation means 230 generates the service policy rankings will be described in detail.</p><p id="p0052" num="0052">First, the user policy (refer to <figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 6</figref>) entered by the privacy information holder and the set of the pairs of the service policy IDs and the service policies (refer to <figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 7</figref>) are entered into the ranking generation means 230 (the step B1).</p><p id="p0053" num="0053">Next, the processing of the step B3 is performed on all the service policies (the step B2). More concretely, the distance between the user policy and a service policy that is the distance calculation target is calculated (the step B3).</p><p id="p0054" num="0054">With reference to a flowchart in <figref idrefs="f0011">Fig. 11</figref>, the calculation of the distance between the user policy and the service policy performed by the policy distance calculation means in the ranking generation means 230 will be described in detail. In the description below, the<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> distance between the user policy and the service policy is expressed by the number of conflicting rules.</p><p id="p0055" num="0055">First, the user policy and the service policy are entered (step C1). Here, the user policy shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 6</figref> and the service policy having the service policy ID "1" in <figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 8</figref> are assumed to be entered.</p><p id="p0056" num="0056">Next, the policy distance calculation means 232 breaks down the user policy into a set of pairs of data types and actions (Up = {(t_u, a_u)}) (step C2). For instance, in the case of the user policy in <figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 6</figref>, a_u = "Provide" for t_u = "NAME," and it is ultimately broken down into Up = {("NAME," "Provide"), ("Address," "Do not provide"), ("Position," "Do not provide"), ("Buying," "Provide")}.</p><p id="p0057" num="0057">Further, when a data type written in the service policy is not mentioned in the user policy, the policy distance calculation means 232 treats this data type as having the action "Do not provide."</p><p id="p0058" num="0058">Next, the policy distance calculation means 232 similarly breaks down the service policy into a set of pairs of data types and actions (Sp = {(t_s, a_s)}) (step C3). For instance, in the case of the service policy having the service policy ID "1" in <figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 8</figref>, a_s = "Acquire" for t_s = "NAME," and it is ultimately broken down into Sp = {("NAME," "Acquire"), ("Address," "Acquire"), ("Position," "Acquire"), ("Buying," "Acquire")}.</p><p id="p0059" num="0059">Next, the policy distance calculation means 232 initializes a distance d to zero (step C4). Further, the policy distance calculation means 232 repeats steps C6 to C9 for all t_s = {"NAME," "Address," "Position," "Buying"} included in the service policy Sp (step C5). Only an operation in the case of t_s = "NAME" will be described below.</p><p id="p0060" num="0060">First, the policy distance calculation means 232 acquires pair<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> combinations (t_s, a_s) and (t_u, a_u) in which the data types match (t_s = t_u) from Up and Sp (the step C6). In the case of t_s = "NAME," (t_s, a_s) = ("NAME," "Provide"), (t_u, a_u) _ ("NAME," "Acquire").</p><p id="p0061" num="0061">Next, the policy distance calculation means 232 determines whether or not a_u = "Do not provide" and a_s = "Acquire" (the step C7).</p><p id="p0062" num="0062">Next, when the judgment above is YES, add one to the distance d (d = d + 1) and the operation moves to the step C9 (the step C8). Meanwhile, when the judgment above is NO, the operation simply moves to the step C9. In the case of t_s = "NAME," since a_u = "Provide" and a_s = "Acquire," the judgment is NO and the operation simply moves to the step C9.</p><p id="p0063" num="0063">Next, the policy distance calculation means 232 changes the data type t_s and returns to the step C6 (the step C9).</p><p id="p0064" num="0064">After performing the steps C6 to C9 on all t_s, the policy distance calculation means 232 outputs the distance d (step C10). In the case of the user policy in <figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 6</figref> and the service policy having the service policy ID "1," d = 2 is ultimately outputted since the rules of the data types "Address" and "Position" conflict.</p><p id="p0065" num="0065"><figref idrefs="f0012">Fig. 12</figref> is a drawing showing the results of calculating the distances between the user policy in <figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 6</figref> and all the service policies stored in the service policy storage means 220 shown in <figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 8</figref>.</p><p id="p0066" num="0066">With reference to <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> again, the ranking calculation means 231 in the ranking generation means 230 generates rankings by sorting the service policies in the order of smallest to largest distance d, and transmits the service policy rankings (a set of combinations of rankings, service policy IDs, and service policies) to the privacy<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> information holder terminal 100 (the step B4).</p><p id="p0067" num="0067"><figref idrefs="f0013">Fig. 13</figref> shows an example of the service policy rankings generated and sorted by the ranking calculation means 231. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0012">Fig. 12</figref>, the service policy having the service policy ID "5" is displayed at the top since it has the smallest distance (d = 0) to the user policy.</p><p id="p0068" num="0068">Next, the ranking display means 120 receives and displays the service policy rankings. <figref idrefs="f0014">Fig. 14</figref> is an example of the service policy rankings displayed by the ranking display means 120 of the privacy information holder terminal 100 using the service policy rankings shown in <figref idrefs="f0013">Fig. 13</figref>.</p><p id="p0069" num="0069">Next, from the privacy information holder, the agreed policy selection means 130 of the privacy information holder terminal 100 receives the selection of a service policy (agreed policy) applied to his privacy information from the service policy rankings. For instance, the agreed policy selection means 130 can be realized by the selection buttons provided for the service policy rankings in <figref idrefs="f0014">Fig. 14</figref> or input means for entering a service policy ID (not shown in the drawing).</p><p id="p0070" num="0070">For instance, if the privacy information holder selects the service policy in first place, the service policy ID "5" is transmitted to the arbitration server 200 as an agreed policy.</p><p id="p0071" num="0071">Finally, the agreed policy receiving means 240 receives the agreed policy transmitted by the privacy information holder terminal 100 and stores it in the agreed policy storage means 250. <figref idrefs="f0015">Fig. 15</figref> is a drawing showing a state in which the selected agreed policy is stored in the agreed policy storage means 250, and the service policy ID "5" is registered as the agreed policy of the privacy information holder having the user ID "1."<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --></p><p id="p0072" num="0072">As described, in the present exemplary embodiment, it becomes possible to lead the user to agree to an agreed policy that he feels the most comfortable with by presenting rankings using the degree of divergence between the user policy entered by the privacy information holder using the user policy input means 110 and the service policies entered by the privacy information user in advance. Further, in the present exemplary embodiment, the total number of data types having "Do not provide" written in the user policy and "Acquire" in the service policy is calculated as the distance between the policies, however, it is possible to calculate the distance by weighting a particular data type containing sensitive private information so as to increase the distance.</p><heading id="h0014">(Second Exemplary Embodiment)</heading><p id="p0073" num="0073">Next, a second exemplary embodiment of the present invention, in which the configuration of the ranking generation means 230 in the first exemplary embodiment is changed so as to be able to present reference information for the selection of an agreed policy, will be described in detail with reference to the drawings. The differences from the first exemplary embodiment will be mainly explained below.</p><p id="p0074" num="0074"><figref idrefs="f0016">Fig. 16</figref> is a block diagram showing a configuration of ranking generation means 230A provided in an arbitration server of the second exemplary embodiment of the present invention. With reference to <figref idrefs="f0016">Fig. 16</figref>, policy difference calculation means 233 and service content acquiring means 234 are newly added to the ranking generation means 230 in the first exemplary embodiment.</p><p id="p0075" num="0075">The policy difference calculation means 233 drives an explanation regarding conflicting rules between a user policy and service policy.</p><p id="p0076" num="0076">The service content acquiring means 234 acquires an<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> explanation regarding the service provided by each service policy.</p><p id="p0077" num="0077">Ranking calculation means 231A of the present exemplary embodiment transmits service policy rankings, to which information sent from the policy difference calculation means 233 and the service content acquiring means 234 is added, to the privacy information holder terminal 100.</p><p id="p0078" num="0078"><figref idrefs="f0017">Fig. 17</figref> is an example of a service policy storage table stored in the service policy storage means of the arbitration server 200 of the present exemplary embodiment. This table differs from the table of the first exemplary embodiment, shown in <figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 8</figref>, in that fields describing the service content are added. The service content acquiring means 234 acquires an explanation regarding the service provided by each service policy from these fields describing the service content.</p><p id="p0079" num="0079">Next, with reference to a flowchart shown in <figref idrefs="f0018">Fig. 18</figref>, an operation of the ranking generation means 230A of the present exemplary embodiment will be described in detail.</p><p id="p0080" num="0080">First, a user policy and a set of service policies are entered into the ranking generation means 230A (step D1). Here, the user policy shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 6</figref> and the set of service policies shown in <figref idrefs="f0017">Fig. 17</figref> are assumed to be entered.</p><p id="p0081" num="0081">Next, the ranking generation means 230A repeats step D3 for each service policy (step D2). More concretely, the distance between the user policy and each service policy is calculated as in the first exemplary embodiment (the step D3). In the present exemplary embodiment, the calculation results shown in <figref idrefs="f0012">Fig. 12</figref> are assumed to be obtained as in the first exemplary embodiment.</p><p id="p0082" num="0082">Next, the policy difference calculation means 233 extracts<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> conflicting rules between the user policy and each service policy and generates texts explaining the differences (step D4). For instance, in a case of the service policy having the service policy ID "4," the rule of the data type "Position" is in conflict, and for example, a text saying, "Must provide the information "Position" that you do not want to provide" is generated as the explanation text.</p><p id="p0083" num="0083">Next, the service content acquiring means 234 acquires the service content from the service policy storage means 220 (step D5). For instance, in the case of the service policy having the service policy ID "4," the service content acquiring means 234 acquires "Provide recommendations based on location information" as the service content of the service policy.</p><p id="p0084" num="0084">Finally, the ranking calculation means 231A sorts the service policies in the order of smallest to largest distance, generates rankings with the texts explaining the differences and the service content added, and transmits the rankings to the privacy information holder terminal 100 (step D6).</p><p id="p0085" num="0085"><figref idrefs="f0019">Fig. 19</figref> is an example of the service policy rankings sorted and created by the ranking calculation means 231A of the present exemplary embodiment. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0012">Fig. 12</figref>, the service policy having the service policy ID "5" is displayed at the top since it has the smallest distance (d = 0) to the user policy. Further, the policy difference information is "NONE" because the service policy having the service policy ID "5" does not have any difference. Meanwhile, each of the other service policies has a difference; therefore, the content of the differences are displayed as the policy difference information.</p><p id="p0086" num="0086">Next, the ranking display means 120 receives and displays the service policy rankings. <figref idrefs="f0020">Fig. 20</figref> is an example of the service policy rankings displayed by the ranking display means 120 of the privacy<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> information holder terminal 100 using the service policy rankings shown in <figref idrefs="f0019">Fig. 19</figref>.</p><p id="p0087" num="0087">As described, in the present exemplary embodiment, it is possible to present the privacy information holder with the policy difference that explains conflicting rules between the user policy and each service policy, and the content of the service that the privacy information holder is able to receive when he agrees to each service policy, in addition to the user policy and the service policy rankings.</p><p id="p0088" num="0088">As a result, in the present exemplary embodiment, it becomes possible to encourage the privacy information holder to select a service policy in which a difference is recognized as an agreed policy by considering the service content thereof and the privacy information utilized, in addition to the effects of the first exemplary embodiment.</p><heading id="h0015">(Third Exemplary Embodiment)</heading><p id="p0089" num="0089">Next, a third exemplary embodiment of the present invention, in which the configuration of the policy distance calculation means 232 of the first exemplary embodiment is changed so as to enable more detailed calculation of the distance between the policies and more flexible policy arbitration, will be described in detail with reference to the drawings. The differences from the first exemplary embodiment will be mainly explained below.</p><p id="p0090" num="0090"><figref idrefs="f0021">Fig. 21</figref> is a block diagram showing a configuration of policy distance calculation means 232A in ranking generation means of an arbitration server of the third exemplary embodiment of the present invention. With reference to <figref idrefs="f0021">Fig. 21</figref>, the configuration comprises policy mapping means 2322 for mapping the action of each data type written in user and service policies to a protection vector, which is a real value or real-valued vector, action information storage means 2323 for storing the relation between the action and the real-valued vector, and vector distance calculation means 2321 for calculating the<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> distance between vectors using the protection vector. Here, the protection vector is a real value or real-valued vector indicating the level of privacy protection derived from the action, which is the content of a rule.</p><p id="p0091" num="0091">In the present exemplary embodiment, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0022">Fig. 22</figref>, as actions (how to handle privacy information, i.e., the content of a rule), not only the binary values ("Provide," "Do not provide," "Acquire," "Do not acquire"), but also an action "Protect" can be handled. Here, the action "Protect" indicates that processing of privacy protection will be provided. In the present exemplary embodiment, since the distance is not the simple calculation of the total number of conflicting rules as in the first and the second exemplary embodiments, an increase in the description capability of the policies can be supported.</p><p id="p0092" num="0092">Further, in the description of the present exemplary embodiment, the service policy storage means 220 is assumed to store service policies in which service policy IDs and the action "Protect" are set, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0023">Fig. 23</figref>.</p><p id="p0093" num="0093">Next, an operation of the present exemplary embodiment will be described in detail with reference to the drawings. First, a method for calculating the distance between user and service policies of the present exemplary embodiment (corresponding to the step B3 in <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4</figref> of the first exemplary embodiment) will be described. Note that explanations of the other operations are omitted since they are the same as those in the first exemplary embodiment.</p><p id="p0094" num="0094"><figref idrefs="f0024">Fig. 24</figref> is a flowchart showing an operation of the policy distance calculation means 232A of an arbitration server of the third exemplary embodiment of the present invention. With reference to <figref idrefs="f0024">Fig. 24</figref>, first a user policy and a service policy are entered into the policy distance calculation means 232A (step E1). Here, the user<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> policy shown in <figref idrefs="f0022">Fig. 22</figref> and the service policy having the service policy ID "3" shown in <figref idrefs="f0023">Fig. 23</figref> are assumed to be entered.</p><p id="p0095" num="0095">Next, the policy distance calculation means 232A breaks down the user policy into a set of pairs of data types and actions (Up = {(t_u, a_u)}) (step E2). For instance, the user policy in <figref idrefs="f0022">Fig. 22</figref> is broken down into Up = {("NAME," "Provide"), ("Address," "Do not provide"), ("Position," "Protect"), ("Buying," "Provide")}.</p><p id="p0096" num="0096">Next, the policy distance calculation means 232A breaks down the service policy into a set of pairs of data types and actions (Sp = {(t_s, a_s)}) (step E3). For instance, the service policy having the service policy ID "3" in <figref idrefs="f0023">Fig. 23</figref> is broken down into Sp = {("NAME," "Acquire"), ("Address," "Acquire"), ("Position," "Protect"), ("Buying," "Do not acquire")}.</p><p id="p0097" num="0097">Next, the policy mapping means 2322 maps the actions to protection vectors by referring to the action information storage means 2323 and maps the user policy Up to Up' = {(t_u, V_u)}, a set of pairs of the data types and the protection vectors (step E4).</p><p id="p0098" num="0098">The procedure of mapping the policy to the protection vectors in the step E4 will be described in detail with reference to <figref idrefs="f0025">Fig. 25</figref>.</p><p id="p0099" num="0099">First, a policy p = {(t, a)} is entered into the policy mapping means 2322. Here, the broken down user policy p = {("NAME," "Provide"), ("Address," "Do not provide"), ("Position," "Protect"), ("Buying," "Provide")} is entered.</p><p id="p0100" num="0100">Next, the policy mapping means 2322 executes the processing of step F3 on each data type t (step F2).</p><p id="p0101" num="0101">More concretely, for an action a associated with a data type t, the policy mapping means 2322 acquires a vector V associated with the<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --> action a from the action information storage means 2323 (the step F3). For instance, when the action information storage means 2323 defines the associations between the rules and the real-valued vectors in a table shown in <figref idrefs="f0026">Fig. 26</figref>, a one-dimensional vector V = (0) is acquired from the action "Provide" of the data type "NAME."</p><p id="p0102" num="0102">After completing the processing of the step F3 on each data type, the policy mapping means 2322 outputs a mapped policy p' = {(t, V)} (step F4). For instance, when the table shown in <figref idrefs="f0026">Fig. 26</figref> is used, mapped policy vectors p' = {("NAME," (0)), ("Address," (1)), ("Position," (0.5)), ("Buying," (0))} are obtained from the user policy shown in <figref idrefs="f0022">Fig. 22</figref>.</p><p id="p0103" num="0103">With reference to <figref idrefs="f0024">Fig. 24</figref> again, the policy mapping means 2322 refers to the action information storage means 2323 and maps the service policy Sp to a policy vector Sp' = {(t_s, V_s)}, a set of pairs of data types and protection vectors (step E5). By performing mapping as in the case of the user policy, mapped policy vectors p' = {("NAME," (0)), ("Address," (0)), ("Position," (0.5)), ("Buying," (1))} are obtained from the service policy having the service policy ID "3: in <figref idrefs="f0023">Fig. 23</figref>.</p><p id="p0104" num="0104">Finally, the service policy in <figref idrefs="f0023">Fig. 23</figref> is mapped as shown in <figref idrefs="f0027">Fig. 27</figref>. Next, the vector distance calculation means 2321 calculates a distance d between the mapped policies Up' and Sp' (step E6).</p><p id="p0105" num="0105">Here, the calculation of the distance between Up' and Sp' in the step E6 will be described with reference to a flowchart in <figref idrefs="f0028">Fig. 28</figref>.</p><p id="p0106" num="0106">First, the user policy vector Up' = {(t_u, V_u)} and the service policy vector Sp' = {(t_s, V_s)} are entered into the vector distance calculation means 2321 (step G1).</p><p id="p0107" num="0107">Next, the vector distance calculation means 2321 initializes the<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --> distance d to zero (step G2). Next, the vector distance calculation means 2321 executes the processing of steps G4 to G7 on each data type t_s of the service policy (step G3).</p><p id="p0108" num="0108">More concretely, the vector distance calculation means 2321 extracts pair combinations (t_u, V_u), (t_s, V_s) in which the data types match (t_s = t_u), and calculates Sr, the difference for each data type, as Sr = V_u_1 - V_s_1 (the step G4). Here, V_u_1 denotes a one-dimensional element of V_u. For instance, when t_s = "Address," V_u = (1), V_s = (0), and Sr is calculated as Sr = 1 - 0 = 1.</p><p id="p0109" num="0109">Next, the vector distance calculation means 2321 determines whether or not Sr satisfies Sr &lt; 0 (the step G5). When Yes, the operation moves to the step G6, and when No, it moves to the step G7. In the case of t_s = "Address," the operation moves to the step G7 since Sr = 1.</p><p id="p0110" num="0110">When Yes in the step G5, the vector distance calculation means 2321 deems Sr to be zero (the step G6).</p><p id="p0111" num="0111">Next, the vector distance calculation means 2321 lets d = d + Sr (the step G7).</p><p id="p0112" num="0112">After completing the steps G4 to G7 on each t_s, the vector distance calculation means 2321 outputs the distance d (step G8). From the sum of the differences between the mapped policy p' = {("NAME," (0)), ("Address," (1)), ("Position," (0.5)), ("Buying," (0))} derived from the user policy in <figref idrefs="f0022">Fig. 22</figref> and p' = {("NAME," (0)), ("Address," (0)), ("Position," (0.5)), ("Buying," (1))} in the case of the service policy having the service policy ID "3" in <figref idrefs="f0023">Fig. 23</figref>, d = 1 is outputted.</p><p id="p0113" num="0113"><figref idrefs="f0029">Fig. 29</figref> is a drawing showing the results of calculating the distances between the user policy in <figref idrefs="f0022">Fig. 22</figref> and all the service<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> policies in <figref idrefs="f0023">Fig. 23</figref>.</p><p id="p0114" num="0114">The ranking generation means of the present exemplary embodiment generates service policy rankings using the distances calculated as described.</p><p id="p0115" num="0115">As described, according to the present exemplary embodiment, policy arbitration can be performed for various policy formats. The reason is that the policy mapping means 2322 maps policies to real-valued vectors based on the information stored in the action information storage means 2323, and using these vectors, the vector distance calculation means 2321 calculates the distance between the policies by calculating the distances between the vectors.</p><p id="p0116" num="0116">Further, in the exemplary embodiment described above, the protection vectors are derived from the actions, regardless of the data type, using the table shown in <figref idrefs="f0026">Fig. 26</figref>, however, it is possible to define the value of a protection vector corresponding to an action for each data type. In this way, the distance can be calculated to be large for a conflict regarding sensitive privacy information.</p><p id="p0117" num="0117">It should be noted that other objects, features and aspects of the present invention will become apparent in the entire disclosure and that modifications may be done without departing the gist and scope of the present invention as disclosed herein and claimed as appended herewith.<br/>
Also it should be noted that any combination of the disclosed and/or claimed elements, matters and/or items may fall under the modifications aforementioned.<br/>
For instance, the data types of the user policies and the service policies cited in the descriptions of the exemplary embodiments are merely examples, and they can be suitably changed according to the privacy information to which the present invention is applied.</p><p id="p0118" num="0118"><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --> Further, the flowcharts used to describe the exemplary embodiment above are shown in simplified forms to facilitate understanding of the present invention and it is possible to add various modifications thereto.</p><p id="p0119" num="0119">Finally, preferred modes of the present invention are summarized.
<ul><li>(MODE 1)<br/>
Refer to the policy arbitration method according to the first aspect.</li><li>(MODE 2)<br/>
The policy arbitration method according to Mode 1, wherein<br/>
the service policy ranking is obtained by sorting the service policy set in an order of smallest to largest degree of divergence between the user policy and the service policy.</li><li>(MODE 3)<br/>
The policy arbitration method according to Mode 1 or 2, wherein a number of conflicting rules between the user policy and the service policy is used to calculate the degree of divergence between the user policy and the service policy.</li><li>(MODE 4)<br/>
The policy arbitration method according to any one of Modes 1 to 3, wherein<br/>
calculating the degree of divergence between the user policy and the service policy comprises:
<ul><li>mapping the user policy to a user policy vector by converting the rule into a real value or real-valued vector;</li><li>mapping the service policy to a service policy vector by converting the rule into a real value or real-valued vector; and</li><li>calculating the degree of divergence using the user policy vector and the service policy vector.</li></ul></li><li>(MODE 5)<br/>
The policy arbitration method according to any one of Modes 1 to 4, further comprising:
<ul><li>extracting a difference between the user policy and the service policy;<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --> and</li><li>displaying the difference as information accompanying the service policy ranking.</li></ul></li><li>(MODE 6)<br/>
The policy arbitration method according to any one of Modes 1 to 5, further comprising:
<ul><li>extracting a characteristic of the service policy; and</li><li>displaying the characteristic of the service policy as information accompanying the service policy ranking.</li></ul></li><li>(MODE 7)<br/>
Refer to the arbitration server according to the second aspect.</li><li>(MODE 8)<br/>
The arbitration server according to Mode 7, wherein<br/>
the ranking generation means generates a ranking in which the service policy set is sorted in an order of smallest to largest degree of divergence between the user policy and the service policy.</li><li>(MODE 9)<br/>
The arbitration server according to Mode 7 or 8, wherein<br/>
the ranking generation means comprises policy distance calculation means for calculating the degree of divergence between the user policy and the service policy, by using a number of conflicting rules between the user policy and the service policy.</li><li>(MODE 10)<br/>
The arbitration server according to any one of Modes 7 to 9, wherein the ranking generation means comprises:
<ul><li>policy mapping means for mapping the user policy and the service policy to a user policy vector and service policy vector, respectively, by converting the rule into a real value or real-valued vector; and</li><li>vector distance calculation means for calculating the degree of divergence using the user policy vector and the service policy vector.</li></ul></li><li>(MODE 11)<br/>
The arbitration server according to any one of Modes 7 to 10, further comprising action information storage means for storing a table that defines a real value or real-valued vector corresponding to content of<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --> the rule, wherein<br/>
the rule is converted into a real value or real-valued vector by referring to the table.</li><li>(MODE 12)<br/>
The arbitration server according to any one of Modes 7 to 11, wherein the table of the action information storage means defines a real value or real-valued vector corresponding to content of the rule for each data type.</li><li>(MODE 13)<br/>
The arbitration server according to any one of Modes 7 to 12, further comprising policy difference calculation means for extracting a difference between the user policy and the service policy, wherein<br/>
the difference is displayed as information accompanying the service policy ranking.</li><li>(MODE 14)<br/>
The arbitration server according to any one of Modes 7 to 13, further comprising service content acquiring means for extracting a characteristic of the service policy, wherein<br/>
the characteristic of the service policy is displayed as information accompanying the service policy ranking.</li><li>(MODE 15)<br/>
Refer to the program according to the third aspect.<br/>
The entire disclosures of the above Patent Literatures and Non-Patent Literatures are incorporated herein by reference thereto. Modifications and adjustments of the exemplary embodiment are possible within the scope of the overall disclosure (including the claims) of the present invention and based on the basic technical concept of the present invention. Various combinations and selections of various disclosed elements (including each element of each claim, each element of each exemplary embodiment, each element of each drawing, etc.) are possible within the scope of the claims of the present invention. That is, the present invention of course includes various variations and modifications that could be made by those skilled in the art according to the overall disclosure including<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --> the claims and the technical concept.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0016">[Industrial Applicability]</heading><p id="p0120" num="0120">The present invention can be applied to uses such as a recommendation service utilizing privacy information and privacy policy arbitration in an SNS (Social Networking Service).</p><heading id="h0017">[Reference Signs List]</heading><p id="p0121" num="0121"><ul><li>100: privacy information holder terminal</li><li>110: user policy input means</li><li>120: ranking display means</li><li>130: agreed policy selection means</li><li>200: arbitration server</li><li>210: user policy receiving means</li><li>220: service policy storage means</li><li>230, 230A: ranking generation means</li><li>231, 231A: ranking calculation means</li><li>232, 232A: policy distance calculation means</li><li>233: policy difference calculation means</li><li>234: service content acquiring means</li><li>2321: vector distance calculation means</li><li>2322: policy mapping means</li><li>2323: action information storage means</li><li>240: agreed policy receiving means</li><li>250: agreed policy storage means</li></ul></p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56982046" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --><claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A policy arbitration method, comprising:
<claim-text>entering a user policy in which a privacy information holder describes at least one rule that is a pair of a data type of privacy information possessed by the privacy information holder and the way to handle the data type;</claim-text>
<claim-text>generating, using the user policy and a service policy set that includes at least one service policy in which a privacy information user describes at least one rule that is a pair of a data type of the privacy information and the way to handle the data type, a ranking of the service policy according to the degree of divergence between the user policy and the service policy;</claim-text>
<claim-text>displaying the service policy ranking on a privacy information holder terminal; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>having the privacy information holder select one service policy from the service policy ranking.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The policy arbitration method according to Claim 1, wherein<br/>
the service policy ranking is obtained by sorting the service policy set in an order of smallest to largest degree of divergence between the user policy and the service policy.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The policy arbitration method according to Claim 1 or 2, wherein<br/>
a number of conflicting rules between the user policy and the service policy is used to calculate the degree of divergence between the user policy and the service policy.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The policy arbitration method according to Claim 1 or 2, wherein<br/>
calculating the degree of divergence between the user policy and the service policy comprises:
<claim-text>mapping the user policy to a user policy vector by converting<!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --> the rule into a real value or real-valued vector;</claim-text>
<claim-text>mapping the service policy to a service policy vector by converting the rule into a real value or real-valued vector; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>calculating the degree of divergence using the user policy vector and the service policy vector.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The policy arbitration method according to any one of Claims 1 to 4, further comprising:
<claim-text>extracting a difference between the user policy and the service policy; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>displaying the difference as information accompanying the service policy ranking.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The policy arbitration method according to any one of Claims 1 to 5, further comprising:
<claim-text>extracting a characteristic of the service policy; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>displaying the characteristic of the service policy as information accompanying the service policy ranking.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>An arbitration server, comprising:
<claim-text>user policy receiving means for receiving from a user a user policy describing at least one rule that is a pair of a data type of privacy information possessed by the user and the way to handle the data type;</claim-text>
<claim-text>ranking generation means for generating, using the user policy and a service policy set that includes at least one service policy describing at least one rule that is a pair of a data type of the privacy information and the way to handle the data type, a ranking of the service policy based on the degree of divergence between the user policy and the service policy; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>agreed policy receiving means for receiving from the user who has referred to the service policy ranking selection of a service policy to be applied to the privacy information of the user.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008"><claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --> The arbitration server according to Claim 7, wherein<br/>
the ranking generation means generates a ranking in which the service policy set is sorted in an order of smallest to largest degree of divergence between the user policy and the service policy.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The arbitration server according to Claim 7 or 8, wherein<br/>
the ranking generation means comprises policy distance calculation means for calculating the degree of divergence between the user policy and the service policy, by using a number of conflicting rules between the user policy and the service policy.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The arbitration server according to Claim 7 or 8, wherein<br/>
the ranking generation means comprises:
<claim-text>policy mapping means for mapping the user policy and the service policy to a user policy vector and service policy vector, respectively, by converting the rule into a real value or real-valued vector; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>vector distance calculation means for calculating the degree of divergence using the user policy vector and the service policy vector.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16670439" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="165" he="225" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="165" he="196" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="36"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="165" he="219" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="37"> --><figure id="f0004" num="4"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="165" he="221" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="38"> --><figure id="f0005" num="5"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="162" he="199" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="39"> --><figure id="f0006" num="6"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="131" he="218" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="40"> --><figure id="f0007" num="7"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="135" he="212" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="41"> --><figure id="f0008" num="8"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="165" he="195" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="42"> --><figure id="f0009" num="9"><img id="if0009" file="imgf0009.tif" wi="165" he="203" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="43"> --><figure id="f0010" num="10"><img id="if0010" file="imgf0010.tif" wi="165" he="205" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="44"> --><figure id="f0011" num="11"><img id="if0011" file="imgf0011.tif" wi="165" he="194" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="45"> --><figure id="f0012" num="12"><img id="if0012" file="imgf0012.tif" wi="165" he="155" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="46"> --><figure id="f0013" num="13"><img id="if0013" file="imgf0013.tif" wi="165" he="187" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="47"> --><figure id="f0014" num="14"><img id="if0014" file="imgf0014.tif" wi="163" he="232" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="48"> --><figure id="f0015" num="15"><img id="if0015" file="imgf0015.tif" wi="165" he="174" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="49"> --><figure id="f0016" num="16"><img id="if0016" file="imgf0016.tif" wi="165" he="181" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="50"> --><figure id="f0017" num="17"><img id="if0017" file="imgf0017.tif" wi="156" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="51"> --><figure id="f0018" num="18"><img id="if0018" file="imgf0018.tif" wi="165" he="199" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="52"> --><figure id="f0019" num="19"><img id="if0019" file="imgf0019.tif" wi="161" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="53"> --><figure id="f0020" num="20"><img id="if0020" file="imgf0020.tif" wi="165" he="202" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="54"> --><figure id="f0021" num="21"><img id="if0021" file="imgf0021.tif" wi="165" he="197" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="55"> --><figure id="f0022" num="22"><img id="if0022" file="imgf0022.tif" wi="141" he="224" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="56"> --><figure id="f0023" num="23"><img id="if0023" file="imgf0023.tif" wi="165" he="205" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="57"> --><figure id="f0024" num="24"><img id="if0024" file="imgf0024.tif" wi="156" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="58"> --><figure id="f0025" num="25"><img id="if0025" file="imgf0025.tif" wi="165" he="181" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="59"> --><figure id="f0026" num="26"><img id="if0026" file="imgf0026.tif" wi="165" he="169" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="60"> --><figure id="f0027" num="27"><img id="if0027" file="imgf0027.tif" wi="148" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="61"> --><figure id="f0028" num="28"><img id="if0028" file="imgf0028.tif" wi="165" he="214" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="62"> --><figure id="f0029" num="29"><img id="if0029" file="imgf0029.tif" wi="163" he="168" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><search-report-data><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="165" he="227" type="tif"/></search-report-data><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
