<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2682800-A1" country="EP" doc-number="2682800" kind="A1" date="20140108" family-id="46757388" file-reference-id="288600" date-produced="20180824" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146584952" ucid="EP-2682800-A1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2682800</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-12752435-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154847144" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12752435</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120227</date><lang>ES</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP220439868" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12752435.3</doc-number><date>20120227</date><lang>ES</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140552220" ucid="ES-201130259-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>ES</country><doc-number>201130259</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20110228</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140550344" ucid="ES-2012070116-W" linkage-type="W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>ES</country><doc-number>2012070116</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20120227</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989316185" load-source="docdb">G01B   9/04        20060101ALI20120920BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989322679" load-source="docdb">G02B  21/00        20060101AFI20120920BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989632096" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G01B   9/04        20130101 FI20130921BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989650499" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G02B  21/14        20130101 LI20130921BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132359489" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">VERFAHREN UND SYSTEM ZUR HERSTELLUNG QUANTITATIVER BILDER IN EINER PHASENKONTRASTMIKROSKOPIE</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132359490" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">METHOD AND SYSTEM FOR PRODUCING QUANTITATIVE IMAGES IN OPTICAL PHASE MICROSCOPY</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132359491" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">PROCÉDÉ ET SYSTÈME POUR OBTENIR DES IMAGES QUANTITATIVES DE PHASE EN MICROSCOPIE OPTIQUE</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919530920" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>UNIV MURCIA</last-name><address><country>ES</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919530027" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>UNIVERSIDAD DE MURCIA</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919009674" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Universidad De Murcia</last-name><iid>101134397</iid><address><street>Avda. Teniente Flomesta N°5</street><city>30003 Murcia</city><country>ES</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919532443" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>IGLESIAS CASARRUBIOS JOSE IGNACIO</last-name><address><country>ES</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919513849" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>IGLESIAS CASARRUBIOS, Jose, Ignacio</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919012500" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>IGLESIAS CASARRUBIOS, Jose, Ignacio</last-name><address><street>Avda. Teniente Flomesta nº 5</street><city>E-30003 Murcia</city><country>ES</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919008452" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Carpintero Lopez, Francisco</last-name><suffix>et al</suffix><iid>100026283</iid><address><street>Herrero &amp; Asociados, S.L. Alcalá 35</street><city>28014 Madrid</city><country>ES</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="ES-2012070116-W"><document-id><country>ES</country><doc-number>2012070116</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20120227</date><lang>ES</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2012117139-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2012117139</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20120907</date><lang>ES</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549812790" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS549741477" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549812791" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549808827" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549742896" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549815621" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549741478" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549813502" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549812792" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549815638" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549740474" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549808828" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549808829" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549813503" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549812793" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549813504" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549815639" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549742909" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549812798" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549808830" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549812799" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549813505" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549741479" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549813510" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549813511" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549741480" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS549741493" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549740475" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549907766" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549740476" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549741494" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549740477" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549741495" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS549740478" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549815640" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549907767" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549907768" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS549811990" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA128673124" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p id="pa01" num="0001">The present invention relates to a method for obtaining images of samples in optical microscopy which allows obtaining images with complete quantitative phase information or optical path difference of microscopic samples (M) by means of generating simultaneous phase gradient images.</p><p id="pa02" num="0002">The light emerging from the sample, illuminated by a variety of plane waves, is split into four beams using optical or electro-optical means. The image of the sample with the four beams is simultaneously generated on an array sensor. The images are directly related to the gradient. A numerical integration algorithm obtains the phase from the gradient information.</p><p id="pa03" num="0003">The present invention is particularly useful as a microscopy technique in biology and biomedicine.<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="78" he="98" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA128737273" lang="EN" source="EPO" load-source="docdb"><p>The present invention relates to a method for obtaining images of samples in optical microscopy which allows obtaining images with complete quantitative phase information or optical path difference of microscopic samples (M) by means of generating simultaneous phase gradient images.  The light emerging from the sample, illuminated by a variety of plane waves, is split into four beams using optical or electro-optical means. The image of the sample with the four beams is simultaneously generated on an array sensor. The images are directly related to the gradient. A numerical integration algorithm obtains the phase from the gradient information.  The present invention is particularly useful as a microscopy technique in biology and biomedicine.</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES63959112" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001"><u>Object of the Invention</u></heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to a method and system for obtaining images of microscopic objects with quantitative phase information particularly suitable for studying samples of biological interest.</p><heading id="h0002"><u>Background of the Invention</u></heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">If is often impossible or inappropriate to use staining in microscopy. In these cases, the biological media are often transparent, such that they can only be seen through the detection of refractive index variation. When light passes through these media, this spatial index variation is imprinted in the phase of the light electric field. Unfortunately, the phase cannot be directly seen. To solve this difficulty, there are different conventional techniques such as the Zernike microscope or the Nomarski microscope. Commercial microscopes include the possibility of the use thereof, however, the information provided is partial: the presence of structures related to index variations can be detected but not quantified. Subsequently, interferential (holographic) techniques have been proposed (<nplcit id="ncit0001" npl-type="s"><text>Cuche, E., F. Bevilacqua, et al. (1999). "Digital holography for quantitative phase-contrast imaging." Opt. Lett. 24(5): 291-293</text></nplcit>; <nplcit id="ncit0002" npl-type="s"><text>Charrière, F., A. Marian, et al. (2006). "Cell refractive index tomography by digital holographic microscopy." Opt. Lett. 31 (2): 178-180</text></nplcit>) which provide complete information but involve the use of coherent light, reference beams and require maintaining mechanical stability in the system during recording. Direct phase detection with a sensor based on the lateral displacement technique, <nplcit id="ncit0003" npl-type="s"><text>Bon, P., G. Maucort, et al. (2009). "Quadriwave lateral shearing interferometry for quantitative phase microscopy of living cells." Opt. Express 17(15): 13080-13094</text></nplcit>, has instead been proposed but it involves instrumental complexity and has limitations relating to light coherence and obtainable data density.</p><heading id="h0003"><u>Description of the Invention</u></heading><p id="p0003" num="0003">The illumination and data acquisition system in quantitative phase microscopy proposed by the invention solves in a fully satisfactory manner the problem described above in the different mentioned aspects. Particularly: it simplifies the method and provides great data density in an adjustable manner.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">To that end, the invention is based on conjugating, by means of a<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> microscope objective and other conventional optical components, the light that has passed through the sample on an intermediate plane where it is split into four parts by means of an optical or electro-optical device. Once split, the light is optically led to an array sensor detecting four images of the sample which are digitally processed, giving rise to a two-dimensional map of the phase change generated by the sample.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">The plane where the light beam is divided into four beams is a focal plane or a plane where the Fourier transform of the electric field has been generated.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">In a preferred example, the preceding split is produced by means of a refractive optical device consisting of a four-sided pyramid the vertices of which define the spatial location of two X and Y axes, the Z axis corresponding to the optical axis of the entire optical system. Each of the prisms making up the pyramid deflects the light towards its respective opposite bases.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">The optics after the beam splitting component conjugates the plane of the sample with a matrix sensor such as a CCD where four simultaneous images are obtained. Such optics can be variable such that it allows modifying the magnifications of the sample on the sensor and therefore sampling of the phase.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">Under static conditions, the sensor records signals relating to the local phase gradient of the phase introduced by the sample but with a restricted range of measurement and little gain. To improve gain, it is advantageous to modulate the system.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">In an alternative configuration, the modulation is obtained by means of the oscillation of the beam or of the splitter device during image acquisition time, such that the recorded signal is proportional to the gradient, the gain being established through controlling oscillation amplitude. In these conditions, the phase gradient <maths id="math0001" num=""><math display="inline"><mfenced><mfrac><mrow><mo>∂</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Φ</mi></mrow><mrow><mo>∂</mo><mi>x</mi></mrow></mfrac><mfrac><mrow><mo>∂</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">Φ</mi></mrow><mrow><mo>∂</mo><mi>y</mi></mrow></mfrac></mfenced></math><img id="ib0001" file="imgb0001.tif" wi="17" he="12" img-content="math" img-format="tif" inline="yes"/></maths> is proportional to the signals (<i>S<sub>x</sub></i>(<i>x,y</i>),<i>S<sub>y</sub></i>(<i>x,y</i>)) obtained from the four images <i>I<sub>i</sub></i>(<i>x,y</i>) in the sensor by means of the expressions <maths id="math0002" num=""><math display="block"><msub><mi>S</mi><mi>x</mi></msub><mfenced><mi>x</mi><mi>y</mi></mfenced><mo>=</mo><mfrac><mrow><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi>I</mi><mn>1</mn></msub><mfenced><mi>x</mi><mi>y</mi></mfenced><mo>+</mo><msub><mi>I</mi><mn>4</mn></msub><mfenced><mi>x</mi><mi>y</mi></mfenced></mfenced><mo>-</mo><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi>I</mi><mn>2</mn></msub><mfenced><mi>x</mi><mi>y</mi></mfenced><mo>+</mo><msub><mi>I</mi><mn>3</mn></msub><mfenced><mi>x</mi><mi>y</mi></mfenced></mfenced></mrow><mstyle displaystyle="false"><mstyle displaystyle="true"><munder><mo>∑</mo><mi>i</mi></munder></mstyle><msub><mi>I</mi><mi>i</mi></msub><mfenced><mi>x</mi><mi>y</mi></mfenced></mstyle></mfrac></math><img id="ib0002" file="imgb0002.tif" wi="94" he="20" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> <maths id="math0003" num=""><math display="block"><msub><mi>S</mi><mi>y</mi></msub><mfenced><mi>x</mi><mi>y</mi></mfenced><mo>=</mo><mfrac><mrow><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi>I</mi><mn>1</mn></msub><mfenced><mi>x</mi><mi>y</mi></mfenced><mo>+</mo><msub><mi>I</mi><mn>2</mn></msub><mfenced><mi>x</mi><mi>y</mi></mfenced></mfenced><mo>-</mo><mfenced separators=""><msub><mi>I</mi><mn>3</mn></msub><mfenced><mi>x</mi><mi>y</mi></mfenced><mo>+</mo><msub><mi>I</mi><mn>4</mn></msub><mfenced><mi>x</mi><mi>y</mi></mfenced></mfenced></mrow><mstyle displaystyle="false"><mstyle displaystyle="true"><munder><mo>∑</mo><mi>i</mi></munder></mstyle><msub><mi>I</mi><mi>i</mi></msub><mfenced><mi>x</mi><mi>y</mi></mfenced></mstyle></mfrac></math><img id="ib0003" file="imgb0003.tif" wi="94" he="18" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths><!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p><p id="p0010" num="0010">Finally, the phase is computationally reconstructed from the gradient information with an integration algorithm.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">In a preferred alternative configuration, signal modulation is statically obtained by means of illuminating the sample using a symmetrical, planar incoherent light emitting surface of controllable extent as a source. This source is optically led to the plane of the sample such that in view of the incoherence of the source, it can be considered that a plurality of collimated beams with different angles with respect to the optical axis simultaneously pass through the sample, simultaneously generating a plurality of Fourier transforms laterally displaced on the beam splitter element. The extent of the source is responsible for the system gain given that the distance from a point of the source to the optical axis is directly related to the displacement generated on the beam splitter element.</p><heading id="h0004"><u>Description of the Drawings</u></heading><p id="p0012" num="0012">To complement the description that is being made and for the purpose of aiding to better understand the features of the invention according to a preferred practical embodiment thereof, a set of drawings in which the following has been depicted with an illustrative and non-limiting character is attached as an integral part of said description:
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> schematically shows the general principle of the proposed instrument.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref> illustrates the method based on the images involved.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0005"><u>Preferred Embodiment of the Invention</u></heading><p id="p0013" num="0013">In view of the described drawings, it can be seen how the method of the invention is based on using an optical system for conjugating the light emerging through the sample on a detector once the beam has been split preferably by the effect of a pyramidal refractive component in the plane corresponding to the Fourier transform.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">As depicted in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1(a)</figref>, a sample (M) is illuminated with an incoherent light source consisting of an extensive emitter (F) having a diaphragm (D) coupled thereto for controlling the extent of the source. This diaphragm is located on the focal plane before a lens such that after exiting the lens (L1) the light beam can be considered a superposition of plane waves with various propagation directions distributed symmetrically about the optical axis. The field thus generated after exiting the lens is optically conjugated by means of lenses (L2) and (L3) on the sample (M).<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p><p id="p0015" num="0015">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1(b)</figref>, a microscope objective (OM) and a lens (L4) conjugate the light emerging from the sample on a lens (L5). The refractive pyramid (P) is located on the image focal plane of this lens. A lens (L6) is used for conjugating the plane of the sample on an array sensor (S).</p><p id="p0016" num="0016"><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2(a)</figref> shows the phase delay or optical path difference generated by a sample consisting of two transparent microspheres. <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2(b)</figref> shows the image which would be obtained by the sensor. The images of <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2(c) and 2(d)</figref> show the gradients in the X and Y directions calculated from the preceding image. <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2(e)</figref> shows the image corresponding to the phase reconstructed from integrating the information contained in the preceding images.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56982137" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --><claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Method for obtaining phase images of samples in optical microscopy, <b>characterized in that</b> it comprises the steps of:
<claim-text>- a. illuminating a sample (M) by means of a light beam,</claim-text>
<claim-text>- b. conjugating the light that has passed through the sample in an intermediate plane where the beam is split into four beams by means of an optical or electro-optical splitter device (P), gradient information thus being obtained</claim-text>
<claim-text>- c. optically leading the light beams resulting from the split to an array sensor (S)</claim-text>
<claim-text>- d. applying a numerical integration algorithm for obtaining the phase from the recorded gradient information</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Method according to claim 1, <b>characterized in that</b> the signal is modulated before illuminating the sample by means of using an incoherent light source of controllable extent with a planar emission surface.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Method according to claim 1, <b>characterized in that</b> the signal is modulated by means of the oscillation of the beam after passing through the sample (M).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Method according to claim 1, <b>characterized in that</b> the signal is modulated by means of the oscillation of the splitter device (P).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Method according to any of the preceding claims, <b>characterized in that</b> the beam splitter is a four-sided pyramid.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Phase microscopy system for carrying out the method of claim 5, <b>characterized in that</b> it comprises an incoherent light emitting source (F), with an extendable planar emission surface, optical means for transmitting the light through a plane of sample (M), an array sensor (S), a four-sided pyramid located on a plane between the sample and the sensor (S) to separate the beam into four beams, thus obtaining gradient information and programming means for applying a numerical integration algorithm for obtaining the phase from the gradient information.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16670527" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1(a),1(b)"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="138" he="177" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2(a),2(b),2(c),2(d),2(e)"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="141" he="132" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><search-report-data><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="155" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="155" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0003" file="srep0003.tif" wi="155" he="233" type="tif"/></search-report-data><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
