<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2959272-A1" country="EP" doc-number="2959272" kind="A1" date="20151230" family-id="48145589" file-reference-id="313851" date-produced="20180825" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="160452859" ucid="EP-2959272-A1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2959272</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20151230</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-14708692-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP193868686" load-source="patent-office" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>14708692.0</doc-number><date>20140224</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP193868687" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>14708692</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20140224</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC162035096" ucid="IB-2014059205-W" linkage-type="W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>IB</country><doc-number>2014059205</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20140224</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC162036560" ucid="IT-PD20130041-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>IT</country><doc-number>PD20130041</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20130225</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1988520688" load-source="docdb">B67D   3/00        20060101ALI20140911BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1988520907" load-source="docdb">B67D   3/02        20060101ALI20140911BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1988522460" load-source="docdb">A47L  13/50        20060101ALI20140911BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1988523006" load-source="docdb">F16K  31/528       20060101ALI20140911BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1988523647" load-source="docdb">G01F  11/32        20060101AFI20140911BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1981010755" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A47L  13/50        20130101 FI20160122BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1981011048" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F16K  31/528       20130101 LI20160121BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1981014057" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B67D   3/0045      20130101 LI20160122BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1981014179" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G01F  11/32        20130101 LI20160122BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT165550043" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">VENTILKÖRPER EINER DOSIERVORRICHTUNG</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT165550044" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">VALVE BODY OF A DOSING DEVICE</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT165550045" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">CORPS DE SOUPAPE D'UN DISPOSITIF DE DOSAGE</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR1103317622" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>T T S CLEANING S R L</last-name><address><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR1103342219" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>T.T.S. CLEANING S.R.L.</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR1101642237" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>T.T.S. Cleaning S.r.l.</last-name><iid>101543661</iid><address><street>Via dell'Artigianato N°. 12/14</street><city>35010 Santa Giustina in Colle (PD)</city><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1103319626" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>ZORZO RENATO</last-name><address><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1103341642" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>ZORZO, RENATO</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1101646864" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>ZORZO, RENATO</last-name><address><street>Via Roncà 17</street><city>I-35010 Onara di Tombolo (PD)</city><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="IB-2014059205-W"><document-id><country>IB</country><doc-number>2014059205</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20140224</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2014128670-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2014128670</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140828</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS660629022" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS660790367" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS660629032" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS660709852" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS660714654" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS660630140" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS660790368" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS660629033" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS660630141" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS660630142" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS660707969" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS660709853" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS660709854" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS660629034" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS660630147" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS660629039" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS660790369" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS660714659" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS660630148" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS660709859" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS660630149" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS660733211" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS660630068" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS660733212" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS660733213" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS660630069" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS660630070" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS660790370" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS660707970" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS660714660" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS660733223" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS660790371" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS660733224" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS660714661" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS660709860" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS660707975" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS660714662" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS660630079" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states><ep-extended-states><ep-extended-state-data><country>BA</country></ep-extended-state-data><ep-extended-state-data><country>ME</country></ep-extended-state-data></ep-extended-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA139078902" ref-ucid="WO-2014128670-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p num="0000">The object of this invention is a valve body of a cleaning appliance, specifically a dosing device, whose valve body can open and close the inlet and outlet pipes of the dosing chamber of said dosing device, to release a correct amount of detergent for soaking a cleaning cloth.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA139545457" ref-ucid="WO-2014128670-A1" lang="EN" source="national office" load-source="docdb"><p>The object of this invention is a valve body of a cleaning appliance, specifically a dosing device, whose valve body can open and close the inlet and outlet pipes of the dosing chamber of said dosing device, to release a correct amount of detergent for soaking a cleaning cloth.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA139078903" ref-ucid="WO-2014128670-A1" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><p num="0000">L'invention concerne un corps de soupape d'un dispositif de nettoyage, en particulier un dispositif de dosage, dont le corps de soupape peut ouvrir et fermer les tuyaux d'entrée et de sortie de la chambre de dosage dudit dispositif de dosage, pour libérer une quantité correcte de détergent dont on souhaite imprégner un chiffon de nettoyage.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA139545458" ref-ucid="WO-2014128670-A1" lang="FR" source="national office" load-source="docdb"><p>L'invention concerne un corps de soupape d'un dispositif de nettoyage, en particulier un dispositif de dosage, dont le corps de soupape peut ouvrir et fermer les tuyaux d'entrée et de sortie de la chambre de dosage dudit dispositif de dosage, pour libérer une quantité correcte de détergent dont on souhaite imprégner un chiffon de nettoyage.</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES78479816" ref-ucid="WO-2014128670-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><invention-title lang="EN"> VALVE BODY OF A DOSING DEVICE 
	 </invention-title><technical-field><heading id="h01">Technical Field</heading><p id="p02" num="1"> The field of application of the invention concerns a
		valve body of a cleaning appliance, specifically a dosing device, whose valve
		body can open and close the inlet and outlet pipes of the dosing chamber of
		said dosing device, to release the right amount of detergent for soaking a
		cleaning cloth. </p></technical-field><background-art><heading id="h03">Background Art</heading><p id="p44" num="2"> It is well known that all appliances in the
		professional sector have to meet higher levels of quality than those to be used
		in a domestic setting.</p><p id="p43" num="3"> This quality level refers both to the construction
		material as well as to the relative design, so that said appliances are durable
		and easy to use, in order to facilitate the continuous operations of a sector
		operator, and furthermore that said equipment can use and consume just the
		amount of detergent that is strictly necessary for cleaning requirements.</p><p id="p42" num="4"> Another important aspect of such appliances is that
		when needed they can be quickly restored to their full functionality following
		a simple and practical maintenance operation.</p><p id="p41" num="5"> It is very clear that said maintenance operations,
		which often concern the parts that are subject to wear, are carried out not by
		cleaning personnel but by specific personnel specialised in maintenance and
		reconditioning.</p><p id="p40" num="6"> This service, which is very often entrusted to
		outside companies, is important and crucial for establishing how successful an
		article is commercially.</p><p id="p39" num="7"> Bearing this in mind, one of the aspects that
		increasingly characterises professional cleaning is the end quality carried out
		with the minimum, but at the same time correct, amount of detergent.</p><p id="p38" num="8"> One piece of equipment that allows you to carry out
		the above-mentioned objectives is concretised in a calibrated dosing device for
		cleaning detergents.</p><p id="p37" num="9"> Indeed, a detergent dosing device has the aim of
		releasing an exact amount of liquid detergent into a specific soaking basin,
		inside which a cleaning cloth is then placed.</p><p id="p36" num="10"> It is very clear that both the dilution of the
		chemical concentrate, as well as the amount of detergent to be released are
		fixed previously according to requirements, like for example the type of cloth
		used and the type of floor to be cleaned and the dirt to be treated.</p><p id="p35" num="11"> In the past there have been attempts to pursue
		these aims with equipment that in many ways have proven to be
		unsatisfactory.</p><p id="p34" num="12"> In fact, the complexity and poor versatility of the
		current detergent dosing devices is well known, which include a top tank that
		is joined to a dosing chamber underneath, inside which there is a valve
		operated by actuating devices controlled by the operator, to release the liquid
		stored inside the chamber itself, into a basin underneath.</p><p id="p33" num="13"> An example of such devices is shown in
		US4174977.</p><p id="p32" num="14"> Later, by adopting a dosing device with a variable
		volume of the type shown in DE3724849, the volume of the dosing chamber was
		rendered variable, to release a pre-set amount of liquid.</p><p id="p31" num="15"> One of these dosing devices, with a variable volume
		chamber of the type shown in DE3724849, and of the same type shown in
		US4174977, but with a complicated, intricate valve, is shown in EP1736091.</p><p id="p30" num="16"> In fact the valve used in the device shown in
		EP1736091 is composed of numerous moving parts connected together with numerous
		springs: and all within the dosing chamber and constantly dampened by the
		detergent.</p><p id="p29" num="17"> These and other examples of previous dosing devices
		for releasing a pre-set amount of detergent, have proven to be poorly accepted
		by professional operators because of their inherent drawbacks.</p><p id="p28" num="18"> One of the main drawbacks of current dosing devices
		concerns the difficult maintenance and the replacement of worn parts, with
		lengthy periods of time required for carrying out the above-mentioned
		operations.</p><p id="p27" num="19"> Moreover, these very dosing devices have evident
		operational difficulty, because the operator has to, with each change of the
		detergent, go to a specific area and discharge/empty out all the detergent,
		even that in the tank, in order to then fill the tank and use a fresh and
		different type of detergent.</p><p id="p26" num="20"> Another negative aspect concerns the impossibility
		of inspecting and checking the valve component in the dosing chamber.</p><p id="p25" num="21"> In fact, generally this valve component is made
		from the assembly of various moving parts united in a chamber that is
		constantly dampened by the detergent, and therefore subject to a premature loss
		of functionality, both regarding the seal as well as the precision
		operations.</p><p id="p24" num="22"> In fact, it is well known that the continual
		wetting-drying of a moving part immersed in a detergent leads to the
		stratification of continual and superimposed films that create encrustations
		limiting/impeding the free operation of the above-mentioned moving parts.</p><p id="p23" num="23"> This loss of functionality renders the device
		unusable because of the continuous and undesired dripping.</p></background-art><disclosure><tech-problem><heading id="h05">Technical Problem</heading><p id="p52" num="24"> The object of this invention is to overcome one
		  or more of the drawbacks of the prior art.</p><p id="p51" num="25"> Another object of this invention is to make
		  available a valve body of a dosing device that is always reliable.</p><p id="p50" num="26"> A further object is to make available a valve
		  body of a dosing device that is easy to construct.</p><p id="p49" num="27"> An even further object is to make available a
		  valve body of a dosing device that is easy to maintain.</p><p id="p48" num="28"> Another object is to make available a valve body
		  of a dosing device that is easy to adjust, both regarding the travel of the
		  stroke as well as regarding the closure of the inlet and outlet conduits of the
		  dosing chamber.</p><p id="p47" num="29"> A further object of this invention is to make
		  available a valve body of a dosing device that is reliable over time and whose
		  moving parts are secure.</p><p id="p46" num="30"> Another object of this invention is to make
		  available a valve body of a dosing device that can be visibly inspected.</p><p id="p45" num="31"> Another object of this invention is to make
		  available a valve body of a dosing device that facilitates the operations for
		  changing the type of detergent, making them quick and simple.</p></tech-problem><tech-solution><heading id="h07">Technical Solution</heading><p id="p08" num="32"> All the above-mentioned aims are realised by a
		  valve body of a dosing device, which has a hollow body of the device for
		  storing and holding a pre-determined amount of a cleaning liquid, where said
		  valve body is composed of a first valve body element and a second valve body
		  element, and moreover said valve body is inserted inside hollow body of the
		  same device for dosing liquid detergent, for the opening and closing of the
		  inlet pipe and outlet pipe, respectively for supplying and emptying the
		  detergent inside the hollow body, where said valve body can move in a sliding
		  manner between two pre-set positions following the operation of the actuating
		  devices, to a first position opening the inlet and the closing of the outlet,
		  and a second position of closing the inlet and opening the outlet, and where
		  said valve body has, near the opposite ends, profiles that join to the relative
		  seals for closing the inlet and outlet pipes, and with the closing profile of
		  the outlet pipe located on the outside of the hollow body since the lower part
		  of the first element of valve body for the closing of the lower pipe, is always
		  exposed outside the hollow body, and the part of the valve body to which the
		  seal is connected for closing the lower pipe, with the lower part of the first
		  element of the valve body protruding partly on the outside of the hollow body,
		  shows the seal for sealing closed the outlet pipe. </p></tech-solution><advantageous-effects><heading id="h09">Advantageous Effects</heading><p id="p68" num="33"> Advantageously the seal for closing the outlet
		  pipe is, during closing, subject to the pressure ofn the lower part of the
		  first element of the valve body that pushes from the outside of the hollow
		  body.</p><p id="p67" num="34"> Advantageously the seal for closing the outlet
		  pipe is on the closing edge of the outlet pipe.</p><p id="p66" num="35"> Avantageously said first element of the valve
		  body can be extracted from within the hollow body through the outlet pipe for
		  its maintenance and/or its replacement.</p><p id="p65" num="36"> Advantageously at least one of said seals is
		  joined solidly to the upper and/or lower element of the valve body, remaining
		  exposed and protruding during at least one of the pre-set positions so that it
		  can be easily replaced.</p><p id="p64" num="37"> Alternatively to the advantage previously set
		  out, at least one of said seals is connected solidly to the mouth of the
		  opening of the inlet pipe and/or outlet pipe, held inside a specific housing,
		  remaining securely sheltered when the device is operating.</p><p id="p63" num="38"> Said first lower element and said second upper
		  element connect, supporting directly or entering into contact following the
		  movement with the relative seals for closing the outlet and inlet pipes; in
		  both modes of installing the seals, because of their arrangement, the
		  inspection and maintenance of the seals are considerably simplified, since the
		  seal on top of the second element is near the inlet mouth and the seal below
		  the first element is near the outlet mouth.</p><p id="p62" num="39"> Advantageously said first and said second element
		  of the valve body are connected to each other, avoiding the need for any moving
		  parts that in the long terms could create the same problems of movement and
		  lack of guaranteed closing reliability of the prior art.</p><p id="p61" num="40"> Opportunely, in a second variant for operating
		  said valve body it is composed of two elements joined together, eventually in
		  an adjustable manner; since the two elements can be easily extracted and
		  removed from the hollow body through the same inlet and outlet openings for
		  eventual cleaning and/or replacement of the elements themselves or their
		  seals.</p><p id="p60" num="41"> Opportunely each of the two elements making up
		  the valve body, a first lower valve body element and a second upper valve body
		  element, has independent elastic devices for closing and/or opening the
		  respective inlet and outlet pipes.</p><p id="p59" num="42"> Advantageously said second element of the valve
		  body for opening and closing the inlet pipe of the hollow body can be removed
		  from inside the hollow body through the inlet pipe for its maintenance and/or
		  its replacement.</p><p id="p58" num="43"> Opportunely said second upper element of the
		  valve body is connected in a moving way to the hollow body.</p><p id="p57" num="44"> Very advantageously said second element of the
		  valve body is connected in a movable manner to a removable tank above the
		  hollow body of the dosing device.</p><p id="p56" num="45"> Advantageously said second element opens the
		  inlet pipe of the hollow body following a push from the upper end of the first
		  element of the valve body.</p><p id="p55" num="46"> Advantageously said second upper element can take
		  up again its inlet closing position brought about by independent elastic
		  devices that act on the upper element of the valve body; guaranteeing in any
		  circumstance a secure closing against the liquid in the tank coming out, in the
		  absence of an efficient push of the underlying lower element of the valve
		  body.</p><p id="p54" num="47"> Advantageously said first and said second element
		  of the valve body are axially overlapping, in itself an excellent design
		  decision, that of the movement of the various parts subject to unidirectional
		  operating forces.</p><p id="p53" num="48"> Opportunely, said second upper element of the
		  valve body is solidly connected to a removable tank on top of the hollow body
		  of the dosing device, allowing for the removal and replacement with an
		  identical tank for changing the detergent or increasing autonomy.</p></advantageous-effects></disclosure><description-of-drawings><heading id="h11">Description of Drawings</heading><p id="p82" num="49"> The technical characteristics of the valve body of
		the dosing device, according to the various actuation modes but always
		according to the same invention, for the above-mentioned objectives, can be
		clearly observed in the claims below, and its benefits will be clearer in the
		detailed description that follows, made with reference to the attached
		diagrams, which represent an example of some ways it could be made, and so
		should not be considered in any way limiting, where:</p><p id="p81" num="50"> fig. 1 shows a perspective view of a dosing device
		accessorised on the top with a tank and on the bottom with a soaking basin;</p><p id="p80" num="51"> fig. 2 shows a perspective view of the dosing
		device that is the object of this invention;</p><p id="p79" num="52"> fig. 3 shows a vertical cross-section perspective
		view of the device of fig. 2 passing through the axis of the valve body;</p><p id="p78" num="53"> fig. 4 shows a plan view of the device of
		fig.3;</p><p id="p77" num="54"> fig. 5 shows an enlarged view of the object of fig.
		3 without the top tank and without any moving parts;</p><p id="p76" num="55"> fig. 6 shows a perspective view of just the valve
		body in one of the construction modes, two elements connected to each
		other;</p><p id="p75" num="56"> fig. 7 shows a vertical cross-section view of only
		the valve body of fig. 6</p><p id="p74" num="57"> fig. 8 shows a perspective and cross-section view
		of the dosing device equipped with a valve body in a different construction
		mode, with the two elements separated from one another;</p><p id="p73" num="58"> fig. 9 shows the device of fig. 8 with the first
		lower element of the valve body lowered and the outlet pipe open;</p><p id="p72" num="59"> figs. 10 and 11 respectively show a vertical
		cross-section view the device of fig. 8 and fig. 9, but perpendicular with
		respect to the previous diagrams;</p><p id="p71" num="60"> fig, 12 shows a perspective view of only the valve
		body of figs. 8 to 11;</p><p id="p70" num="61"> fig. 13 shows a vertical cross-section view of only
		the valve body of fig. 12;</p><p id="p69" num="62"> figs. 14 and 15 show the removable tank with the
		second upper element of the valve body on the bottom.</p></description-of-drawings><best-mode><heading id="h13">Best Mode</heading><p id="p126" num="63"> On top of the dosing device 1 there is a tank 10
		communicating hydraulically with the hollow body 2 beneath, from which is
		released the detergent stored in its dosage volume 12, into a soaking basin 11
		underneath.</p><p id="p125" num="64"> The inlet 8 and outlet 9 pipes of the hollow body
		2 are opened and closed by a float valve 3 inside said hollow body 2.</p><p id="p124" num="65"> In a first preferred and not limiting realisation
		of the valve body 3, it has two individual elements 4, 5 floating in the hollow
		body 2, with a possibility of their limited movement along its main axis.</p><p id="p123" num="66"> The first element 4 of the valve body 3 is lower
		down and has a tubular configuration, preferably conical or truncated-conical;
		said first element 4 near the lower base has a hydraulic seal 6 for sealing the
		outlet pipe 9, or closing pipe, of the hollow body 2, in a first raised
		position explained above.</p><p id="p122" num="67"> In this configuration, said first element 4, on
		the bottom, pushes with its top end the second element 5 of the valve body 3,
		on the top, and preferably with a single main axis between the two
		elements.</p><p id="p121" num="68"> Following the push of the first element 4, the
		seal 7, which the second element 5 has, opens the inlet 8 of the hollow body 2
		and hydraulically connects the inside of the tank 10, above the hollow body 2,
		with its dosing volume 12, and allowing it to fill with detergent that flows
		from the top tank 10.</p><p id="p120" num="69"> In this situation, with the first element 4, the
		one lower than the valve body 3, which closes the outlet 9 of the dosing device
		1 and with the second element 5, the one above the valve body, kept open,
		pulled aside from the high end of the lower element 4, the dosing device 1 is
		in a rest configuration, with the dosing volume chamber 12 filled with liquid
		detergent and communicating hydraulically with the inside of the tank 10
		above.</p><p id="p119" num="70"> Following a movement of the actuating devices,
		which act on the lower element 4 of the valve body 3, this latter shifts
		downwards in a sliding manner along its main axis, pulling the seal 6 with
		which it is equipped at the base away from the respective housing in the outlet
		pipe 9 of the hollow body 2, and opening the outlet of the dosing device 1.</p><p id="p118" num="71"> Said opening of the outlet of the dosing device 1
		makes the detergent in the dosing chamber 12 flow into the soaking basin 11
		underneath to soak a cleaning cloth or mop.</p><p id="p117" num="72"> With this shifting of the lower element 4,
		following a movement of the actuating devices, also the closing of the inlet 8
		of the hollow body 2 starts, following the shifting from the raised rest
		position of the second element 5.</p><p id="p116" num="73"> Said second element 5, usually kept pushed upwards
		by the upper part of the first element, positioned lower down, following the
		absence of a lower push, moves downwards with its seal 7 with which it is
		fitted, with the closing of the inlet 8 of the hollow body 2.</p><p id="p115" num="74"> This closing of the inlet 8 prevents the hydraulic
		communication between the tank 10 and the hollow body 2, preventing the flow of
		the detergent from the tank 10 inside the dosing chamber 12 until the outlet 9
		of the hollow body 2 is open.</p><p id="p114" num="75"> The movement downwards of the second element 5,
		the one above the valve body 3, is possible after the pressure of the liquid
		detergent inside the tank 10, but can also occur through independent elastic
		device 13 that act directly on the upper element 5.</p><p id="p113" num="76"> After the dosing chamber 12 has been completely
		emptied, these same actuating devices that previously moved towards the opening
		of the first element 4, or also other elastic devices 14 that act directly on
		said lower element 4, bring that first element 4 back to its rest condition,
		with the closure of the outlet 9 of the dosing device 1.</p><p id="p112" num="77"> After the dosing chamber 12 has been empties, and
		the outlet pipe 9 of the seal 6 at the base of the first element 4 has
		re-closed, the filling cycle for the dosing chamber restarts with the shifting
		to an opening state of the inlet 8 of the upper element 5 of the valve body
		3.</p><p id="p111" num="78"> Advantageously dais first element 4, the one below
		the valve body 3, partially comes out from the hollow body 2 during the opening
		of the outlet 9.</p><p id="p110" num="79"> In this state it is possible to evaluate the state
		of wear and intervene to eventually replace the seal 6 at the base of the lower
		element 4.</p><p id="p109" num="80"> Moreover, with this shifting of the valve body 3,
		a visual evaluation and consequent maintenance work is possible, to clean
		and/or replacement, directly on the housing against which the lower seal 6
		realises the hydraulic seal.</p><p id="p108" num="81"> In fact it is very important that the lower part
		of the first element of the valve body is always exposed on the outside of the
		hollow body, and therefore able to connect to the closing profile of the outlet
		pipe on the outside of the hollow body.</p><p id="p107" num="82"> The closing seal of the outlet pipe, which is
		compressed due to the hydraulic seal between the lower part of the first
		element of the valve body and the closing profile of the outlet pipe is
		therefore exposed during the moving away towards the outside of the lower part
		of the first element of the hollow body and made visible for an inspection.</p><p id="p106" num="83"> Said sealing of the outlet pipe is on the closing
		edge of the outlet pipe, preferably on a specific housing of the lower part of
		the first element of the hollow body, but could also be on a specific housing
		of the valve body facing its outside.</p><p id="p105" num="84"> With the above-mentioned configuration, the first
		element of the valve body can be easily removed from the valve body, without
		requiring any intervention, for example opening one of its parts or
		disassembling it.</p><p id="p104" num="85"> This extraction of the first element of the valve
		body is therefore simple to carry out by pulling it through the outlet pipe of
		the valve body after eventually disconnecting the relative actuating devices
		and/or elastic devices that act on said first element of the valve body.</p><p id="p103" num="86"> In this way the hollow body is simple to construct
		and easy to maintain, but above all the seals, at least the one of the outlet
		pipe is easy to replace, without having to, as in known devices of the prior
		art, disassemble the hollow body itself to access a valve body that is inside
		said hollow body and with the seals on the inside.</p><p id="p102" num="87"> Another advantage is the fact that the thrust due
		to the closing action of the first element of the valve body, takes place by
		means of elastic devices on the outside of the hollow body.</p><p id="p101" num="88"> Said push compresses the seal between the lower
		part of the first element of the valve body against the external profile of the
		outlet pipe, is a push of the first element of the valve body from outside the
		valve body.</p><p id="p100" num="89"> In order to also easily work on the upper seal 7,
		designated to close the inlet 8, you necessarily have to pass through the
		inside of the tank 10.</p><p id="p99" num="90"> It is clear that in the case where this is still
		full of detergent, this maintenance intervention is quite awkward.</p><p id="p98" num="91"> In an improved actuation method, shown as a second
		variant for actuating the invention, the tank 15 can be removed from the dosing
		device 1.</p><p id="p97" num="92"> Advantageously, therefore, said tank 15 has its own
		valve 16 for closing its detergent outlet pipe 17, which moves, when opening
		and closing, just like the inlet valve of the hollow body 2; namely pushed from
		below upwards by the second element 5 underneath, the one above the valve body
		3 for opening, and returns to a closed position following the pressure of the
		liquid detergent above or by means of the independent elastic devices 18.</p><p id="p96" num="93"> This possibility of removing said tank 15 provides
		not only the user with a convenient way to carry out maintenance, because the
		upper element 5 of the valve body 3, and its seal 7, can be accessed directly,
		but this also allows you to easily replace the type of detergent for the
		cleaning you intend to carry out.</p><p id="p95" num="94"> This simple replacement of the tank 15, without the
		need to empty a tank 10 fixed to the dosing unit 1, considerably simplifies the
		cleaning operations, facilitating the cleaning of each environment completely
		before moving on to other operations.</p><p id="p94" num="95"> Moreover, this availability of further tanks 15
		with the exact dilution of the chemical concentrate, effectively prepared at
		the start of the cleaning operations, increases autonomy in cleaning
		operations, without any forced downtime.</p><p id="p93" num="96"> For a simple and inexpensive realisation, the
		replacement of the second element 5, the one above the valve body 3, joined to
		the hollow body 2, can be provided for depending on the functions and location,
		with the closing valve 16 of the outlet pipe of the removable tank 15.</p><p id="p92" num="97"> This valve 16 acts as and takes the place of the
		one fixed to the hollow body 2 when the removable tank 15 is installed above
		the dosing device 1, with its outlet pipe 17 above the inlet 8 of the hollow
		body 2, and is the independent closing element after the tank 15 of the dosing
		device 1 has been removed.</p><p id="p91" num="98"> Clearly the maintenance of this valve 16, connected
		directly to the removable tank 15, can be easily carried out, both from above,
		through the inside of the tank 15 itself, and from below, since the valve 16 is
		practically exposed at the bottom on the outlet pipe 17 of the tank 15.</p><p id="p90" num="99"> It can easily be understood that the installation
		phase of the tank 15 onto the dosing device 1 is carried out in a guided manner
		so that the valve 16 of the tank 15 and the part of the valve body 3 that can
		connect correctly to each other to correctly open the valve 16 of the tank 15
		after the hydraulic seal has been realised between the outlet pipe 17 of the
		tank 15 and the inlet 8 of the hollow body 2.</p><p id="p89" num="100"> In a second preferred and non-limiting actuation
		method for the valve body 3, it is two elements 4, 5 joined solidly to each
		other, in a floating manner with respect to the hollow body 2, with the
		possibility of their limited movement along its main axis.</p><p id="p88" num="101"> Eventually said connection of the two elements 4
		and 5 is adjustable in order to recuperate and regulate the reciprocal distance
		between the seals with respect to the dedicated housing on the inlet and
		outlet.</p><p id="p87" num="102"> Advantageously this distance between the two seals
		for the inlet and the outlet is less than the distances of the closing sections
		of the inlet and outlet pipes of the hollow body, thereby guaranteeing the
		closing of a first pipe before the opening of the second pipe.</p><p id="p86" num="103"> In this last method there is never any direct
		hydraulic communication between the tank 10 and the soaking basin 11, something
		that would cause the direct passage of the detergent through the hollow body
		2.</p><p id="p85" num="104"> The invention, conceived in this way, is
		susceptible to numerous modifications and variants, all falling within the
		ambit of the inventive concept; moreover, all the parts can be replaced by
		other technically equivalent components.</p><p id="p84" num="105"> In practice, the materials used, as well as the
		dimensions and the contingent forms, can be whatever is required and according
		to the state of the art.</p><p id="p83" num="106"> Where the characteristics and the technologies
		mentioned in any claim are followed by reference marks, these marks are there
		for the only purpose of making the claims more understandable and as a
		consequence these references in no way limit the interpretation of each element
		identified by way of example by these reference marks.</p></best-mode></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM70080145" ref-ucid="WO-2014128670-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><claim id="c21" num="1"><claim-text><claim-text>Valve body of a dosing device (1), fitted with a hollw body
			 (2) for stroing and retaining a pre-determined amount of a cleaning liquid,
			 where said valve body (3) is composed of a first valve body element (4) and a
			 second valve body element (5), where also said valve body (3) is inserted
			 inside a hollow body (2) of the same dosing device (1) for a liquid detergent,
			 for the opening and closing of the inlet pipe (8) and the outlet pipe (9),
			 respectively for supplying and emptying the detergent inside the hollow 5 body
			 (2), with said valve body (3) being able to slide between two pre-set positions
			 following the operation of the actuation devices, in a first position with the
			 opening of the inlet (8) and the closing of the outlet (9) and a second
			 position with the inlet (8) closed and the outlet (9) open, characterised by
			 the fact that said valve body (3) has, near the opposite ends, profiles that
			 join to the relative seals (6, 7) for closing the inlet (8) and outlet (9)
			 pipes, and having the closing profile of the outlet pipe (9) on the outside of
			 the hollow body (2) since the lower part of the first element (4) of the valve
			 body (3) suited to closing the outlet pipe (9) is always exposed on the outside
			 of the hollow body (2)</claim-text><claim-text>and the part (4) of the valve body (3) to which the seal
			 (6) is joined for the closing of the lower pipe, following an opening movemnt
			 of the outlet pipe (9), with the lower part of the first element (4) of the
			 valve body (3) partially protruding on the outside of the hollow body (2),
			 shows the seal for sealing the closing of the outlet pipe (9), following a
			 closing movement of the outlet (9), moves the part (5) of the valve body (3) to
			 which is joined the seal (7) dedicated to the closing of the upper
			 pipe.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c127" num="2"><claim-text><claim-text>Valve body of a dosing device according to claim 1,
			 characterized by the fact that the seal for closing the outlet pipe (9) is,
			 when closing, subject to the pressure from the lower part of the element (4) of
			 the valve body (3) thta pushes from outside the hollow body (2).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c128" num="3"><claim-text><claim-text>Valve body of a dosing device (1) according to claim 1,
			 characterised by the fact that the seal for closing the outlet pipe (9) is on
			 the closing edge of the oputlet pipe (9).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c129" num="4"><claim-text><claim-text>Valve body of a dosing device according to claim 1,
			 characterised by the fact that at least one of said first element (4) of the
			 valve body (3) can be removed from inside the hollow body (2) through the
			 outlet pipe (9) for its maintenance and/or replacement.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c130" num="5"><claim-text><claim-text>Valve body of a dosing device according to claim 1,
			 characterised by the fact that said valve body (3) and a second upper elemnt
			 (5) which are connected directly to each other, supporting either directly or
			 entering into contact following the movement of the relative seals (6, 7) for
			 closing the outlet pipe (9)and the inlet pipe (8).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c131" num="6"><claim-text><claim-text>Valve body of a dosing device (1) according to the previous
			 claim, characterised by the act that said first lower element (4) of the valve
			 body (3) aid said second upper element (4) of the valve body (3) are joined
			 together in an adjustable manner.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c132" num="7"><claim-text><claim-text>Valve body of a dosing device according to one or more of
			 the previous claims, characterised by the fact that one of said seals (6, 7) is
			 solidly connected to the upper element (5) and/or lower element (4) of the
			 valve body (3), remaining exposed and protruding during at least one of the
			 pre-set positions.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c133" num="8"><claim-text><claim-text>Valve body of a dosing device according to one or more of
			 the previous claims, characterised by the act that one of said seals (6, 7) is
			 solidly connected to the mouth opening of the inlet pipe (8) and/or the outlet
			 pipe (9) retained within a specific housing.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c134" num="9"><claim-text><claim-text>Valve body of a dosing device according to one or more of
			 the previous claims, characterised by the act that said first lower element (4)
			 of the valve body (3) can take up again its closing poistion of the outlet (9)
			 brought about bu independent elastic devices that act on the part outside the
			 hollow body (2) of the first element (4) of the valve body (3).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c135" num="10"><claim-text><claim-text>Valve body of a dosing device according to one or more of
			 the previous claims, characterised by the act that said upper element (5) of
			 the valve body (3) can take up again its closing poistion of the inlet (8)
			 brought about by independent elastic devices (13) that act on the upper element
			 (5) of the valve body (3).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c136" num="11"><claim-text><claim-text>Valve body of a dosing device according to one or more of
			 the previous claims, characterised by the act that said first element (4) and
			 said second element (5) of the valve body (3) are axially
			 overlapping.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c137" num="12"><claim-text><claim-text>Valve body of a dosing device according to one or more of
			 the previous claims, characterised by the act that said second element (5) of
			 the valve body is connected to a removanble tank (15) above the hollow body (2)
			 of the dosing device (1).</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
