<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2042829-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2042829" kind="B1" date="20140101" family-id="40279134" file-reference-id="311124" date-produced="20180822" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146554241" ucid="EP-2042829-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2042829</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-08102554-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154828164" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>08102554</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20080312</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP231459916" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>08102554.6</doc-number><date>20080312</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140446206" ucid="EP-07117240-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>07117240</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20070926</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140445541" ucid="EP-08102554-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>08102554</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20080312</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130812</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988103184" load-source="docdb">G01B  21/04        20060101AFI20090202BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988118854" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G01B  21/042       20130101 FI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132195207" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Modulare Kalibrierung</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132195208" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Modular calibration</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132195209" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Étalonnage modulaire</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918142011" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>HEXAGON METROLOGY AB</last-name><address><country>SE</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918159603" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>HEXAGON METROLOGY AB</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918170147" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>PETTERSSON BO</last-name><address><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918153171" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>PETTERSSON, BO</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918999197" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>PETTERSSON, BO</last-name><address><street>22 Coval Gardens</street><city>London, Greater London SW14 7DG</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918999199" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Hexagon Metrology AB</last-name><iid>100958123</iid><address><street>Box 1112</street><city>131 26 Nacka Strand</city><country>SE</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918999198" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>P&amp;TS SA (AG, Ltd.)</last-name><iid>101264802</iid><address><street>Av. J.-J. Rousseau 4 P.O. Box 2848</street><city>2001 Neuchâtel</city><country>CH</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548876116" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS548992885" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548985792" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548992886" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548985793" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS548991538" load-source="docdb">LI</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63957681" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001"><u>Field of the invention</u></heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to a calibration method for a coordinate measuring machine (CMM), and a computer-readable medium therefore.</p><heading id="h0002"><u>Description of related art</u></heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">Calibration methods are meant to ensure the accuracy of measurement tools by providing a preliminary reliability check. Generally speaking, calibration consists in comparing measurement outputs to known references values. When discrepancies are noticed between the two sets of values, an error correction is carried out, so that the actual measured value and the known theoretical values are aligned. The calibration step is usually performed prior to the first use of a system, in order to make sure that it is delivers the right values when used. It can be then repeated at major overhauls.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">In the CMM domain, machines usually have at least three degrees of freedom (a.k.a. DOF). Systems with six or more DOF are however known. CMM systems usually comprise a support moving linearly according to the three axis of space X, Y, Z and a stylus of lighter weight attached to it, that is moveable in rotation, for example by the interposition of an articulated probe head. The most common calibration processes consists in measuring coordinates over a so-called calibration artefact that is typically a sphere so that all the degrees of freedom can be simultaneously tested, i.e. as well the position and the orientation over the full range of operation of the machine.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">In general, CMM systems offer a selection of measuring probes, which can be connected to the positioning head, and are specialized to the execution of different measurement tasks. A CMM could be fitted, for example, with a selection of trigger touch probes of different length and<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> shapes, scanning probes, contactless probes, optical inspection probes, and so on. Each individual probe requires an individual and separate calibration. On the other hand, when a new probe head is introduced in the system, or whenever an element of the cinematic chain of the CMM is altered, all the probes ought to be individually recalibrated to ensure optimal precision.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">The need of frequent calibration is a drawback for the user of the CMM, in that it reduces the availability of the CMM system. Furthermore, the management of the calibration data for each probe is a burden to the user of the CMM.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">Another drawback of the calibration processes known from the art is that the calibration is done only on a discrete number of selected positions, so that the accuracy optimisation is not guaranteed for all positions. Furthermore, since the full global calibration operation always takes place on mounted machines, it is always difficult to identify the right sources of the major deviations since there is no way to distinguish between parameters at this stage a priori, so that the parameter weighting and adjustment is quite time-consuming.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">Another issue for ensuring the precision of the calibration is to include dynamic and bending parameters, in order to know how the system reacts to forces applied on the stylus and what the influences of forces of inertia are. To this effect, it is known to include, in the calibration process, measurements of the displacement of the CMM probe as a function of the contact force, for example.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">Many numeric models have been developed for error correction in order to improve the accuracy of the calibration systems. A first model, presented in <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US5594668A"><text>US5594668</text></patcit>, takes into account elastic properties of a probe and derives distortions due to acceleration through matrix calculations. Similarly in <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="WO2006114603A"><text>WO2006/114603</text></patcit> an inertia matrix is used and deflection forces are taken into account. Yet in both case the intrinsic elastic properties of the probe used are not derived from a preliminary calibration step, but<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> are hard-coded based on manufacturer data, so that the precision is not individually adapted to each device.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009"><patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="US20020087233A"><text>US20020087233</text></patcit> describes a modular portable CMM with interchangeable probes, in which an EEPROM circuit board contains calibration and identification data for avoiding unit mix-up; nevertheless those data are not derived from any calibration operation on the probes themselves and hence do not contain any probe-specific data.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010"><patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="WO2007097841A"><text>WO-A-2007/097841</text></patcit> discloses a CMM of modular design, but no map files. <patcit id="pcit0005" dnum="US6668466B"><text>US-B-6 668 466</text></patcit> discloses an articulated CMM, and map files relating to the calibration of the whole CMM.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">The present invention is based on the recognition of the above shortcoming of the prior art, and aims to overcome them. In particular the present invention proposes a method to reduce the impact of the calibrations on the availability of a CMM system, and to lessen the burden of managing a large set of calibration data, so that the ease of use is improved. The accuracy is improved as well since the calibration steps prior to the mounting of the machine are not generic for a given component type or model any more, but derive specific characteristics of each tested component.</p><heading id="h0003"><u>Brief summary of the invention</u></heading><p id="p0012" num="0012">According to the invention, these aims are achieved by means of a modular calibration method for a CMM, which comprises a plurality of components, where preliminary calibration steps take place according to the appended claims.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">In preferred embodiments such preliminary calibration steps are carried out prior to the step of mounting said CMM and, preferably, parts of said components are individually calibrated for each degree of freedom of said components and yield specific mapping information. The mapping information is then stored, after map files have been generated and associated to the calibrated components. A final alignment step take place after said CMM is mounted. It just processes and aligns the mapping information gathered during the preliminary calibration steps.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p><p id="p0014" num="0014">Such a modular approach allows to best fit to the actual intrinsic properties of each single component, each single movement and each single degree of freedom in each relative positioning reference. It hence ensures a high quality accuracy since specialized equipment can be used at production site for their calibration. It also shifts the overall optimisation complexity towards single optimisation problems, so that the computation requirements on the mounted machine, which have always been cumbersome and time-consuming, are strongly simplified. Furthermore, such a modular approach is suited for repeated calibration operations when only simple add-ons or piece exchanges need to be carried out.</p><heading id="h0004"><u>Brief Description of the Drawings</u></heading><p id="p0015" num="0015">The invention will be better understood with the aid of the description of an embodiment given by way of example and illustrated by the figures, in which:
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> shows a sequence diagram of the calibration steps according to a preferred embodiment of the invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> shows a detailed diagram of the calibration steps prior to the CMM mounting according to a preferred embodiment of the invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig 3</figref> shows a logical view of a physical system according to a preferred embodiment for the invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 4</figref> shows a CMM system equipped with a rotary head and a touch probe, used to illustrate the terminology of the description of the invention.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0005"><u>Detailed Description of possible embodiments of the Invention</u></heading><p id="p0016" num="0016">As mentioned earlier, the state of the art calibration methods for CMMs 90 are known to be cumbersome and time-consuming. Indeed,<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> the calibration process is delicate and long because several calibration parameters have to be adjusted simultaneously. In the general case involving translation and rotation DOF, each position of the calibration probe can be obtained by several configurations of the CMM, each requiring a separate calibration. Due to the time-consuming character of the optimisation process in order to ensure the best accurate tuning, usually only a limited number of points in the configuration space of the machines are calibrated, and calibration data relative to the remaining configuration are obtained by interpolation. The sparseness of the calibration points limits the precision of this technique.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">The modular calibration method according to the invention is meant to improve the accuracy of the machine calibration settings while providing single individual calibrations of components prior to the mounting of the probe, and using this information once the machine is mounted. This way, the complex optimisation problem is split into single optimisation problems that can better be handled with specific quality machines for each component, e.g. at their own production site. The calibration procedure on the mounted CMM, consisting in aligning all available calibration information gathered in the previous individual calibration procedures is thus much simpler. On one hand, the use of specific tailored calibration information yielded by individual testing procedures for each component allows to improve the overall calibration accuracy, since the calibration can cover optimally the configuration space of each single component; on the other hand, it provides more scalability and improved availability of the system, because a component swap or exchange is possible without needing to go through an overall calibration procedure again.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">According to one aspect of the invention, a CMM system is considered as a combination of simple components, for example a moving platform in a XYZ three-dimensional reference, an orientable probe head having one or two rotation axes, probes and accessories, like touch trigger probes, styli, and lengthening elements, out of a set of compatible interchangeable elements. Some of the components are active elements,<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> corresponding to degrees of freedom in the CMM system and include preferably, for each DOF, an actuator to set the DOF and an encoder to read its position out.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">In a general way, the CMM system can be decomposed in an ensemble of single components, which define a complex cinematic chain. For example, a CMM measuring system fitted with a rotary head and a touch probe, as shown in example <figref idrefs="f0004">figure 4</figref> could be formally decomposed into:a linear actuator and encoder corresponding to the translation along the horizontal "Y" axis;
<ol><li>b. a linear actuator and encoder corresponding to the translation along the horizontal "X" axis;</li><li>c. a linear actuator and encoder corresponding to the translation along the vertical "Z" axis;</li><li>d. a rotary actuator and encoder corresponding to the rotation about the vertical "A" axis of the wrist of the probe</li><li>e. a rotary actuator and encoder corresponding to the rotation about the horizontal "B" axis of the wrist of the probe;</li><li>f. a fixed translation corresponding to the stylus 135 in use</li></ol></p><p id="p0020" num="0020">The combination of each elementary subsystem a)-f) determines the coordinate and the orientation of the sensed point. Each one of those subsystems has a specific orientation in a relative reference. The presented example shows, for the sake of simplicity, a cinematic serial chain, i.e. a chain of actuators which are connected one after the other. The invention, however, is not limited to this case, and also comprises the case of parallel actuators, like for example a six-axis Stewart platform.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">The presented CMM system comprises, beyond the three-axis XYZ actuators, a plurality of modular components, for example the rotary<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> head 132 and the stylus 135. Depending from the task to be performed, the CMM system can be fitted, with a combination of components chosen from a modular set. The decomposition of the cinematic chain in subsystem can correspond to a detachable or modular component of the overall system, but this is in no way a requirement of the invention. The rotary head 132, for example is decomposed in two independent elementary systems, corresponding to its independent degrees of freedom.<br/>
As mentioned in the introduction, the calibration of such a complex measuring machine is time-consuming and delicate, and must be repeated every time the machine's configuration is altered. When the measuring system is decomposed in subsystems, however, and each subsystem is individually calibrated, a global calibration can be obtained by composition of the individual calibrations.<br/>
Formally, the configuration of the CMM system is fully determined by a set of parameters, including, for example, displacements and rotation angles relative to the various degrees of freedom, plus eventually the temperature and other global parameters. The static calibration of the CMM system can be regarded as a correspondence, or map M, <maths id="math0001" num="(1)"><math display="block"><mover><mi>X</mi><mo>‾</mo></mover><mo>=</mo><mi>M</mi><mfenced><mi mathvariant="normal">Ξ</mi></mfenced></math><img id="ib0001" file="imgb0001.tif" wi="94" he="13" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths><br/>
between the parameter space of the CMM system (whose elements are represented by vectors of parameters <img id="ib0002" file="imgb0002.tif" wi="4" he="6" img-content="character" img-format="tif" inline="yes"/>= ξ<sub>1</sub>,ξ<sub>2</sub>,...ξ<i><sub>n</sub></i>, the values of ξ being usually known from the encoders of the CMM system) and <i><o>X</o></i> the actual position of the measured point, for example in a cartesian coordinate system <i><o>X</o></i> = (<i>x,y,z</i>). This is obtained, in a conventional way, by measuring a set of reference points, or the surface of a reference object, and by known numeric error minimization techniques. The present invention deals with a process of constructing a global calibration <i>M</i>, by a set of subsystem calibration.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></p><p id="p0022" num="0022">In the simple but very common case in which the kinematical chain of the CMM system is fully serial, one can consider each degree of freedom as independent subsystem, and construct <i>M</i> as a composition of correspondences <i>M<sub>j</sub></i> (ξ<i><sub>j</sub></i>), each one corresponding to a degree of freedom <maths id="math0002" num="(2)"><math display="block"><mi>M</mi><mo>=</mo><msub><mi>M</mi><mn>1</mn></msub><mfenced><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">ξ</mi><mn>1</mn></msub></mfenced><mo>⋅</mo><msub><mi>M</mi><mn>2</mn></msub><mfenced><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">ξ</mi><mn>2</mn></msub></mfenced><mo>⋅</mo><mo>…</mo><mo>⋅</mo><msub><mi>M</mi><mi>n</mi></msub><mfenced><msub><mi mathvariant="normal">ξ</mi><mi>n</mi></msub></mfenced></math><img id="ib0003" file="imgb0003.tif" wi="111" he="11" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0023" num="0023">In a more general case, the submaps <i>M<sub>j</sub></i> may depend of one or more parameters of the machine to qualify each component relatively to the reference space of the CMM, each default can induce relative reference changes in the cinematic chain. The calibration needs not be limited to a static correspondence, put also include dynamic effect, thus introducing a dependence from velocitiesξ̇, accelerations ξ̈, and the masses of the various elements. In all these cases, the global calibration function can be computed, from single calibrations of the subsystems.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024"><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> illustrates the overall concept of the invention through a sequence diagram of a preferred embodiment. In the diagram, the two dotted boxes 100 and 700 stand respectively for the set of steps taking place before the CMM is mounted and after the CMM is mounted, and the dotted arrows 900 stand for a mutual information exchange between those two sets of steps, since the step or steps after the mounting use information precisely provided by the steps prior to the mounting. The sequence of steps unfolds as follows:
<ul><li>200: preliminary calibration step of some subsystem or individual components making up the CMM. This individual testing can be carried out off-site with specific equipment in order to ensure a high level of quality for the error correction and compensation;</li><li>300: as a result of the individual testing processes, calibration information is provided, which is specific to the subsystem or individual component and not generic to all the component of the same model. According to the modular calibration method of the invention, the calibration information relative to different individual<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> components having the same specifications (e.g. two scanning probe of the same model) can thus be different, even if only slightly, which would not be the case if only model-generic information was be stored and attached in a static manner to a piece. The output of this step is to generate a so-called map file which will be associated to the calibrated component;</li><li>According to the needs, the map file of a component can include different calibration data, for example geometric calibration data, or sensivity to deformation induce by some combination of heavy final elements as well as stiffness calibration and dynamic data, by known methods. In the case of an active element, the calibration will include several different configurations of the elements, in order to cover appropriately the element's configuration space;</li><li>400: once the individual calibration procedures have delivered an output, the yielded calibration information can be further processed and organized according to different criteria that will be discussed based on <figref idrefs="f0002">figure 2</figref> further in this document;</li><li>500: the storing of calibration information. Different strategies for the storing are possible and are also discussed further in this document based on <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>;</li><li>600: the combination of the elements to provide a working CMM system with a set of desired features. This step could be done manually, for example when fitting a probe on the spindle of a CMM positioning platform, or automatically, for example in the case of a system equipped with an automatic tool-changing magazine;</li><li>800: the final alignment procedure for mapping and coordinating all the calibration information. In a preferred embodiment of the invention, this step can be fully automatic, i.e. requiring no human intervention. As a result, once the different elements of the CMM are combined together, the system is "auto-calibrated" in the sense that<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> a calibration supervisor detects the components, selects the relevant calibration files, and combines them in a system calibration file. According to another preferred embodiment for the invention, the alignment function can be semi-automatic, as explained later in this document.</li></ul></p><p id="p0025" num="0025"><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> illustrates in more detail the steps prior to the mounting of the CMM according to a preferred embodiment of the invention. The subsystems 10 of the CMM system, which are further referenced according to letters A, B, C, D etc. organized in rows to distinguish between them, are preferably tested by a corresponding specialized equipment in production 14 (step 200). The calibration operation provides specific calibration data (step 300) for each subsystem or component. The calibration information can span different parameters, possibly depending on the component. It is usually distinguished between geometrical mapping, where the encoders associated to either of the 6 degrees of freedom of the machine derive the position, and stiffness mapping, where an encoder derives a position shift based on a force applied due to some bending of a component. Dynamic mapping can also be applied to a CMM in deriving a position shift based on inertia forces applied to the CMM.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">It is precisely the goal of the gathering and organization step (step 400) to group the information of the map files into map sets 18 (illustrated later on <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig.2</figref>) which are structured so that the final alignment procedure is simplified as much as possible through such pre-processing. An adequate segmentation and presentation of the calibration information further allows to perform the final alignment procedure in a modular fashion, the user being able to select what needs to be aligned and what doesn't. He can e.g. decide whether if any further mapping like stiffness or dynamic mapping should be done on top of the basic geometrical mapping. Logical calibration information maps 19 can hence be formed and stored into a set of maps 18 (step 500), from which the user will select the sets or subsets of his choice, as shown on <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig.2</figref>.<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --></p><p id="p0027" num="0027">According to the preferred embodiment disclosed in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig.2</figref>, the map files generated by the preliminary calibration steps 100 and associated to the subsystems are organized into matrix. The combination of each specific subsystem matrix of a component define a component matrix. Each entries of the component matrix define a reference orientation, linear parameters, rotational parameters and some others parameters such as the ones previously listed above (degrees of Freedom, stiffness mapping, dynamic mapping, this list not trying to be exhaustive). The component matrix can be optimized to define mathematical functions depending of the complexity of the component. They define exactly the dynamic behaviour of the component for each position. To gain time, single subsystem matrix is more accurate and easier to recalibrate. As result, the semi-automatic alignment step provided by the modular calibration method of the invention will allow the user to choose to which elements or part of the element (subsystem) the alignment will be applied, as well as which parameters will come into play at that stage. Obviously, the information maps can be designed in a modular mode so that it takes into account only selected elements of the matrix.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">Although the storing process depends to some extent on the data representation and associated pre-processing strategy adopted for building the information maps based on the map files, there are also different strategies for the physical storing if the information. According to a preferred embodiment of the invention, the storage of the information is done locally on each component itself. An auto-discovery feature during the mounting step could then allow to detect and fetch the files corresponding to each component so that those files can be processed during the alignment procedure. According to another embodiment, the storing step can also be performed on a remote storage device, like e.g. a central database, from which as well rough map files and information map sets could be selectively or automatically downloaded in the frame of the alignment step.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029"><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> shows a logical view of a physical system according to a preferred embodiment for the invention, comprising a CMM 90 and a<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> controller for the CMM 15, linked by a physical input/output (I/O) connection. The CMM comprises a plurality of subsystems 10 distinguished by the letters (A), (B), and (C) arranged in columns and, to which position transducers 12 are coupled for the geometrical mapping and optionally sensors 13, e.g. strain gauges or touch trigger switches, are also coupled. The link between the CMM subsystems and the sensors has been drawn in dotted lines to represent that not all subsytems need be associated with a sensor 13. The invention, however is not limited to the calibration of active elements including position transducers 12 and, indeed, some of the simplest subsystems 10, may be, for example, passive extension elements, without transducers or actuators.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">In order for all elements to communicate among each other, a data transfer link, for example a connection bus 11, is also provided.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">The CMM controller 15 comprises a processor 16 for carrying out the alignment step, and a memory or storage device 17 for providing all the necessary calibration information to be processed. According to the preferred embodiment of <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig.3</figref>, the memory contains individual map files 20 (A), (B), (C) etc. associated to each respective component 10 (A), (B), (C), etc. The association between the map files 20 and the components should be, however, understood as a logical link, not limitative in terms of physical implementation options. Indeed, many physical embodiments are possible for the storage, as well as for the recognition and retrieval of the associated file.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">A computer program can for example be provided with an autodiscovery function for detecting the components and/or retrieve map files 20 before the alignment step is carried out. This can be e.g. through a polling functionality in charge of periodically screening if calibration files are available. Such an autodiscovery function can be associated as well with a tool-changer module (not shown) in order to determine which tools are actually present on the machine, based on port number information.<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --></p><p id="p0033" num="0033">Although this invention has been described with reference to CMMs, the scope could be broadened to robotics as well as any other suitable industrial domain for which such a modular calibration method is potentially relevant.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980532" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Verfahren zur Kalibrierung eines modularen Koordinatenmesssystems, wobei das besagte Koordinatenmesssystem eine Mehrzahl an Teilsystemen umfasst, mit:
<claim-text>Testkalibrierungsschritten (100), vor dem Montageschritt des besagten modularen Koordinatenmesssystems, worin mindestens ein Teil besagter Teilsysteme individuell kalibriert werden (200) und spezifische Kalibrierungsinformationen (300) für jedes Teilsystem liefern, worin Map-Dateien (20) generiert und dem besagten Teilsystem zugeordnet werden;</claim-text>
<claim-text>einem Schritt, worin die besagten Kalibrierungsinformationen (500) gespeichert werden, und</claim-text>
<claim-text>einem Montageschritt des besagten modularen Koordinatenmesssystems, nach den Testkalibrierungsschritten, mit einem Ausrichtungsschritt (800) des Verarbeitens besagter während der Testkalibrierungsschritten gesammelter Kalibrierungsinformationen.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Verfahren gemäss dem vorhergehenden Anspruch, worin jedes Teilsystem einem Freiheitsgrad eines Elementes des Koordinatenmesssystems entspricht.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Verfahren gemäss Anspruch 1, ausserdem umfassend einen Schritt, worin die besagte Kalibrierung (400) vor der Speicherung (500) besagter Kalibrierungsinformationen eingesammelt und organisiert wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Verfahren gemäss Anspruch 1, worin mindestens eines der besagten Teilsysteme einer modularen Komponente des besagten Koordinatenmesssystems entspricht.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Verfahren gemäss irgendeinem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, worin der besagte Speicherungsschritt auf separaten Speichermitteln für jedes Teilsystem ausgeführt wird.<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Verfahren gemäss dem vorhergehenden Anspruch, worin der besagte Speicherungsschritt (500) lokal auf jeder Komponente selbst ausgeführt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Verfahren gemäss einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 6, worin der besagte Speicherungsschritt (500) auf einem fernen Speichermittel ausgeführt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Verfahren gemäss einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, worin die Map-Dateien (20) in einer Matrix organisiert sind.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Verfahren gemäss einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, worin die einzelnen Map-Dateien für jedes Freiheitsgrad einer Komponente mit ihren eigenen relativen Positionierungsreferenzen in eine zusammengesetzte optimierte Matrix für jede Komponente kombiniert werden.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Verfahren gemäss einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, worin der Ausrichtungsschritt (800) automatisch ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Verfahren gemäss einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, worin der Ausrichtungsschritt (800) halb-automatisch ist, wobei ein Benutzer einen einzigen spezifischen auszuführenden Kalibrierungsparameter auszuwählen vermag.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Eine Kombination einer Komponente eines Koordinatenmesssystems (10), wobei die besagte Komponente mindestens ein Teilsystem und eine durch einen Testkalibrierungsschritt (100) generierte und gespeicherte Map-Datei (20) umfasst, worin mindestens Teile des besagten Teilsystems individuell kalibriert werden (200) und spezifische Kalibrierungsinformationen (300) für jedes Teilsystem liefern, worin Map-Dateien (20) generiert und besagtem Teilsystem zugeordnet werden, wobei die besagte Kombination dergestalt angepasst wird, um das Verfahren eines beliebigen der Ansprüche 1 bis 11 auszuführen.<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Ein Computerprogrammprodukt, angepasst zur Ausführung des Verfahrens eines beliebigen der Ansprüche 1 bis 11.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Ein Computerprogrammprodukt gemäss dem vorhergehenden Anspruch, welches zusätzlich eine auto-Erkennungsfunktion zur Ermittlung der Komponenten und/oder zur Abrufung der Map-Dateien (20) vor dem besagten Ausrichtungsschritt (800) durchführt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Eine Kontrollvorrichtung (15) für ein Koordinatenmesssystem, mit einer Speichervorrichtung (17) und einem Prozessor (16), dergestalt angepasst, um das Verfahren eines beliebigen der Ansprüche 1 bis 11 auszuführen.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980533" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A method for the calibration of a modular coordinate measuring system, said coordinate measuring system comprising a plurality of subsystems, comprising:
<claim-text>preliminary calibration steps (100) prior to the step of mounting said modular coordinate measuring system, wherein at least part of said subsystems are individually calibrated (200) and provide specific calibration information (300) for each subsystem, wherein map files (20) are generated and associated to said calibrated subsystem;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a step of storing said calibration information (500), and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a step of mounting said modular coordinate system, after the preliminary calibration steps, comprising an alignment step (800) of processing said calibration information gathered during said preliminary calibration steps.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The method of the previous claim, wherein each subsystem corresponds to a degree of freedom of one element of the coordinate measuring system.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The method of claim 1, further comprising a step of gathering and organizing said calibration (400) before storing (500) said calibration information.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The method of claim 1, wherein at least one of said subsystems corresponds to a modular component of said coordinate measuring system.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The method of any of the previous claims, wherein said storing step is done on separate storage means for each subsystem.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The method of the previous claim, wherein said storing step (500) is done locally on each component itself.<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The method of one of the claims from 1 to 6, wherein said storing step (500) is done on a remote storage device.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The method of one of the previous claims, wherein the map files (20) are organized into matrix.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The method of one of the previous claims, wherein the single map files for each degree of freedom of a component are combined with their own relative positioning reference into a composed and optimized matrix for each component.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The method of one of the previous claims, wherein the alignment step (800) is automatic.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>The method of one of the previous claims, wherein the alignment step (800) is semi-automatic, a user being able to select a single specific calibration parameter which needs to be done.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>A combination of a component of a coordinate measuring system (10),<br/>
said component comprising at least one subsystem and of a map file (20) generated and stored by a preliminary calibration steps (100), wherein at least part of said subsystems are individually calibrated (200) and provide specific calibration information (300) for each subsystem, wherein map files (20) are generated and associated to said calibrated subsystem, said combination being adapted to carry out the method of any of claims 1-11</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>A computer program product adapted to carry out the method of any of claims 1-11.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>A computer program product according to the previous claim, further performing an auto-discovery function for detecting the components and/or retrieve map files 20 before said alignment step (800).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>A controller (15) for a coordinate measuring system, comprising a storage device (17) and a processor (16) adapted to carry out the method of any of claims 1-11.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980534" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Procédé pour l'étalonnage d'un système modulaire de mesure de coordonnées, ledit système de mesure de coordonnées comprenant une pluralité de sous-systèmes, comprenant:
<claim-text>des étapes de calibration préliminaires (100) avant l'étape d'assembler ledit système modulaire de mesure de coordonnées, dans lesquelles au moins une partie desdits sous-systèmes sont calibrés individuellement (200) et fournissent des informations spécifiques de calibration (300) pour chaque sous-système, où des fichiers de mappage (20) sont générés et associés audit sous-système calibré;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une étape de stockage desdites informations de calibration (500), et</claim-text>
<claim-text>une étape d'assemblage dudit système modulaire de coordonnées après les étapes de calibration préliminaires, comprenant une étape d'alignement (800) où lesdites informations de calibration recueillies durant lesdites étapes de calibration préliminaires sont traitées.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Le procédé de la revendication précédente, dans lequel chaque sous-système correspond à un degré de liberté d'un élément du système de mesure de coordonnées.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Le procédé de la revendication 1, comprenant en outre une étape de captage et d'organisation de ladite calibration (400) avant le stockage (500) desdites informations de calibration.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Le procédé de la revendication 1, dans lequel au moins un desdits sous-systèmes correspond à un composant modulaire dudit système de mesure de coordonnées.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Le procédé de l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans lequel ladite étape de stockage est effectuée sur un moyen de stockage séparé pour chaque sous-système.<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Le procédé de la revendication précédente, dans lequel ladite étape de stockage (500) est effectuée localement sur chaque composant lui-même.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Le procédé de l'une des revendications 1 à 6, dans lequel ladite étape de stockage (500) est effectuée sur un dispositif de stockage à distance.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Le procédé de l'une des revendications précédentes, dans lequel les fichiers de mappage (20) sont organisés sous forme de matrices.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Le procédé de l'une des revendications précédentes, dans lequel les fichiers de mappage individuels pour chaque degré de liberté d'un composant sont combinés avec leur propre référence de positionnement relatif dans une matrice composée et optimisée pour chaque composant.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Le procédé de l'une des revendications précédentes, dans lequel l'étape d'alignement (800) est automatique.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Le procédé de l'une des revendications précédentes, dans lequel l'étape d'alignement (800) est semi-automatique, un utilisateur étant en mesure de sélectionner un paramètre de calibration spécifique unique qui doit être effectué.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Une combinaison d'un composant d'un système de mesure de coordonnées (10), ledit composant comprenant au moins un sous-système et un fichier de mappage (20) généré et stocké par une étape de calibration préliminaire (100), dans laquelle au moins une partie desdits sous-systèmes sont calibrés individuellement (200) et fournissent des informations de calibration spécifiques (300) pour chaque sous-système, où des fichiers de mappage (20) sont générés et associés audit sous-système calibré, ladite combinaison étant adaptée pour mettre en oeuvre le procédé de l'une quelconque des revendications 1-11.<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Un produit logiciel informatique adapté pour mettre en oeuvre le procédé de l'une quelconque des revendications 1-11.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Un produit logiciel informatique selon la revendication précédente, exécutant en outre une fonction d'auto-détection pour détecter les composants et/ou récupérer les fichiers de mappage 20 avant ladite étape d'alignement (800).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Un contrôleur (15) pour un système de mesure de coordonnées, comprenant un dispositif de stockage (17) et un processeur (16) adapté pour mettre en oeuvre le procédé de l'une quelconque des revendications 1-11.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16669188" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="142" he="218" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2(A),2(B),2(C),2(D)"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="158" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="163" he="199" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --><figure id="f0004" num="4"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="142" he="139" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
