<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2682534-A1" country="EP" doc-number="2682534" kind="A1" date="20140108" family-id="48745973" file-reference-id="303553" date-produced="20180822" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146585756" ucid="EP-2682534-A1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2682534</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-12174927-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154847948" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12174927</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120704</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP192284379" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12174927.9</doc-number><date>20120704</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140556032" ucid="EP-12174927-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12174927</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120704</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989320401" load-source="docdb">E03F   1/00        20060101AFI20130221BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989630602" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">E03F   1/005       20130101 FI20130812BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132361901" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Bewässerungskasten, Entwässerungskasten und ein Satz aus zwei dieser Kästen</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132361902" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Irrigation box, drainage box, or an attenuation box and a set of two of these boxes</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132361903" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Dispositif distributeur</invention-title><citations><patent-citations><patcit mxw-id="PCIT242944925" load-source="docdb" ucid="EP-0943737-A1"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>0943737</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>19990922</date></document-id><sources><source name="APP" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT371081346" load-source="docdb" ucid="EP-1416099-A2"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>1416099</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20040506</date></document-id><sources><source name="APP" created-by-npl="N"/><source name="SEA" category="XD" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT371081347" load-source="docdb" ucid="EP-1997970-A1"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>1997970</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20081203</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="XY" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT242944929" load-source="docdb" ucid="EP-2385178-A2"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>2385178</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20111109</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="Y" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit></patent-citations></citations></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919538017" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>WAVIN BV</last-name><address><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919517666" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>WAVIN B.V.</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919014352" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Wavin B.V.</last-name><iid>100252826</iid><address><street>Stationsplein 3</street><city>8011 CW Zwolle</city><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919529791" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>POPPE RICHARD</last-name><address><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919537993" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>POPPE, RICHARD</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919008308" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>POPPE, RICHARD</last-name><address><street>c/o Rollepaal 20</street><city>7701 BS Dedemsvaart</city><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919504523" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>VAN DIJK BEREND JAN</last-name><address><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919526962" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>VAN DIJK, BEREND JAN</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919013735" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>VAN DIJK, BEREND JAN</last-name><address><street>c/o Rollepaal 20</street><city>7701 BS Dedemsvaart</city><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919524925" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>VAN DER SCHEER MARCO</last-name><address><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919510144" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>van der Scheer, Marco</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919017116" load-source="patent-office" sequence="3" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>van der Scheer, Marco</last-name><address><street>c/o Rollepaal 20</street><city>7701 BS Dedemsvaart</city><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919009414" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>HOFFMANN EITLE</last-name><iid>100061036</iid><address><street>Patent- und Rechtsanwälte Arabellastrasse 4</street><city>81925 München</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549823759" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS549837645" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549823761" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549828990" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549751816" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549829443" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549837666" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549823766" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549829444" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549829445" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549911638" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549828991" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549752787" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549823767" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549829454" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549823768" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549837667" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549751825" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549829455" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549752788" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549829456" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549828992" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549756538" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549828993" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549828998" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549756539" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS549756540" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549751826" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549911639" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549751827" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549756545" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549752793" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549756546" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS549751828" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549837668" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549911640" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549751833" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS549828999" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states><ep-extended-states><ep-extended-state-data><country>BA</country></ep-extended-state-data><ep-extended-state-data><country>ME</country></ep-extended-state-data></ep-extended-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA128673810" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p id="pa01" num="0001">Irrigation box, drainage box or attenuation box, comprising as integral parts of the box a base (4), at least one side wall (5a-d), several columns (7, 7a, 7b)and at least one connecting part (8, 8a, 8b). The base has openings (4a) therein for passage of fluid and the side wall(s) also have openings (5e) therein for the same purpose. The box has an open side (6) opposite the base which allows coupling with a further identical box. The connecting part is integral with the box and extends either between a column that is positioned free from direct contact with the side wall and a column which is in direct contact with the side wall, or between a column which that is positioned freee from direct contact with the side wall and the side wall itself.
<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="134" he="97" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA128738088" lang="EN" source="EPO" load-source="docdb"><p>Irrigation box, drainage box or attenuation box, comprising as integral parts of the box a base (4), at least one side wall (5a-d), several columns (7, 7a, 7b)and at least one connecting part (8, 8a, 8b). The base has openings (4a) therein for passage of fluid and the side wall(s) also have openings (5e) therein for the same purpose. The box has an open side (6) opposite the base which allows coupling with a further identical box. The connecting part is integral with the box and extends either between a column that is positioned free from direct contact with the side wall and a column which is in direct contact with the side wall, or between a column which that is positioned freee from direct contact with the side wall and the side wall itself.</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES63959798" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><p id="p0001" num="0001">The invention relates to an irrigation box, a drainage box, or an attenuation box for handling ground water, that can control or otherwise attenuate water which falls for instance as rain, particularly in "flash" storms or from flooding, including flooding caused by melting ice and/or snow.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="EP0943737A"><text>EP 0 943 737</text></patcit> discloses an irrigation and/or drainage box which, in combination with another box or other boxes, form an irrigation and/or drainage unit or system to be placed in the ground. Such a unit or system can then withstand loads from the surrounding earth and/or loads on the ground. However, such a unit or system is not very capable of withstanding side soil loads or other side forces. For certain circumstances, it is desirable that the strength in lateral direction is improved. Such a box may also be known and used as an attenuation box.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">From <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="EP1416099A"><text>EP 1 416 099</text></patcit> grids are known for placement between two boxes which form together a unit or system, referred to as a ground water or attenuation system. The positioning of the grid where the open sides of two boxes meet enhances stability, particularly when the grids are connected with other structures which are integral parts of each box. Such systems can then provide an improved capability to withstand side soil loads or other side forces, so that the strength in lateral direction is acceptable.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">However, the necessity of such a grid causes a number of problems. For a start, it makes the unit or system more complex, so that assembling such a unit or system could lead<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> to fatal errors. It is possible that the placement of such a grid will be forgotten, something which is not so easily noticeable once the unit or system has been assembled. The unit or system will then not have the expected lateral strength. The placement of the grid requires additional time for the assembling. This increases labour costs. Furthermore, the production of the grid raises the costs for the entire unit or system. Finally, materials management at a construction site is needed to ensure that there is a sufficient number of grids for appropriately assembling the unit or system. The use of such a system will thus increase overhead costs.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">The invention aims to solve at least one of the above problems. This is achieved by providing an irrigation and/or drainage box in accordance with claim 1. Accordingly, the invention provides an irrigation box, a drainage box, or an attenuation box, comprising as integral parts of the box:
<ul><li>a base having openings therein for passage of fluid into and/or out of the box;</li><li>at least one side wall having openings therein for passage of fluid into and/or out of the box;</li><li>an open side which lies opposite the base, the open side being designed such that two of these boxes can be placed with the open sides towards one another and then be connected to one another to adopt an assembled condition;</li><li>at least one column which extends substantially vertically from the base towards the open side; and</li><li>at least one connecting part between
<ul><li>one column which is positioned free from direct contact with one of the at least one side wall and one column which is positioned in direct contact with one of the at least one side wall, and/or between</li><li>one column which is positioned free from direct contact with one of the at least one side wall and one of the at least one side wall,</li></ul><!-- EPO <DP n="3"> -->
the connecting part being free from direct contact with the base.</li></ul></p><p id="p0006" num="0006">By providing as an integral part of the box a connecting part between columns and/or a side wall, the capability of withstanding side soil loads or other side forces is improved, whilst also at least one of the prior art problems is solved.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">In an embodiment of a box according to the invention, the box is such that in the assembled condition the columns of one of these boxes is one-to-one connected up with the columns of the other one of these two boxes. Within the context of the present invention, this has the advantage that the additional strength in lateral direction can be "passed on" from one box to the other. Consequently, it is not necessary that each column in each box is stiffened up by the maximum number of connecting parts. It will be possible to reduce the number of connecting parts without a significant loss of lateral strength. Less connecting parts will obviously ease manufacturing, reduce the material needed for the production of such a box and overall minimize the costs.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">In an embodiment of a box according to the invention, the at least one connecting part is positioned such that in the assembled condition none of the at least one connecting parts of one box has a mirror position with respect to the position of the connecting parts of the other box, the mirror plane being the plane where the open sides meet. In such an embodiment, there is per area of interface between the boxes an optimized number of connecting parts. Such a box strikes a balance between costs and improvement of strength in lateral direction.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">In an embodiment of a box according to the invention, the at least one connecting part is positioned such that in the assembled condition each of the at least one connecting part<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> of one box has a point symmetrical position with respect to the position of the connecting parts of the other box, the point of symmetry being the centre point of the plane where the open sides meet. Advantageously, this embodiment can be such that only one type of box needs to be produced, keeping production costs low, planning, material management, storage control, etc. easy and straightforward. Furthermore, the box can still be produced in such a way that also without placement in the assembled condition, the box has sufficient strength in all relevant directions, so that for instance, stacking of such boxes other than in an assembled condition, will not lead to deformation of such boxes under their own weight and will avoid undesirable phenomena such as creep and other forms of plastic deformation.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">In an embodiment of a box according to the invention, the at least one connecting part is positioned such that in the assembled condition each of the at least one connecting part of one box is in a mirror position with respect to the position of the connecting parts of the other box, the mirror plane being the plane where the open sides meet. In this embodiment, the columns of the two boxes connected up one-to-one, are supported in the lateral direction by double the amount of connecting parts, giving superior strength in lateral direction.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">In an embodiment of a box according to the invention, a number of connecting parts is oriented perpendicular to the orientation of the remaining number of connecting parts. In such an embodiment, the strength in the lateral direction is improved not only in one lateral direction but in two lateral directions which are perpendicular to each other.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">In an embodiment of a box according to the invention, at least one of the connecting parts is positioned between the base and the ends of the at least one column. In such an embodiment, the position of the connecting parts can be<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> optimized such that two connecting parts in mirror position (the open sides forming the mirror plane) can optimally contribute to the overall thickness of two columns which are one-to-one connected up with each other. The lateral strength and stiffness of a single box may optimally be improved in that case.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">The invention is further related to a set of two boxes wherein one of the at least one connecting parts of one box is arranged to adopt a mating position with respect to one of the at least one connecting parts of the other box for reinforcing the respective parts.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">The invention also relates to a set of two boxes as described above, wherein the boxes are identical and are connectable to one another through male and female connector parts.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">The invention will further be explained on the basis of a drawing which shows in:
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig.1</figref>: schematically a first embodiment of a box according to the invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2</figref>: schematically a second embodiment of a box according to the invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 3</figref>: schematically a third embodiment of a box according to the invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 4</figref>: schematically a fourth embodiment of a box according to the invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 5</figref>: schematically a fifth embodiment of a box according to the invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 6</figref>: schematically a sixth embodiment of a box according to the invention; and</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 7</figref>: schematically a seventh embodiment of a box according to the invention.</li></ul></p><p id="p0016" num="0016">In the drawing, like references refer to like parts.<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></p><p id="p0017" num="0017"><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> shows an embodiment of an irrigation box, a drainage box, or an attenuation box. The box is a one-part construction, i.e. all parts are integral parts of the box 1. The box has a base 4 with openings 4a therein for passage of fluid into and/or out of the box 1. The box has four side walls 5a, 5b, 5c, 5d with openings 5e therein for passage of fluid into and/or out of the box. Two side walls 5a, 5b extend along the longitudinal direction and two side walls 5c, 5d extend along a transverse direction. As shown, box 1 is block-shaped. However, it is also conceivable that the block is cylindrical in shape and that the side wall concerns one wall which is closed in itself, i.e. endless. Of course, also other shapes are possible, such as formed by side walls which extend in vertical direction and form together a triangle, a pentagon, a hexagon, an octagon, etc. The box can also be substantially L-shaped, or cross-shaped. In any case, the box 1 has an open side 6 which is situated opposite the base 4. The open side 6 is designed such that two of these boxes 1 can be placed with the open sides 6 towards one another and then be connected to one another to adopt an assembled condition.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">Box 1 is provided with columns 7 which extend substantially vertically from the base 4 towards the open side 6. A number of columns 7 may be positioned free from direct contact with any of the side walls 5a, 5b, 5c, 5d. Such free-standing columns are denoted by the reference 7a. However, it is also possible that one or more columns are positioned in direct contact with one of the side walls 5a, 5b, 5c, 5d. Those columns are denoted with reference 7b. Box 1 comprises connecting parts 8 as further integral parts of box 1. Such a connecting part 8 may be between one column 7a which is positioned free from direct contact with one of the side walls 5a, 5b, 5c, 5d and one column 7b which is positioned in direct contact with one of the side walls 5a, 5b, 5c, 5d. Such connecting parts are denoted by the reference 8a. However, additionally, or alternatively, such connecting<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> parts 8 may also be between one of the side walls 5a, 5b, 5c, 5d and one column 7a which is positioned free from direct contact with one of the side walls 5a, 5b, 5c, 5d. Such connecting parts are not shown in the drawing. However, the drawing shows embodiments wherein connecting parts 8b are between two columns 7a which are each free from direct contact with side walls 5a, 5b, 5c, 5d.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">In general it applies that the connecting parts 8, 8a, 8b are free from direct contact with the base 4. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0001 f0002">Figs. 1-4</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 6</figref>, it is possible that the connecting parts 8, 8a, 8b each connect up with column 7, 7a, 7b at the free end 9 of the respective column 7, 7a, 7b. The free end 9 is considered to be the end of the column which is opposite the end that is connected up with base 4.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020"><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 5</figref> shows an embodiment wherein the connecting parts 8, 8a, 8b are each positioned between the base 4 and the end 9 of columns 7, 7a, 7b.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">It is possible that in the assembled condition the columns 7, 7a, 7b of one of two boxes 1 are one-to-one connected up with the columns 7, 7a, 7b of the other one of two such boxes 1. This can easily be imagined for each of the embodiments shown.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">Note that the free ends 9 of the columns 7, 7a, 7b of the box shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2</figref> are provided with so-called male connector parts 10. This equally applies to the embodiment shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 4</figref>. However, also note that the embodiments of a box 1 according to the invention as shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1, 3</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0002">5</figref>, depict so-called female connector parts 11 at the free ends 9 of the columns 7a, 7b, 7c.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">It will be understood that the box shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2</figref> can easily be put into an assembled condition by letting the open sides 6 of the box shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2</figref> and in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 3</figref> meet and the male<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> connectors 10 and female connectors 11 connect up. Note that in the embodiment shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2</figref>, the connecting parts 8, 8a are oriented parallel to the transverse side walls 5c, 5d. In contrast, in the embodiment of box 1 as shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 3</figref>, the connecting parts 8, 8a, 8b are oriented parallel to the longitudinal side walls 5a, 5b. By assembling the box shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2</figref> with the box shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 3</figref>, the columns 7, 7a, 7b in each of these boxes are optimally supported and the obtained assemblage of two irrigation boxes 1 has a relatively strong lateral strength (in this context understood to be a strength considered in a direction parallel to base 4 and/or open side 6).</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">It is possible to have both male connector parts 10 and female connector parts 11 in equal numbers distributed over the free ends 9 of the columns 7a, 7b,. <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 6</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 7</figref> show an example of this. Note that the free ends 9 of the column 7d have partly a male connector part 10 and partly a female connector part 11. It is also possible that the box having the male connector parts 10 and female connector parts 11 distributed over the free ends 9 of the column 7a, 7b, can be such that two identical boxes 1 can be put together in an assembled condition. An embodiment of a box suitable for that purpose is shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 7</figref>. That box is connectable to an identical box by means of connecting the male and female connector parts 10, 11.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">For such boxes 1, it is possible that connecting parts 8, 8a, 8b are positioned such that in the assembled condition each of these connecting parts 8, 8a, 8b of that box 1 are in a mirror position with respect to the position of the connecting parts 8, 8a, 8b of the other, identical, box 1. The mirror plane is then the plane where the open sides 6 meet. Examples of such configurations of the connecting parts 8, 8a, 8b are shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 5</figref>.<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --></p><p id="p0026" num="0026">However, it is also possible that the connecting parts 8, 8a, 8b are positioned such that in the assembled condition none of the connecting parts 8, 8a, 8b of one box has a mirror position with respect to the position of the connecting parts 8, 8a, 8b of the other, identical, box 1. Again, the mirror plane is also in this context the plane where the open sides 6 meet. An example of such an embodiment is shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 6</figref>.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">It is further also possible that the connecting parts 8, 8a, 8b are positioned such that in an assembled position each of these connecting parts 8, 8a, 8b of one box has a point-symmetrical position with respect to the position of the connecting parts 8, 8a, 8b of the other, identical, box. In this context the point of symmetry is the centre point of the plane where the open sides 6 meet. Although the drawing does not show such an embodiment, a skilled person will have no problem in visualizing such an embodiment.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028"><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 4</figref> shows an embodiment of a box 1 according to the invention wherein a number of the connecting parts 8, 8a, 8b are oriented perpendicular to the orientation of the remaining number of the connecting parts 8, 8a, 8b. The <figref idrefs="f0001 f0002">Figs. 1-5</figref> show boxes wherein each of the connecting parts 8, 8a, 8b is oriented parallel to one of the side walls 5a, 5b, 5c, 5d. In contrast, <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 6</figref> shows an embodiment of a box 1 according to the invention wherein the connecting parts 8 are oriented diagonally with respect to the side walls 5a, 5b, 5c, 5d.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">Although the drawing only shows embodiments of boxes according to the invention wherein the connecting parts 8, 8a, 8b extend in a direction parallel to base 4 and/or open side 6, it is not inconceivable that at least one of the connecting parts 8, 8a, 8b is oriented diagonally with respect to the base 4. An example is shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 6</figref>.<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></p><p id="p0030" num="0030">It is also not inconceivable that one of the connecting parts 8, 8a, 8b connects at least three columns 7, 7a, 7b, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 6</figref>.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">Although not shown in the drawing, the disclosure is also related to a set of two boxes according to the invention as explained with reference to various embodiments, wherein the connecting parts 8, 8a, 8b of one box 1 are arranged to adopt in the assembled condition a mating position with respect to one of the connecting parts 8, 8a, 8b of the other box, for reinforcing the respective connecting parts. Thus one box may have connecting parts having a U-shape in cross-section, and the other box may have connecting parts which fit in the U-shaped connecting parts of the other box. This would enhance the stability and stiffness of the two boxes in their assembled condition.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">It will be clear that other configurations for the connecting parts are possible. Besides the U-shape in cross section other shapes are possible e.g. +, |, ○, ┘, ┴, □, H, or a segment of a circle.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">The boxes as described above can be made of plastic, for instance by molding techniques.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">The invention is not limited to the embodiments described above. Many variations and modifications are possible. For instance, a box according to the invention may comprise more than one connecting part between a pair of two columns and/or between a certain column and a certain part of a side wall. Although the connecting parts are in the drawing shown to be straight, it is not inconceivable that some curvature is included. The columns may be round columns, square columns, pentagons, hexagons, octagons, etc. The term "column" also embraces a part of a side wall which is locally thicker to provide the function of a column. Such a thicker part of the side wall may equally extend substantially vertically from<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> the base toward the open side. The openings may have various shapes. In principle there is no limitation to the shape of the openings. Although it has been shown that the connector parts may be of the type male and female, both integral parts of the respective boxes, it should be understood that the invention is not limited to boxes having connector parts as integral parts of the box. It is equally possible that the connector parts are separate parts.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">The side walls are not necessarily panels which extend in vertical direction. The side walls may equally be composed of bars which have, for instance, a circular or a rectangular cross section and extend in horizontal direction.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">Many variations and modifications are possible within the framework of the invention as defined by the appending claims.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56982851" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --><claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Irrigation box, drainage box, or attenuation box comprising as integral parts of the box (1):
<claim-text>- a base (4) having openings (4a) therein for passage of fluid into and/or out of the box (1);</claim-text>
<claim-text>- at least one side wall (5a, 5b, 5c, 5d) having openings (5e) therein for passage of fluid into and/or out of the box;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- an open side (6) which lies opposite the base, the open side (6) being designed such that two of these boxes (1) can be placed with the open sides (6) towards one another and then be connected to one another to adopt an assembled condition;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- at least one column (7, 7a, 7b) which extends substantially vertically from the base (4) towards the open side (6); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>- at least one connecting part (8, 8a, 8b) between
<claim-text>• one column (7a) which is positioned free from direct contact with one of the at least one side wall and one column (7b) which is positioned in direct contact with one of the at least one side wall (5a, 5b, 5c, 5d), and/or between</claim-text>
<claim-text>• one column (7a) which is positioned free from direct contact with one of the at least one side wall (5a, 5b, 5c, 5d) and one of the at least one side wall (5a, 5b, 5c, 5d),<br/>
the connecting part (8, 8a, 8b) being free from direct contact with the base (4).</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>A box according to claim 1, wherein the at least one connecting part is between two columns which are each positioned free from direct contact with one of the at least one side wall.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>A box according to claim 1 or 2 where the at least one connecting part connects up with at least one column at the free end of that column.<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>A box according to claim 1, 2 or 3, wherein the at least one connecting part has a U-shaped cross section.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>A box according to any one of the previous claims, such that in the assembled condition the columns of one of these two boxes are one-to-one connected up with the columns of the other one of these two boxes.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>A box according to claim 5, wherein the at least one connecting part is positioned such that in the assembled condition each of the at least one connecting parts of one box is in a mirror position with respect to the position of the connecting parts of the other box, the mirror plane being the plane where the open sites meet.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>A box according to claim 5, wherein the at least one connecting part is positioned such that in an assembled condition none of the at least one connecting parts of one box has a mirror position with respect to the position of the connecting parts of the other box, the mirror plane being the plane where the open sites meet.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>A box according to claim 5, 6 or 7, wherein the at least one connecting part is positioned such that in an assembled condition each of the at least one connecting parts of one box has a point-symmetrical position with respect to the position of the connecting parts of the other box, the point of symmetry being the center point of the plane where the open sites meet.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>A box according to any one of the previous claims, wherein a number of connecting parts is oriented perpendicular to the orientation of the remaining number of connecting parts.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>A box according to any one of the previous claims, wherein at least one of the connecting parts is oriented parallel to at least a part of the at least one side wall.<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>A box according to any one of the previous claims, wherein at least one of the connecting parts is oriented diagonally with respect to at least a part of the at least one side wall.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>A box according to any one of the previous claims, wherein at least one of the connecting parts is oriented diagonally with respect to the base.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>A box according to any one of the previous claims, wherein at least one of the connecting parts is positioned between the base and the ends of the at least one column.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>A box according to any one of the previous claims, wherein one of the connecting parts connects at least three columns,<br/>
or two columns and one of the at least one side walls.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>A set of two boxes according to any one of the previous claims, wherein one of the at least one connecting parts of one box is arranged to adopt in the assembled condition a mating position with respect to one of the at least one connecting parts of the other box for reinforcing the respective connecting parts.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0016" num="0016"><claim-text>A set of two boxes according to any one of the previous claims wherein the boxes are identical and are connectable to one another through male and female connector parts.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16671177" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1,2,3"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="158" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --><figure id="f0002" num="4,5,6"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="157" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --><figure id="f0003" num="7"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="165" he="215" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><search-report-data><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="158" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="161" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0003" file="srep0003.tif" wi="164" he="233" type="tif"/></search-report-data><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
