<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2531015-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2531015" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="42082536" file-reference-id="315063" date-produced="20180825" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146587742" ucid="EP-2531015-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2531015</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-11703256-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154849934" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>11703256</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20110204</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140551058" ucid="GB-201001902-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>GB</country><doc-number>201001902</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20100205</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140547898" ucid="GB-2011050199-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>GB</country><doc-number>2011050199</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20110204</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130801</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989323755" load-source="docdb">A01D  34/06        20060101AFI20110824BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989323756" load-source="docdb">A01D  75/28        20060101ALI20110824BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2125164046" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A01D  75/28        20130101 FI20141219BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2125166395" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A01D  34/86        20130101 LI20141219BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132367859" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">MASCHINE MIT AM BODEN ARBEITENDEN ARBEITSELEMENTEN MIT VERBESSERTER STABILITÄT</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132367860" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">MACHINE WITH GROUND WORKING ELEMENTS PROVIDING IMPROVED STABILITY</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132367861" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">MACHINE COMPRENANT DES UTILES TRAVAILANT SUR SOL AVEC UNE STABILITÉ AMELIORÉE</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919538054" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>RANSOMES JACOBSEN LTD</last-name><address><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919514147" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>RANSOMES JACOBSEN LIMITED</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919535218" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>CLIFFORD CHRISTIAN DEAN</last-name><address><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919510282" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>CLIFFORD, CHRISTIAN, DEAN</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919019857" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>CLIFFORD, CHRISTIAN, DEAN</last-name><address><street>53 Pearsons Way Copdock</street><city>Ipswich, Suffolk IP8 3LG</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919019856" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Ransomes Jacobsen Limited</last-name><iid>101264259</iid><address><street>West Road Ransomes Europark</street><city>Ipswich, Suffolk IP3 9TT</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919019855" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Garratt, Peter Douglas</last-name><iid>100020166</iid><address><street>Mathys &amp; Squire LLP 120 Holborn</street><city>London EC1N 2SQ</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="GB-2011050199-W"><document-id><country>GB</country><doc-number>2011050199</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20110204</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2011095822-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2011095822</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20110811</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549777455" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS549792627" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549777456" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549865376" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549884781" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549777487" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549792628" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549777469" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549777488" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549777497" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549860887" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549865377" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549865394" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549777470" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549777498" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549777471" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549792637" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549884786" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549777472" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549865395" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549777499" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549862976" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549792638" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549862977" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549862986" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549921052" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS549921053" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549860888" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549792639" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549921054" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549777500" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549860889" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549777505" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS549860894" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549777506" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549792640" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549921055" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS549884787" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63960178" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><p id="p0001" num="0001">This invention relates to cutting machines such as grass cutting machines for sports or municipal usage. A typical ride-on grass cutting machine for such usage has multiple grass cutting units which may take the form, for example, of cutter reels or rotating cutters. There will typically be a centrally disposed cutting unit with left and right hand cutting units (or pairs of cutting units) mounted laterally so as to cut contiguous or slightly overlapping swathes as the machine is driven forward over the ground. Often, the left and right cutting units are liftable with respect to the chassis from a grass cutting position to a transport position in which the overall width of the machine is reduced.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002">In many cases, each cutting unit will incorporate a roller or other ground engaging element which serves in the cutting position to orientate the cutting blade or blades with respect to the ground so as to give the desired height of cut.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">In many municipal areas and in some sports, it is a requirement to cut grass on ground that has substantial undulations. It is recognised that for the safety of the ride-on operator - and persons nearby - great care must be taken in design and in operation of the machine to ensure stability over the undulating ground.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">As for example in <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="NL7902576A"><text>NL 7 902 576 A</text></patcit>, it has been proposed on certain grass cutting machines and other utility vehicles to install an inclinometer and to provide a warning as a measured incline approaches a pre-set threshold or thresholds. It is recognised however that through inattentiveness - or because of competing demands - an operator may ignore warnings given to him.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">Advantage is seen in providing an improved machine and method of operation in which steps are taken under certain conditions to improve the stability of the machine without reliance being placed on operator action.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">According to one aspect of present invention there is provided a machine comprising: a chassis having ground engaging wheels; at least two ground working units mounted on the chassis at locations spaced in a first direction, each working unit having a ground engaging element and being liftable with respect to the chassis from a working position in which the respective ground engaging element is in<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> ground contact; an inclinometer adapted to monitor an inclination of the chassis in the first direction with respect to the horizontal; and a controller adapted to receive an inclination value from the inclinometer and configured when the inclination value exceeds a defined threshold to lift that one of the working units that is by virtue of the inclination at a higher level than the other of the working units.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">The controller may be configured to lifting a working unit from a working position in which a substantial proportion of the weight of the working unit is borne by the ground, to a lifted position in which a substantial proportion of the weight of the working unit is borne by the chassis.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">It will thus be seen that embodiments of the invention can react to a measured inclination - without reliance upon operator involvement - to lift some but not all working units in a manner predetermined to improve the stability of the machine.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">Grass cutting units are often carried on lift arms, with the lift arm being rotatable from a grass cutting position, in which the cutting unit is horizontal, to a transport position in which the cutting unit is vertical. The transport position will typically reduce the overall width of the machine for transport along roads or through gateways. The present inventors have recognised that the stability of the machine on a left to right incline (that is to say in the direction in which the left and right hand cutting units are separated) can be improved by lifting the higher of the two cutting units to a stability lift position. The moment exerted on the chassis by the lifted unit, in the rotational sense which improves stability, is greater in the stability lift position than in either of the working or transport positions. This is because, in the working position, the weight or a substantial proportion of the weight of the cutting unit is borne on the ground. Taking into account geometrical considerations, lifting to the stability lift position may involve rotating the lift arm through that minimum angle that can be assumed to (or be determined to) transfer substantially all of the weight of the unit from the ground to the chassis. Rotation beyond that minimum angle may of course unhelpfully reduce the moment applied.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">The chassis may be adapted to be driven in a forward direction with said first direction being transverse to the forward direction. Whilst the typical situation will have differential lifting of left and right hand units (together with lifting or not of a<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> central unit), situations may arise where differential lifting of forward and backward units can improve stability in the front and back direction. A practical situation may require an optimal strategy to be selected in accordance with a measured left to right incline and a measured fore and aft incline.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">Each working unit may be mounted on a lift arm extending in the first direction, the lift arm being rotatable with respect to the chassis about an axis extending in the forward direction. Preferably, the lift arm is rotatable with respect to the chassis from a working position in which the working unit is essentially horizontal to a transport position in which the working unit is essentially vertical, the controller being configured when the inclination value exceeds a defined threshold to rotate the lift arm of that one of the working units to a stability lift position intermediate the working and transport positions. Advantageously, the moment exerted on the chassis by the working unit is greater in the stability lift position than in the transport position.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">The working units will typically comprise grass cutting units, each grass cutting unit suitably comprising a driven cutter reel cooperating with a fixed blade.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">Usefully, the defined threshold can be set in the range of 60% to 90% or preferably in the range of 70% to 80% of the measured stability angle, being the maximum inclination of the chassis in the first direction with respect to the horizontal at which the machine remains stable.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">In another aspect the present invention consists in a method of operating a machine comprising a chassis having ground engaging wheels; at least two ground working units mounted on the chassis at locations spaced in a first direction, and being liftable with respect to the chassis from a working position; the method comprising the steps of measuring an inclination of the chassis in the first direction with respect to the horizontal; and in dependence upon the measured inclination initiating differential lifting of the working units so as to increase a moment exerted on the chassis by a working unit in a rotational sense which improves the stability of the chassis with regard to the inclination.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">The step of differential lifting the working units may comprises lifting a working unit from a working position in which a substantial proportion of the weight of the working<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> unit is borne by the ground, to a stability lift position in which a substantial proportion of the weight of the working unit is borne by the chassis.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">Where the working unit is further liftable from the stability lift position to a transport position, the stability lift position may be selected such that the moment exerted on the chassis by the working unit is greater in the stability lift position than in the transport position.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">The measured inclination may be compared with one or more predetermined inclination thresholds with distinct visual or audible warnings being optionally provided at each threshold.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">The present invention will now be described by way of example with reference to the accompanying drawings in which:-
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> is a side view of a grass cutting machine.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 2</figref> is a front view of the machine shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 3</figref> is a pictorial view of the machine on inclined ground.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 4</figref> is a view similar to <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 3</figref> but illustrating operation of an example of the invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 5</figref> is a flow diagram illustrating control of the machine in accordance with an example of the invention.</li></ul></p><p id="p0019" num="0019">The grass cutting machine shown in the drawings is of generally conventional construction and the physical layout of the working parts of the machine need not be described in detail.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">The grass cutting machine shown at (10) comprises a chassis (12) supported on forward (14) and rear (16) wheels. An operator seat unit (18) is provided on the chassis.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">The machine carries three reel cutting units: a central cutting unit (20) hung beneath the chassis and two front cutting units (left 22 and right 24, as seen by the operator) disposed forwardly of the front wheels (14). Each front cutting unit (22,24) is mounted on a lift arm (26). At the inward end, each lift arm is mounted on the chassis for rotation about a horizontal axis (28) oriented fore and aft of the machine.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> At the outward end, the lift arm supports the cutting unit through a sleeve (30), the arrangement providing relative rotation of the outward end of the lifting arm and the cutting reel about an axis (32) parallel to the axis (28).</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">A hydraulic ram (not shown) is connected with each lift arm (26) via a lug (34). Thus, introduction of hydraulic fluid into the ram will affect rotation of the lifting arm about the axis (28) to lift the associated cutting unit. It will be seen that each cutting unit contains a ground roller (36). This extends parallel to the axis of the cutting reel and is positioned so that in the cutting orientation, engagement of the roller with the ground serves to control the height of cut. In this cutting orientation, the cutter unit floats with respect to the chassis with relative rotation about the parallel axes (28) (32) serving to accommodate ground contours.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023"><figref idrefs="f0001">Figures 1 and 2</figref> show the cutting units in a transport position. Each lift arm (26) has been lifted to the maximum extent by extension of the corresponding ram. In this transport position, the left and right cutting units are locked in a vertical orientation and the overall width of the machine has been significantly reduced..</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">An inclinometer (38) is mounted on the chassis, conveniently at a location beneath the operator seat unit (18). This provides an input to the control system of the machine, this input providing a value of the forward-and-backward inclination (that is to say the left-right horizontal direction in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>) and the side-to-side inclination (that is to say the lef<b>t-</b> right horizontal direction in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 2</figref>). The inclinometer (38) may take the form of a commercially available accelerometer having digital outputs.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">The manner in which the control system of the machine utilises these incline values will now be described.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026"><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 3</figref> shows a machine positioned on a left to right incline of 22° to the horizontal. The machine is shown with the cutting unit that is lower on the slope, raised into the transport position. The central cutting unit and the cutting unit which is upper on the slope are both in the grass cutting position, that is to say with the roller of each of those two units in ground contact and the unit floating with respect to the chassis. This orientation is chosen as an illustration because it poses a greater risk to stability than the orientation in which all three cutting units are in the cutting position. This orientation with one cutting reel in the transport position may occur, for example,<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> where grass is being cut on an incline adjacent a path or other obstacle. Whilst this orientation has been chosen as an illustration, it will be understood that a risk to stability would occur in other orientations.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">In the position shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 3</figref>, the centre of gravity of the machine (which is shown at 40 in the figure) is displaced from the machine's centre line by virtue of the illustrated orientation of the cutting units. That is to say the cutting reel in the transport position has its weight borne by the chassis and contributes a turning moment. In contrast, the two cutting units which are in the grass cutting position have their weight essentially borne by the respective ground rollers and thus contribute effectively no turning moment. A vertical line is shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 3</figref> which represents the outer edge of the ground engagement of the forward wheel (14), this being the edge about which any toppling would occur. It will be understood that as shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 3</figref>, the machine will loose stability and topple if the centre of gravity shown at (40) moves to the left (in the figure) of the vertical line (42).</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">In accordance with this invention, detection of an inclination in the left-right direction which is in excess of a predetermined threshold (in this example 22°) results in a lifting movement of the cutting unit which is at the higher level with respect to the slope. This lifting movement is not intended to bring the cutting unit to the transport position but is sufficient to lift both ends of the ground roller of the unit clear of the ground. The weight of the lifted cutting unit is then taken on the chassis and a turning moment is applied. The centre of gravity of the machine is shifted to the position (44) shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 4</figref>. With the cutting unit normally floating with respect to the chassis, it is advantageous to control this lifting by pulsing the corresponding hydraulic ram, that is to say by introducing a defined amount of hydraulic fluid into that ram. That defined amount of hydraulic fluid should be sufficient, with the geometry shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 4</figref>, to lift the right hand end of the ground engaging roller (36) from all ground contact.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">A flow diagram for a preferred control process is shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 5</figref>.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">It will be seen that before any lift/lower function is initiated, checks are made first to determine whether an operator is present and second to determine whether a measured slope angle is less than a first threshold which in this case is 16°. For<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> convenience, the same threshold is applied to the slope measured front and back and to the slope measured left and right. It may in some cases be useful to have separate threshold values. One way to pre-determine this first threshold value is to measure the actual stability of the machine, that is to say to measure the maximum angle of an incline that can be encountered before stability is lost. The first threshold may be chosen to be a proportion, for example approximately 50%, of the maximum stability angle.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">If an operator is present and if the measured slope of angle is less than the first threshold of in this case 16°, control solenoids are operated allowing selected units to lift or lower and the run cutter control system is allowed to drive the cutting reels conventionally.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">If a slope angle is detected in excess of the first threshold value, a determination is made of whether action is required at a first, second or third level. In a preferred example, the angles associated with the first, second and third levels are:-
<tables id="tabl0001" num="0001"><table frame="all"><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="44mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="48mm"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="15mm"/><thead><row><entry valign="top"><b>Measured inclination</b></entry><entry valign="top"><b>% of maximum stability angle</b></entry><entry valign="top"><b>Level</b></entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry>Up to 15<sup>0</sup></entry><entry>Up to 50%</entry><entry/></row><row><entry>Greater than or equal to 16<sup>0</sup></entry><entry/><entry>First</entry></row><row><entry>Greater than or equal to 18<sup>0</sup></entry><entry/><entry>Second</entry></row><row><entry>Greater than or equal to 22<sup>0</sup></entry><entry>Over 70%</entry><entry>Third</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></tables></p><p id="p0033" num="0033">At the first level, a warning sub-system is initiated but operation otherwise proceeds as before. The first level warning sub-system might include a display with real-time slope reading, with a selected colour or temporal variation of the display or an appropriate icon.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">At the second level, a second level warning sub-system is initiated; this may comprise a different colour or a different temporal variation of the visual display and may further include an appropriate audible alarm. Also, lift, lower and float functions of all three cutter units are blocked. It will be observed that this blocking is the same blocking that occurs in the event of an operator <u>not</u> being present.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></p><p id="p0035" num="0035">At the third level, a third level warning sub-system is initiated in which visual and/or audible alarms are varied to convey still greater urgency to the operator. Also, any of the cutters which are running are stopped. Lift, lower and float functions continue to be blocked. A determination is then made as to the sense of any slope in the left right direction, shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 5</figref> as +X or -X. This determination of the sense of the incline enables the upper of the left and right cutting units to be determined so that, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 4</figref>, the hydraulic ram associated with the upper cutting unit can pulsed to lift that upper cutting unit from the ground. Advantageously, the centre unit is also lifted so that the weight of the unit is borne by the chassis, again providing a moment which tends to improve stability.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">In appropriate cases, the position of each lift arm may be monitored as the associated cutting unit floats. Then, the hydraulic ram associated with the upper cutting unit can be controlled to rotate the lift arm by that precise minimum amount necessary to lift the cutting unit wholly from the ground. In another arrangement, a similar degree of precision can be obtained by monitoring the proportion of the weight of each cutting unit borne by the chassis, for example with strain gauges.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">In certain embodiments, decisions on whether to lift particular units will be taken in dependence upon the measured value of both the left/right and the fore/aft inclinations. On ground having a substantial slope in both directions, it may for example to lift only the centre unit or only the higher forward unit, if the previously described lifting of both the centre and the higher forward unit would not improve fore/aft stability.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">In large machines, there may be five or more cutting units and the invention may be employed to lift the central and either the two left or the two right units, as appropriate.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">Where a machine has other parameters controlled in dependence upon a measured slope - for example limit of ground speed on a down incline - the above described control processes can be integrated.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">Whilst the invention has been described in relation to grass cutting machines, it will be understood to have application to other machines with ground working units, where similar stability considerations apply.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56983271" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Maschine, die Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>ein Chassis (12) mit Rädern, die mit dem Boden in Eingriff sind;</claim-text>
<claim-text>mindestens zwei Bodenbearbeitungseinheiten (14, 16), die auf dem Chassis an Stellen angebracht sind, die in einer ersten Richtung beabstandet sind, wobei jede Bearbeitungseinheit ein Bodeneingriffselement (26) aufweist und in Bezug auf das Chassis aus einer Arbeitsstellung angehoben werden kann, in der das jeweilige Bodeneingriffselement in Bodenkontakt ist, und</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Neigungsmesser (38), die so ausgelegt ist, dass er eine Neigung des Chassis in der ersten Richtung in Bezug auf die Horizontale überwacht, <b>gekennzeichnet durch</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Steuerung, die dafür ausgelegt ist, einen Neigungswert vom Neigungsmesser zu empfangen und die so konfiguriert ist, diejenige Bearbeitungseinheit anzuheben, die sich aufgrund der Neigung auf einem höheren Niveau befindet als die andere Bearbeitungseinheit, wenn der Neigungswert einen bestimmten Schwellenwert überschreitet.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Maschine nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Steuerung so konfiguriert ist, dass sie eine Bearbeitungseinheit (20, 22, 24) von einer Arbeitsposition, bei der ein wesentlicher Anteil des Gewichts der Bearbeitungseinheit von dem Boden getragen wird, in eine angehobene Position anhebt, bei der ein wesentlicher Anteil des Gewichts der Bearbeitungseinheit von dem Chassis (12) getragen wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Maschine nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei das Chassis (12) dafür ausgelegt ist, in einer<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> Vorwärtsrichtung angetrieben zu werden und wobei die erste Richtung quer zu der Vorwärtsrichtung verläuft.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Maschine nach Anspruch 3, wobei jede Bearbeitungseinheit (20, 22, 24) an einem Hubarm (26) angebracht ist, der sich in der ersten Richtung erstreckt, wobei der Hubarm (26) in Bezug auf das Chassis (12) um eine Achse (28) gedreht werden kann, die sich in der Vorwärtsrichtung erstreckt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Maschine nach Anspruch 4, wobei der Hubarm (26) in Bezug auf das Chassis (12) aus einer Arbeitsposition, in welcher die Bearbeitungseinheit im Wesentlichen horizontal angeordnet ist, in eine Transportstellung gedreht werden kann, in der die Bearbeitungseinheit im Wesentlichen vertikal angeordnet ist, wobei die Steuerung so konfiguriert ist, dass sie den Hubarm dieser Bearbeitungseinheit in eine Stabilitätshubposition zwischen der Arbeits- und Transportposition dreht, wenn der Neigungswert einen bestimmten Schwellenwert überschreitet.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Maschine nach Anspruch 5, wobei das Moment, das die Bearbeitungseinheit auf das Chassis (12) ausübt, in der Stabilitätshubposition größer ist als in der Transportposition.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Maschine nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei die Bearbeitungseinheiten (20, 22, 24) Rasenschnitteinheiten umfassen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Maschine nach Anspruch 7, wobei jede Rasenschnitteinheit (20, 22, 24) eine angetriebene<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> Messerwalze umfasst, die mit einer feststehenden Klinge zusammenwirkt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Maschine nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei die Maschine einen gemessenen Stabilitätswinkel aufweist, der der maximalen Neigung des Chassis (12) in der ersten Richtung in Bezug auf die Horizontale, bei der die Maschine stabil bleibt, entspricht, wobei der definierte Schwellenwert im Bereich von 60% bis 90% und vorzugsweise im Bereich von 70% bis 80% des gemessenen Stabilitätswinkels liegt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Verfahren zum Betreiben einer Maschine, das Folgendes umfasst: ein Chassis (12) mit Rädern (14, 16), die mit dem Boden in Eingriff sind; mindestens zwei Bodenbearbeitungseinheiten (20, 22, 24), die auf dem Chassis (12) an Stellen angebracht sind, die in einer ersten Richtung beabstandet sind, und die in Bezug auf das Chassis (12) aus einer Arbeitsposition angehoben werden können; wobei das Verfahren die Schritte des Messens einer Neigung des Chassis (12) in der ersten Richtung in Bezug auf die Horizontale umfasst, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> in Abhängigkeit von der gemessenen Neigung ein differentieller Hub der Arbeitseinheiten (20, 22, 24) durchgeführt wird, so dass ein Moment vergrößert wird, das durch eine Arbeitseinheit in einer Drehrichtung auf das Chassis (12) ausgeübt wird, das die Stabilität des Chassis (12) in Bezug auf die Neigung verbessert.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 10, wobei der Schritt des differenziellen Anhebens der Bearbeitungseinheiten (20, 22, 24) das Anheben einer Bearbeitungseinheit aus einer Arbeitsposition, bei der ein wesentlicher Anteil des Gewichts<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> der Bearbeitungseinheit von dem Boden getragen wird, in eine Stabilitätshubposition umfasst, bei der ein wesentlicher Anteil des Gewichts der Bearbeitungseinheit von dem Chassis (12) getragen wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 11, wobei die Bearbeitungseinheit ferner aus der Stabilitätshubposition in eine Transportposition angehoben werden kann, wobei die Stabilitätshubposition so gewählt wird, dass das Moment, das die Bearbeitungseinheit auf das Chassis (12) ausübt, in der Stabilitätshubposition größer ist als in der Transportposition.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 10 bis 12, das den Schritt des Vergleichens der gemessenen Neigung mit einem vorbestimmten Neigungsschwellenwert umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 13, das ferner den Schritt des Vergleichens der gemessenen Neigung mit einer Vielzahl von Neigungsschwellenwerten und des Bereitstellens verschiedener optischer oder akustischer Warnsignale bei jedem Schwellenwert umfasst.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56983272" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A machine comprising:
<claim-text>a chassis (12) having ground engaging wheels;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least two ground working units (14, 16) mounted on the chassis at locations spaced in a first direction, each working unit having a ground engaging element (26) and being liftable with respect to the chassis from a working position in which the respective ground engaging element is in ground contact; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an inclinometer (38) adapted to monitor an inclination of the chassis in the first direction with respect to the horizontal; <b>characterised by</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>a controller adapted to receive an inclination value from the inclinometer and configured when the inclination value exceeds a defined threshold to lift that one of the working units that is by virtue of the inclination at a higher level than the other of the working units.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>A machine according to Claim 1, wherein the controller is configured to lifting a working unit (20, 22, 24) from a working position in which a substantial proportion of the weight of the working unit is borne by the ground, to a lifted position in which a substantial proportion of the weight of the working unit is borne by the chassis (12).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>A machine according to any one of the preceding claims, wherein the chassis (12) is adapted to be driven in a forward direction and wherein said first direction is transverse to the forward direction.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>A machine according to Claim 3, wherein each working unit (20, 22, 24) is mounted on a lift arm (26) extending in the first direction, the lift arm (26) being rotatable with respect to the chassis (12) about an axis (28) extending in the forward direction.<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>A machine according to Claim 4, wherein the lift arm (26) is rotatable with respect to the chassis (12) from a working position in which the working unit is essentially horizontal to a transport position in which the working unit is essentially vertical, the controller being configured when the inclination value exceeds a defined threshold to rotate the lift arm of that one of the working units to a stability lift position intermediate the working and transport positions.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>A machine according to Claim 5, wherein the moment exerted on the chassis (12) by the working unit is greater in the stability lift position than in the transport position.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>A machine according to any one of the preceding claims, wherein the working units (20, 22, 24) comprise grass cutting units.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>A machine according to Claim 7, wherein each grass cutting unit (20, 22, 24) comprises a driven cutter reel cooperating with a fixed blade.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>A machine according to any one of the preceding claims, wherein the machine has a measured stability angle being the maximum inclination of the chassis (12) in the first direction with respect to the horizontal at which the machine remains stable, said defined threshold being in the range of 60% to 90% and preferably in the range of 70% to 80% of the measured stability angle.<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>A method of operating a machine comprising a chassis (12) having ground engaging wheels (14, 16); at least two ground working units (20, 22, 24) mounted on the chassis (12) at locations spaced in a first direction, and being liftable with respect to the chassis (12) from a working position; the method comprising the steps of measuring an inclination of the chassis (12) in the first direction with respect to the horizontal <b>characterized in that</b> in dependence upon the measured inclination differential lifting of the working units (20, 22, 24) is initiated so as to increase a moment exerted on the chassis (12) by a working unit in a rotational sense which improves the stability of the chassis (12) with regard to the inclination.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>A method according to Claim 10, wherein the step of differential lifting the working units (20, 22, 24) comprises lifting a working unit from a working position in which a substantial proportion of the weight of the working unit is borne by the ground, to a stability lift position in which a substantial proportion of the weight of the working unit is borne by the chassis (12).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>A method according to Claim 11, wherein the working unit is further liftable from the stability lift position to a transport position, the stability lift position being selected such that the moment exerted on the chassis (12) by the working unit is greater in the stability lift position than in the transport position.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>A method according to any one of Claims 10 to 12, comprising the step of comparing the measured inclination with a predetermined inclination threshold.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>A method according to Claim 13, further comprising the step of comparing the measured inclination with a plurality of inclination thresholds and providing distinct visual or audible warnings at each threshold.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56983273" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Machine comportant :
<claim-text>un châssis (12) ayant des roues entrant en contact avec le sol ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>au moins deux unités de travail du sol (14, 16) montées sur le châssis en des emplacements espacés dans une première direction, chaque unité de travail ayant un élément entrant en contact avec le sol (26) et étant en mesure d'être soulevée par rapport au châssis depuis une position de travail dans laquelle l'élément respectif entrant en contact avec le sol est en contact avec le sol ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un inclinomètre (38) adapté à des fins de surveillance d'une inclinaison du châssis dans la première direction par rapport à l'horizontale ; <b>caractérisée par</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>un contrôleur adapté à des fins de réception d'une valeur d'inclinaison en provenance de l'inclinomètre et configuré, quand la valeur d'inclinaison est supérieure à un seuil défini, à des fins de levage de l'une parmi les unités de travail qui est, en vertu de l'inclinaison, à un niveau supérieur par rapport à l'autre parmi les unités de travail.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Machine selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle le contrôleur est configuré à des fins de levage d'une unité de travail (20, 22, 24) depuis une position de travail dans laquelle une proportion sensible du poids de l'unité de travail est supportée par le sol, jusqu'à une position soulevée dans laquelle une proportion sensible du poids de l'unité de travail est supportée par le châssis (12).<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Machine selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans laquelle le châssis (12) est adapté pour être conduit dans une direction avant et dans laquelle ladite première direction est transversale par rapport à la direction avant.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Machine selon la revendication 3, dans laquelle chaque unité de travail (20, 22, 24) est montée sur un bras de levage (26) s'étendant dans la première direction, le bras de levage (26) étant rotatif par rapport au châssis (12) autour d'un axe (28) s'étendant dans la direction avant.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Machine selon la revendication 4, dans laquelle le bras de levage (26) est rotatif par rapport au châssis (12) depuis une position de travail dans laquelle l'unité de travail est essentiellement horizontale par rapport à une position de transport dans laquelle l'unité de travail est essentiellement verticale, le contrôleur étant configuré, quand la valeur d'inclinaison est supérieure à un seuil défini, pour faire tourner le bras de levage de ladite une parmi les unités de travail jusqu'à une position de levage de stabilité intermédiaire entre la position de travail et la position de transport.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Machine selon la revendication 5, dans laquelle le moment exercé sur le châssis (12) par l'unité de travail est supérieur dans la position de levage de stabilité par rapport à la position de transport.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Machine selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans laquelle les unités de travail (20, 22, 24) comportent des unités de coupe d'herbe.<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Machine selon la revendication 7, dans laquelle chaque unité de coupe d'herbe (20, 22, 24) comporte une bobine de coupe entraînée coopérant avec une lame fixe.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Machine selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans laquelle la machine a un angle de stabilité mesuré comme étant l'inclinaison maximum du châssis (12) dans la première direction par rapport à l'horizontale où la machine reste stable, ledit seuil défini étant de l'ordre de 60 % à 90 % et de préférence de l'ordre de 70 % à 80 % de l'angle de stabilité mesuré.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Procédé permettant de faire fonctionner une machine comportant un châssis (12) ayant des roues entrant en contact avec le sol (14, 16) ; au moins deux unités de travail du sol (20, 22, 24) montées sur le châssis (12) en des emplacements espacés dans une première direction, et étant en mesure d'être soulevées par rapport au châssis (12) depuis une position de travail ; le procédé comportant les étapes consistant à mesurer une inclinaison du châssis (12) dans la première direction par rapport à l'horizontale, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b>, en fonction de l'inclinaison mesurée, un levage différentiel des unités de travail (20, 22, 24) est initialisé de manière à augmenter un moment exercé sur le châssis (12) par une unité de travail dans un sens de la rotation à des fins d'amélioration de la stabilité du châssis (12) par rapport à l'inclinaison.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 10, dans lequel l'étape de levage différentiel des unités de travail (20, 22, 24) comporte l'étape consistant à soulever une unité de<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> travail depuis une position de travail dans laquelle une proportion sensible du poids de l'unité de travail est supportée par le sol, jusqu'à une position de levage de stabilité dans laquelle une proportion sensible du poids de l'unité de travail est supportée par le châssis (12).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 11, dans lequel l'unité de travail est par ailleurs en mesure d'être soulevée depuis la position de levage de stabilité jusqu'à une position de transport, la position de levage de stabilité étant sélectionnée de sorte que le moment exercé sur le châssis (12) par l'unité de travail est supérieur dans la position de levage de stabilité par rapport à la position de transport.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications 10 à 12, comportant l'étape consistant à comparer l'inclinaison mesurée par rapport à un seuil d'inclinaison prédéterminé.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 13, comportant par ailleurs l'étape consistant à comparer l'inclinaison mesurée par rapport à une pluralité de seuils d'inclinaison et l'étape consistant à fournir des avertissements visuels ou sonores distincts à chaque seuil.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16671502" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1,2"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="152" he="231" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --><figure id="f0002" num="3,4"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="165" he="218" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --><figure id="f0003" num="5"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="165" he="203" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
