<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-1681439-B1" country="EP" doc-number="1681439" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="34130931" file-reference-id="299940" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146589093" ucid="EP-1681439-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>1681439</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-05257166-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154851285" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>05257166</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20051122</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP237996287" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>05257166.8</doc-number><date>20051122</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140552946" ucid="GB-0428368-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>GB</country><doc-number>0428368</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20041224</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130821</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989327578" load-source="docdb">F01D   5/14        20060101AFI20130723BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989327579" load-source="docdb">F01D   5/28        20060101ALI20130723BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989327580" load-source="docdb">F04D  29/38        20060101ALI20130723BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989633201" load-source="docdb">B29K 105/06        20060101ALN20130723BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989642255" load-source="docdb">B29L  31/08        20060101ALN20130723BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1786219316" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B29L2031/08        20130101 LA20170712BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1786220131" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F05D2300/505       20130101 LA20170710BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1786220547" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F01D   5/148       20130101 FI20170712BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1786220648" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F01D   5/282       20130101 LI20170712BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1786221569" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F04D  29/382       20130101 LI20170712BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1786223388" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B29K2105/06        20130101 LA20170712BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1786225876" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F04D  29/388       20130101 LI20170712BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1786227166" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y02T  50/672       20130101 LA20170712BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1786228997" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y02T  50/673       20130101 LA20170712BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1786231820" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F01D   5/147       20130101 LI20170712BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132371912" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Schaufel aus Verbundwerkstoff</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132371913" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">A composite blade</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132371914" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Aube en composite</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919524964" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>ROLLS ROYCE PLC</last-name><address><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919515494" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>ROLLS-ROYCE PLC</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919515624" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>MCMILLAN ALISON JANE</last-name><address><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919523175" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>MCMILLAN, ALISON JANE</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919026302" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>MCMILLAN, ALISON JANE</last-name><address><street>Health Cottage, 100 Cheadle Road</street><city>Uttoxeter, Staffordshire, ST14 7BY</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919526960" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>JACKSON ANDREW DAVID</last-name><address><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919516918" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>JACKSON, ANDREW DAVID</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919026303" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>JACKSON, ANDREW DAVID</last-name><address><street>88 Broadway, Duffield</street><city>Derbyshire, DE56 4BY</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919026305" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>ROLLS-ROYCE PLC</last-name><iid>100210143</iid><address><street>65 Buckingham Gate</street><city>London, SW1E 6AT</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919026304" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Barcock, Ruth Anita</last-name><suffix>et al</suffix><iid>100039602</iid><address><street>Rolls-Royce plc Intellectual Property Department P.O. Box 31</street><city>Derby DE24 8BJ</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549793395" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549791086" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549793396" load-source="docdb">GB</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63961507" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to a composite blade and in particular to a composite compressor blade, a composite fan blade, a composite propeller blade or a composite turbine blade for a gas turbine engine.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002">It is known that different aerofoil shapes for fan blades, or compressor blades, perform differently at different operating conditions. A fan blade, may be optimised for take off conditions, or for cruise conditions, but to perform adequately for both take off conditions and cruise conditions generally requires a compromised aerofoil shape. The compromise to the aerofoil shape is based upon the mission that a particular gas turbine engine is to perform, for example whether the gas turbine engine is for long distance flight, short distance flight etc.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">A fan blade, or a compressor blade, generally comprises a twisted aerofoil, e.g. the stagger angle increases from the root to the tip of the aerofoil portion of the fan blade or compressor blade, to give the correct angle of incidence at each point along the length, radius, of the aerofoil portion of the fan blade, or compressor blade. In operation due to rotation of the rotor upon which the fan blades, or compressor blades, are mounted the aerofoil portions of the fan blades, or compressor blades, untwist due to the centripetal loads and these centripetal loads increase with increasing rotational speed. Typically the aerofoil portion of a fan blade untwists by about 5°, where 4° of the fan blade untwist is due to the centripetal loads and 1° of the fan blade untwist is due to gas pressure loads. Generally the increase of untwist with increasing rotational speed is an advantage because it results in an increase in efficiency, but the untwist of the aerofoil portions of current fan blades does not provide as much untwist as is required.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p><p id="p0004" num="0004">A fan blade, or compressor blade, generally comprises an aerofoil portion, which is strongly curved, or cambered, into a C-shaped cross-section near the root portion of the fan blade, or compressor blade, because the gas flow velocity is relatively low and the curvature of the aerofoil portion enables the gas flow impinging on the radially inner region of the aerofoil portion to work harder on the inner region of the aerofoil portion. The aerofoil portion 138 is nearly straight in cross-section in the tip region of the aerofoil portion 138, with a suction surface 148, a pressure surface 150 and a bend at the trailing edge 146, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">figure 11A</figref>. The straightness and amount of bend at the trailing edge 146 of the aerofoil portion 138 is a matter of compromise between part speed, e.g. cruise, and high-speed, e.g. take off, operational requirements.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">A fan blade, or compressor blade, optimised for high-speed, e.g. take off, operation is S-shaped in cross-section at the tip region of the aerofoil portion 238 as shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">figure 11B</figref>. An S-shaped cross-section is generally one where the suction surface 248 is initially concave 247 and then convex 249 between the leading edge 244 and the trailing edge 246 and the pressure surface 250 is initially convex 251 and then concave 253 between the leading edge 244 and the trailing edge 246.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">A compressor blade, optimised for part speed, e.g. cruise, operation is C-shaped in cross-section at the tip region of the aerofoil portion 338 as shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">figure 11C</figref>. A C-shaped cross-section is generally one where the suction surface 348 is convex between the leading edge 344 and the trailing edge 346 and the pressure surface 350 is concave between the leading edge 344 and the trailing edge 346.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">High speed operation, for example take off, is 100% rotational speed and part speed, for example cruise, is 95% rotational speed, although it is desirable to reduce the air speed of an aircraft during cruise conditions to<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> increase the efficiency of the aircraft and this results in a corresponding reduction in rotational speed of the rotor and fan blades and therefore cruise speed may be less than 95% rotational speed.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">Fan blades, which can be optimised for a wide variation in operating rotational speeds have a significant advantage to enable a significant reduction in specific fuel consumption.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="GB1328167A"><text>GB1328167</text></patcit> discloses a composite blade for a gas turbine engine. This composite blade is arranged such that the angle of twist varies with rotational speed of the blade and enables the blade to be better matched to a range of running speeds. The composite blade comprises a plurality of laminations of carbon fibre reinforced epoxy resin. The composite blade comprises a layer with unidirectional fibres, which extend at an angle θ to the blade axis, a layer (5) with unidirectional fibres, which extend parallel to the blade axis, and a layer with unidirectional fibres which extend at an angle -θ to the blade axis. The degree of twist varies along the length of the composite blade.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">Accordingly the present invention seeks to provide a novel composite blade.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">Accordingly the present invention provides a composite blade comprising a root portion and an aerofoil portion, the aerofoil portion having a tip, a chord, a leading edge, a trailing edge, a suction surface extending from the leading edge to the trailing edge and a pressure surface extending from the leading edge to the trailing edge, the composite blade comprising reinforcing fibres in a matrix material, the aerofoil portion adjacent the tip having at least a region at the mid chord comprising an asymmetric arrangement of reinforcing fibres, the asymmetric arrangement of reinforcing fibres being subjected to in plane loads during operation, the in plane loads causing bending of the aerofoil portion at the region at the mid<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> chord such that in operation the tip of the composite blade is moveable between a first position having a C-shaped cross-section at a first rotational speed and a second position having an S-shaped cross-section at a second higher, rotational speed.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">Preferably the aerofoil portion adjacent the root portion having regions at least at the leading edge and trailing edge comprising an asymmetric arrangement of reinforcing fibres such that in operation the composite blade is moveable between a first position having a first twist angle at the first rotational speed and a second position having a smaller twist angle at the second, higher, rotational speed.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">Preferably the composite blade is a compressor, blade, a fan blade, a propeller blade or a turbine blade.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">Preferably the composite blade comprises an organic matrix material.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">Preferably the organic matrix material comprises an epoxy resin.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">Preferably the reinforcing fibres comprise carbon fibres or glass fibres.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">Alternatively the composite blade comprises a metal matrix material or a ceramic matrix material.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">Alternatively the composite blade comprises ceramic fibres.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">Alternatively the ceramic fibres comprise silicon carbide fibres or silicon nitride fibres.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">Preferably the aerofoil portion adjacent the tip having regions at the leading edge and trailing edge comprising a symmetric lay up of reinforcing fibres.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">Preferably the aerofoil position adjacent the root portion having a mid chord region between the regions at the leading edge and the trailing edge comprising a symmetric lay up of reinforcing fibres.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">The present invention also provides a rotor assembly comprising a rotor carrying a plurality of<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> circumferentially arranged radially outwardly extending composite blades, as described in the previous eleven paragraphs.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">The present invention will be more fully described by way of example with reference to the accompanying drawings in which:-
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> shows a turbofan gas turbine engine having a composite blade according to the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 2</figref> shows is an enlarged perspective view of a composite blade according to the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 3</figref> is an enlarged cross-sectional view along line A-A through the composite blade shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">figure 2</figref>.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 4</figref> is an enlarged cross-sectional view along line B-B through the composite blade shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">figure 2</figref>.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 5</figref> is a perspective view of the tip of the composite blade.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 6</figref> is an asymmetric arrangement of the reinforcing fibres for use in the composite blade according to the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 7</figref> is another asymmetric arrangement of the reinforcing fibres for use in the composite blade according to the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 8</figref> is a further arrangement of the reinforcing fibres for use in the composite blade according to the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 9</figref> is an alternative asymmetric arrangement of the reinforcing fibres for use in the composite blade according to the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 10</figref> is a further alternative arrangement of the reinforcing fibres for use in the composite blade according to the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Figures 11A, 11B and 11C</figref> show enlarged cross-sectional views of alternative tip arrangements of the aerofoil portions of fan blades.</li></ul></p><p id="p0024" num="0024">A turbofan gas turbine engine 10, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">figure 1</figref>, comprises in flow series an intake 12, a fan section 14,<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> a compressor section 16, a combustion section 18, a turbine section 20 and an exhaust 22. The fan section 14 comprises a fan rotor 24 and a plurality of circumferentially spaced radially outwardly extending fan blades 26 secured to the fan rotor 24. The fan section 14 also comprises a fan casing 28, which surrounds the fan rotor 24 and fan blades 26 and the fan casing 28 partially defines a fan duct 30. The fan casing 28 is secured to a core casing 32 by a plurality of circumferentially spaced radially extending fan outlet guide vanes 34.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">The turbofan gas turbine engine 10 is quite conventional and its operation and construction will not be discussed further.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">A fan blade 26 is shown more clearly in <figref idrefs="f0001">figures 2</figref>, <figref idrefs="f0002">3, 4 and 5</figref>. The fan blade 26 comprises a root portion 36 and an aerofoil portion 38. The root portion 36 is preferably dovetail shape in cross-section, but may be firtree shape in cross-section. The root portion 36 is arranged to locate in a correspondingly shaped groove 40 in the rim of the fan rotor 24. The aerofoil portion 38 comprises a tip 42 remote from the root portion 36, a chord C, a leading edge 44, a trailing edge 46, a suction surface 48 extending from the leading edge 44 to the trailing edge 46 and a pressure surface 50 extending from the leading edge 44 to the trailing edge 46.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">The fan blade 26 operates at subsonic conditions over radially extending region D and the fan blade operates at supersonic conditions over radially extending region E, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">figure 2</figref>. The extent of radially extending region D is greater when the rotational speed of the fan rotor 24 and fan blades 26 is lower, e.g. cruise, and the extent of radially extending region E is correspondingly less. The extent of radially extending region E is greater when the rotational speed of the fan rotor 24 and fan blades 26 is higher, e.g. take off, and the extent of radially extending region D is correspondingly less.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p><p id="p0028" num="0028">The fan blade 26 is a composite fan blade and comprises reinforcing fibres 52 in a matrix material 54. The reinforcing fibres 52 for example comprise carbon fibres, glass fibres or other suitable fibres. The matrix material 54 comprises an organic matrix material for example epoxy resin sold under the trade name RTM6.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">The aerofoil portion 38 of the fan blade 26 comprises an arrangement of the lay up of the reinforcing fibres 52 within the matrix material 54 such that in operation of the turbofan gas turbine engine 10 the aerofoil portion 38 of the fan blade 26 untwists, reduces in stagger angle, with increasing rotational speed and the tip 42 of the aerofoil portion 38 changes from a C-shaped cross-section to an S-shaped cross-section with increasing rotational speed. This untwisting of the aerofoil portion 38 of the fan blade 26 with increasing rotational speed increases the efficiency of the fan blade 26 and the changing of the cross-sectional shape of the tip 42 of the aerofoil portion 42 of the fan blade 26 with increasing rotational speed also increases the efficiency of the fan blade 26. Thus the tip 42 of the aerofoil portion 38 of the fan blade 26 is C-shaped in cross-section at part speed, e.g. cruise, conditions, e.g. cruise conditions, and is S-shaped in cross-section at high speed, e.g. take off conditions. <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 2</figref> actually shows the shape of the fan blade 26 at high-speed conditions.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">In one example, the aerofoil portion 38 of the fan blade 26 is arranged such that the aerofoil portion 38 adjacent the root portion 36 has regions 56 and 58 at the leading edge 44 and trailing edge 46 respectively, which comprise an asymmetric lay up of reinforcing fibres 52, as shown more clearly in <figref idrefs="f0002">figure 3</figref>. The lay up of the reinforcing fibres 52 within a mid-chord region 60 between the regions 56 and 58 comprises a symmetric lay up of reinforcing fibres 52. The aerofoil portion 38 of the fan blade 26 is arranged such that the aerofoil portion 38<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> adjacent the tip 42 of the fan blade 26 is arranged such that a region 62 at the mid-chord comprises an asymmetric lay up of reinforcing fibres 52, as shown more clearly in <figref idrefs="f0002">figure 4</figref>. The lay up of the reinforcing fibres 52 within the regions 64 and 66 at the leading edge 44 and trailing edge 46 respectively comprises a symmetric lay up of reinforcing fibres 52. The regions 62, 64 and 66 extend longitudinally of the fan blade 26 from the tip 42 over the region E where fan blade 26 operates at supersonic rotational speeds. The position of the interface between regions D and E depends upon the maximum operational rotational speed of the fan rotor 24. Thus the regions 62, 64 and 66 extend from the tip 42 to a longitudinal, or radial, position on the fan blade 26 where there is an instantaneous Mach 1 speed at 100% rotational speed, e.g. take off, of the fan rotor 24 and fan blades 26. The asymmetric lay up of reinforcing fibres 52 within the region 62 is such that the S-shaped cross-section is most pronounced at the tip 42 and reduces to nothing towards the interface between regions D and E. The point of inflexion also moves towards the leading edge 44 as indicated by dashed line L and may reach the leading edge 44 or reduce to nothing at the leading edge 44.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">In <figref idrefs="f0002">figure 3</figref> the dashed lines indicate the shape of the aerofoil portion 38 of the fan blade 26 adjacent the root portion 36 at part speed, e.g. cruise, conditions and the full lines indicate the position of the aerofoil portion 38 of the fan blade 26 adjacent the root portion 36 at high-speed conditions and in <figref idrefs="f0002">figure 4</figref> the full lines indicate the shape of the tip 42 of the fan blade 26 at part speed, e.g. cruise, conditions and the dashed lines indicate the shape of the tip 42 of the fan blade 26 at high-speed conditions. <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 3 and 4</figref> also show the direction of flow F of the airflow onto the fan blades 26 and the direction of rotation of the fan blades 26 and the stagger angle S. Stagger angle is well known to those skilled in the art.<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> Thus, it is seen in <figref idrefs="f0002">figure 3</figref> that the stagger angle S, or twist, has been reduced in the high speed, e.g. take off, condition compared to the part speed, e.g. cruise, condition.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">For example the asymmetric lay up of reinforcing fibres 52 comprises two bonded layers L1 and L2 with the reinforcing fibres 52 in one layer L1 arranged perpendicularly to the reinforcing fibres 52 in the other layer L2, the reinforcing fibres 52 in one layer L1 are arranged in the radial direction and the layers L1 and L2 are the same thickness, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">figure 6</figref>. In another example the asymmetric lay up of reinforcing fibres 52 comprises two bonded layers L3 and L4 with the reinforcing fibres 52 in one layer L3 arranged at angles of +θ to the radial direction and the reinforcing fibres 52 in the other layer L4 arranged at an angle of -θ to the radial direction and the layers L3 and L4 have the same thickness, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">figure 7</figref>. A further example of an asymmetric lay up of reinforcing fibres 52 includes an even number, for example six, of bonded layers L5 to L10 with the reinforcing fibres 52 in the layers L5 to L10 arranged alternately at angles of +θ and -θ to the radial direction and the layers L5 to L10 are of equal thickness, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">figure 8</figref>. Another example of an asymmetric lay up of reinforcing fibres 52 includes an even number of, for example four, bonded layers L11 to L14 with the reinforcing fibres 52 in the first and last layers L11 and L14 arranged at an angle of +θ radial direction and the reinforcing fibres 52 in the second and third layers L12 and L13 arranged at an angle of -θ to the radial direction and three of the layers L12, L13 and L14 are of equal thickness, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">figure 9</figref>. Another example of an asymmetric lay up of reinforcing fibres 52 comprises three bonded layers L15 to L17 with the reinforcing fibres 52 in adjacent layers L15 to L17 arranged perpendicularly and the reinforcing fibres 52 in two layers L15 and L17 arranged in the radial direction and<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> the reinforcing fibres 52 in two adjacent layers L16 and L17 have the same thickness, but L15 has a different thickness as shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">figure 10</figref>. Other suitable arrangements well know to those skilled in the art may be used, for example the angles of the fibres in the layers may be different and not just +θ and -θ. An asymmetric lay up of reinforcing fibres is a lay up where the layers are not symmetric about the centre plane P. The planes of these layers of reinforcing fibres 52 are generally arranged to extend in the direction from leading edge 44 to trailing edge 46 of the fan blade 26 and from root portion 36 to tip 42.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">These asymmetric lay ups of reinforcing fibres 52 are subjected to in plane loads during operation of the fan blade 26 in the turbofan gas turbine engine 10. These in plane loads cause bending of the aerofoil portion 38 at the regions 56, 58 and 62 having the asymmetric lay ups of reinforcing fibres 52. The bending of the aerofoil portion 38 at the regions 56 and 58 at the leading and trailing edges 44 and 46 adjacent the root portion 36 causes the whole of the aerofoil portion 38 to untwist, to reduces its stagger angle, with increasing rotational speed of the fan rotor 24. The bending of the aerofoil portion 38 at the region 62 at the mid-chord at the tip 42 of the aerofoil portion 38 causes the tip of the aerofoil portion 38 to bend from a C-shaped cross-section in which the suction surface 48 is convex and the pressure surface 50 is concave to an S-shaped cross-section in which the suction surface 48 has a concave portion 70 and a convex portion 72 and the pressure surface 50 has a convex portion 74 and a concave portion 76 with increasing rotational speed of the fan rotor 24. The concave portion 70 on the suction surface 48 gives rise to an effect called precompression, which is a supersonic effect. There is a point at each radial position, in the direction from the root portion 36 to the tip 42, along the aerofoil portion 38 of the fan blade 26<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> in the region E at which the bending, inflexion, of the tip 42 of the aerofoil portion 38 commences, as indicated by dashed line L.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">The untwisting effect and the inflexion effect, the changing from C-shape cross-section to S-shape cross-section, work together, but it may be possible to use the untwisting effect without the inflexion effect and visa-versa.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">The advantage of the present invention is that the fan blades are more aerodynamically efficient at both take off conditions and at cruise conditions and results in a reduction in the specific fuel consumption (SFC) of the turbofan gas turbine engine. It is estimated that the fan blades may reduce the specific fuel consumption (SFC) during take off by up to 3%, where gas turbine engines continue to operate at conventional cruise speeds.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">In addition, the present invention has additional benefits such as a reduction in engine heating during high speed, e.g. take off, conditions and this may enable the use of materials with lower temperature capability and hence cheaper materials.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">In addition, in order to further reduce the specific fuel consumption (SFC) it is desirable to operate with lower cruise speeds and lower altitudes. The present invention may enable the optimisation of the fan blade aerodynamics over a wider difference in rotational speed from take off to cruise than has hitherto been possible.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">In the case of start up and windmill home, where the rotational speed of the fan rotor and fan blades is usually very low, the centripetal force is minimal and the fan blade is very closed, twisted. It may be necessary to provide additional asymmetric lay ups of reinforcing fibres so as to counteract the untwist effect. Ideally the fan blades are oriented such that the windmill effect does not take place, i.e. such that the effect of the gas stream on the aerofoil portions of the fan blades does not supply<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> sufficient torque to overcome the friction of the damaged rotor assembly, so that the fan rotor cannot rotate. The advantage of this is that damaging vibration levels normally associated with windmill home would not take place.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">Although the present invention has been described with reference to asymmetric lay ups of layers of reinforcing fibres it is equally possible to provide asymmetric arrangements of three dimensionally woven reinforcing fibres to achieve the same effects.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">Although the present invention has been described with reference to organic matrix composites with carbon fibres or glass fibres, it is equally applicable to metal matrix composites or ceramic matrix composites with ceramic fibres, for example silicon nitride or silicon carbide.</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">Although the present invention has been described with reference to fan blades it may equally well apply to compressor blades, propeller blades or turbine blades. It may be used for different types of fluids e.g. gas, air, liquid, water.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">It may be possible to provide active control mechanisms to actuate the untwist mechanism and the inflexion mechanism. The active control mechanism may comprise piezoelectric members or shape memory material members provided within the fan blade at the appropriate positions e.g. at the mid chord region at the tip and/or the leading edge and trailing edge regions adjacent the root portion of the aerofoil portion to actively move the fan blade at those positions. The piezoelectric member would be supplied with electricity from an electrical power supply to accentuate the effect of the asymmetric lay up of reinforcing fibres in the composite material to change the shape of the fan blade. The electricity may be supplied directly through a slip ring or indirectly through magnetic induction. The magnetic field would be generated in the fan casing, radially outward of the fan blades in order to<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> produce changes near the tips of the aerofoil portions of the fan blades and also in the bearing housing directly radially inward the fan blades in order to produce changes in the aerofoil portions of the fan blades near the root portion. The bearing housing is normally offset axially from the fan rotor, and the magnetic forces would have a greater effect on the region at the trailing edge than on the region at the leading edge, but nevertheless an untwist effect is possible. The shape memory alloy would be heated for example by an electrical power supply to accentuate the effect of the asymmetric lay up of reinforcing fibres in the composite material to change the shape of the fan blade. The use of shape memory material and asymmetric lay up of reinforcing fibres effects together enable the optimisation of aerodynamic configurations of the aerofoil portions of the fan blades for windmill home or to further optimise the flight cycle for a range of different mission types.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">The present invention is also applicable to other types of composite blades e.g. bimetallic blades, in which the aerofoil portion adjacent the root portion having regions at least at the leading edge and trailing edge comprising an asymmetric arrangement of layers of two different metals/alloys. The present invention is also applicable to bimetallic blades in which the aerofoil portion adjacent the tip having at least a region at the mid chord comprising an asymmetric arrangement of layers of two different metals/alloys. An asymmetric arrangement of metals/alloys is an arrangement where the layers of metals/alloys are not symmetric about a centre plane. The plane of the layers of the metal/alloys are arranged to extend in the direction from leading edge to trailing edge of the fan blade and from root portion to tip. Thus layers of different metals are bonded to each other.</p><p id="p0044" num="0044">These asymmetric arrangements of layers of different metals/alloys are subjected to in plane loads during<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> operation of the fan blade in the turbofan gas turbine engine. These in plane loads cause bending of the aerofoil portion at the regions having the asymmetric arrangement of different metals/alloys.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045">The composite blades may comprise other asymmetric sandwich, layered, structures.</p><p id="p0046" num="0046">The present invention may also be applicable to integrally bladed rotors, wherein the blades are formed integrally with the rotor and thus the blades are not provided with a root which locates in a slot in a rotor disc. Rather the root portion is formed integrally with a rotor disc.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56987261" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Verbund-Schaufel (26) mit einem Wurzelteil (36) und einem Flügelteil (38), wobei der Flügelteil (38) eine Spitze (42), eine Sehne (c), eine Vorderkante (44), eine Hinterkante (46), eine Saug-Oberfläche (48), die sich von der Vorderkante (44) zu der Hinterkante (46) erstreckt, und eine Druck-Oberfläche (50) aufweist, die sich von der Vorderkante (44) zu der Hinterkante (46) erstreckt, wobei die Verbund-Schaufel Verstärkungsfasern (52) in einem Matrix-Material (54) umfasst, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> der Flügelteil (38) benachbart zu der Spitze (42) zumindest einen Bereich (62) an der Mittelsehne aufweist, der eine unsymmetrische Anordnung von Verstärkungsfasern (52) umfasst, wobei die asymmetrische Anordnung von Verstärkungsfasern (52) im Betrieb in der Ebene liegenden Belastungen ausgesetzt ist, wobei die in der Ebene liegenden Belastungen ein Biegen des Flügelteils (38) an dem Bereich (62) der Mittelsehne hervorrufen, derart, dass im Betrieb die Spitze (42) der Verbund-Schaufel (26) zwischen einer ersten Position mit einem C-förmigen Querschnitt bei einer ersten Drehgeschwindigkeit und einer zweiten Position mit einem S-förmigen Querschnitt bei einer zweiten höheren Drehgeschwindigkeit beweglich ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Verbund-Schaufel nach Anspruch 1, bei der der Flügelteil (38) benachbart zu dem Wurzelteil (36) Bereiche (56, 58) zumindest an der Vorderkante (44) und der Hinterkante (46) aufweist, die eine asymmetrische Anordnung von Verstärkungsfasern (52) derart aufweisen, dass im Betrieb die Verbund-Schaufel (26) zwischen einer ersten Position, in der sie einen ersten Verwindungswinkel bei einer ersten Drehgeschwindigkeit aufweist, und einer zweiten Position beweglich ist, in der sie einen kleineren Verwindungswinkel bei der zweiten höheren Drehgeschwindigkeit aufweist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Verbund-Schaufel nach Anspruch 1 oder 2, bei der die Verbund-Schaufel (26) eine Kompressor-Schaufel, eine Gebläse-Schaufel, eine Propeller-Schaufel oder eine Turbinen-Schaufel ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Verbund-Schaufel nach Anspruch 1, 2 oder Anspruch 3, bei der die Verbund-Schaufel (26) ein organisches Matrix-Material umfasst.<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Verbund-Schaufel nach Anspruch 4, bei der das organische Material ein Epoxy-Harz umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Verbund-Schaufel nach Anspruch 4 oder 5, bei der die Verstärkungsfasern Kohlenstofffasern oder Glasfasern umfassen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Verbund-Schaufel nach Anspruch 1, 2 oder 3, bei der die Verbund-Schaufel (26) ein Metall-Matrix-Material oder ein keramisches Matrix-Material umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Verbund-Schaufel nach Anspruch 7, bei der die Verbund-Schaufel (26) Keramik-Fasern umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Verbund-Schaufel nach Anspruch 8, bei der die Keramik-Fasern Siliziumcarbid-Fasern oder Siliziumnitrid-Fasern umfassen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Verbund-Schaufel nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 9, bei der die asymmetrische Anordnung der Verstärkungsfasern (52) eine asymmetrische Auflage von Schichten von Verstärkungsfasern umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Verbund-Schaufel nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 9, bei der die asymmetrische Anordnung der Verstärkungsfasern (52) eine asymmetrische Anordnung von dreidimensional verwebten Verstärkungsfasern umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Verbund-Schaufel nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 11, bei der ein aktiver Steuermechanismus in dem Flügelteil vorgesehen ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Verbund-Schaufel nach Anspruch 1, bei der der Flügelteil (38) benachbart zu der Spitze (42) Bereiche (64, 66) an der Vorderkante (44) und der Hinterkante (46) aufweist, die eine symmetrische Auflage von Verstärkungsfasern (52) aufweisen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Verbund-Schaufel nach Anspruch 2, bei der der Flügelteil (38) benachbart zu dem Wurzelteil (36) einen Mittelsehnen-Bereich (60) zwischen den Bereichen (56, 58) an der Vorderkante (44) und der Hinterkante (46) aufweist, der eine symmetrische Auflage von Verstärkungsfasern aufweist.<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Verbund-Schaufel nach Anspruch 12, bei der der aktive Steuermechanismus ein Bauteil aus Formgedächtnis-Material oder ein piezoelektrisches Bauteil umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0016" num="0016"><claim-text>Rotor-Baugruppe mit einem Rotor (24), der eine Vielzahl von am Umfang verteilten sich radial nach außen erstreckenden Verbund-Schaufeln (26) nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 15 trägt.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56987262" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A composite blade (26) comprising a root portion (36) and an aerofoil portion (38), the aerofoil portion (38) having a tip (42), a chord (c), a leading edge (44), a trailing edge (46), a suction surface (48) extending from the leading edge (44) to the trailing edge (46) and a pressure surface (50) extending from the leading edge (44) to the trailing edge (46), the composite blade (26) comprising reinforcing fibres (52) in a matrix material (54), <b>characterised in that</b> the aerofoil portion (38) adjacent the tip (42) having at least a region (62) at the mid chord comprising an asymmetric arrangement of reinforcing fibres (52), the asymmetric arrangement of reinforcing fibres (52) being subjected to in plane loads during operation, the in plane loads causing bending of the aerofoil portion (38) at the region (62) at the mid chord such that in operation the tip (42) of the composite blade (26) is moveable between a first position having a C-shaped cross-section at a first rotational speed and a second position having an S-shaped cross section at a second, higher, rotational speed.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>A composite blade as claimed in claim 1 wherein the aerofoil portion (38) adjacent the root portion (36) having regions (56, 58) at least at the leading edge (44) and trailing edge (46) comprising an asymmetric arrangement of reinforcing fibres (52) such that in operation the composite blade (26) is moveable between a first position having a first twist angle at the first rotational speed and a second position having a smaller twist angle at the second, higher, rotational speed.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>A composite blade as claimed in claim 1 or claim 2 wherein the composite blade (26) is a compressor blade, a fan blade, a propeller blade or a turbine blade.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>A composite blade as claimed in claim 1, claim 2 or claim 3 wherein the composite blade (26) comprises an organic matrix material.<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>A composite blade as claimed in claim 4 wherein the organic matrix material comprises an epoxy resin.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>A composite blade as claimed in claim 4 or claim 5 wherein the reinforcing fibres comprise carbon fibres or glass fibres.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>A composite blade as claimed in claim 1, claim 2 or claim 3 wherein the composite blade (26) comprises a metal matrix material or a ceramic matrix material.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>A composite blade as claimed in claim 7 wherein the composite blade (26) comprises ceramic fibres.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>A composite blade as claimed in claim 8 wherein the ceramic fibres comprise silicon carbide fibres or silicon nitride fibres.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>A composite blade as claimed in any of claims 1 to 9 wherein the asymmetric arrangement of reinforcing fibres (52) comprising an asymmetric lay up of layers of reinforcing fibres.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>A composite blade as claimed in any of claims 1 to 9 wherein the asymmetric arrangement of reinforcing fibres (52) comprising an asymmetric arrangement of three dimensionally woven reinforcing fibres.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>A composite blade as claimed in any of claims 1 to 11 wherein an active control mechanism being provided in the aerofoil portion.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>A composite blade as claimed in claim 1 wherein the aerofoil portion (38) adjacent the tip (42) having regions (64, 66) at the leading edge (44) and trailing edge (46) comprising a symmetric lay up of reinforcing fibres (52).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>A composite blade as claimed in claim 2 wherein the aerofoil portion (38) adjacent the root portion (36) having a mid chord region (60) between the regions (56, 58) at the leading edge (44) and the trailing edge (46) comprising a symmetric lay up of reinforcing fibres (52).<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>A composite blade as claimed in claim 12 wherein the active control mechanism comprising a shape memory material member or a piezoelectric member.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0016" num="0016"><claim-text>A rotor assembly comprising a rotor (24) carrying a plurality of circumferentially arranged radially outwardly extending composite blades (26), as claimed in any of claims 1 to 15.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56987263" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Aube en composite (26) comprenant une partie d'emplanture (36) et une partie de surface portante (38), la partie de surface portante (38) ayant une pointe (42), une corde (c), un bord d'attaque (44), un bord de fuite (46), une surface d'aspiration (48) s'étendant du bord d'attaque (44) au bord de fuite (46) et une surface de pression (50) s'étendant du bord d'attaque (44) au bord de fuite (46), l'aube en composite (26) comprenant des fibres de renforcement (52) dans un matériau de matrice (54), <b>caractérisée en ce que</b> la partie de surface portante (38) adjacente à la pointe (42) ayant au moins une région (62) à mi-corde comprenant un agencement asymétrique de fibres de renforcement (52), l'agencement asymétrique de fibres de renforcement (52) étant soumis à des charges de traînée pendant le fonctionnement, les charges de traînée provoquant la flexion de la partie de surface portante (38) au niveau de la région (62) à mi-corde, de sorte qu'en fonctionnement, la pointe (42) de l'aube en composite (26) est mobile entre une première position ayant une section transversale en forme de C à une première vitesse de rotation et une seconde position ayant une section transversale en forme S à une seconde vitesse de rotation plus élevée.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Aube en composite selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle la partie de surface portante (38) adjacente à la partie d'emplanture (36) ayant des régions (56, 58) au moins au niveau du bord d'attaque (44) et du bord de fuite (46) comprenant un agencement asymétrique de fibres de renforcement (52), de sorte qu'en fonctionnement, l'aube en composite (26) est mobile entre une première position ayant un premier angle de goujure à la première vitesse de rotation et une seconde position ayant un angle de goujure plus petit à la seconde vitesse de rotation plus élevée.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Aube en composite selon la revendication 1 ou la revendication 2, dans laquelle l'aube en composite (26) est une aube de compresseur, une aube de ventilateur, une aube d'hélice ou une aube de turbine.<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Aube en composite selon la revendication 1, la revendication 2 ou la revendication 3, dans laquelle l'aube en composite (26) comprend un matériau de matrice organique.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Aube en composite selon la revendication 4, dans laquelle le matériau de matrice organique comprend une résine époxy.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Aube en composite selon la revendication 4 ou la revendication 5, dans laquelle les fibres de renforcement comprennent des fibres de carbone ou des fibres de verre.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Aube en composite selon la revendication 1, la revendication 2 ou la revendication 3, dans laquelle l'aube en composite (26) comprend un matériau de matrice en métal ou un matériau de matrice en céramique.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Aube en composite selon la revendication 7, dans laquelle l'aube en composite (26) comprend des fibres de céramique.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Aube en composite selon la revendication 8, dans laquelle les fibres de céramique comprennent des fibres de carbure de silicium ou des fibres de nitrure de silicium.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Aube en composite selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 9, dans laquelle l'agencement asymétrique de fibres de renforcement (52) comprend une superposition asymétrique de couches de fibres de renforcement.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Aube en composite selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 9, dans laquelle l'agencement asymétrique de fibres de renforcement (52) comprend un agencement asymétrique de fibres de renforcement tissées en trois dimensions.<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Aube en composite selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 11, dans laquelle un mécanisme de commande actif est prévu dans la partie de surface portante.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Aube en composite selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle la partie de surface portante (38) adjacente à la pointe (42) a des régions (64, 66) au niveau du bord d'attaque (44) et du bord de fuite (46) comprenant une disposition symétrique de fibres de renforcement (52).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Aube en composite selon la revendication 2, dans laquelle la partie de surface portante (38) adjacente à la partie d'emplanture (36) a une région à mi-corde (60) entre les régions (56, 58) au niveau du bord d'attaque (44) et du bord de fuite (46) comprenant une superposition symétrique de fibres de renforcement (52).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Aube en composite selon la revendication 12, dans laquelle le mécanisme de commande actif comprend un élément en matériau à mémoire de forme ou un élément piézoélectrique.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0016" num="0016"><claim-text>Ensemble de rotor comprenant un rotor (24) portant une pluralité d'aubes en composite (26) agencées de manière circonférentielle, s'étendant radialement vers l'extérieur, selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 15.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16672699" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1,2"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="163" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --><figure id="f0002" num="3,4,5"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="162" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --><figure id="f0003" num="6,7,8"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="165" he="225" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --><figure id="f0004" num="9,10,11A,11B,11C"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="165" he="219" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
