<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2217522-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2217522" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="38786641" file-reference-id="299959" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146588161" ucid="EP-2217522-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2217522</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-08849581-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154850353" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>08849581</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20081107</date><lang>FI</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140556191" ucid="FI-20070856-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>FI</country><doc-number>20070856</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20071112</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140552255" ucid="FI-2008000122-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>FI</country><doc-number>2008000122</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20081107</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130924</date></intention-to-grant-date><search-report-dispatch-date><date>20130107</date></search-report-dispatch-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989324863" load-source="ipcr">B66D   5/08        20060101AFI20130815BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989324864" load-source="ipcr">F16D  49/16        20060101ALI20130815BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989324865" load-source="ipcr">F16D  65/48        20060101ALI20130815BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989637230" load-source="ipcr">F16D 127/04        20120101ALN20130815BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989646526" load-source="ipcr">F16D 121/22        20120101ALN20130815BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989620356" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F16D  49/16        20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989631795" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F16D  65/48        20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989644579" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B66D   5/08        20130101 FI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989648167" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F16D2121/22        20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989651178" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F16D2127/04        20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132369116" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">AUFZUGBREMSE</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132369117" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">ELEVATOR BRAKE</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132369118" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">FREIN POUR ASCENSEUR</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919525311" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>KONE CORP</last-name><address><country>FI</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919526865" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>KONE CORPORATION</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919540771" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>HULT ARTTU</last-name><address><country>FI</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919526005" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>HULT, ARTTU</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919021790" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>HULT, ARTTU</last-name><address><street>Elontie 104</street><city>FI-00660 Helsinki</city><country>FI</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919525231" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>OLKKONEN MIKA</last-name><address><country>FI</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919512630" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>OLKKONEN, MIKA</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919021789" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>OLKKONEN, MIKA</last-name><address><street>Heleniuksenkatu 36 D 8</street><city>FI-05860 Hyvinkää</city><country>FI</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919021791" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Kone Corporation</last-name><iid>100159746</iid><address><street>Kartanontie 1</street><city>00330 Helsinki</city><country>FI</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919021792" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>K &amp; H Bonapat</last-name><iid>101355857</iid><address><street>Patentanwälte Eduard-Schmid-Strasse 2</street><city>81541 München</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="FI-2008000122-W"><document-id><country>FI</country><doc-number>2008000122</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20081107</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2009063123-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2009063123</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20090522</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549870530" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549782065" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549799157" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549922943" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549867725" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549867730" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549783238" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549782066" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549782067" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549874423" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549799158" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549799159" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549783239" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549782068" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549783240" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549867731" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549922944" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549782073" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549799160" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549782074" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549783249" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549870531" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549799173" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549783250" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549870532" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549874424" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549889974" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549874425" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549799174" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549867732" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549874431" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549922945" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549889975" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549870533" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states><ep-extended-states><ep-extended-state-data><country>AL</country></ep-extended-state-data><ep-extended-state-data><country>BA</country></ep-extended-state-data><ep-extended-state-data><country>MK</country></ep-extended-state-data><ep-extended-state-data><country>RS</country></ep-extended-state-data></ep-extended-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63960589" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to an elevator brake as described in the preamble of claim 1.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002">Elevators are generally provided with a holding brake, which is used to hold the elevator car stationary when the car is standing at a landing. This same brake is also often used as an emergency brake, which is required by elevator regulations and which is activated in the event of emergencies, such as electric power failures. The brake used may be e.g. a drum brake or a disc brake.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">Traditionally, elevators use a drum brake, which comprises an active part provided with at least a brake block and an actuator for moving the brake block and, as a passive part, a brake drum attached to and rotating with the rotor of a hoisting motor comprised in the elevator hoisting machine, a braking surface being provided on the outer circumference of the brake drum. The operation of an elevator drum brake is generally such that, when the brake is in a closed position, a spring comprised in the active part of the brake presses a brake shoe and the brake block attached to it against the braking surface of the brake drum, thereby keeping the elevator car stationary. During travel, an electromagnet comprised in the active part of the brake is in an energized state and the magnet pulls the brake shoe and brake block clear of the braking surface of the brake drum, keeping the brake open and permitting the elevator car to move up or down in the elevator shaft. The elevator brake may be implemented e.g. by using a design that comprises two brakes serving as active parts, placed outside the circumference of the brake<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> drum, on mutually opposite sides of the brake drum circumference as seen from the front in the direction of the axis of rotation of the brake drum.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">When the brake is engaged, the force acting on the brake drum of the drum brake is relatively great, and consequently the brake wheel absorbs a great deal of kinetic energy. This produces a loud noise when the brake block hits the brake drum. An attempt to solve this problem has been to minimize the air gap between the brake block and the brake drum. In such a brake, the brake block can not reach a very high speed and kinetic energy by the moment it hits the brake drum, and consequently the impact is weaker. However, an air gap that is sufficiently small is difficult to implement and adjust, and such a solution leads to a quite sensitive construction and requires very accurate manufacturing tolerances. Another problem encountered in drum brakes is a defective orientation of the brake shoe and the movable parts of the electromagnet, which produces skewness in the air gap and additionally a load straining the other parts of the brake. This problem is particularly pronounced in the case of narrow brake drums.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">According to documents <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US2652132A"><text>US 2 652 132 A</text></patcit>, <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="US2871994A"><text>US 2 871 994 A</text></patcit>, <patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="US3894617A"><text>US 3 894 617 A</text></patcit>, <patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="DE1288376B"><text>DE 12 88 376 B</text></patcit> and <patcit id="pcit0005" dnum="US1646932A"><text>US 1 646 932 A</text></patcit> an elevator brake is disclosed, respectively, the brake block of which can be adjusted to determine the size of an air gap between a brake block and a braking surface. This is realized by means of an eccentric adjusting element.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">The object of the present invention is to eliminate the above-mentioned drawbacks and to achieve an elevator brake that is easily and quickly adjustable, takes up as little space as<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> possible and is as quiet as possible in operation. A further object is to achieve an elevator brake in which an adjustment has a substantially identical effect on the behavior of the brake regardless of the traveling direction of the elevator.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">The elevator brake of the invention is characterized by claim 1. Other embodiments of the invention are characterized by what is disclosed in the other claims.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">Inventive embodiments are also discussed in the description part of the present application. Different details described in connection with each example embodiment of the invention can be used in other embodiment examples as well.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">The solution of the invention has the advantage that even a small brake air gap can be adjusted easily and quickly. A further advantage is that the adjustment has the same effect regardless of the traveling direction of the elevator. Another advantage is that the stop faces in the brake body which are relevant to the size of the air gap can be made during manufacture by the same attaching operation, with the result that the stop faces are mutually parallel with a high accuracy. This permits more accurate adjustment while at the same time reducing the noise produced by operation of the brake, because the brake blocks hit the brake drum surface more smoothly. Yet another advantage is that the brake elements are substantially simple, from which it follows that the brake solution is economical to implement.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">In the following, the invention will be described in detail by referring to different embodiment examples and the attached drawings, wherein<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> -->
<dl id="dl0001" compact="compact"><dt>Fig. 1</dt><dd>presents a diagrammatic and simplified front view of an elevator hoisting machine in which a brake solution according to the invention is used,</dd><dt>Fig. 2</dt><dd>presents a lateral view of an elevator brake system according to the invention,</dd><dt>Fig. 3</dt><dd>presents a partially sectioned front view of the elevator brake system according to <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2</figref>,</dd><dt>Fig. 4</dt><dd>presents a lateral view of a second preferred elevator brake system according to the invention,</dd><dt>Fig. 5</dt><dd>presents a lateral view of a third preferred elevator brake system according to the invention, and</dd><dt>Fig. 6</dt><dd>presents a lateral view of a magnified detail of one end of the brake system according to <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 5</figref></dd></dl></p><p id="p0011" num="0011">In <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, an elevator hoisting machine 1 which uses a solution according to the invention is presented in a diagrammatic and simplified front view, i.e. as seen from the direction of the axis of rotation of the brake drum. The machine comprises at least a hoisting motor, which in the figure is hidden behind other components, a frame part 2 and a traction sheave 3 rotated by the hoisting motor. Attached to the traction sheave is a brake drum 4 provided with a cylindrical braking surface 5 and fitted to rotate with the traction sheave 3. The hoisting machine 1 additionally comprises at least brakes 6 fitted to produce a braking effect on the brake drum 4 by friction and disposed on the outer circumference of the brake drum 4 on mutually opposite sides of the brake drum 4 as seen in the direction of the axis of rotation of the brake drum 4. Each brake 6 is hingedly secured at least by one of its mounting brackets 9 or 10 e.g. to the<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> frame part 2 of the hoisting machine 1. The securing and adjustment of the brake 6 are implemented using eccentric shafts 11, which serve as eccentric adjustment elements and are substantially parallel to each other, each brake 6 having two such shafts, disposed substantially symmetrically on either side of the brake 6 as seen in the direction of the center axis of the eccentric shafts 11. The center axis of the eccentric shafts 11 is substantially parallel to the axis of rotation of the brake drum 4.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">Inside the body of the brake 6 are one or more compression springs, which have been fitted to press a brake block 8 of the brake, said brake block being provided with a braking surface, which is pressed against the braking surface 5 of the brake drum 4 when the brake is engaged and is e.g. holding the elevator car immovable. Correspondingly, placed inside the body of the brake 6 is also one or more electromagnets, which have been fitted to pull the brake block 8 away from the braking surface 5 against the spring force pressing the brake block 8 and thus to release the brake when the elevator car is starting to move.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013"><figref idrefs="f0001">Figs. 2</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0002">3</figref> are diagrams representing an elevator brake system according to the invention in a simplified and partially sectioned view. In <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2</figref>, the brake is shown as seen from the front of the hoisting machine and turned through 90° relative to <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, and in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 3</figref> the brake is shown as seen from the side of the hoisting machine and turned through 90° relative to <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>. In <figref idrefs="f0001">Figs. 2</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0002">3</figref>, the frame part 2 of the hoisting machine is partially visible, and likewise the brake drum 4 and the braking surface 5 of the brake drum 4,<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> whereas the hoisting motor and traction sheave are not shown in the figures.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">The brake 6 comprises at least a hollow body 6a and mounting brackets 9 and 10, which are attached to the body 6a on mutually opposite sides of the body 6a and extend outward from the body 6a substantially in the direction of the plane of rotation of the braking surface 5 of the brake drum 4. When the brake is engaged, the brake block 8 is pressed against the braking surface 5 of the brake drum 4, but otherwise the brake block 8 and the braking surface 5 are separated by an air gap 8a. The brake 6 is hingedly secured by its first mounting bracket 9 to the frame part 2 of the hoisting machine 1 by means of an eccentric shaft 11. Similarly, the second mounting bracket 10 of the brake 6 is provided with a substantially identical eccentric shaft 11, which has been fitted in the through hole 14 of the second mounting bracket 10, the diameter of said hole being substantially larger than the diameter of the eccentric shaft 11. In addition, the brake comprises a spring element 15, which in this case is a draw-spring attached to the second mounting bracket 10 and arranged to pull the brake in a direction away from the braking surface 5 of the brake drum 4.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">The two eccentric shafts 11 are mutually substantially identical. Provided at the first end of each eccentric shaft 11 is a flange 11a having a diameter larger than that of the shafts, the flange being fitted e.g. by threads to the first end of the first cylindrical part 11b of the eccentric shaft 11. The flange 11a serves to lock the eccentric shafts 11 and at the same time the brakes 6 in position. As an extension of the first cylindrical part 11b, the eccentric shaft has a<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> second cylindrical part 11c, which is substantially parallel to the first cylindrical part 11b but whose center axis is, however, located at a distance from the center axis of the first cylindrical part 11b, so that the cylindrical parts 11b and 11c together form an eccentric shaft. In this example, the cylindrical parts 11b and 11c are equal in diameter, but they may just as well have unequal diameters. In addition, the second end of each eccentric shaft 11 has a hex head 11d or an equivalent form-locking element which can be used to rotate the eccentric shafts 11 about their center axis to adjust the size of the air gap 8a.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">The frame part 2 of the hoisting machine 1 is provided with mounting holes 12, whose diameter has been adapted to correspond to the diameter of the first cylindrical part 11b of the eccentric shafts 11, so that the mounting hole 12 receives the first cylindrical part 11b. The first cylindrical part 11b fits in the mounting hole 12 as tightly as possible and substantially without clearance, but the cylindrical part 11b can still be rotated about its center axis by the hex head 11d when the eccentric shaft 11 is being rotated.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">The first mounting bracket 9 of the brake 6 has a mounting hole 13, whose diameter has been adapted to correspond to the diameter of the second cylindrical part 11c so that the mounting hole 13 receives the second cylindrical part 11c. In this embodiment of the invention, the second cylindrical part 11c fits in the mounting hole 13 as tightly as possible and substantially without clearance, but still so that it can be rotated about the center axis of the first cylindrical part 11b by the hex head 11d when the eccentric shaft 11 is being rotated. This causes the mounting bracket 9 and consequently<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> the brake 6 as a whole to be displaced by an amount corresponding to the rotated eccentricity of the eccentric shaft 11, while the frame part 2 remains immovable. The center axis of the mounting hole 13 lies substantially in the tangential plane of the point of contact between the brake block 8 and the braking surface 5, and consequently the braking force is substantially the same in both directions of rotation of the brake drum 4.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">In another embodiment of the invention, a sleeve (not shown in the figure) is provided between the cylindrical part 11c and the mounting hole 13, so that the second cylindrical part 11c can be rotated in the mounting hole 13 by means of the sleeve.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">Correspondingly, the diameter of the through hole 14 in the second mounting bracket 10 is substantially greater than the diameter of the second cylindrical part 11c of the eccentric shaft 11. The through hole 14 is so disposed in the mounting bracket 10 that the lowest point along its periphery, i.e. the point closest to the braking surface 5, is substantially leveled with the lowest point along the periphery of through hole 13, in other words, in each hole 13 and 14, the point closest to the braking surface 5 is located at a substantially equal distance from the braking surface 5. The brake drum-side portion of the periphery of through hole 14 forms a stop face 16, which has been fitted to be pressed against the second cylindrical part 11c of the second eccentric shaft 11 by the spring force of the spring element 15 acting substantially in a direction away from the braking surface 5. Correspondingly, the distance between the centers of holes 13 and 14 is substantially equal to the distance between the centers of the<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> mounting holes 12 in the frame part 2 of the hoisting machine 1.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">The brake 6 additionally comprises a releasing element 7 fitted to be mechanically operable, by means of which the brake can be released manually when no electricity is supplied to the brake.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021"><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 4</figref> represents another elevator brake system according to the invention as seen in lateral view. In this solution, all other parts of the brake 6 except for the second mounting bracket 10 are substantially identical to those in the solution represented by <figref idrefs="f0001">Figs. 2</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0002">3</figref>. Instead of a through hole 14, the second mounting bracket 10 now has only a stop face 16 which opens in a direction away from the brake drum 4 and whose distance from the braking surface 5 has been adapted to be substantially equal to the distance of the closest point along the periphery of the mounting hole 13 of the first mounting bracket 9 from the braking surface 5 of the brake drum 4.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022"><figref idrefs="f0003">Figs. 5 and 6</figref> represent a third preferred elevator brake system according to the invention as seen in lateral view. In this solution, too, all other parts of the brake 6 except for the second mounting bracket 10 and the associated auxiliary components are substantially identical to those in the solution represented by <figref idrefs="f0001">Figs. 2</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0002">3</figref>. The second mounting bracket 10 is now provided with a separate, carriage-type or similar supporting element 17 arranged to be substantially linearly movable and functioning as a slipper pad, which has been fitted to be movable between the second eccentric shaft 11 and the second mounting bracket 10. The supporting element<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> 17 has a substantially curved stop face 16 opening in a direction away from the brake drum 4. The distance of the closest point of said stop face from the braking surface 5 has been adapted to be substantially equal to the distance of the closest point along the periphery of the mounting hole 13 of the first mounting bracket 9 from the braking surface 5 of the brake drum 4. The stop face 16 of the supporting element 17 is so shaped that the surface pressure between the second eccentric shaft 11 and the supporting element 17 will be as small as possible in all adjustment positions of the eccentric shaft 11.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">The second mounting bracket 10 is provided e.g. with guide tracks 18, along which the supporting element 17 has been fitted to slide in mutually opposite directions as indicated by arrow 19 due to the force exerted by the eccentricity of the second eccentric shaft 11 when the second eccentric shaft 11 is being rotated in connection with adjustment of the air gap 8a.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">The air gap 8a of the brakes 6 presented in <figref idrefs="f0001 f0002 f0003">Figs. 2-6</figref> is adjusted in the same way in all the brake types according to the example. All these brake solutions have at least in the mounting hole 13 at the first end a substantially clearance-free eccentric shaft 11, which is rotatable about its center axis and serves as a means of adjusting the size of the air gap 8a, and at the second end a stop face 16, which has been fitted to be pressed by a spring element 15 against that surface of the second cylindrical part 11c of the second eccentric shaft 11 which faces towards the braking surface 5. Adjustment of the size of the air gap 8a has been adapted to be effected by rotating the eccentric shafts 11 by the hex<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> head 11d. On the side of the first mounting bracket 9, the brake 6 is moved farther away from the braking surface 5 and closer towards the braking surface 5 by the force exerted by the eccentric motion of the second cylindrical part 11c of the eccentric shaft 11. Similarly, on the side of the second mounting bracket 10, the brake 6 is moved farther away from the braking surface 5 by the spring force of the spring element 15 when permitted by the eccentric motion of the second cylindrical part 11c of the eccentric shaft 11 and likewise moved closer towards the braking surface 5 when forced by the eccentric motion of the second cylindrical part 11c of the eccentric shaft 11 against the spring force of the spring element 15. In each brake solution, the brake 6 comprises two eccentric shafts 11 functioning as eccentric adjusting devices, one eccentric shaft being placed on either side of the brake block 8 as seen in the direction of the axis of rotation of the brake drum 4, i.e. relative to the direction of the plane of rotation of the braking surface 5.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">It is obvious to a person skilled in the art that the invention is not exclusively limited to the example described above but that it may be varied within the scope of the claims presented below. Thus, for example, the fastening and structure of the adjusting elements may differ from those described above.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">It is also obvious to a person skilled in the art that the first and second cylindrical parts of the eccentric shafts may differ from each other in diametric size, for example so that the second cylindrical part going through the mounting bracket is smaller in diameter than the first cylindrical part in the mounting hole of the frame part of the hoisting machine.<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></p><p id="p0027" num="0027">It is further obvious to a skilled person that the first and second cylindrical parts of the eccentric shafts may also differ from each other in diametric size so that the second cylindrical part going through the mounting bracket is larger in diameter than the first cylindrical part in the mounting hole of the frame part of the hoisting machine.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">It is likewise obvious to a skilled person that the structure of the eccentric shaft may also differ from the structure described above so that the shaft itself is straight and has a substantially uniform thickness throughout its length but is provided with an eccentric sleeve placed on the cylindrical part going through the mounting bracket or on the cylindrical part in the frame part of the hoisting machine.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56984504" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Aufzugsbremse für einen Aufzug, wobei der Aufzug eine Hebemaschine (1) aufweist, die mit zumindest einem Rahmenteil (2) und einer Treibscheibe (3) versehen ist, sowie ferner eine mit der Treibscheibe (3) rotierbar angeordnete Bremstrommel (4), die mit einer Bremsfläche (5) versehen ist, und eine Bremse (6), die eine Wirkung auf die Drehbewegung der Treibscheibe (3) ausübt, wobei die Bremse (6) zumindest einen Bremsblock (8) aufweist, der mit einer Bremsfläche versehen ist, welcher Bremsblock (8) angeordnet ist, um auf die Bremsfläche (5) der Bremstrommel (4) mit einer Kraft zu wirken, die im Wesentlichen auf die Bremsfläche (5) gerichtet ist, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> zur Ermöglichung einer Justierung der Größe eines Luftspaltes (8a) zwischen der Bremsfläche des Bremsblocks (8) und der Bremsfläche (5) der Bremstrommel (4), die Bremse (6) gelenkig an der Hebemaschine mit Hilfe zweier exzentrischer Achsen (11) festgelegt ist, die als exzentrische Justierelemente fungieren, wobei eines auf jeder Seite des Bremsblocks (8) relativ zur Richtung der Rotationsebene der Bremsfläche (5) vorliegt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Aufzugsbremse nach Anspruch 1, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die exzentrischen Achsen (11) relativ zueinander im Wesentlichen parallel sind und zugleich auch im Wesentlichen parallel zu der Rotationsachse der Bremstrommel (4).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Aufzugsbremse nach einem der vorangehenden Ansprüche, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die Bremse (6) an ihrem ersten Ende ein Montageloch (13) hat, wobei das Montageloch (13) eine der zwei exzentrischen Achsen als eine<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> im Wesentlichen zwischenraumfireie erste exzentrische Achse (11) aufinimmt, die um ihre Zentralachse rotierbar ist, und dass die Bremse (6) an ihrem zweiten Ende die andere der beiden exzentrischen Achsen als eine zweite exzentrische Achse (11) und eine Anschlagfläche (16) hat, die dazu angepasst ist, durch ein Federelement (15) gegen die Fläche der exzentrischen Achse (11) gedrückt zu werden, die in Richtung zur Bremsfläche (5) ausgerichtet ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Aufzugsbremse nach Anspruch 3, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die zweite exzentrische Achse (11) an dem zweiten Ende der Bremse (6) in einem im Wesentlichen fireiräumigen Durchgangsloch (14) platziert ist, dessen Durchmesser im Wesentlichen größer ist als der Durchmesser der zweiten exzentrischen Achse (11), in welchem Durchgangsloch (14) derjenige Abschnitt des Außenumfanges des Loches, der näher an der Bremstrommel (4) liegt, dazu angepasst ist, die Anschlagfiläche (16) für den zweiten zylindrischen Teil (11) zu bilden.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Aufzugsbremse nach Anspruch 3, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> sie an dem zweiten Ende der Bremse (6) in Verbindung mit einer Montageklammer als die zweite Montageklammer (10) ein käfigförmiges Trägerelement (17) oder ein Trägerelement aufweist, das zu einer Bewegung in entsprechender Weise bestimmt ist, welches zwischen der zweiten exzentrischen Achse (11) und der zweiten Montageklammer (10) angeordnet ist, und in welchem Trägerelement (17) eine Fläche, die als die Anschlagsfläche (16) für die zweite exzentrische Achse (11) füngiert, so geformt ist, dass der Flächendruck zwischen der zweiten exzentrischen Achse (11) und dem Trägerelement (17) so klein wie möglich ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Aufzugsbremse nach einem der vorangehenden Ansprüche, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die Einstellung des Luftspaltes (8a) der Bremse (6) so<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> vorgesehen ist, dass sie durch Drehen einer jeden exzentrischen Achse (11) um ihre Zentralachse ausgeführt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Aufzugsbremse nach Anspruch 3, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die Zentralachse des Montagelochs (13) im Wesentlichen in der Tangentialebene des Kontaktpunktes zwischen dem Bremsblock (8) und der Bremsfläche (5) der Bremstrommel (4) liegt.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56984505" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>An elevator brake for an elevator, said elevator comprising a hoisting machine (1) provided with at least a frame part (2) and a traction sheave (3), and a brake drum (4) arranged to be rotatable with the traction sheave (3) and provided with a braking surface (5), and a brake (6) having an effect on the rotary motion of the traction sheave (3), said brake (6) comprising at least one brake block (8) provided with a braking surface, which brake block (8) has been arranged to act on the braking surface (5) of the brake drum (4) with a force directed substantially towards the braking surface (5), <b>characterized in that</b>, to allow adjustment of the size of an air gap (8a) between the braking surface of the brake block (8) and the braking surface (5) of the brake drum (4), the brake (6) is hingedly secured to the hoisting machine by means of two eccentric shafts (11) functioning as eccentric adjusting elements, one on either side of the brake block (8) relative to the direction of the plane of rotation of the braking surface (5).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>An elevator brake according to claim 1, <b>characterized in that</b> the eccentric shafts (11) are substantially parallel relative to each other and at the same time also substantially parallel to the axis of rotation of the brake drum (4).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>An elevator brake according to any one of the preceding claims, <b>characterized in that</b> the brake (6) has at its first end a mounting hole (13), said mounting hole (13) accommodating one of the two eccentric shafts as a substantially clearance-free first eccentric shaft (11)<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> rotatable about its center axis, and that the brake (6) has at its second end the other one of the two eccentric shafts as a second eccentric shaft (11) and a stop face (16), which has been adapted to be pressed by a spring element (15) against that surface of the eccentric shaft (11) which faces towards the braking surface (5).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>An elevator brake according to claim 3, <b>characterized in that</b> the second eccentric shaft (11) at the second end of the brake (6) is placed in a substantially loose through hole (14) whose diameter is substantially larger than the diameter of the second eccentric shaft (11), in which through hole (14) that portion of the periphery of the hole which lies closer to the brake drum (4) has been adapted to form the stop face (16) for the second cylindrical part (11).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>An elevator brake according to claim 3, <b>characterized in that</b> it has at the second end of the brake (6), in conjunction with a mounting bracket as the second mounting bracket (10), a carriage-type supporting element (17) or a supporting element arranged to be movable in a corresponding manner, which is disposed between the second eccentric shaft (11) and the second mounting bracket (10), and in which supporting element (17) a surface functioning as the stop face (16) for the second eccentric shaft (11) has been so shaped that the surface pressure between the second eccentric shaft (11) and the supporting element (17) is as small as possible.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>An elevator brake according to any one of the preceding claims, <b>characterized in that</b> the adjustment of the air gap (8a) of the brake (6) has been arranged to be<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> performed by rotating each eccentric shaft (11) about its center axis.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>An elevator brake according to claim 3, <b>characterized in that</b> the center axis of the mounting hole (13) lies substantially in the tangential plane of the point of contact between the brake block (8) and the braking surface (5) of the brake drum (4).</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56984506" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Frein pour ascenseur, ledit ascenseur comprenant une machine de levage (1) pourvu d'au moins une partie de bâti (2) et d'une poulie de traction (3), et un tambour de frein (4) agencé de façon à pouvoir tourner avec la poulie de traction (3) et pourvu d'une surface de freinage (5), et un frein (6) ayant un effet sur le mouvement de rotation de la poulie de traction (3), ledit frein (6) comprenant au moins un bloc de frein (8) pourvu d'une surface de freinage, lequel bloc de frein (8) a été agencé de façon à agir sur la surface de freinage (5) du tambour de frein (4) avec une force dirigée sensiblement vers la surface de freinage (5), <b>caractérisé par le fait que</b>, pour permettre le réglage de la taille de la lame d'air (8a) entre la surface de freinage du bloc de frein (8) et la surface de freinage (5) du tambour de frein (4), le frein (6) est fixé par charnière au mécanisme de levage au moyen de deux arbres excentriques (11) fonctionnant comme des éléments de réglage excentriques, un sur chaque côté du bloc de frein (8) par rapport à la direction du plan de rotation de la surface de freinage (5).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Frein d'ascenseur selon la revendication 1, <b>caractérisé par le fait que</b> les arbres excentriques (11) sont sensiblement parallèles entre eux et simultanément également sensiblement parallèles à l'axe de rotation du tambour de frein (4).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Frein d'ascenseur selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, <b>caractérisé par le fait que</b> le frein (6) dispose à sa première extrémité d'un orifiice de montage (13), ledit orifiice de montage (13) logeant un des deux arbres excentriques en tant qu'un premier arbre excentrique sensiblement sans jeu (11) pouvant entrer en rotation autour de son axe central, et que le frein (6)<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> dispose à sa seconde extrémité de l'autre des deux arbres excentriques en tant que second arbre excentrique (11) et d'une surface d'arrêt (16), qui a été adaptée pour être soumise à une pression par un élément de ressort (15) contre la surface de l'arbre excentrique (11) faisant face à la surface de freinage (5).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Frein d'ascenseur selon la revendication 3, <b>caractérisé par le fait que</b> le second arbre excentrique (11) à la seconde extrémité du frein (6) est placé dans un trou traversant sensiblement large (14) dont le diamètre est sensiblement plus important que le diamètre du second arbre excentrique (11), dans lequel trou traversant (14) cette portion de la périphérie du trou qui se trouve plus près du tambour de frein (4) a été adaptée pour former la surface d'arrêt (16) pour la seconde pièce cylindrique (11).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Frein d'ascenseur selon la revendication 3, <b>caractérisé par le fait qu'</b>il dispose à sa seconde extrémité du frein (6), conjointement avec un support de fixation en tant que second support de fixation (10), d'un élément de support de type chariot (17) ou d'un élément de support destiné à être mobile d'une manière correspondante, qui est disposé entre le second arbre excentrique (11) et le second support de fixation (10), et dans lequel élément de support (1 7) une surface fonctionnant en tant que surface d'arrêt (16) pour le second arbre excentrique (11) a été façonnée de telle sorte que la pression de surface entre le second arbre excentrique (11) et l'élément de support (1 7) est aussi faible que possible.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Frein d'ascenseur selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, <b>caractérisé par le fait que</b> le réglage de la lame d'air (8a) du frein (6) a été agencé pour être effectué en faisant tourner chaque arbre excentrique (11) autour de son axe central.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Frein d'ascenseur selon la revendication 3, <b>caractérisé par le fait que</b> l'axe central de l'orifiice de montage (13) se trouve sensiblement dans le plan<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> tangentiel du point de contact entre le bloc de frein (8) et la surface de freinage (5) du tambour de frein (4).</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16671876" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1,2"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="157" he="230" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --><figure id="f0002" num="3,4"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="162" he="226" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --><figure id="f0003" num="5,6"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="162" he="218" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
