<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-1498025-B1" country="EP" doc-number="1498025" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="33477016" file-reference-id="280268" date-produced="20180823" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146589187" ucid="EP-1498025-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>1498025</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-04253891-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154851379" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>04253891</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20040629</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140557581" ucid="US-50907003-P" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>50907003</doc-number><kind>P</kind><date>20030630</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130802</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989327855" load-source="ipcr">C12N   5/04        20060101ALI20111205BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989327856" load-source="ipcr">G01N  15/14        20060101AFI20111205BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989622410" load-source="ipcr">C12Q   1/02        20060101AFI20051220RMJP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989628306" load-source="ipcr">A01H   4/00        20060101A I20051008RMEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989651474" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10S  47/09        20130101 LA20130518BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1991272099" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">C12N   5/04        20130101 LI20140110BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1991273340" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G01N  15/147       20130101 LI20140110BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1991274970" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A01H   4/006       20130101 LI20140110BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1991275436" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G01N2015/0019      20130101 LA20140110BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1991276677" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G01N  15/1475      20130101 LI20140110BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1991278562" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A01H   1/04        20130101 LI20140110BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1991278879" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G01N2015/1497      20130101 LA20140110BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1991278986" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A01H   4/00        20130101 FI20140110BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132372194" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Automatisiertes System und Verfahren zum Ernten und mehrstufige Screening von Planzenembryonen</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132372195" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Automated system and method for harvesting and multi-stage screening of plant embryos</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132372196" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Système automatisé et procédé de récolte et criblage multi-étapes des embryons végétaux</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919530107" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>WEYERHAEUSER CO</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919522202" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>WEYERHAEUSER COMPANY</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919505607" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>TIMMIS ROGER</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919541165" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>TIMMIS, ROGER</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919026751" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>TIMMIS, ROGER</last-name><address><street>3520 Country Club Drive NW</street><city>Olympia, Washington 98502</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919524327" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>HIRAHARA EDWIN</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919533452" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>HIRAHARA, EDWIN</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919026752" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>HIRAHARA, EDWIN</last-name><address><street>32524 40th Avenue SW</street><city>Federal Way, Washington 98023</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919529201" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>FOLSTER HARRY G</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919533931" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>FOLSTER, HARRY G.</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919026753" load-source="patent-office" sequence="3" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>FOLSTER, HARRY G.</last-name><address><street>5113 Chinook Drive NE</street><city>Tacoma, Washington 98422-1953</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919545873" load-source="docdb" sequence="4" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>SUPERUS-LOPEZ HEATHER</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919537863" load-source="docdb" sequence="4" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>SUPERUS-LOPEZ, HEATHER</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919026754" load-source="patent-office" sequence="4" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>SUPERUS-LOPEZ, HEATHER</last-name><address><street>1300 Pierce Place</street><city>Renton, Washington 98056</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919026755" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>WEYERHAEUSER COMPANY</last-name><iid>100254116</iid><address><street>P.O. Box 9777</street><city>Federal Way, WA 98063-9777</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919026756" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Boult Wade Tennant</last-name><iid>101370347</iid><address><street>Verulam Gardens 70 Gray's Inn Road</street><city>London WC1X 8BT</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549807345" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549794103" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549794104" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549875873" load-source="docdb">SE</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63961599" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><p id="p0001" num="0001">The invention is directed generally to manufactured seeds and, more particularly, to a method and system for automatically harvesting and screening mass-produced plant embryos in multiple stages to identify those embryos that are suited for incorporation into manufactured seeds.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002">Reproduction of selected plant varieties by tissue culture has been a commercial success for many years. The technique has enabled mass production of genetically identical selected ornamental plants, agricultural plants and forest species. The woody plants in this last group have perhaps posed the greatest challenges. Some success with conifers was achieved in the 1970s using organogenesis techniques wherein a bud, or other organ, was placed on a culture medium where it was ultimately replicated many times. The newly generated buds were placed on a different medium that induced root development. From there, the buds having stems and roots were planted in soil.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">While conifer organogenesis was a breakthrough, costs were high due to the large amount of handling needed. There was also some concern about possible genetic modification. It was a decade later before somatic embryogenesis achieved a sufficient success rate so as to become the predominant approach to conifer tissue culture. With somatic embryogenesis, an explant, usually a seed or seed embryo, is placed on an initiation medium where it multiplies into a multitude of genetically identical immature embryos. These can be held in culture for long periods and multiplied to bulk up a<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> particularly desirable clone. Ultimately, the immature embryos are placed on a development medium where they grow into somatic analogs of mature seed embryos. As used in the present description, a "somatic" embryo is a plant embryo developed by the laboratory culturing of totipotent plant cells or by induced cleavage polyembryogeny, as opposed to a zygotic embryo, which is a plant embryo removed from a seed of the corresponding plant. These embryos are then individually selected and placed on a germination medium for further development. Alternatively, the embryos may be used in artificial seeds, known as manufactured seeds.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">There is now a large body of general technical literature and a growing body of patent literature on embryogenesis of plants. Examples of procedures for conifer tissue culture are found in <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US5036007A"><text>U.S. Patent Nos. 5,036,007</text></patcit> and <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="US5236841A"><text>5,236,841 to Gupta et al.</text></patcit>; <patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="US5183757A"><text>5,183,757 to Roberts</text></patcit>; <patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="US5464769A"><text>5,464,769 to Attree et al.</text></patcit>; and <patcit id="pcit0005" dnum="US5563061A"><text>5,563,061 to Gupta</text></patcit>. Further, some examples of manufactured seeds can be found in <patcit id="pcit0006" dnum="US5701699A"><text>U.S. Patent No. 5,701,699 to Carlson et al.</text></patcit>, the disclosure of which is hereby expressly incorporated by reference. Briefly, a typical manufactured seed is formed of a seed coat (or a capsule) fabricated from a variety of materials such as cellulosic materials, filled with a synthetic gametophyte (a germination medium), in which an embryo surrounded by a tube-like restraint is received. After the manufactured seed is planted in the soil, the embryo inside the seed coat develops roots and eventually sheds the restraint along with the seed coat during germination.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">One of the more labor intensive and subjective steps in the embryogenesis procedure is the selective harvesting from the development medium of individual embryos suitable for germination (e.g., suitable for incorporation into manufactured seeds). The embryos may be present in a number of stages of maturity and development. Those that are most likely to successfully germinate into normal plants are preferentially selected using a number of visually evaluated screening criteria. A skilled technician evaluates the morphological features of each embryo embedded in the development medium, such as the embryo's size, shape (e.g., axial symmetry), cotyledon development, surface texture, color, and others, and manually plucks desirable embryos out of the development medium with a pair of tweezers. The plucked desirable embryos are then carefully laid out on a tray in a two-dimensional array for further processing. This is a highly skilled yet tedious job that is time consuming and expensive. Further, it poses a<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> major production bottleneck when the ultimate desired output will be in the millions of plants.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">It has been proposed to use some form of instrumental image analysis for embryo selection to supplement or replace the visual evaluation described above. For example, PCT Application Serial No. <patcit id="pcit0007" dnum="US0040720W"><text>PCT/US00/40720</text></patcit> (<patcit id="pcit0008" dnum="WO0113702A2"><text>WO 01/13702 A2</text></patcit>) discloses an embryo delivery system for manufactured seeds including an imaging camera, which acquires and digitally stores images of embryos. The images are then sent to a computer, which classifies the embryos according to their desirability (i.e., likelihood to germinate and grow into normal plants) based on predetermined parameters (axial symmetry, cotyledon development, surface texture, color, etc.) using a classification method disclosed in PCT Application Serial No. <patcit id="pcit0009" dnum="US9912128W"><text>PCT/LJS99/12128</text></patcit> (<patcit id="pcit0010" dnum="WO9963057A"><text>WO 99/63057</text></patcit>). Those embryos that are classified as desirable are thereafter removed by mini-robotic pick and place systems and inserted into manufactured seeds.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">While instrumental imaging analysis and subsequent automatic insertion of desirable embryos into manufactured seeds have been successful in increasing the efficiency of the embryogenesis procedure, there has not been a complete automated process of harvesting embryos, e.g., removing embryos from a development medium, sorting embryos according to their size/shape and singulating them into discrete units (e.g., by removing any undesirable tissues or other debris), and classifying them according to their desirability for incorporation into manufactured seeds. In other words, there has not been an automated process that could replace the current manual operation, of plucking desirable embryos out of a development medium and placing them in an array suitable for further maturation treatments. The present invention is directed to providing a complete automated process of harvesting somatic embryos, which could replace the current manual operation.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">"<nplcit id="ncit0001" npl-type="s"><text>Bioprocessing for Tree Production in the Forest Industry: Conifer Somatic Embryogenesis" by Roger Timmis, Biotechnology Prog. 1998, 14, p156-166</text></nplcit>, discloses machine separation and selection of embryos in liquid culture or on plates.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">"<nplcit id="ncit0002" npl-type="s"><text>Automation of Somatic Embryo Production" by Yasuomi Ibaraki and Kenji Kurata, Plant cell, tissue and organ culture 2001, 65, pages 179-199</text></nplcit>, discloses similar automation.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p><p id="p0010" num="0010">According to a first aspect of the invention there is provided a method as defined in claim 1</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">According to a second aspect of the invention there is provided a system as defined in claim 4</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">In a preferred embodiment, the automatic harvesting method screens plant embryos in multiple stages to identify those embryos that are suited for incorporation into manufactured seeds, i.e., those embryos that are both physically fit for incorporation into manufactured seeds (not too big, not too small, not<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> too bent, etc.) and also qualitatively determined to be likely to germinate and grow into normal plants. The automatic harvesting method includes three steps. First, plant embryos are automatically sorted according to their size/shape and also singulated into discrete embryo units. For example, the embryos may be washed off from a development medium (e.g., from a development pad) using aqueous liquid and sieved through a porous material. During sieving, the embryos may be further sprayed with aqueous liquid to facilitate removal and washing away of any undesirable material, such as undersized embryos, tissues, and residual embryonal suspensor masses (ESM), through the holes of the porous material. In one preferred embodiment, the porous material is formed as a moving porous conveyor belt so that the embryos being sorted and singulated are simultaneously transported to the subsequent classification stage. Second, the sorted and singulated plant embryos are classified using a first classification method. For example, each of the embryos may be imaged by a camera and the image is used to ascertain the embryo's size/shape. Those embryos within a predefined size/shape range are considered to have passed the first classification method. Third, at least for those embryos that have passed the first classification method, a second classification method is applied to further select those embryos desirable for incorporation into manufactured seeds. For example, a pre-developed classification algorithm to classify embryos according to their putative germination vigor (i.e., likelihood of successful germination) may be applied to the same image used in the first size/shape classification method, to identify those embryos that are likely to germinate. The embryos that have passed both the first and second classification methods are identified as suitable for incorporation into manufactured seeds.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">In preferred embodiments, the first and second classification methods are carried out along a classification conveyor belt while the sorted and singulated embryos are transported thereon. In some classification methods, it is preferred that the embryos are generally arranged in a single file on the classification conveyor belt. Various means for achieving the single file configuration are proposed. For example, the classification conveyor belt may be arranged generally perpendicularly to the porous conveyor belt on which the embryos are sorted and singulated. According to this configuration, the sorted and singulated embryos transported to the end of the porous conveyors may drop therefrom by gravity onto the classification conveyor belt to generally form a single file<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> thereon. To achieve sufficient spacing between the embryos in a single file, the initial rate of washing off embryos from a development medium onto the porous conveyor belt or the speed of the porous conveyor belt may be adjusted, perhaps based on the actual rate of embryos being dropped from the porous conveyor belt onto the classification conveyor belt as observed by a suitable optical scanning system.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">Optionally , the method further includes the step of automatically removing those undesirable embryos that have failed the first or second classification method from the classification conveyor belt. For example, a computer-controlled air or liquid jet may be used to eject undesirable embryos. The precise timing of the jet activation can be computer controlled because the position of each undesirable embryo is precisely known based on the firing time of the camera that has imaged each embryo and the speed of the classification conveyor belt.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">Optionally, the method further includes the step of automatically removing those desirable embryos that have passed both the first and second classification methods from the classification conveyor belt. In one embodiment, the desirable embryos are automatically transferred onto a receiving surface in an evenly spaced array, suitable for various further maturation treatments. For example, the receiving surface may be provided by a tray mounted on a motorized platform configured to adjust the position of the tray relative to the classification conveyor belt. By adjusting the position of the tray based on the known position of each desirable embryo as it is dropped from the classification conveyor belt, the desirable embryos may be received on the tray in an evenly spaced two-dimensional array.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">Optionally, the method may include a step of automatically removing those desirable embryos that have passed one or more initial classification methods from a conveyor belt. For example, a mini-robotic system may be used to pick up those embryos determined to be within an acceptable size/shape range and to precisely place them in an evenly spaced two-dimensional array on a receiving tray. At this time, the embryos may be oriented uniformly, for example, with their cotyledon ends facing the same direction. The properly oriented and precisely spaced apart embryos in a tray may then be forwarded to receive further treatments, for example, drying and subsequent further classification methods. Thereafter, these properly oriented and spaced apart<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> embryos in a tray can be readily transferred and inserted into manufactured seeds which, advantageously, may be arranged in a correspondingly evenly spaced array.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">Classifying the embryos in multiple stages achieves efficient screening of embryos. For example, by classifying embryos using a relatively less sophisticated and less time-consuming classification method first, one can reduce the number of embryos to be forwarded to the second classification method that is more sophisticated and more time-consuming. Thus, by carefully selecting suitable classification methods to be combined, one can achieve increasingly selective and discriminating classification of embryos in a time efficient manner. Embodiments can provide a complete automated process of harvesting somatic embryos, including sorting and singulating embryos (starting with removing the embryos from a development medium), classifying the sorted and singulated embryos according to their putative germination vigor, and further arranging those embryos classified as desirable in a manner suitable for further maturation treatments, e.g., in an evenly spaced two-dimensional array on a tray. Thus, an automated harvesting method and system of the present invention could replace the current manual operation of plucking desirable embryos from a development medium.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">The foregoing aspects and many of the attendant advantages of this invention will become more readily appreciated as the same become better understood by reference to the following detailed description, when taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings, wherein:
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURE 1 A </figref>schematically illustrates a system for automated harvesting and multi-stage screening of plant embryos, in accordance with the present invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">FIGURE 1 B</figref> schematically illustrates an alternative system for automated harvesting and multi-stage screening of plant embryos, in accordance with the present invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">FIGURE 2</figref> is a flowchart illustrating an overall flow of a method for automatically harvesting and screening embryos in multiple stages, in accordance with the present invention; and</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">FIGURES 3A and 3B</figref> illustrate alternative methods of automatically sorting and singulating embryos, according to the present invention.</li></ul><!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></p><p id="p0019" num="0019">The invention pertains to a method and system for automatically harvesting and screening mass-produced embryos, such as somatic embryos, preferably in multiple stages of increasing complexity to identify those embryos that are suited for incorporation into manufactured seeds. As used herein, an embryo suited for incorporation into a manufactured seed means an embryo that is both biochemically matured (i.e., likely to germinate and grow into a normal plant) and morphologically or physically suited for incorporation into a manufactured seed (i.e., having a size/shape appropriate to be included in a manufactured seed).</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURE 1A</figref>, in a Development Room 10, somatic embryos have been developed from embryonal suspensor masses (ESM) and supported/suspended in or on a development surface 16. A development surface may be provided by a development pad, as illustrated, or may be provided by any other suitable development medium including a gel-form medium, or may further be provided by an intervening surface that is placed on a development medium such as a stainless steel mesh. While the following description illustrates a case in which a development pad is used to provide a development surface, it should be understood that a development surface, as used in the present application, refers to any surface that supports or suspends embryos that are developed from ESM.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">Methods of developing somatic embryos are known and described in various publications, as discussed in the background section above. Desirable embryos are to various degrees attached to and embedded in suspensor tissues and residual underdeveloped ESM (or culture material) in the pad 16, together with incompletely developed embryos, abnormally formed embryos, undersized or oversized embryos, and other pieces of non-embryo plant material. The embryos suspended in a development pad 16 are forwarded to a Harvesting and Classification Room 12, in which the embryos (embedded in the culture material) are removed from the development pad and further automatically sorted, singulated, and classified according to their desirability. Classification may be carried out using multiple stages of increasingly sophisticated and yet time-consuming classification methods, to achieve progressively higher selection accuracy and operational efficiency. Those embryos that are classified as desirable are thereafter forwarded to receive further maturation treatments, for example, to a Post<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> Development Treatment Room (Drying Room in the illustrated embodiment) 14 to be dried for storage and subsequent incorporation into manufactured seeds. The present invention is generally directed to the automated process of harvesting and classifying embryos, which occurs in the Harvesting and Classification Room 12. It is contemplated that the harvesting and classification are carried out preferably in a humid clean room conditioned to sustain viability of the embryos being processed.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">Referring additionally to <figref idrefs="f0003">FIGURE 2</figref>, a method of the present invention in one embodiment includes generally four steps. First, referring to step "A" in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURES 1A</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0003">2</figref>, embryos are washed off the development surface (e.g., development pad surface) 16 using pressure-controlled sprays of aqueous liquid (e.g., isotonic nutrient solution) from a suitably arranged nozzle 18. This washing off process separates the culture material including embryos from the development surface 16, but at least some of the embryos remain embedded in or attached to suspensor tissues, residual underdeveloped ESM, and other materials at this point. As illustrated, the development surface 16 may be placed on an inclined surface 20 to facilitate washing off and removal of the culture material including embryos via gravity toward a reservoir 22 (or a hydrocyclone-type separator). The bottom 26 of the reservoir 22 has an elongate opening (slit) extending generally perpendicularly to the direction of a conveyor belt 24 and extending substantially throughout the width of the conveyor belt 24, so that the embryos (embedded in or attached to suspensor tissues or residual ESM) are placed onto the conveyor belt 24 in a generally spread or spatially uniform manner. Alternatively, a flow of liquid-dispersed embryos from the reservoir 22 can be regulated by various other means, such as constriction, flow path length adjustment, etc., to place the embryos on the conveyor belt 24 in a regulated, spatially uniform manner.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">Next referring to step "B," the conveyor belt 24 is formed of a porous continuous belt 28 driven by a suitable motor (not shown), which sorts and singulates the embryos by sieving. As used herein, "sorting and singulating" means rudimentarily classifying embryos according to their size/shape and also separating the embryos into discrete units, for example by separating embryos apart and also by removing any undesirable materials from each embryo. For example, sieving by the porous continuous belt 28 achieves both sorting and singulation by causing any undersized material, such as undersized embryos and debris, to drop through its holes.<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></p><p id="p0024" num="0024">Specifically, while on the porous continuous belt 28, the embryos perhaps still embedded in suspensor tissues and residual ESM may be further sprayed with aqueous liquid from a second nozzle 30 to cause the embryos (and other adhering materials) to be further dispersed in the aqueous liquid. The liquid spray causes adhering suspensor tissues and residual ESM to be detached from the embryos and washed away and dropped through the porous belt 28. Any undersized or incompletely formed embryos will also be dropped through the porous belt 28. In one embodiment, the conveyor belt 24 may be of a vibrating type, as well known in the conveyor belt technology field, to further facilitate the sorting and singulation process. Any material dropped through the porous belt 28 may be collected in a waste receptacle 32 placed underneath the porous belt 28. Optionally, a second coarser porous belt (not shown) may be provided in series with the first conveyor belt 24 having the first porous belt 28, perhaps prior to the first porous belt 28, to carry away any oversized embryos and other oversized pieces of material. Thus, only those mostly singulated embryos of generally desired size and/or shape, which are more or less free of suspensor tissue and other fine plant material, remain on the first porous belt 28. By adjusting the mesh (hole) size/shape of the porous belt 28 (and of any other additional porous belts), only those embryos within a desirable size/shape range can be selected. It should be noted that, alternatively to the one or more porous conveyor belts described above, one or more sieves of wire or other mesh, for example, vibrating inclined sieves, may be used, although the use of porous conveyor belt(s) is preferred because they sieve and transport (to the next stage) embryos at the same time.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">As described above, during steps "A" and "B", the heterogeneous milieu (containing, e.g., acceptable quality embryos, unacceptable embryos, suspensor tissues, residual ESM, and other plant material) is dispersed in aqueous liquid and subjected to separation of components by physical forces (e.g., by sieving) that act differently on the components based on their physical properties (mass, size, shape, specific gravity, drag coefficient, wettability, etc.). As a result, fine plant material and embryo-adhering suspensor tissues are removed, with reduction in amount of any other undesirable components, to produce a population comprising mostly singulated embryos substantially free of suspensor tissues.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">After the spray-assisted sieving process, referring to step "C," at the end of the first conveyor belt 24, the sorted and singulated embryos are dropped by gravity onto<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> another conveyor belt, or a classification conveyor belt 34. The classification conveyor belt 34 is arranged generally perpendicularly to the first conveyor belt 24 so that the dropping embryos will generally form a single file 36 along the length of the selection conveyor belt 34 suitable for subsequent imaging. In case the embryos tend to stick to the first conveyor belt 24 and cannot be easily dropped, the separation of the embryos from the first conveyor belt 24 may be assisted by various means. For example, the embryo removal may be assisted by an air/liquid jet (e.g., a gentle squirt of nutrient solution or puff of air―not shown) suitably arranged beneath the porous belt 28 near the end 35 of the first conveyor belt 24, or a fine vibrating wire placed perpendicularly to and just above the first conveyor belt 24 near the end 35, so as to break the surface tension and knock the embryos off the first conveyor belt 24. Alternatively, a dryer (not shown) may be arranged adjacent to the first conveyor belt 24 to dry off the embryos as they move down the first conveyor belt 24.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">For the purpose of subsequent imaging, the embryos are sufficiently spaced apart from each other on the classification conveyor belt 34. To achieve sufficient spacing between the embryos in a single file 36, the initial rate of washing off the embryos from the development surface 16 may be adjusted. Also, the configuration of the reservoir 22 (or a hydrocyclone-type separator) may be adjusted, as discussed above, to achieve controlled dispensing of the embryos onto the first conveyor belt 24 and hence controlled dropping of the embryos from the first conveyor belt 24 onto the classification conveyor belt 34. While the reservoir 22 is illustrated to be positioned upstream of the sprayed sieving process in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURE 1A</figref>, it should be understood that the reservoir 22 may be located downstream from the sprayed sieving process, near the end 35 of the first conveyor belt 24, so as to receive and controllably drop the embryos from the first conveyor belt 24 onto the classification conveyor belt 34. As yet another example, an electronic embryo position mapper (not shown) controlled by a computer 40 may be positioned near the end 35 of the first conveyor belt 24 downstream of the sprayed sieving process. The embryo position mapper consists of a suitable optical sensor and detector combination to determine the position of each embryo as it is carried on the first conveyor belt 24. The computer 40, based on the positional information received from the embryo position mapper, continuously adjusts the belt speed of the first conveyor belt 24 and/or the classification conveyor belt 34 so as to achieve a uniform dropping rate<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> of the embryos from the first conveyor belt 24 onto the classification conveyor belt 34. Any of the methods hereinabove described may be combined together. For example, the embryo position mapper positioned near the end 35 of the first conveyor belt 24 may be used to control the initial washing off rate of the embryos from the development surface 16. Also, any other methods for achieving sufficient spacing between the embryos, as they are placed onto the first conveyor belt 24, as will be apparent to one skilled in the art, may be used.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">In one alternative embodiment, the single file configuration preferred for imaging purposes may be obtained by utilizing the flow of liquid-dispersed embryos along a pipe. Specifically, referring to <figref idrefs="f0004">FIGURE 3A</figref>, embryos are washed off the development surface 16 using aqueous liquid from a suitably arranged nozzle 18 and placed into a reservoir 22, as with the embodiment illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURE 1A</figref>. The reservoir communicates with a pipe 21 having a properly chosen diameter, through which the liquid dispersed embryos still entangled with other tissues, ESM, and plant debris, flow, preferably at a predefined controllable velocity, and exit onto the porous conveyor belt 25. In one embodiment, the pipe 21 is clear so that an optical scanner 23 arranged along the clear pipe 21 can observe the flow therethrough to provide feedback to the initial rate of washing off the embryos from the development medium to ensure a desired level of spacing between materials (e.g., embryos) passing through the pipe 21. As before, the conveyor belt 25 is porous, at least in its upstream portion, so that any undersized embryos and other fine materials (suspensor tissues, residual ESM, etc.) fall through the belt 25, as further facilitated by an aqueous liquid spray from the nozzle 30. As illustrated, because the culture stream dispensed from the pipe 21 is generally lined up on the porous conveyor belt 25, the embryos remaining on the belt 25 after the sprayed sieving process are already in a single file configuration 34. Thus, the embryos may continue directly for further classification on the same conveyor belt 25, for example, for image acquisition by a camera 38 and subsequent selective removal of undesirable embryos by an ejector 42, both controlled by the computer 40. The embryos eventually drop from the end of the conveyor belt 25 onto a receiving tray 54, as will be more fully described below.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">As a further alternative method of achieving the single file configuration, referring to <figref idrefs="f0004">FIGURE 3B</figref>, a flow cytometer may be used to sort and singulate embryos. In this<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> embodiment, the embryos are washed off the development surface 16 using aqueous liquid from a suitably arranged nozzle 18 and placed into a reservoir 22, as with the previous embodiments, and thereafter travel through a clear pipe 21. A flow cytometer (or cell separator) 27, which is well known in the art, is arranged along the clear pipe 21 to observe and separate the desirable embryos from other materials such as undersized/oversized embryos, suspensor tissues, and residual ESM. Briefly, the flow cytometer differentiates different cells transported in liquid based on the cell properties as observed by optical sensors 27a, and further electrostatically sorts (separates) the cells using deflectors 27b based on ink jet technology, i.e., by deflecting selectively charged liquid droplets containing the targeted cells. In the illustrated embodiment, the flow cytometer 27 is used to sort and separate (branch off) embryos 31 that meet the predefined size/shape criteria onto the classification conveyor belt 34, while other materials 33, such as undersized or oversized embryos and suspensor tissues and residual ESM, drop into a rejects receptacle 29. Therefore, the flow cytometer 27 not only sorts and singulates the embryos, but also places them in a generally single file on the classification conveyor belt 34.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">Referring back to <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURES 1A</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0003">2</figref>, in step "C", the sorted and singulated embryos preferably placed in a single file and spaced sufficiently far apart from each other on the classification conveyor belt 34 are classified according to their desirability. For example, each of the embryos may be imaged by a camera 38 placed adjacent to (e.g., above) the classification conveyor belt 34. The image of each embryo is transmitted to the computer 40 to be analyzed and classified according to one or more high-speed algorithms.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">In one embodiment, each image (monochromatic or in color) of an embryo is analyzed in two steps. First, referring to <figref idrefs="f0003">FIGURE 2</figref>, block 46, a suitable algorithm is used to identify those embryos that do not meet basic size and shape criteria to be incorporated into manufactured seeds. Second, referring to block 48, a pre-developed classification model, such as those disclosed in PCT Application Serial No. <patcit id="pcit0011" dnum="US9912128W"><text>PCT/US99/12128</text></patcit> (<patcit id="pcit0012" dnum="WO9963057A"><text>WO 99/63057</text></patcit>) discussed above, is applied to the remaining embryos (i.e., the embryos that have met the first size/shape criteria) to identify those embryos having a lower probability of germinating (lacking in germination vigor). Briefly, a suitable classification model can be developed based on a sample population of embryos<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> for which images and actual germination data have been obtained. In a preferred example, a pre-developed classification model to classify embryos according to their putative germination vigor is applied to the same image used in the first size/shape classification step, so that a single image can be used in both of the first and second classification steps. Referring additionally to <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURE 1A</figref>, the programs (algorithms) that effect the actual classification and other evaluation of the embryos based on the images produced by the camera 38, e.g., pre-developed classification models, are stored in the computer 40.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">Those embryos rejected either by the first classification step as not meeting the size/shape criteria (block 46) or by the second classification step as not likely to germinate (block 48) may thereafter be ejected from the classification conveyor belt 34, for example, by a precisely timed air/liquid jet 42 controlled by the computer 40 into a waste receptacle 44. The precise timing of the jet activation can be computer controlled because the position of each undesirable embryo is precisely known based on the firing time of the camera 38 that has imaged each embryo and the known speed of the classification conveyor belt 34. The use of an image-actuated precision jet to remove undesirable materials from a conveyor belt is well known in the food industry, for example to sort foods based on their visual characteristics. After undesirable embryos have been removed, only those embryos that have passed both the first and second classification steps remain on the classification conveyor belt 34. Alternatively, the ejector 42 may be configured to remove desirable embryos from the classification conveyor belt 34 onto another location, such as another conveyor belt or a harvest chamber, for further maturation treatments, as will be apparent to one skilled in the art.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">The embryo classification step "C" may include further steps or stages of data acquisition and classification/screening operations. For example, after the two-step camera image analysis (blocks 46 and 48 in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIGURE 2</figref>) is carried out as described above, the embryos may undergo a further imaging analysis (e.g., block 50) or a spectroscopic analysis using IR, NIR, or Raman spectroscopy (block 52), as will be more fully described below, before undesirable embryos are removed from the selection conveyor belt 34. Alternatively, after the two-step camera image analysis described above is completed and any undesirable embryos are ejected, the remaining desirable embryos may be placed in a tray and dried for storage purposes (step "D"), and thereafter (at a later<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> time) undergo further stages of data acquisition and classification, or the "secondary" classification step "E", as will be more fully described below. In other words, in accordance with the present invention, the embryos may undergo any number of classification stages, and further, not all of the classification stages need to occur at the same time.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">The camera 38 may be of any suitable type as will be apparent to one skilled in the art, either monochromatic or color, though preferably a digital camera containing a charge-coupled device (CCD) linked to a digital storage device is used so as to permit subsequent digital processing of the acquired image. Further, the camera 38 may be a single-view camera (e.g., taking only the top view of each embryo carried on the classification conveyor belt 34) or a multiple-view camera (e.g., taking the top view, side view, and end view of each embryo). To acquire multiple views of an embryo, one camera may be moved into multiple positions, or multiple cameras may be used. However, preferably, a method and system for simultaneously imaging multiple views of an embryo using a single camera and suitably arranged reflective surfaces (e.g., prisms) may be used so as to shorten the time and operation required to obtain multiple views. Such a method and system for simultaneously imaging multiple views of an embryo are disclosed in a copending U.S. patent application <patcit id="pcit0013" dnum="US2004263957A"><text>US 2004/263957</text></patcit>, filed concurrently herewith, titled "Method and System for Simultaneously Imagine Multiple Views of a Plant Embryo". A classification model algorithm may then be applied to each of the multiple views of an embryo to classify the embryo according to its putative germination vigor.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">Additionally or alternatively, during the embryo classification step "C", an apical dome located at the cotyledon end of a plant embryo may be three dimensionally imaged and analyzed to determine the embryo's germinant vigor (i.e., potential for rapid epicotyl development after germination). (See <figref idrefs="f0003">FIGURE 2</figref>, block 50.) Because the apical dome is where most plant cells that produce the plant body are formed, it has been determined that the dome's morphological features (size, shape, etc.) are reliable indicators of the embryo's tendency for rapid growth after germination. In other words, the three-dimensional information of the apical dome of an embryo can be used as an input to a classification model algorithm to further classify the embryos according to their desirability. Some methods of three-dimensionally imaging an apical dome of a plant<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> embryo can be found in a copending U.S. patent application <patcit id="pcit0014" dnum="US2004268445A"><text>US 2004/268445</text></patcit>, filed concurrently herewith, titled "Method and System for Three-Dimensionally Imaging an Apical Dome of a Plant Embryo".</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">Further additionally or alternatively, during the embryo classification step "C", an embryo may be analyzed using a spectroscopic analysis method, such as IR spectroscopy, NIR spectroscopy, or Raman spectroscopy. (See <figref idrefs="f0003">FIGURE 2</figref>, block 52). The classification models disclosed in PCT Application Serial No.<patcit id="pcit0015" dnum="US9912128W"><text>PCT/US99/12128</text></patcit> (<patcit id="pcit0016" dnum="WO9963057A"><text>WO 99/63057</text></patcit>) discussed above, may be applied to any absorption, transmittance, or reflectance spectra of embryos, to further qualitatively classify the embryos according to their chemical composition. Briefly, a spectroscopic analysis permits identification of chemistry of each embryo and thus identification of targeted chemical(s) or analytes in an embryo. Embryos that are biochemically mature and likely to germinate are known to include certain levels of targeted chemicals or analytes, such as sugar alcohols. Thus, spectroscopic analysis of embryos is a reliable method of qualitatively identifying biochemically mature embryos. Some methods of spectroscopically analyzing and classifying embryos using NIR spectroscopy are disclosed in PCT Application Serial No. <patcit id="pcit0017" dnum="US9912128W"><text>PCT/US99/12128</text></patcit> (<patcit id="pcit0018" dnum="WO9963057A"><text>WO 99/63057</text></patcit>) discussed above. Further, a method of assessing embryo quality using Raman spectroscopy is disclosed in a copending U.S. patent application <patcit id="pcit0019" dnum="US2004268446A"><text>US 2004/268446</text></patcit>, filed concurrently herewith, titled "Method for Classifying Plant Embryos Using Raman Spectroscopy". As used herein, spectroscopic analysis encompasses the analysis of an image taken in one or more specific spectral bands, commonly known as multi-spectral imaging (or chemical imaging, chemical mapping).</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">It should be noted that other imaging or spectroscopic technologies to determine the biochemical composition or morphological structure of an embryo may be used additionally or alternatively to any of the classification methods described above. As new imaging or spectroscopic technologies emerge or mature, these technologies can be readily incorporated into the present method of automated harvesting and multi-stage screening of plant embryos. For example, Teraherz rays (T-rays) may be used to spectroscopically image a plant embryo to discern its chemical and physical compositions. As a further example, fluorescent labeling technology, such as the<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> quantum dots technology developed by Quantum Dot Corporation of Hayward, California, may be used to detect specific compounds and also to track biological events within a plant embryo. Still further, cosmic rays may be utilized to measure the density of an embryo. As will be apparent to one skilled in the art based on these examples, any other technologies that could determine the biochemical or morphological (structural) properties of a plant embryo, based on the use of a broad spectrum of electromagnetic radiation, may be used in accordance with the present invention.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">It is noted that the method described hereinabove screens or classifies embryos in multiple stages, first by sieving based on rudimentary size/shape criteria (step "B ") then by increasingly sophisticated and hence generally time-consuming means during step "C", such as an image-based size/shape analysis (block 46), image-based classification model analysis (block 48), image-based apical dome analysis (block 50), and spectra-based chemical analysis (block 52). It should be understood that more classification methods may be added as further additional screening criteria are developed. For example, a method of determining the disease resistance of an embryo may be developed using some sensor. Then, a classification stage to classify embryos based on the disease-resistance criteria may be added to further refine the overall classification process. As more screening criteria are developed and their corresponding classification methods incorporated into the present method, the method will be able to identify those embryos that are highly likely to grow into plants that are strong, healthy, and have various other desirable characteristics.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">It is contemplated that only those embryos that have passed the previous classification stage will be forwarded to the subsequent screening stage so that a lesser number of embryos need to be evaluated by a later screening stage of perhaps increasing sophistication and complexity, since complex screening stages tend to be more time consuming. However, in some situations two or more screening stages may be carried out in parallel, substantially simultaneously. For example, when multiple views (e.g., the top view, the side view, and the end view) of an embryo are taken and analyzed according to a classification model (block 48), one of the views (e.g., the cotyledon end view containing three-dimensional information of an apical dome) may be simultaneously analyzed in depth to ascertain the morphological features of the embryo's apical dome (block 50).<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --></p><p id="p0040" num="0040">Still referring to <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURES 1A</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0003">2</figref>, in step "D", at the end of the classification conveyor belt 34, those desirable embryos remaining on the conveyor belt 34 are dropped by gravity (perhaps assisted by an air/liquid jet―not shown) onto a tray (or pad, or any suitable surface) 54 mounted on a two-dimensional drive system (or motorized platform) 56, which is also controlled by the computer 40. The drive system 56 two-dimensionally (or perhaps three-dimensionally) adjusts the position of the tray 54 relative to the end of the classification conveyor belt 34 so as to receive embryos dropping therefrom into an evenly spaced array (e.g., a two-dimensional array). The positioning of the tray 54 relative to the end of the classification conveyor belt 34 is determined based on the precisely known position of each embryo on the classification conveyor belt 34 according to the firing time of the camera 38 and the speed of the conveyor belt 34. Thus, even a somewhat irregularly spaced linear array of desirable embryos on the classification conveyor belt 34 can be transformed into an evenly spaced two-dimensional array on the tray 54. The construction and operation of the drive system 56 should be apparent to one skilled in the art and thus need not be described in detail here. The tray 54, perhaps containing 100 plus embryos arranged in an evenly spaced array, may thereafter be forwarded to receive further maturation treatments. For example, the tray 54 may be forwarded to the Post Development Treatment Room (Drying Room in the illustrated embodiment) 14 to dry the embryos for storage and for subsequent incorporation into manufactured seeds.</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">Additionally, referring specifically to <figref idrefs="f0003">FIGURE 2</figref>, in step "E", the embryos placed and dried in the tray 54 may undergo a further, secondary series of classification stages prior to incorporation into manufactured seeds. The embryos may be rehydrated prior to the secondary series of classification stages, or may remain desiccated during one or more of the secondary series of classification stages, depending on each application. As with the previous classification step "C", the secondary classification step "E" may also include one or more classification stages of increasing sophistication and complexity to achieve progressively higher selection accuracy and operational efficiency. Because only a relatively small number of embryos, having passed the previous classification step "C", are remaining at this time, more sophisticated and thus time-consuming classification methods can be carried out, such as the multi-view color imaging analysis using a classification model (block 54), an apical dome analysis (block 56), or a spectroscopic<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> analysis, perhaps also using multiple views (block 58). It is also contemplated that when robotic pick and place systems are used to automatically pick up and insert embryos into manufactured seeds, some digital imaging may be required to ascertain the position of each embryo for that purpose, and therefore this digital imaging can be advantageously combined with image acquisition required for one or more of the classification stages during this secondary classification step "E".</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">For example, in one embodiment, after being removed from - development medium in step "A", and further being sorted and singulated in step "B", during the embryo classification step "C", the embryos may undergo two classification stages. First, a single-view (e.g., the top view) monochromatic image analysis is carried out to eliminate those embryos that do not meet the basis size/shape criteria (block 46). Second, a classification model is applied to the same single-view monochromatic image to eliminate those embryos that are not likely to germinate (block 48). In step "D", those remaining embryos that have passed both of the two classification stages are placed in a tray and dried. Thereafter, during the secondary classification step "E", the embryos forwarded from step "D" undergo a further series of classification stages that are perhaps more sophisticated and therefore time-consuming. For example, the embryos may be subjected to a multiple-view (e.g., the top view, side view, and end view) color image analysis to eliminate undesirable embryos according to a classification model (block 54), and further to an apical dome analysis (block 56) and/or a spectroscopic analysis (block 58) to still further eliminate undesirable embryos, again according to a suitable classification model.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043"><figref idrefs="f0002">FIGURE 1B</figref> illustrates an alternative embodiment of a system for automated harvesting and multi-stage screening of plant embryos. As with the embodiment of <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURE 1A</figref>, embryos are washed off a development surface and placed onto the porous conveyor belt 24 and sieved, perhaps as assisted by additional washing with aqueous liquid (corresponding to <figref idrefs="f0003">FIGURE 2</figref>, steps "A" and "B"). The embryos remaining on the conveyor belt 24 are then imaged by a camera 38. The image of each embryo is transmitted to the computer 40 to be analyzed and classified according to their morphological features (corresponding to <figref idrefs="f0003">FIGURE 2</figref>, step "C"). For example, a suitable algorithm is used to identify those embryos that meet basic size and shape criteria to be incorporated into manufactured seeds.<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --></p><p id="p0044" num="0044">Then, a smart mini-robotic transfer system 60 under the control of the computer 40 is used to pick up and place each of those embryos meeting the basic size and shape criteria onto a receiving tray 54 in an evenly spaced array. Briefly, the transfer system 60 includes a housing 61 laterally movable along a rail 62, and a robotic arm 63 extending from the housing 61 and including a vacuum tip end. The robotic arm 63 is longitudinally extendible and also axially rotatable. The details of one example of the mini-robotic transfer system 60 suitable for use in the present embodiment are disclosed in PCT Application Serial No. <patcit id="pcit0020" dnum="US00M0720W"><text>PCT/U500M0720</text></patcit> (<patcit id="pcit0021" dnum="WO0113702A2"><text>WO 01/13702 A2</text></patcit>). In the illustrated embodiment of <figref idrefs="f0002">FIGURE 1B</figref>, after an embryo is picked up from the conveyor belt 24 by the arm 63, the housing 61 is translated along the rail 62 to a new position 61', at which point the arm 63' is extended downwardly to place the embryo on the tray 54. At this point, the arm 61' may be controllably rotated axially, based on the original orientation of the embryo as imaged by the camera 38 and stored in the computer 40, so that the embryos as placed on the tray 54 are properly oriented, for example, with their cotyledon ends all facing the same direction. In one preferred embodiment, the embryos are precisely placed on the tray 54 in the same orientation and with their cotyledon ends precisely aligned with each other. In the present description, a tray on which embryos are arranged in the same orientation and in a precise array (e.g., with the positions of their cotyledon ends precisely known) is called an "index tray."</p><p id="p0045" num="0045">Thereafter, the index trays 54 are forwarded to receive maturation treatments, for example to the post development treatment room (drying room in the illustrated embodiment) 14 to dehydrate the embryos (corresponding to <figref idrefs="f0003">FIGURE 2</figref>, step "D"). Next, the embryos may be rehydrated and undergo a secondary classification process (corresponding to <figref idrefs="f0003">FIGURE 2</figref>, step "E"). Specifically, the index trays 54 each carrying a properly oriented and evenly spaced array of embryos may be placed on a secondary classification conveyor belt 64, and the embryos may be subjected to additional classification stages as they are transported on the conveyor belt 64. For example, a suitable scanner 68, coupled to a computer 70, is used to further classify the embryos to identify those that are likely to successfully germinate and grow into normal plants. During the secondary classification, the use of the index tray 54 may be advantageous because it permits localized analysis of each embryo on the tray. For example, certain imaging or spectroscopic analysis may be carried out with respect to a localized area of<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> each embryo (e.g., its cotyledon end portion). Because the precise positions of the embryos (e.g., their cotyledon ends) on the index tray 54 are known, such localized analysis is possible.</p><p id="p0046" num="0046">At the end of the secondary classification conveyor belt 64, another robotic embryo placement system 71 is provided to pick up only those embryos that have been further selected as desirable, and to insert them into manufactured seeds 76. In the illustrated embodiment, the embryo placement system 71 includes a housing 72 translated along a rail 73 and a robotic arm 74 extending from the housing 72. After a desirable embryo is picked up by the arm 74, the housing 72 is translated along the rail 73 to a new position 72', at which point the arm 74' may be lowered to place the embryo into a manufactured seed 76 (or a tubular restraint of the manufactured seed). The details of a suitable embryo placement system is disclosed in PCT Application Serial No. <patcit id="pcit0022" dnum="US0040720W"><text>PCT/US00/40720</text></patcit> (<patcit id="pcit0023" dnum="WO0113702A2"><text>WO 01/13702 A2</text></patcit>) discussed above. Various other alternative systems for transferring and inserting the embryos into manufactured seeds 76 are possible, as will be apparent to one skilled in the art. For example, the housing 72 and the arm 74 may be two- or three-dimensionally movable. Also, a tray holding the plurality of manufactured seeds 76 may be made one-, two-, or three-dimensionally movable so as to precisely position each of the seeds 76 relative to an embryo carried by the embryo placement system 71.</p><p id="p0047" num="0047">Notably, because the precise positions of the embryos on the index tray 54 are known, the embryo placement system 71 needs not have the capability to determine or correct the position and/or orientation of each embryo as it is picked up from the tray 54. For example, based on the known position and orientation of each embryo, it is possible for the embryo placement system 71 to precisely position the cotyledon end of each embryo within the manufactured seed 76.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048">According to the invention, a complete method and system for automatically harvesting somatic embryos are provided, which could replace the current manual operation including the steps of sorting and singulating and further classifying mass-produced embryos according to their putative germination vigor. Classification of the embryos is carried out in multiple stages to efficiently identify those embryos that are suited for incorporation into manufactured seeds. By carefully selecting suitable classification methods to be combined together, one can achieve progressively higher<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> selection accuracy that would match or exceed the level of selectivity currently achievable only by a highly skilled technician. Further, the throughput of the present automated method of multi-stage screening (classification) is calculated to be approximately 5 million embryos per year, which is sufficient to meet the 1.5-2 seconds/embryo rate required for the classification of sorted and singulated embryos for the purpose of mass production of manufactured seeds.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56987537" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Verfahren zum automatischen Ernten und Screenen von Pflanzen-Embryos in mehreren Schritten, umfassend:
<claim-text>automatisches Sortieren und Vereinzeln von Pflanzen-Embryos;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Verwenden einer Kamera, um jedes sortierte und vereinzelte Embryo darzustellen;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Übertragen des Bilds jedes Embryos auf einen Computer, um durch eine zweistufige Kamera-Bildanalyse analysiert und klassifiziert zu werden; wobei:
<claim-text>der Computer das Bild analysiert und die sortierten und vereinzelten Embryos automatisch klassifiziert, durch Verwenden eines ersten Klassifikations-verfahrens, basierend auf der Form und Größe der Embryos, um jene Embryos zu identifizieren, die die Basis-Größe und Form-Kriterien nicht erfüllen; und</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b>: der Computer nur jene Bilder der Pflanzen-Embryos analysiert, die das erste Klassifikationsverfahren unter Verwenden eines zweiten Klassifikationsverfahrens, basierend auf der mutmaßlichen Keimungs-Vitalität der Embryos, bestanden haben, welches jene Embryonen identifiziert, die eine geringere Wahrscheinlichkeit zum Keimen aufweisen; die aussortierten Embryos im ersten oder zweiten Klassifikationsschritt werden entfernt, um die verbleibenden gewünschten Embryos zurückzulassen; und das zweite Klassifikationsverfahren umfasst eine oder mehrere von: Mehrfach-Ansicht-Farbbildanalyse durch Verwenden eines Klassifikationsmodells; eine apikale Rundungsanalyse; und eine spektroskopische Analyse.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Verfahren, wie in Anspruch 1 beansprucht, wobei der Schritt des automatischen Sortierens und Vereinzeln das automatische Entfernen der Pflanzen-Embryos aus einem Entwicklungsmedium umfasst.<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Verfahren, wie in Anspruch 2 beansprucht, wobei das automatische Entfernen der Pflanzen-Embryos das Weg-Waschen des Entwicklungsmediums von den Pflanzen-Embryos durch Verwenden einer wässrigen Flüssigkeit umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Verfahren, wie in einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 3 beansprucht, wobei der Schritt des Sortierens und Vereinzeln der Embryos das Verwenden eines Durchflusszytometers umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Verfahren, wie in einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 3 beansprucht, wobei der Schritt des Sortierens und Vereinzeln der Embryos das Setzen der Embryos auf ein poröses Material zum Sieben umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Verfahren, wie in Anspruch 5 beansprucht, wobei die auf das poröse Material gesetzten Embryos mit einer wässrigen Flüssigkeit besprüht werden, um alle Suspensor-Gewebe oder restliche embryonale Suspensor Massen (ESM) von den Embryos zu entfernen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Verfahren, wie in Anspruch 5 oder Anspruch 6 beansprucht, wobei das poröse Material ein poröses Förderband umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Verfahren, wie in Anspruch 7 beansprucht, wobei die Embryos in ein Reservoir gesetzt werden, welches die Embryos auf dem porösen Förderband verteilt, wobei das Reservoir aufgebaut wird, um die Embryos auf dem Band in regulierter Weise zu verteilen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Verfahren, wie in Anspruch 8 beansprucht, wobei das Reservoir eine Röhre umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Verfahren, wie in einem der Ansprüche 7 bis 9 beansprucht, wobei die nach dem Sieben sortierten und vereinzelten Pflanzen-Embryos auf ein Klassifizierungs-Förderband gesetzt werden, nach welchem das erste und zweite automatische Klassifikations-Verfahren ausgeführt wird.<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Verfahren, wie in Anspruch 10 beansprucht, wobei die sortierten und vereinzelten Embryos von dem porösen Förderband auf das Klassifikations-Förderband durch Schwerkraft transferiert werden.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Verfahren, wie entweder in Anspruch 10 oder Anspruch 11 beansprucht, wobei sich das Klassifikations-Förderband allgemein senkrecht zum porösen Förderband erstreckt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Verfahren, wie in einem der Ansprüche 10 bis 12 beansprucht, wobei die sortierten und vereinzelten Pflanzen-Embryos auf das Klassifikations-Förderband in einem einzelnen Vorgang entlang der Länge des Klassifikations-Förderbands gesetzt werden.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Verfahren, wie in Anspruch 13 beansprucht, wobei die Pflanzen-Embryos in einem einzelnen Vorgang im Abstand voneinander gesetzt werden.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Verfahren, wie in einem der Ansprüche 10 bis 14 beansprucht, wobei ferner der Schritt des automatischen Entfernens das Auswerfen der Embryos vom Klassifikations-Förderband jener Embryos umfasst, die als durch das erste und zweite automatische Klassifikationsverfahren als unerwünscht klassifiziert worden sind.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0016" num="0016"><claim-text>Verfahren, wie in Anspruch 15 beansprucht, wobei das automatische Entfernen der unerwünschten Embryos durch einen Strahl ausgeführt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0017" num="0017"><claim-text>Verfahren, wie in einem der Ansprüche 10 bis 16 beansprucht, ferner den Schritt des automatischen Entfernens jener Embryos umfassend, die als durch das erste und zweite automatische Klassifikationsverfahren als unerwünscht klassifiziert worden sind.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0018" num="0018"><claim-text>Verfahren, wie in Anspruch 17 beansprucht, wobei der Schritt des automatischen Entfernens von gewünschten Embryos das Transferieren dieser gewünschten Embryos auf eine empfangende Oberfläche in vordefinierter Anordnung umfasst.<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0019" num="0019"><claim-text>Verfahren, wie in Anspruch 18 beansprucht, wobei die empfangende Oberfläche eine an einer motorisierten Plattform befestigte Ablage umfasst, die konfiguriert ist, um die Position der Ablage relativ zum Klassifikations-Förderband einzustellen, um so die durch Schwerkraft fallenden Embryos vom Klassifikations-Förderband in eine vordefinierte Anordnung zu erreichen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0020" num="0020"><claim-text>Verfahren, wie in Anspruch 19 beansprucht, wobei das Fallen der Embryos durch Schwerkraft vom Klassifikations-Förderband durch einen Strahl unterstützt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0021" num="0021"><claim-text>Verfahren, wie in einem der Ansprüche 7 bis 20 beansprucht, wobei die sortierten und vereinzelten Pflanzen-Embryos nach dem ersten Klassifikationsverfahren auf dem porösen Förderband klassifiziert werden, und die Pflanzen-Embryos, die das erste Klassifikationsverfahren bestanden haben, werden von dem porösen Förderband auf eine Index-Ablage in einer vordefinierten Anordnung transferiert.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0022" num="0022"><claim-text>Verfahren, wie in Anspruch 21 beansprucht, wobei das zweite Klassifikationsverfahren an den Pflanzen-Embryos ausgeführt wird, die auf die Index-Ablage gesetzt werden.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0023" num="0023"><claim-text>System zum automatischen Ernten und Screenen von Pflanzen-Embryos in mehreren Schritten, umfassend:
<claim-text>Mittel (22, 24, 28, 34; 21, 22, 25, 30; 21, 22, 27, 34) zum automatischen Sortieren und Vereinzeln der Pflanzen-Embryos;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Kamera (38) zum Darstellen jedes der sortierten und vereinzelten Embryos, wobei:
<claim-text>der Computer (40) automatisch die sortierten und vereinzelten Pflanzen-Embryos durch Verwenden eines ersten Klassifikationsverfahren klassifiziert;</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b>:
<claim-text>der Computer (40) automatisch nur die Pflanzen-Embryos klassifiziert, die das erste Klassifikationsverfahrens unter Verwenden eines zweiten Klassifikationsverfahrens, basierend auf der mutmaßlichen Keimungs-Vitalität der Embryos, bestanden haben, welches jene Embryonen identifiziert, die eine<!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --> geringere Wahrscheinlichkeit zum Keimen haben;</claim-text><claim-text>das zweite Klassifikationsverfahren umfasst eine oder mehrere von: Mehrfach-Ansicht-Farbbildanalyse durch Verwenden eines Klassifikationsmodells; eine apikale Rundungsanalyse; und eine spektroskopische Analyse ; und</claim-text><claim-text>ein Luft/Flüssigkeitsstrom (42), der von dem Computer (40) kontrolliert wird, wirft jene Embryos in einen Abfallbehälter (44), die entweder durch das erste Klassifikationsverfahren oder durch das zweite Klassifikationsverfahren aussortiert wurden.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56987538" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A method of automatically harvesting and screening plant embryos in multiple stages, comprising:
<claim-text>automatically sorting and singulating plant embryos;</claim-text>
<claim-text>using a camera to image each of the sorted and singulated embryos;</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting the image of each embryo to a computer to be analysed by a two-step camera image analysis and classified; wherein:
<claim-text>the computer analyses the images and automatically classifies the sorted and singulated plant embryos using a first classification method based on the shape and size of the embryos to identify those embryos that do not meet basic size and shape criteria; and</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>characterised in that</b>: the computer analyses only those images of the plant embryos that have passed the first classification method using a second classification method based on the putative germination vigour of the embryos which identifies those embryos having a lower probability of germinating;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the embryos rejected by the first or second classification step are removed to leave remaining desirable embryos; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second classification method comprises one or more of: multi-view colour imaging analysis using a classification model; an apical dome analysis; and a spectroscopic analysis.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>A method as claimed in claim 1, wherein the step of automatic sorting and singulating comprises automatically removing plant embryos from a development medium.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>A method as claimed in claim 2, wherein the automatic removal of plant embryos comprises washing off the plant embryos from the development medium using aqueous liquid.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>A method as claimed in any of claims 1 to 3, wherein the step of sorting and singulating embryos comprises using a flow cytometer.<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>A method as claimed in any of claims 1 to 3, wherein the step of sorting and singulating embryos comprises placing the embryos onto a porous material for sieving.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>A method as claimed in claim 5, wherein the embryos placed on the porous material are sprayed with aqueous liquid to remove any suspensor tissues or residual embryonal suspensor masses (ESM) from the embryos.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>A method as claimed in claim 5 or claim 6, wherein the porous material comprises a porous conveyor belt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>A method as claimed in claim 7, wherein the embryos are placed in a reservoir which dispenses the embryos onto the porous conveyor belt, the reservoir being configured to dispense the embryos onto the belt in a regulated manner.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>A method as claimed in claim 8, wherein the reservoir comprises a pipe.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>A method as claimed in any of claims 7 to 9, wherein the plant embryos sorted and singulated after sieving are placed on a classification conveyor belt, along which the first and second automatic classification methods are carried out.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>A method as claimed in claim 10, wherein the sorted and singulated plant embryos are transferred from the porous conveyor belt to the classification conveyor belt by gravity.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>A method as claimed in either claim 10 or claim 11, wherein the classification conveyor belt extends generally perpendicularly to the porous conveyor belt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>A method as claimed in any of claims 10 to 12, wherein the sorted and singulated plant embryos are placed on the classification conveyor belt in a single file along the length of the classification conveyor belt.<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>A method as claimed in claim 13, wherein the plant embryos are placed in a single file spaced apart from each other.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>A method as claimed in any of claims 10 to 14, further wherein the step of automatically removing those embryos that have been classified as undesirable by the first or second automatic classification method comprises ejecting the said embryos from the classification conveyor belt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0016" num="0016"><claim-text>A method as claimed in claim 15, wherein the automatic removal of undesirable embryos is carried out by a jet.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0017" num="0017"><claim-text>A method as claimed in any of claims 10 to 16, further comprising the step of automatically removing those embryos that have been classified as desirable by the first and second automatic classification methods from the classification conveyor belt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0018" num="0018"><claim-text>A method as claimed in claim 17, wherein the step of automatically removing desirable embryos comprises transferring those desirable embryos onto a receiving surface in a predefined array.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0019" num="0019"><claim-text>A method as claimed in claim 18, wherein the receiving surface comprises a tray mounted on a motorized platform configured to adjust the position of the tray relative to the classification conveyor belt so as to receive the embryos dropping by gravity from the classification conveyor belt into a predefined array.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0020" num="0020"><claim-text>A method as claimed in claim 19, wherein the dropping of the embryos by gravity from the classification conveyor belt is assisted by a jet.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0021" num="0021"><claim-text>A method as claimed in any of claims 7 to 20, wherein the sorted and singulated plant embryos are classified according to the first classification method while on the porous conveyor belt, and the plant embryos that have passed the first classification method are transferred from the porous conveyor belt onto an index tray in a predefined array.<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0022" num="0022"><claim-text>A method as claimed in claim 21, wherein the second classification method is carried out on the plant embryos that are placed on the index tray.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0023" num="0023"><claim-text>A system for automatically harvesting and screening plant embryos in multiple stages, comprising:
<claim-text>means (22, 24, 28, 34; 21, 22, 25, 30; 21, 22, 27, 34) for automatically sorting and singulating plant embryos;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a camera (38) for imaging each of the sorted and singulated embryos, wherein:
<claim-text>the computer (40) automatically classifies the sorted and singulated plant embryos using a first classification method; <b>characterised in that</b>:
<claim-text>the computer (40) automatically classifies only the plant embryos that have passed the first classification method using a second classification method based on the putative germination vigour of the embryos which identifies those embryos having a lower probability of germinating;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second classification method comprises one or more of: multi-view colour imaging analysis using a classification model; an apical dome analysis; and a spectroscopic analysis; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an air/liquid jet (42) controlled by the computer (40) ejects to a waste receptacle (44) those embryos rejected either by the first classification method of by the second classification method.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56987539" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Procédé de récolte et de criblage de manière automatique d'embryons végétaux en plusieurs étapes, comprenant le fait :
<claim-text>de trier et séparer de manière automatique des embryons végétaux ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>d'utiliser un appareil photographique afin de capturer une image de chacun des embryons triés et séparés ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>de transmettre l'image de chaque embryon à un ordinateur afin d'être analysée par une analyse d'image d'appareil photographique en deux étapes et d'être classée ; dans lequel :
<claim-text>l'ordinateur analyse les images et classe de manière automatique les embryons végétaux triés et séparés en utilisant un premier procédé de classification basé sur la forme et la taille des embryons afin d'identifier les embryons qui ne satisfont pas à des critères basiques de taille et de forme ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>caractérisé en ce que</b> : l'ordinateur analyse seulement les images des embryons végétaux qui ont été retenus à l'issue du premier procédé de classification en utilisant un deuxième procédé de classification basé sur la vigueur de germination présumée des embryons qui identifie les embryons présentant une faible probabilité de germination ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>les embryons rejetés par la première ou la deuxième étape de classification sont retirés afin de laisser des embryons souhaitables restants ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>le deuxième procédé de classification comprend une ou plusieurs analyse(s) parmi : une analyse d'imagerie en couleur multi-vues utilisant un modèle de classification ; une analyse de dôme apical ; et une analyse spectroscopique.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Procédé tel que revendiqué dans la revendication 1, dans lequel l'étape de tri et de séparation automatiques comprend le retrait de manière automatique des embryons végétaux à partir d'un milieu de développement.<!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Procédé tel que revendiqué dans la revendication 2, dans lequel le retrait automatique d'embryons végétaux comprend un lavage des embryons végétaux à partir du milieu de développement à l'aide d'un liquide aqueux.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Procédé tel que revendiqué dans l'une des revendications 1 à 3, dans lequel l'étape de tri et de séparation d'embryons comprend l'utilisation d'un cytomètre en flux.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Procédé tel que revendiqué dans l'une des revendications 1 à 3, dans lequel l'étape de tri et de séparation d'embryons comprend le fait de placer les embryons sur un matériau poreux permettant un tamisage.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Procédé tel que revendiqué dans la revendication 5, dans lequel les embryons placés sur le matériau poreux sont aspergés avec un liquide aqueux afin de retirer tout tissu de suspenseur ou toute masse de suspenseur embryonnaire (ESM) résiduelle à partir des embryons.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Procédé tel que revendiqué dans la revendication 5 ou la revendication 6, dans lequel le matériau poreux comprend une bande transporteuse poreuse.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Procédé tel que revendiqué dans la revendication 7, dans lequel les embryons sont placés dans un réservoir qui distribue les embryons sur la bande transporteuse poreuse, le réservoir étant configuré pour distribuer les embryons sur la bande de manière régulée.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Procédé tel que revendiqué dans la revendication 8, dans lequel le réservoir comprend un conduit.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Procédé tel que revendiqué dans l'une des revendications 7 à 9, dans lequel les embryons végétaux triés et séparés après tamisage sont placés sur une bande transporteuse de classification, le long de laquelle les premier et deuxième procédés de classification automatique sont réalisés.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Procédé tel que revendiqué dans la revendication 10, dans lequel les embryons végétaux triés et séparés sont<!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --> transférés à partir de la bande transporteuse poreuse vers la bande transporteuse de classification par gravité.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Procédé tel que revendiqué dans la revendication 10 ou la revendication 11, dans lequel la bande transporteuse de classification s'étend globalement de manière perpendiculaire à la bande transporteuse poreuse.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Procédé tel que revendiqué dans l'une des revendications 10 à 12, dans lequel les embryons végétaux triés et séparés sont placés sur la bande transporteuse de classification en une file unique le long de la longueur de la bande transporteuse de classification.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Procédé tel que revendiqué dans la revendication 13, dans lequel les embryons végétaux sont placés dans une file unique espacés les uns des autres.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Procédé tel que revendiqué dans l'une des revendications 10 à 14, dans lequel en outre l'étape consistant à retirer de manière automatique les embryons qui ont été classés comme étant non souhaitables par le premier ou le deuxième procédé de classification automatique comprend une éjection desdits embryons à partir de la bande transporteuse de classification.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0016" num="0016"><claim-text>Procédé tel que revendiqué dans la revendication 15, dans lequel le retrait automatique d'embryons non souhaitables est réalisé par un jet.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0017" num="0017"><claim-text>Procédé tel que revendiqué dans l'une des revendications 10 à 16, comprenant en outre l'étape consistant à retirer de manière automatique de la bande transporteuse de classification les embryons qui ont été classés comme étant souhaitables par le premier et le deuxième procédés de classification automatique.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0018" num="0018"><claim-text>Procédé tel que revendiqué dans la revendication 17, dans lequel l'étape consistant à retirer de manière automatique les embryons souhaitables comprend un transfert de ces embryons souhaitables sur une surface de réception en un agencement prédéfini.<!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0019" num="0019"><claim-text>Procédé tel que revendiqué dans la revendication 18, dans lequel la surface de réception comprend un plateau monté sur une plate-forme motorisée configurée pour ajuster la position du plateau par rapport à la bande transporteuse de classification de manière à recevoir les embryons tombant par gravité à partir de la bande transporteuse de classification en un agencement prédéfini.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0020" num="0020"><claim-text>Procédé tel que revendiqué dans la revendication 19, dans lequel la chute des embryons par gravité à partir de la bande transporteuse de classification est assistée par un jet.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0021" num="0021"><claim-text>Procédé tel que revendiqué dans l'une des revendications 7 à 20, dans lequel les embryons végétaux triés et séparés sont classés selon le premier procédé de classification pendant qu'ils sont sur la bande transporteuse poreuse, et les embryons végétaux qui ont été retenus à l'issue du premier procédé de classification sont transférés à partir de la bande transporteuse poreuse sur un plateau d'indexation en un agencement prédéfini.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0022" num="0022"><claim-text>Procédé tel que revendiqué dans la revendication 21, dans lequel le deuxième procédé de classification est réalisé sur les embryons végétaux qui sont placés sur le plateau d'indexation.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0023" num="0023"><claim-text>Système destiné à récolter et à cribler de manière automatique des embryons végétaux en plusieurs étapes, comprenant :
<claim-text>des moyens (22, 24, 28, 34, 21, 22, 25, 30 ; 21, 22, 27, 34) destinés à trier et à séparer de manière automatique des embryons végétaux ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un appareil photographique (38) pour capturer une image de chacun des embryons triés et séparés, dans lequel :
<claim-text>l'ordinateur (40) classe de manière automatique les embryons végétaux triés et séparés en utilisant un premier procédé de classification ; <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> :
<claim-text>l'ordinateur (40) classe de manière automatique seulement les embryons végétaux qui ont été retenus à<!-- EPO <DP n="36"> --> l'issue du premier procédé de classification en utilisant un deuxième procédé de classification basé sur la vigueur de germination présumée des embryons qui identifie les embryons présentant une faible probabilité de germination ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>le deuxième procédé de classification comprend une ou plusieurs analyse(s) parmi : une analyse d'imagerie en couleur multi-vues utilisant un modèle de classification ; une analyse de dôme apical ; et une analyse spectroscopique ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un jet d'air/de liquide (42) commandé par l'ordinateur (40) éjecte vers un réceptacle à déchets (44) les embryons rejetés soit par le premier procédé de classification ou par le deuxième procédé de classification.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16672777" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="37"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1A"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="158" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="38"> --><figure id="f0002" num="1B"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="153" he="232" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="39"> --><figure id="f0003" num="2"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="92" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="40"> --><figure id="f0004" num="3A,3B"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="161" he="221" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
