<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2256338-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2256338" kind="B1" date="20140101" family-id="41099187" file-reference-id="317924" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146553297" ucid="EP-2256338-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2256338</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-10168320-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154827220" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>10168320</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20081103</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP191077335" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>10168320.9</doc-number><date>20081103</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140453490" ucid="EP-08019186-A" linkage-type="3" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>08019186</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20081103</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140450760" ucid="EP-10168320-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>10168320</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20081103</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130725</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1928768427" load-source="docdb">F03D  13/20        20160101AFI20160601BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1608520699" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">E02D  27/425       20130101 LI20180808BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1944066510" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F03D  13/22        20160502 FI20160502BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1996945258" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y02P  70/523       20151101 LA20151126BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2102647505" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 403/459       20130101 LA20150123BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988099903" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F05B2240/90        20130101 LA20130917BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988115862" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y02E  10/728       20130101 LA20130917BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132192375" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Fundament, insbesondere für eine Windturbine, und Windturbine</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132192376" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Foundation particularly for a wind turbine and wind turbine</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132192377" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Fondation particulièrement pour une éolienne et éolienne</invention-title></technical-data><related-documents><relation type="division"><child-doc ucid="EP-10168320-A"><document-id load-source="patent-office" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>10168320</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20081103</date></document-id></child-doc><parent-doc ucid="EP-08019186.9"><document-id load-source="patent-office" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>08019186.9</doc-number><date>20081103</date></document-id><parent-grant-document ucid="EP-2182201-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2182201</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20160113</date></document-id></parent-grant-document></parent-doc></relation></related-documents><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918148485" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>SIEMENS AG</last-name><address><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918148307" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>SIEMENS AKTIENGESELLSCHAFT</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918164860" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>FRANK ANDRE</last-name><address><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918165748" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>FRANK, ANDRE</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918996698" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Frank, André</last-name><address><street>Rückertstr. 31</street><city>28199 Bremen</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918148888" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>ARMBRECHT ACHIM</last-name><address><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918163203" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>ARMBRECHT, ACHIM</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918996697" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>ARMBRECHT, ACHIM</last-name><address><street>Diedrich-Dannemann-Str. 63c</street><city>26203 Wardenburg</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918996699" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Siemens Aktiengesellschaft</last-name><iid>101362070</iid><address><street>Wittelsbacherplatz 2</street><city>80333 München</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548973776" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS548828020" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS548982343" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS548882693" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS548969638" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS548973777" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS548828021" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548969639" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS548969640" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS548976474" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS548982344" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS548982345" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548828022" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548969641" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS548828023" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS548973778" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS548882694" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS548969642" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS548982346" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS548969643" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS548969020" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS548973779" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS548969021" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS548969026" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS548858691" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS548976475" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS548982347" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS548858692" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS548882695" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS548976476" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS548858693" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS548882696" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS548982348" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS548969644" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63957173" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The invention relates to a foundation particularly a foundation of a wind turbine and to a wind turbine.</p><heading id="h0002">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">Wind turbines are installations with a very tall tower which typically carries a rotor, housing and an electric generator of the wind turbine on its top. Since the used towers are very large in height in order to enable the use of a rotor with a large radius or length of the rotor blades the wind turbines are very heavy. Additionally the wind turbines are of course typically installed in topographic areas in which a strong wind is quite common and therefore the construction of the wind turbines have to be that strong to withstand the forces acting on such turbines due to the strong wind with typically high wind speed.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">Therefore strong foundations are necessary requirements of the construction of such wind turbines.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">Such foundations are well known in the art. The article <nplcit id="ncit0001" npl-type="s"><text>BONUS Wind Turbines, Foundations, Foundation, Bonus Wind turbines, rev. 3 pages 1 to 4, 21.03.02 </text></nplcit>discloses a gravity foundation with a concrete base plate with a central concrete plinth. Furthermore it discloses piled foundations with pre-fabricated piles which will be hammered to the necessary depth into the ground and foundations with piles which will be cast in situ.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">The prior art document <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="EP1058787B1"><text>EP 1058787 B1</text></patcit> discloses a foundation which is assembled of essentially uniformly formed base piece segments which are made of steel and which are arranged such<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> that the assembled piece segments create a circular steel foundation with a hole at the center of the circle.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">On-shore foundations are usually created at the location of the wind turbine installation using standard concrete casting technology to cast the foundation in situ. The above mentioned document <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="EP1058787B1"><text>EP 1058787 B1</text></patcit> discloses an off-shore foundation which is not used on-shore.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">The above mentioned foundations show the disadvantage that the concrete foundations are difficult to produce at the location of the wind turbine installation and that the steel foundation is not well suited for heavy on-shore wind turbine installations.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008"><patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="WO2004101898A2"><text>WO 2004/101898 A2</text></patcit> describes a foundation for a wind energy plant. The foundation comprises a central base element in form of a hollow cylinder and pre-fabricated supporting and lateral stabilizing elements connected to the base element.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009"><patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="WO2008036934A2"><text>WO 2008/036934 A2</text></patcit> describes a prefabricated modular foundation system that comprises a mud slab and stiffener ribs. Couplers of the stiffener ribs can be coupled to a pedestal cage.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010"><patcit id="pcit0005" dnum="WO2005012651A1"><text>WO 2005/012651 A1</text></patcit> describes a reinforced concrete foundation for a wind turbine tower. The foundation comprises a concrete slab and a plurality of tensioned tendons and ground anchors. The foundation also includes a mounting element in the form of a cylinder which is partly embedded in the concrete slab. The mounting element is shaped complementary and adapted to the welded or otherwise connected to a corresponding bottom portion of the wind turbine tower.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011"><patcit id="pcit0006" dnum="EP1074663A1"><text>EP 1 074 663 A1</text></patcit> describes a foundation for supporting a building structure, in particular for the foundation of tower structure, a wind turbine, or the like. The foundation comprises a central portion and three or more stabilizing<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> members that are radially arranged about said central supporting section.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012"><patcit id="pcit0007" dnum="WO9943956A1"><text>WO 99/43956 A1</text></patcit> describes a method of installation of wind turbines at sea and a corresponding foundation. The foundation comprises a base piece that consists of a number of base piece segments which each makes up a segment of circle formed or essentially circle formed ground plate for the base piece.</p><heading id="h0003">OBJECT AND SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading><p id="p0013" num="0013">It is a first object of the invention to create a foundation particularly for a wind turbine which can be produced more easily and which saves time at the location of the construction site of the wind turbine and which can be produced with higher equality.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">It is a second object of the invention to provide a wind turbine wit an advantageous foundation.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">The first object of the invention will be solved by a foundation according to the features of claim 1, the second object by a wind turbine as claimed in claim 6. The depending claims contain further developments of the invention.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">An inventive foundation particularly a foundation of a wind turbine comprises a central foundation member and a plurality of foundation segments which are segments of a circular, ring shaped or polygonal foundation element and which are connected to the central foundation member by means of one or more locking elements. The foundation may, in particular, be realised as a shallow foundation.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p><p id="p0017" num="0017">The foundation segments and the foundation member are joined together by means of concrete, grout or mortar. This allows a better connection between the segments and the member and reduces relative movement of the segments and the member respectively. Since the amount of used concrete, grout or mortar is quite low compared to the material which has to be used for an in situ cast process this process is much faster in production than the in situ process of casting the whole foundation. Furthermore, the foundation member is or comprises a bottom plate. Both the foundation segments and the bottom plate comprise rebars where the rebars of the foundation segments and the bottom plate overlap when the foundation segments and the bottom plate are in place at the location of the foundation. The foundation segments with the rebars and the bottom plate with the rebars are joined together by means of concrete, grout or mortar.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">It is of advantage that the foundation segments and the bottom plate are joined together by means of concrete. After hardening the joining concrete can form the foundation member together with the bottom plate. In other words, the foundation member may be not fully pre-fabricated but partly cast at the construction site while the segments are pre-manufactured.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">In the inventive foundation the foundation segments may comprise anchoring elements for anchoring a wind turbine tower. Alternatively, the foundation segments may comprise support elements for such anchoring elements instead anchoring elements itself.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">An inventive wind turbine comprises an inventive foundation and a tower anchored at the foundation.</p><heading id="h0004">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading><!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --><p id="p0021" num="0021">The above and other features and advantages of the invention will be apparent from the following description of an exemplary embodiment of the invention with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which:
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> shows a perspective view of an embodiment of the inventive foundation;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2</figref> shows a schematic sectional view of the embodiment of the inventive foundation;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 3</figref> shows an arrangement of foundations or foundation segments;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 4</figref> shows a further arrangement of foundations or foundation segments;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 5</figref> shows a still further arrangement of foundations or foundation segments;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 6</figref> shows a still further arrangement of foundations or foundation segments;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 7</figref> shows a tilting of foundations or foundation segments; and</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 8</figref> shows a tilting of foundations or foundation segments.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0005">DESCRIPTION OF EMBODIMENTS</heading><p id="p0022" num="0022"><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> show a foundation 1 according to an embodiment of the invention especially for wind turbines in a perspective view.. The foundation 1 contains a plurality of foundation segments 2, which are arranged to build a circular or polygonal foundation. Each segment 2 comprises a shoulder 3 which protrudes towards the center of the foundation, i.e. towards the wind turbine, and at which fastening means 4 are<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> provided to be used to fasten an element 5 of the wind turbine tower to the foundation 1.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">The fastening means 4 are preferably bolts or anchors, especially stud bolts, to be able to fasten an element 5 of a tower of a wind turbine to the foundation 1. Since the bolts or stud bolts are integrally connected to the segments 2 of the foundation they allow the fastening of the circular element 5 of the tower to the circular or polygonal shaped foundation by means of nuts and screws. However, instead of providing the fastening means 4 itself at the shoulder 3 it is also possible to only provide supports for which bay be part of the tower element 5 of individual elements which are neither part of the foundation segments 2 nor of the tower element 5.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">The foundation 1 is an assembly of a plurality of segments and a central foundation member which are connected and fastened to build a single piece of foundation at the construction site. The creation and manufacturing of the segments at a different production site than at the construction site of the wind turbine allows the manufacturing at a less whether dependent site which may cause a higher concrete quality, a better control of the manufacturing process, a better quality control of the product and the process and a shorter construction time at the construction site, which is appreciated since this may lead to reduced costs.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">According to the embodiment of the invention the central foundation member 7 can be cast at the construction site while the segments 2 are pre-manufactured and pre-assembled before filling out the central space within the hole of the segments 2 arrangement. Such an embodiment is schematically shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2</figref>. In the embodiment, the central foundation member 7 comprises a pre-manufactured bottom plate 71 around which the foundation segments 2 will be arranged at the construction side. The bottom plate 71 centers the<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> segments 2 at their bottom ends. A tool 72, like e.g. a steel plate, may be used to center the segments 2 at their top ends.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">Both the bottom plate 71 and the foundation segments 2 are equipped with rebars 73, 74. The rebars 74 of the segments 2 are located at their radial inner ends and project over the rebars 73 of the bottom plate 71 when the foundation segments 2 are in place. A top layer of rebars 75 may be arranged on top of the rebars 74 of the foundation segments 2 after removing the tool 72 and before filling the space between the segments 2 with concrete. The rebars 73, 74, 75 provide for good monolithic structure of the foundation 1 after the concrete is hardened. In other words, the rebars 73, 74, 75 and the hardened concrete serve as locking members to prevent tilting of the foundation segments 2 relative to the central foundation member.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027"><figref idrefs="f0002">Figures 3 to 6</figref> show different solutions to arrange a plurality of foundations of a tower of a wind turbine. <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 3</figref> shows an arrangement of four rectangular foundations 50 which are arranged like a cross. <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 4</figref> shows an arrangement of eight rectangular foundations 51 which are arranged like two crosses which are arranged with a respective angle of 45°. Such an arrangement comes already close to a circle. <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 5</figref> shows an arrangement of twelve rectangular foundations 52 which are arranged like three crosses which are arranged with a respective angle of 30°. Such an arrangement is already almost like a circle. Last but not least <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 6</figref> shows an arrangement of twenty foundation segments 53 having the shape like a pieces of cake and which are arranged such that they create a circle or a ring as continuous shell.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028"><figref idrefs="f0002">Figures 7 and 8</figref> both show an effect of a tilting of foundations 60, 61 like two foundations of <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 6</figref>. In Fig. 10 both foundations 60 are tilted anti-parallel. This means that the tilting angle with respect to the normal axis has<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> the same size but an opposite algebraic sign. In Fig. 11 both foundations 61 are tilted in the same direction. This means that the tilting angle with respect to the normal axis has the same size and the same algebraic sign.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">This means that the foundations have to be fixed with respect to the other foundations or foundation segments. This is done according to invention by using a bottom plate, rebars and concrete which connects the bottom plate to segments and forms together with the bottom plate a central foundation member after the concrete is hardened.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56979008" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Fundament (1), insbesondere Fundament einer Windenergieanlage, umfassend ein zentrales Fundamentelement (7) und eine Vielzahl von vorgefertigten Fundamentsegmenten (2), welche Segmente eines kreisförmigen, ringförmigen oder polygonalen Fundamentelements sind und welche mit dem zentralen Fundamentelement (7) mittels eines oder mehrerer Verriegelungselemente verbunden sind, wobei die Fundamentsegmente (2) und das Fundamentelement (7) mittels Beton, Einpressmörtel oder Mörtel miteinander verbunden sind,<br/>
<b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b>
<claim-text>- das Fundamentelement (7) eine vorgefertigte Bodenplatte (71) ist oder umfasst;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- die Fundamentsegmente (2) und die Bodenplatte (71) Bewehrungsstäbe (73, 74) umfassen, wobei die Bewehrungsstäbe (74) der Fundamentsegmente (2) und die Bewehrungsstäbe (73) der Bodenplatte (71) einander überlappen, wenn die Fundamentsegmente (2) und die Bodenplatte (71) eingebaut sind;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- die Fundamentsegmente (2) und die Bodenplatte (71) mit den Bewehrungsstäben (73, 74) mittels Beton, Einpressmörtel oder Mörtel miteinander verbunden sind.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Fundament nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Bewehrungsstäbe (74) der Segmente (2) an deren radial inneren Enden angeordnet sind und über den Bewehrungsstäben (73) der Bodenplatte (71) vorstehen, wenn die Fundamentsegmente (2) eingebaut sind.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Fundament (1) nach Anspruch 1 oder Anspruch 2, wobei eine obere Schicht von Bewehrungsstäben (75) auf den Bewehrungsstäben (74) der Fundamentsegmente (2) angeordnet wird, bevor der Raum zwischen den Segmenten (2) mit Beton verfüllt wird.<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Fundament (1) nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei die Fundamentsegmente (2) Verankerungselemente (4) für einen Windenergieanlagenturm (5) umfassen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Fundament (1) nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei das Fundament (1) ein Flachfundament ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Windenergieanlage mit einem Fundament (1) nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 3 und einem Turm (5), der auf dem Fundament (1) verankert ist.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56979009" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A foundation (1), particularly a foundation of a wind turbine, comprising a central foundation member (7) and a plurality of pre-manufactured foundation segments (2) which are segments of a circular, ring shaped or polygonal foundation element and which are connected to the central foundation member (7) by means of one or more locking elements, wherein the foundation segments (2) and the foundation member (7) are joined together by means of concrete, grout or mortar,<br/>
<b>characterised in that</b>,
<claim-text>- the foundation member (7) is or comprises a pre-manufactured bottom plate (71);</claim-text>
<claim-text>- the foundation segments (2) and the bottom plate (71) comprise rebars (73, 74) where the rebars (74) of the foundation segments (2) and the rebars (73) of the bottom plate (71) overlap when the foundation segments (2) and the bottom plate (71) are in place;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- the foundation segments (2) and the bottom plate (71) with the rebars (73, 74) are joined together by means of concrete, grout or mortar.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The foundation as claimed in claim 1, wherein the rebars (74) of the segments (2) are located at their radial inner ends and project over the rebars (73) of the bottom plate (71) when the foundation segments (2) are in place.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The foundation (1) as claimed in claim 1 or claim 2, wherein a top layer of rebars (75) is arranged on top of the rebars (74) of the foundation segments (2) before filling the space between the segments (2) with concrete.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The foundation (1) as claimed in any of the preceding claims, wherein the foundation segments (2) comprises anchoring elements (4) for a wind turbine tower (5).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The foundation (1) as claimed in any of the preceding claims, wherein the foundation (1) is a shallow foundation.<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>A wind turbine with a foundation (1) as claimed in any of the claims 1 to 3 and a tower (5) anchored at the foundation (1).</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56979010" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Fondation (1), particulièrement une fondation d'une éolienne, comprenant un élément (7) de fondation central et une pluralité de segments (2) de fondation préfabriqués qui sont des segments d'un élément de fondation circulaire, annulaire ou polygonal et qui sont connectés à l'élément (7) de fondation central au moyen d'un ou plusieurs élément(s) de blocage, dans laquelle les segments (2) de fondation et l'élément (7) de fondation sont joints ensemble au moyen d'un béton, d'un coulis ou d'un mortier,<br/>
<b>caractérisée en ce que</b>,
<claim-text>- l'élément (7) de fondation est ou comprend une plaque de fond (71) préfabriquée ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- les segments (2) de fondation et la plaque de fond (71) comprennent des barres d'armature (73, 74) où les barres d'armature (74) des segments (2) de fondation et les barres d'armature (73) de la plaque de fond (71) se chevauchent lorsque les segments (2) de fondation et la plaque de fond (71) sont en place ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- les segments (2) de fondation et la plaque de fond (71) avec les barres d'armature (73, 74) sont joints ensemble au moyen d'un béton, d'un coulis ou d'un mortier.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Fondation selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle les barres d'armature (74) des segments (2) sont situées à leurs extrémités intérieures radiales et se projettent par-dessus les barres d'armature (73) de la plaque de fond (71) lorsque les segments (2) de fondation sont en place.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Fondation (1) selon la revendication 1 ou la revendication 2, dans laquelle une couche supérieure de barres d'armature (75) est agencée au-dessus des barres d'armature (74) des<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> segments (2) de fondation avant remplissage de l'espace entre les segments (2) avec un béton.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Fondation (1) selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans laquelle les segments (2) de fondation comprennent des éléments (4) d'ancrage pour une tour (5) d'éolienne.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Fondation (1) selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans laquelle la fondation (1) est une fondation peu profonde.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Éolienne avec une fondation (1) selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 3 et une tour (5) ancrée dans la fondation 1.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16668739" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1,2"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="165" he="198" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --><figure id="f0002" num="3,4,5,6,7,8"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="145" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
