<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2680988-A1" country="EP" doc-number="2680988" kind="A1" date="20140108" family-id="45592856" file-reference-id="311174" date-produced="20180823" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146586780" ucid="EP-2680988-A1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2680988</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-12707087-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154848972" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12707087</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120301</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP209887905" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12707087.8</doc-number><date>20120301</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140552675" ucid="EP-11156936-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>11156936</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20110304</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140550559" ucid="EP-12707087-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12707087</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120301</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140550434" ucid="EP-2012053519-W" linkage-type="W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>2012053519</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20120301</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989316404" load-source="docdb">B21D  43/24        20060101AFI20120927BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989317070" load-source="docdb">B65G  59/10        20060101ALI20120927BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989319588" load-source="docdb">B21D  51/44        20060101ALI20120927BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989322683" load-source="docdb">B65H   3/08        20060101ALI20120927BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989323246" load-source="docdb">B65G  59/06        20060101ALI20120927BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989626765" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B65G  59/062       20130101 LI20131203BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989628368" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B21D  43/24        20130101 FI20131203BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989635496" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B65H   3/0883      20130101 LI20131203BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989640596" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B21D  51/446       20130101 LI20131203BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989645491" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B65H   3/54        20130101 LI20131203BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989652820" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B65H   3/085       20130101 LI20131203BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132364973" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">VORRICHTUNG UND VERFAHREN ZUM TRENNEN VON METALLSCHEIBEN AUS EINEM SCHEIBENSTAPEL</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132364974" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">APPARATUS AND METHOD FOR SEPARATING DISCS OF METAL FROM A STACK OF DISCS</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132364975" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">APPAREIL ET PROCÉDÉ DE SÉPARATION DE DISQUES DE MÉTAL D'UNE PILE DE DISQUES</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919540144" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>CROWN PACKAGING TECHNOLOGY INC</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919525954" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>CROWN PACKAGING TECHNOLOGY, INC.</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919015860" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Crown Packaging Technology, Inc.</last-name><iid>101142096</iid><address><street>11535 S. Central Avenue</street><city>Alsip, IL 60803-2599</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919539886" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>WOULDS WILLIAM</last-name><address><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919528685" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>WOULDS, WILLIAM</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919006313" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>WOULDS, WILLIAM</last-name><address><street>Dockfield Road</street><city>Shipley West Yorkshire BD17 7AY</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919011220" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Ratliff, Ismay Hilary</last-name><iid>100968846</iid><address><street>Crown Packaging UK PLC Group Intellectual Property Downsview Road</street><city>Wantage Oxfordshire OX12 9BP</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="EP-2012053519-W"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2012053519</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20120301</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2012119915-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2012119915</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20120913</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549776097" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS549764665" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549776098" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549846424" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549844200" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549916506" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549764666" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549776099" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549916507" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549916508" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549845350" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549846425" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549846430" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549776100" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549916509" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549776109" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549764667" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549844201" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549916510" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549846431" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549916511" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549859300" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549765048" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549859301" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549859306" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549765053" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS549765054" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549776110" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549846432" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549859307" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549844254" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549776111" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549844255" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS549859308" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549845351" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549846433" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549859309" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS549916512" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA100073049" ref-ucid="WO-2012119915-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p num="0000">A device (17) for separating discs (10) of metal from a stack of discs held in an infeed (16, 23) to a machine such as a cupping press or other machinery used in can manufacture. In one embodiment a separator ring (17) includes four segments (20) on its inner surface. The segments have a central aperture through which the lowermost disc of the stack is extracted by suction (12), the disc forming a four-leaf clover shape as it is pulled between the four segments.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA100341089" ref-ucid="WO-2012119915-A1" lang="EN" source="national office" load-source="docdb"><p>A device (17) for separating discs (10) of metal from a stack of discs held in an infeed (16, 23) to a machine such as a cupping press or other machinery used in can manufacture. In one embodiment a separator ring (17) includes four segments (20) on its inner surface. The segments have a central aperture through which the lowermost disc of the stack is extracted by suction (12), the disc forming a four-leaf clover shape as it is pulled between the four segments.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA100073050" ref-ucid="WO-2012119915-A1" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><p num="0000">La présente invention se rapporte à un dispositif (17) destiné à séparer des disques (10) de métal depuis une pile de disques maintenus dans un chargeur (16, 23) vers une machine telle qu'une presse d'emboutissage ou autres machines utilisées pour la fabrication de boîtes. Selon un mode de réalisation, une bague de séparation (17) comprend quatre segments (20) sur sa surface intérieure. Les segments comportent une ouverture centrale par laquelle le disque le plus bas de la pile est extrait par aspiration (12), le disque prenant une forme de trèfle à quatre feuilles quand il est tiré entre les quatre segments.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA100341090" ref-ucid="WO-2012119915-A1" lang="FR" source="national office" load-source="docdb"><p>La présente invention se rapporte à un dispositif (17) destiné à séparer des disques (10) de métal depuis une pile de disques maintenus dans un chargeur (16, 23) vers une machine telle qu'une presse d'emboutissage ou autres machines utilisées pour la fabrication de boîtes. Selon un mode de réalisation, une bague de séparation (17) comprend quatre segments (20) sur sa surface intérieure. Les segments comportent une ouverture centrale par laquelle le disque le plus bas de la pile est extrait par aspiration (12), le disque prenant une forme de trèfle à quatre feuilles quand il est tiré entre les quatre segments.</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES51372120" ref-ucid="WO-2012119915-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><invention-title lang="EN">[Title established by the ISA under Rule 37.2] APPARATUS AND METHOD FOR SEPARATING DISCS OF METAL FROM A STACK OF DISCS</invention-title><heading id="h0001"><b>Technical Field</b></heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">This invention relates to an assembly and method for separating metal discs for use in the can making industry, for example for feeding individual discs to a machine which forms a disc into a cup shape, known as a “cupper” or cupping press or to a bodymaker for drawing hollow articles such as metal containers or cans. Alternatively the cupping press may be a press for forming any shallow metal cap or closure. </p><heading id="h0002"><b>Background Art</b></heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">In the canmaking industry, metal such as steel or aluminium is supplied from the manufacturer as a coil, typically of lubricated metal. The metal requirements are set by the manufacturer, with standard parameters such as metal type, surface roughness and friction coefficient at boundary lubrication being standard in the trade. The coil manufacturer will, in general, supply pre-lubricated coil with a set amount of lube on the metal. The coil then passes through a wet lubricator, which is almost as wide as the cupping press, before entering the press itself.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">For the purpose of manufacture, a cupper is fed with a sheet of steel or aluminium from a large roll or coil. The cupper then cuts discs (up to 14 at a time) out of the sheet metal and forms each of the discs into a cup in one operation.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004"><patcit dnum="EP10162130" id="pcit0001" num="0001"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>10162130</doc-number><name>CROWN PACKAGING TECHNOLOGY, INC</name><date>20100506</date></document-id></patcit>(unpublished) refers to a type of existing apparatus for the formation of a “two piece” container (i.e. a one piece can body with integral side wall and base, and a separate end component) in which a cupping press is first fed with a coil of metal and then punches discs out of the metal to be made into cups. The flat circular blanks or discs of metal are each drawn through one or more drawing dies in the cupping press to form the shallow cups. The cups are subsequently transferred to a bodymaker for conversion into the finished can body. </p><p id="p0005" num="0005">As noted in <patcit dnum="EP10162130" id="pcit0002" num="0002"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>10162130</doc-number></document-id></patcit>, the cupping press is a large and extremely expensive machine (currently around £1.5 million). The tooling for it is also very expensive. The material left from the coil once the discs have been cut from it is scrap. The scrap then has to be collected via a vacuum chute system and transferred to the bailer, which is again an expensive item to run. All the coil handling and lubricating equipment also cost money and takes up a large footprint (floor space). Finally, there is a massive amount of cup conveying equipment, which transfers the cups from the cupper to the bodymaker. If the cupper or any of the related equipment stops then the whole line shuts down and total production is lost.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">In the invention of unpublished patent application <patcit dnum="EP10162130" id="pcit0003" num="0003"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>10162130</doc-number></document-id></patcit>discs are stacked ready for direct supply into a can bodymaker. A vacuum feed is also referred to in that application for separating the discs but no further details of this separator device are given. </p><p id="p0007" num="0007">It is known from <patcit dnum="FR9202212" id="pcit0004" num="0004"><document-id><country>FR</country><doc-number>9202212</doc-number><kind>B</kind><name>CMB PACKAGING SA</name></document-id></patcit>to feed the top sheet from a stack of metal sheets by applying suction cups to the rear end of the sheet. The sheet is then displaced forwards over a front guide into engagement with a traction mechanism. The device also includes a means of raising and lowering the gripped sheet and a means of blowing air to create an air cushion under each sheet. This is noted as being particularly useful in the case of lubricated metal sheets, which tend to adhere to adjacent sheets and are not always raised sufficiently to strip one sheet from another sheet below. This patent is another example of the extensive equipment requirements for handling a stack of large sheets of metal.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">It is a first object of this invention to provide a separator and method of separating metal discs bought pre-cut from out of the lubricated coil. As in  <patcit dnum="EP10162130" id="pcit0005" num="0005"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>10162130</doc-number></document-id></patcit>the purchase of pre-cut discs avoids the expense of buying and maintaining a large cupper of the sort, which cuts the discs as well as forming cups. The purchase of pre-cut discs also reduces or avoids many of the associated costs such as all the coil handling equipment (including the wet lubricator) and scrap collection equipment. </p><p id="p0009" num="0009">In known cupping presses, sheet metal is supplied from the wet lubricator with a wet lube applied for the cupping process. This metal sheet can be handled immediately as the wet lube does not need any drying time before cupping. Nonetheless, it is known for discs in the cupping press to have adhered to each other, which leads to multiple feeds of the discs and, as a result, subsequent risk of shut down etc. as described above. It is the main object of this invention to provide a solution both to the separation of each individual disc and the extraction of that disc from a stack of lubricated discs.</p><heading id="h0003"><b>Summary of invention</b></heading><p id="p0010" num="0010">According to the present invention there is provided an assembly for separating discs of metal, the assembly comprising:<br/>a separator ring having an interior surface profile adapted to support a stack of discs and to separate a single disc from the bottom of the stack, and <br/>an extractor for extracting the single disc from the separator ring, <br/>in which the interior surface profile of the separator ring includes one or more inwardly protruding features, which define an opening which is smaller than the disc diameter, and<br/>the extractor includes a “vacuum” pad such that, in use, when a vacuum is applied to the pad, the extractor pulls the disc through the opening, breaking any attraction between the disc and the adjacent one in the stack.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">The mechanical separation of discs by the separator ring is much more simple and effective than the sheet separator of the prior art. Preferably, the inwardly protruding features comprise two or more equi-spaced segments which may be positioned in the same plane perpendicular to the longitudinal axis of the separator ring. Usually there are four equi-spaced segments, which would generally be positioned at the same distance from the exit edge of the separator ring, typically adjacent that edge. </p><p id="p0012" num="0012">Alternatively, the inwardly protruding feature or features comprise(s) a single segment with a helical profile or multiple segments arranged as a spaced screw thread. </p><p id="p0013" num="0013">The extractor may comprise one or more vacuum pads, which pull the bottom disc down and distort the material to pull the disc over the segments. In the case of four segments, the disc may distort into a four-leaf clover shape over the segments.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">The extractor may be rotatable to assist release of the disc from the segments. In addition, the separator ring may have a profiled inner surface, which guides the end disc of the stack onto the segments. This is optional when the segments are symmetrically positioned at the same “height” but is preferred when there is a helical profile or threads.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">The separator ring is smaller than the disc in order that the ring supports the stack. The profile of the separator and segments provides a hole, which is as close to the disc diameter as possible without risk of the stack dropping through the ring. In a separator for feeding separate discs to a cupper or bodymaker, the output diameter of the separator is generally about 3 mm smaller than the disc. The separator ring size is made to suit the disc size, regardless of whether the disc is fed into a bodymaker or cupper. </p><p id="p0016" num="0016">The extractor of the assembly preferably includes a guide block with a central chamber and a port for supplying vacuum to the chamber; an extractor shaft having a slot, and which is reciprocable through the chamber; and in which the slot in the extractor shaft and the port in the guide black form a switch such that, in use, when the slot in the shaft passes across the port, vacuum is turned on and off.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">As an alternative, the apparatus may include an electrically operated solenoid, which supplies the vacuum. This has the advantage of an adjustable on/off window but requires more electrical equipment. </p><p id="p0018" num="0018">The extractor shaft may further include a plate fixed to the shaft, in which the plate retains a vacuum spindle with a spring at one end, a central bore for supply of vacuum, and the vacuum pad at the other, and in which, in use, the plate acts as a bush and allows the spindle to move against the spring to extract the disc.  In this assembly, there may also be rods which are mounted on the plate and support stops mounted on springs, the stops being set at a stop position which is fixed relative to the extractor shaft and is reciprocable with the extractor shaft to contact the bottom of the stack.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">The vacuum spindle and pad may have a position at the top of the up stroke, which is higher than the stop position, and in which the vacuum pad contacts and grips the bottom disc. </p><p id="p0020" num="0020">According to another aspect of the present invention, there is provided a method of extracting a single disc from the bottom of a stack of discs, the method comprising: reciprocating an extractor shaft to contact the stack of discs; retaining and sliding a spindle within the extractor shaft; mounting a vacuum pad at the upper end of the spindle; switching on a vacuum supply through the vacuum spindle and into the vacuum pad on the up stroke, and thereby gripping the bottom disc of the stack; pulling down the gripped disc on the down stroke and breaking any attraction between the bottom disc and the adjacent disc; switching off the vacuum supply and releasing the disc.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">Preferably, in this method, the reciprocating step comprises lifting the extractor shaft up and down through a guide block and moving a plate fixed to the shaft and sprung stops on the plate to a stop position at the end of the up stroke when the stops contact the stack of discs; the retaining and sliding steps comprise retaining a vacuum spindle within both the plate and the extractor shaft, the spindle having a spring at its lower end; and allowing the spindle to slide up and down against the bias of the spring; the step of switching on a vacuum supply comprises switching on the vacuum supply to a chamber in the guide block when a slot in the extractor shaft passes a vacuum supply port thereby switching vacuum through the centre of the vacuum spindle and into the vacuum pad on the up stroke, and gripping the bottom disc of the stack; and the step of switching off the vacuum supply comprises switching off the vacuum supply when the slot in the extractor shaft passes the vacuum supply port on the down stroke.</p><heading id="h0004"><b>Brief description of drawings</b></heading><p id="p0022" num="0022">The invention will now be described with reference to the drawings, in which:<br/>Figure 1 is a schematic side section of an apparatus according to the invention, showing separator and extractor; <br/>Figure 2 is a plan view of the separator ring;<br/>Figure 3 is a side sectional view along X-X of figure 2; and<br/>Figure 4 is a general perspective view of a disc separator and disc feed.</p><heading id="h0005"><b>Description of embodiments</b></heading><p id="p0023" num="0023">Figure 1 shows the assembly in a disc release position. In figure 1, the discs 10 are stacked above a suction pad or vacuum cup 12, which is biased towards the discs by a spindle 6. Plate 4 is fixed to an extractor shaft 15 by a manufactured screw which locks the plate 4 in position, retains the vacuum spindle 6 and spring 14 and also includes a bush, which allows the spindle to slide up and down against the spring 14. </p><p id="p0024" num="0024">There are two extractor shafts 15 (only one shown in figure 1), which move up and down and are positioned on the edge of the disc. The extractor shaft 15 is shown at the bottom of its stroke, for releasing a disc 10. </p><p id="p0025" num="0025">By positioning the extractor shafts close to the edge of the disc, it is easier to separate the bottom disc from the rest of the disc. The shafts are guided by a pair of bushes 19 in a guide block 18, with a chamber between the bushes 19. The shafts protrude below this block to connect to a link and lever mechanism. </p><p id="p0026" num="0026">A port 25 in the guide block 18 connects a vacuum supply to the chamber between the bushes 19. A slot 26 in the shaft passes across this port as the extractor shafts 15 move up and down turning the vacuum on and off to release a disc 10 at the bottom of the stroke. </p><p id="p0027" num="0027">A hole through the centre of the vacuum spindle 6 allows the vacuum into the suction cup 12, which is therefore also switched on and off as the shafts move up and down. The two stops 5 with springs 2, 3 are held in place by rods 7, which are threaded at the bottom. The nuts 8 on the rod on the lower side of plate 4 allow the rods 7 to be adjusted in height. The stops 5 are set higher than the vacuum cup 12 so that on the up stroke they stop when they hit the bottom of the stack 10 whilst the vacuum spindle and cup continue up to grip the bottom disc and separate it from the stack on the down stroke. </p><p id="p0028" num="0028">On the down stroke, the vacuum cup 12 pulls the disc down between the two stops forming a small bow in the disc which breaks the vacuum between the bottom disc and the one above it. An air blow nozzle 9 on both sides of the stack blows air into this bow to help accelerate the separation. The vacuum on/off position of the disc is shown dotted as 10’ in figure 1. The assembly continues down and the vacuum is switched off, as the slot 26 passes below the port 25, releasing the disc onto the flighted belt 30 at the bottom of the stroke. </p><p id="p0029" num="0029">Also as shown in figure 1, discs 10 are stacked between guide rods 23, which form a hopper. After the discs have been cut, and because they are cut from a coil, they form a natural bow of up to 3 mm. The discs can be loaded either way up into the hopper. As all the discs have a bow, the bottom discs’ surface position can vary up to 6 mm. As a result, the extractor assembly has all active components mounted on springs.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">The assembly is positioned to extract a disc loaded with the bow upwards. If the stack changes to bow downwards (up to 6 mm lower) the springs will compensate, allowing the stops and vacuum spindle to be pushed further down, yet retaining their set position on the bottom disc as the extractor moves down. The position of spring 14 at the base of vacuum spindle 6 is not critical but it must be flexible. </p><p id="p0031" num="0031">A separator ring is shown generally at 17 and a pair of sensors detects double discs, i.e. un-separated, discs when extracted from the separator ring centre. There are four slots cut in the bottom of the separator ring to form four segments 20. </p><p id="p0032" num="0032">When the discs are stacked they are not all exactly in line, which makes the total stack slightly wider than a single disc. The guide rods have to accommodate this. The taper on the top section of the separator ring 17 also guides the discs onto the segments.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">If the segments are flat on the top section, the friction caused by the weight of the stack is too great for the vacuum to pull the discs across it. To overcome this friction, the segments have a top section with a radius. The bottom disc is then only held at the very edge against this radius. When the vacuum cup pulls this down, the disc slides around the radius and at no point is trapped against a flat surface.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">Figures 2 and 3 give more detail of one example of the separator “ring” 17. Four features or “segments” 20 extend radially inwardly by 2mm in this example, which shows a ring internal diameter of 141mm. This ring serves to separate discs, which are about 3mm larger than the output diameter of the separator. Large diameter features 23 show the position of guide rods 23 which together form a hopper 16 (see figure 4). </p><p id="p0035" num="0035">When the suction pad 12 pulls the centre of the bottom disc down, the disc forms a bow in the material with the material forming a four-leaf clover shape over the segments and then out through the smaller diameter bottom hole. This deformation helps to break the vacuum between the bottom disc and the next one, leaving the next disc sat on the four segments. Of course more than one suction pad could be used in which case the disc’s shape would deform in a different manner according to the number and positions of the suction pads.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">A sectional view X-X of the ring of figure 2 is shown in figure 3. Guide rods 23 are located as shown by the large holes and segments 20 are fixed to the separator ring. The separator is smaller than the disc in order to support the stack. The largest aperture possible in the centre of the separator is selected for this so as to cause the minimum interference whilst preventing the stack from dropping straight through.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">Figure 4 is a general perspective view of a disc separator and extractor, showing a flighted belt 30 onto which individual discs are released. In the figure, a stack of discs would be supplied pre-lubricated from the coil manufacturer and fed to the hopper 16 or region between the guide rods 23. The lubrication on the discs is a very thin non-wet lube rather than the full amount of wet lube, which is applied by a pair of spray guns after the discs have been individually separated. Full wet lube would make the discs very difficult to separate at speed, even at test rig operating speeds of 500 discs/min. </p><p id="p0038" num="0038">The spray guns for application of wet lube sit inside the disc handling equipment with a small bulk tank (not shown) mounted close by. The spray guns apply layers to both sides of each disc after the discs have been individually separated and before each disc goes into the cupping press or other subsequent process. This lubrication, which is applied by the spray guns in the disc feeder, is a wet lube. The wet lube is only applied as required by the process and does not require any drying time.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">The general view of figure 4 shows one of a pair of belts 30 with spaced flights 32 which run laterally within the extractor and vacuum pad positions 12. The individual discs on the flighted belt could be fed directly to a cupper or closure press, for example, as desired. The disc separation and extractor of the invention avoids the double or multiple feeds, which occurred regularly in disc feeds known in the prior art.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">The invention has been described above by way of example only and changes may be made to the separator and, in particular to the equipment to which the individual discs are fed, without departing from the scope of the invention as defined by the claims.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM44996683" ref-ucid="WO-2012119915-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>An assembly for separating discs of metal, the assembly comprising:</claim-text><claim-text>a separator ring having an interior surface profile adapted to support a stack of discs and to separate a single disc from the bottom of the stack, and </claim-text><claim-text>an extractor for extracting the single disc from the separator ring, </claim-text><claim-text>in which the interior surface profile of the separator ring includes one or more inwardly protruding features, which define an opening which is smaller than the disc diameter, and</claim-text><claim-text>the extractor includes a “vacuum” pad such that, in use, when a vacuum is applied to the pad, the extractor pulls the disc through the opening, breaking any attraction between the disc and the adjacent one in the stack.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The assembly of claim 1, in which the inwardly protruding features comprise two or more equi-spaced segments.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The assembly of claim 2, in which the segments are positioned in the same plane perpendicular to the longitudinal axis of the separator ring.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The assembly of claim 1, in which the inwardly protruding feature or features comprise(s) a single segment with a helical profile or multiple segments arranged as a spaced screw thread. </claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The assembly of any one of claims 1 to 4, in which the extractor is rotatable to assist release of the disc from the segments. </claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The assembly of any one claims 1 to 5, in which the extractor includes:</claim-text><claim-text>a guide block with a central chamber and a port for supplying vacuum to the chamber;</claim-text><claim-text>an extractor shaft having a slot, and which is reciprocable through the chamber;</claim-text><claim-text>in which the slot in the extractor shaft and the port in the guide black form a switch such that, in use, when the slot in the shaft passes across the port, vacuum is turned on and off.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The assembly of claim 6, in which the extractor shaft further includes a plate fixed to the shaft, in which the plate retains a vacuum spindle with a spring at one end, a central bore for supply of vacuum, and the vacuum pad at the other, and in which, in use, the plate acts as a bush and allows the spindle to move against the spring to extract the disc.  </claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The assembly of claim 7, further including rods which are mounted on the plate and support stops mounted on springs, the stops being set at a stop position which is fixed relative to the extractor shaft and is reciprocable with the extractor shaft to contact the bottom of the stack.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The assembly of claim 8, in which the vacuum spindle and pad have a position at the top of the up stroke, which is higher than the stop position, and in which the vacuum pad contacts and grips the bottom disc. </claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>A method of extracting a single disc from the bottom of a stack of discs, the method comprising:</claim-text><claim-text>	reciprocating an extractor shaft to contact the stack of discs;</claim-text><claim-text>	retaining and sliding a spindle within the extractor shaft;</claim-text><claim-text>	mounting a vacuum pad at the upper end of the spindle;</claim-text><claim-text>	switching on a vacuum supply through the vacuum spindle and into the vacuum pad on the up stroke, and thereby gripping the bottom disc of the stack;</claim-text><claim-text>	pulling down the gripped disc on the down stroke and breaking any attraction between the bottom disc and the adjacent disc;</claim-text><claim-text>	switching off the vacuum supply and releasing the disc.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>A method according to claim 10, in which: </claim-text><claim-text>	the reciprocating step comprises lifting the extractor shaft up and down through a guide block and moving a plate fixed to the shaft and sprung stops on the plate to a stop position at the end of the up stroke when the stops contact the stack of discs;</claim-text><claim-text>	the retaining and sliding steps comprise retaining a vacuum spindle within both the plate and the extractor shaft, the spindle having a spring at its lower end; and	allowing the spindle to slide up and down against the bias of the spring;</claim-text><claim-text>	the step of switching on a vacuum supply comprises switching on the vacuum supply to a chamber in the guide block when a slot in the extractor shaft passes a vacuum supply port thereby switching vacuum through the centre of the vacuum spindle and into the vacuum pad on the up stroke, and gripping the bottom disc of the stack; and	</claim-text><claim-text>	the step of switching off the vacuum supply comprises switching off the vacuum supply when the slot in the extractor shaft passes the vacuum supply port on the down stroke.</claim-text><claim-text/><claim-text/></claim></claims><amended-claims mxw-id="PCLM44996684" ref-ucid="WO-2012119915-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><claim id="amended_c-en-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>
[Amended] <br/>An assembly for separating discs of pre-lubricated metal, the assembly comprising:<br/>a separator ring having an interior surface profile adapted to support a stack of pre-lubricated discs and to separate a single disc from the bottom of the stack, and <br/>an extractor for extracting the single disc from the separator ring, <br/>in which the interior surface profile of the separator ring includes one or more inwardly protruding features, which define an opening which is smaller than the disc diameter, and<br/>the extractor includes a “vacuum” pad such that, in use, when a vacuum is applied to the pad, the extractor pulls the disc through the opening, breaking any attraction between the disc and the adjacent one in the stack.
</claim-text></claim><claim id="amended_c-en-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The assembly of claim 1, in which the inwardly protruding features comprise two or more equi-spaced segments.</claim-text></claim><claim id="amended_c-en-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The assembly of claim 2, in which the segments are positioned in the same plane perpendicular to the longitudinal axis of the separator ring.</claim-text></claim><claim id="amended_c-en-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The assembly of claim 1, in which the inwardly protruding feature or features comprise(s) a single segment with a helical profile or multiple segments arranged as a spaced screw thread. </claim-text></claim><claim id="amended_c-en-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The assembly of any one of claims 1 to 4, in which the extractor is rotatable to assist release of the disc from the segments. </claim-text></claim><claim id="amended_c-en-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The assembly of any one claims 1 to 5, in which the extractor includes:</claim-text><claim-text>a guide block with a central chamber and a port for supplying vacuum to the chamber;</claim-text><claim-text>an extractor shaft having a slot, and which is reciprocable through the chamber;</claim-text><claim-text>in which the slot in the extractor shaft and the port in the guide black form a switch such that, in use, when the slot in the shaft passes across the port, vacuum is turned on and off.</claim-text></claim><claim id="amended_c-en-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The assembly of claim 6, in which the extractor shaft further includes a plate fixed to the shaft, in which the plate retains a vacuum spindle with a spring at one end, a central bore for supply of vacuum, and the vacuum pad at the other, and in which, in use, the plate acts as a bush and allows the spindle to move against the spring to extract the disc.  </claim-text></claim><claim id="amended_c-en-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The assembly of claim 7, further including rods which are mounted on the plate and support stops mounted on springs, the stops being set at a stop position which is fixed relative to the extractor shaft and is reciprocable with the extractor shaft to contact the bottom of the stack.</claim-text></claim><claim id="amended_c-en-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The assembly of claim 8, in which the vacuum spindle and pad have a position at the top of the up stroke, which is higher than the stop position, and in which the vacuum pad contacts and grips the bottom disc. </claim-text></claim><claim id="amended_c-en-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>
[Amended] <br/>A method of extracting a single disc from the bottom of a stack of pre-lubricated discs, the method comprising:<br/>reciprocating an extractor shaft to contact the stack of discs;<br/>retaining and sliding a spindle within the extractor shaft;<br/>mounting a vacuum pad at the upper end of the spindle;<br/>switching on a vacuum supply through the vacuum spindle and into the vacuum pad on the up stroke, and thereby gripping the bottom disc of the stack;<br/>pulling down the gripped disc on the down stroke and breaking any attraction between the bottom disc and the adjacent disc by deformation of the disc shape;<br/>switching off the vacuum supply and releasing the disc.
</claim-text></claim><claim id="amended_c-en-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>A method according to claim 10, in which: </claim-text><claim-text>	the reciprocating step comprises lifting the extractor shaft up and down through a guide block and moving a plate fixed to the shaft and sprung stops on the plate to a stop position at the end of the up stroke when the stops contact the stack of discs;</claim-text><claim-text>	the retaining and sliding steps comprise retaining a vacuum spindle within both the plate and the extractor shaft, the spindle having a spring at its lower end; and	allowing the spindle to slide up and down against the bias of the spring;</claim-text><claim-text>	the step of switching on a vacuum supply comprises switching on the vacuum supply to a chamber in the guide block when a slot in the extractor shaft passes a vacuum supply port thereby switching vacuum through the centre of the vacuum spindle and into the vacuum pad on the up stroke, and gripping the bottom disc of the stack; and	</claim-text><claim-text>	the step of switching off the vacuum supply comprises switching off the vacuum supply when the slot in the extractor shaft passes the vacuum supply port on the down stroke.</claim-text><claim-text/><claim-text/></claim></amended-claims><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
