<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2682305-A1" country="EP" doc-number="2682305" kind="A1" date="20140108" family-id="48576735" file-reference-id="257905" date-produced="20180822" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146585911" ucid="EP-2682305-A1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2682305</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-13168888-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154848103" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>13168888</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20130523</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP196971936" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>13168888.9</doc-number><date>20130523</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140553440" ucid="US-201213542708-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>201213542708</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120706</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989318403" load-source="docdb">B60Q   3/04        20060101AFI20131002BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1852739704" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B60Q   3/10        20170201 LI20170201BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1852739705" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B60Q   3/225       20170201 LI20170201BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1852739706" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B60Q   3/62        20170201 LI20170201BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1852739707" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B60Q   3/14        20170201 LI20170201BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1852739708" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B60Q   3/12        20170201 LI20170201BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1973212714" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B60K2350/2043      20130101 LA20160208BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1973214901" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G01D  11/28        20130101 FI20160210BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1973215279" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B60K2350/203       20130101 LA20160208BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132362366" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Lichtleiter für einen Instrumentencluster</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132362367" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Light Guide for an Instrument Cluster</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132362368" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Guide de lumière pour groupe d'instruments</invention-title><citations><patent-citations><patcit mxw-id="PCIT376756218" load-source="docdb" ucid="DE-102010055077-A1"><document-id format="epo"><country>DE</country><doc-number>102010055077</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20120621</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="XY" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT242945465" load-source="docdb" ucid="US-20060209525-A1"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>20060209525</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20060921</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="X" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT376756217" load-source="docdb" ucid="US-6682201-B2"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>6682201</doc-number><kind>B2</kind><date>20040127</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="XY" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit></patent-citations><non-patent-citations><nplcit><text>None</text><sources><source mxw-id="PNPL45211938" load-source="docdb" name="APP"/></sources></nplcit></non-patent-citations></citations></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919543096" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>CONTINENTAL AUTOMOTIVE SYSTEMS</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919537782" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>CONTINENTAL AUTOMOTIVE SYSTEMS US, INC.</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919016332" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Continental Automotive Systems US, Inc.</last-name><iid>101039764</iid><address><street>One Continental Drive</street><city>Auburn Hills, MI 48326</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919542419" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>DYER KEVIN MICHAEL</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919520443" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>DYER, KEVIN MICHAEL</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919019108" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>DYER, KEVIN MICHAEL</last-name><address><street>18310 Mackay</street><city>Macomb Township, MI Michigan 48042</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919537713" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>OLLILA CURT</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919507617" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>Ollila, Curt</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919012367" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Ollila, Curt</last-name><address><street>1473 Joann St.</street><city>Fenton, MI Michigan 48430</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919515017" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>WANG TAOCHUAN BRUCE</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919506568" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>WANG, TAOCHUAN BRUCE</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919009891" load-source="patent-office" sequence="3" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>WANG, TAOCHUAN BRUCE</last-name><address><street>46472 Galway</street><city>Novi, MI Michigan 48374</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919016050" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Reinhard - Skuhra - Weise &amp; Partner GbR</last-name><iid>100060500</iid><address><street>Patent- und Rechtsanwälte Friedrichstrasse 31</street><city>80801 München</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549759537" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS549831869" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549759539" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549753768" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549754726" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549841010" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549831874" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549759540" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549841011" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549841012" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549830743" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549753777" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549753778" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549759561" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549841013" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549759562" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549831875" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549754727" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549841018" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549753779" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549841019" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549912367" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549825521" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549912368" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549912369" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549825526" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS549825527" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549830744" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549753780" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549825528" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549754728" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549830745" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549754737" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS549825529" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549759563" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549753785" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549825534" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS549841020" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states><ep-extended-states><ep-extended-state-data><country>BA</country></ep-extended-state-data><ep-extended-state-data><country>ME</country></ep-extended-state-data></ep-extended-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA128673965" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p id="pa01" num="0001">An example instrument cluster includes a light guide having a first end portion and a display located adjacent the first end portion of the light guide for emitting light into the light guide.
<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="103" he="122" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA128738247" lang="EN" source="EPO" load-source="docdb"><p>An example instrument cluster includes a light guide having a first end portion and a display located adjacent the first end portion of the light guide for emitting light into the light guide.</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES63959953" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001"><b>BACKGROUND</b></heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">This disclosure generally relates to an instrument cluster. More particularly, this disclosure relates to an instrument cluster for a vehicle and a method of illuminating the instrument cluster.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002">Vehicles include instrument clusters having illuminated gages and screens to aid a user in monitoring vehicle information such as speed, oil pressure, RPM, fuel, voltage, etc. Illuminated gauges generally comprise a dial associated with vehicle information on the face of the gauge, a light source, and a pointer that is driven by a motor for movement relative to the gauge face. The gauge face includes spaced markings that indicate specified vehicle information over a given range. The light source generally includes bulbs or LEDs located behind the illuminated gauges to increase the visibility and aesthetics of the gauges.</p><heading id="h0002"><b>SUMMARY</b></heading><p id="p0003" num="0003">An example instrument cluster includes a light guide having a first end portion and a display located adjacent the first end portion of the light guide.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">The example instrument cluster assembly includes a housing, at least one light guide<br/>
having a first end portion located within the housing and at least one display located adjacent each first end portion of the at least one light guide.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">An example method of illuminating an instrument cluster includes illuminating a light guide with a display and varying a luminance and a color of the display to vary a luminance and a color of the light guide.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">These and other features of the disclosed examples can be understood from the following description and the accompanying drawings, which can be briefly described as follows.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p><heading id="h0003"><b>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</b></heading><p id="p0007" num="0007"><ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> illustrates an example instrument cluster assembly.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 2</figref> illustrates a cross-sectional view of an instrument cluster gage taken along line A-A of <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0004"><b>DETAILED DESCRIPTION</b></heading><p id="p0008" num="0008"><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> illustrates an example instrument cluster assembly 10. The instrument cluster assembly 10 includes a first instrument cluster gage 12 and a second instrument cluster gage 14. The first instrument cluster gage 12 and the second instrument cluster gage 14 include a light guide 16 and an instrument face 18. The first and second instrument cluster gages 12 and 14 are located within a housing 20. In the illustrated example, the first and second instrument cluster gages 12 and 14 may provide any one of the following: vehicle speed, engine RPM, fuel level, voltage level, or other vehicle information relevant to the operation of a vehicle.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">Although, the illustrated example only includes the first and second instrument cluster gages 12 and 14, one of ordinary skill in the art would recognize that the number, size, and shape of the instrument cluster gages could vary depending on the number and type of operational states desired to be displayed on the instrument cluster assembly 10.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010"><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 2</figref> illustrates a cross-sectional view of the first instrument cluster gage 12 of <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> taken along line A-A. A display 22, such as a thin film transistor (TFT) display or another type of display capable of producing a multitude of colors at varying luminance, is located adjacent a first end portion 24 of the light guide 16. The first end portion 24 of the light guide 16 is spaced inwardly from a perimeter of the display 22.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">The light guide 16 in this example is made of a clear acrylic material or another transparent thermoplastic. Although the light guide 16 is shown with a generally tubular shape, one of ordinary skill in the art would recognize that the light guide 16 could be rectangular, elliptical, or have a discontinuous perimeter.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p><p id="p0012" num="0012">The instrument face 18 is located radially inward from the light guide 16 and adjacent the first end portion 24 of the light guide 16. The first end portion 24 of the light guide 16 includes a light receiving portion 26 for accepting light from the display 22. The second end portion 28 of the light guide 16 includes a transitional portion 30 for engaging the housing 20 and providing a sealed transition between the light guide 16 and the housing 20.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">A first side 34 of the light guide 16 extends a first distance from the first end portion 24 to the second end portion 28 and a second side 36 of the light guide 16 extends a second distance from the first end portion 24 to the second end portion 28. In the illustrated example, the first distance is greater than the second distance.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">The display 22 includes a light emitting surface 38 located adjacent the light guide 16. The display 22 illuminates the light guide 16 and is capable of producing multiple colors of the same or varying luminance. The light emitted from the display 22 is received by the light receiving portion 26 causing the light guide 16 to glow according to the light being emitted by the display 22. A first portion 40 of the display 22 is capable of producing a first color having a first luminance and a second portion 42 of the display 22 is capable of producing a second color having a second luminance. The first and second colors and the first and second intensities may be the same or different. Although the above illustrated example discloses two different portions on the display 22, the display 22 may include any number of portions as dictated by the number of pixels on the display 22.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">Although a preferred embodiment of this disclosure has been disclosed, a worker of ordinary skill in this art would recognize that certain modifications would come within the scope of this disclosure. For that reason, the following claims should be studied to determine the true scope and content of this invention.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p><heading id="h0005"><b>FURTHER EMBODIMENTS</b></heading><p id="p0016" num="0016"><ol><li>1. An instrument cluster comprising:
<ul><li>a light guide having a first end portion; and</li><li>a display located adjacent the first end portion of the light guide, wherein the display is configured to emit light into the light guide.</li></ul></li><li>2. The instrument cluster of embodiment 1, wherein the light guide is tubular.</li><li>3. The instrument cluster of embodiment 2, comprising an instrument face located radially inward from the light guide and adjacent the first end portion of the light guide.</li><li>4. The instrument cluster of embodiment 1, wherein the light guide is made of a transparent thermoplastic.</li><li>5. The instrument cluster of embodiment 1, wherein the first end portion of the light guide includes a light receiving portion.</li><li>6. The instrument cluster of embodiment 5, wherein the display is configured to emit light into the light receiving portion.</li><li>7. The instrument cluster of embodiment 1, wherein a second end portion of the light guide including a transitional portion.</li><li>8. The instrument cluster of embodiment 1, wherein the display is a thin film transistor.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></li><li>9. The instrument cluster of embodiment 1, wherein the first end portion of the light guide is spaced inwardly from a perimeter of the display.</li><li>10. The instrument cluster of embodiment 1, wherein a first side of the light guide extends a first distance from the first end portion to a second end portion of the light guide and a second side of the light guide extends a second distance from the first end portion to the second end portion, wherein the first distance is greater than the second distance.</li><li>11. An instrument cluster assembly comprising:
<ul><li>a housing;</li><li>at least one light guide having a first end portion located within the housing; and</li><li>at least one display located adjacent each first end portion of the at least one light guide, wherein the at least one display is configured to communicate light to the light guide for illuminating the light guide.</li></ul></li><li>12. The instrument cluster assembly of embodiment 11, wherein the at least one light guide is tubular.</li><li>13. The instrument cluster assembly of embodiment 12, further including an instrument face located radially inward from the at least one light guide and adjacent the first end portion of the at least one light guide.</li><li>14. The instrument cluster assembly of embodiment 11, wherein the first end portion of the at least one light guide includes a light receiving portion.</li><li>15. The instrument cluster assembly of embodiment 14, wherein the display is configured to emit light into the light receiving portion.<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></li><li>16. The instrument cluster assembly of embodiment 11, wherein a first side of the light guide extends a first distance from the first end portion to a second end portion and a second side of the light guide extends a second distance from the first end portion to the second end portion, wherein the first distance is greater than the second distance.</li><li>17. A method of illuminating an instrument cluster comprising:
<ul><li>illuminating a light guide with a display; and</li><li>varying a luminance and a color of the display to vary a luminance and a color of the light guide.</li></ul></li><li>18. The method of embodiment 17, wherein a first portion of the display has a first luminance and a second portion of the display has a second luminance that is different from the first luminance.</li><li>19. The method of embodiment 18, wherein a first portion of the display has a first color and a second portion of the display has a second color that is different from the first color.</li><li>20. The method of embodiment 17, wherein the light guide is tubular and includes an instrument face located radially inward from the light guide.</li></ol></p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56983008" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --><claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>An instrument cluster comprising:
<claim-text>a light guide having a first end portion; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a display located adjacent the first end portion of the light guide, wherein the display is configured to emit light into the light guide.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The instrument cluster of claim 1, wherein the light guide is tubular.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The instrument cluster according to any of the preceding claims, comprising an instrument face located radially inward from the light guide and adjacent the first end portion of the light guide.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The instrument cluster according to any of the preceding claims, wherein the light guide is made of a transparent thermoplastic.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The instrument cluster according to any of the preceding claims, wherein the first end portion of the light guide includes a light receiving portion.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The instrument cluster of claim 5, wherein the display is configured to emit light into the light receiving portion.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The instrument cluster according to any of the preceding claims, wherein a second end portion of the light guide including a transitional portion.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The instrument cluster according to any of the preceding claims, wherein the display is a thin film transistor.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The instrument cluster according to any of the preceding claims, wherein the first end portion of the light guide is spaced inwardly from a perimeter of the display.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The instrument cluster of according to any of the preceding claims, wherein a first side of the light guide extends a first distance from the first end portion to a second end portion of the light guide and a second side of the light guide extends a second distance from the first end portion to the second end portion, wherein the first distance is greater than the second distance.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>An instrument cluster assembly comprising:
<claim-text>a housing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one instrument cluster according to any of the claims 1-10.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>The instrument cluster assembly of claim 11,<br/>
wherein the instrument cluster comprising:
<claim-text>at least one light guide having a first end portion located within the housing; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one display located adjacent each first end portion of the at least one light guide, wherein the at least one display is configured to communicate light to the light guide for illuminating the light guide.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>A method of illuminating an instrument cluster comprising:
<claim-text>illuminating a light guide with a display; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>varying a luminance and a color of the display to vary a luminance and a color of the light guide.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>The method of claim 13, wherein a first portion of the display has a first luminance and/or color and a second portion of the display has a second luminance and/or color that is different from the first luminance and first color, respectively.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>The method of claims 13 or 14, wherein the light guide is tubular and includes an instrument face located radially inward from the light guide.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16671315" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1,2"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="161" he="232" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><search-report-data><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="158" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="163" he="233" type="tif"/></search-report-data><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
