<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2582927-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2582927" kind="B1" date="20140101" family-id="44625002" file-reference-id="316852" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146553377" ucid="EP-2582927-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2582927</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-10801286-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154827300" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>10801286</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20101119</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140453759" ucid="NL-2010000098-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>NL</country><doc-number>2010000098</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20100618</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140445174" ucid="NL-2010000164-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>NL</country><doc-number>2010000164</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20101119</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130718</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988107820" load-source="ipcr">F01K  25/02        20060101AFI20120105BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988103174" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F01K  25/02        20130101 FI20130425BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132192615" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">VERFAHREN ZUR UMWANDLUNG VON WÄRMEENERGIE IN MECHANISCHE ENERGIE, UND VORRICHTUNG</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132192616" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">A METHOD OF CONVERTING THERMAL ENERGY INTO MECHANICAL ENERGY, AND AN APPARATUS</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132192617" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">PROCÉDÉ PERMETTANT DE CONVERTIR DE L'ÉNERGIE THERMIQUE EN ÉNERGIE MÉCANIQUE, ET APPAREIL</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918146838" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>CYCLO DYNAMICS B V</last-name><address><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918157154" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>CYCLO DYNAMICS B.V.</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918173596" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>VAN DER WERFF JEICHIENUS ADRIAAN</last-name><address><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918153610" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>VAN DER WERFF, JEICHIENUS, ADRIAAN</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918996818" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>VAN DER WERFF, JEICHIENUS, ADRIAAN</last-name><address><street>Onder de Boompjes 33</street><city>NL-3417 HE Montfoort</city><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918996820" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>CYCLO DYNAMICS B.V.</last-name><iid>101290258</iid><address><street>Blokland 3</street><city>NL-3417 MN Montfoort</city><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918996819" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Altenburg, Bernardus Stephanus Franciscus</last-name><iid>101077783</iid><address><street>ALTENBURG PATENT Ravelijnstraat 125</street><city>4102 AJ Culemborg</city><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="NL-2010000164-W"><document-id><country>NL</country><doc-number>2010000164</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20101119</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2011159145-A2"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2011159145</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20111222</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548883139" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS548969998" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS548883140" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS548860086" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS548975381" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS548983474" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS548969999" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS548883141" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548983475" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS548983476" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS548972375" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS548860087" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS548860088" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548883142" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548983477" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS548883143" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS548970000" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS548975386" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS548883144" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS548860089" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS548983478" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS548977181" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS548970001" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS548977182" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS548977183" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS548828385" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS548828386" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS548970002" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS548972376" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS548975387" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS548977184" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS548970003" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS548977185" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS548970004" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS548977186" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS548972377" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS548975388" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS548828387" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63957197" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to a method of converting thermal energy into mechanical energy using a non-gaseous working medium present in an apparatus comprising a plurality of heat exchangers and an outgoing shaft according to the preamble of claim 1.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002">There is an enormous drive to use energy as well as possible, both for economical and environmental reasons. Low-grade heat is available in large quantities, be it waste heat from industrial processes or other sources, or by generating it using solar energy. Unfortunately, most in demand is high-grade energy, such as mechanical energy which can be converted into electricity, which is even more in demand. <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="WO983078A"><text>WO983078</text></patcit> (<patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="NL9800012W"><text>PCT/NL98/00012</text></patcit>) discloses a method and an apparatus for converting thermal energy into mechanical energy. It makes use of paraffin as a working medium. Paraffin is a substance that over a (limited) temperature range displays superexpansion, that is an expansion of &gt; 0.01% per °C. A typical value for the coefficient of expansion of paraffin is 0.05% per °C, and in a more limited range even as high as &gt;0.2% per °C. By selecting the working medium with the upper end of the superexpansion range near the temperature of the heating heat exchange medium, it is possible to convert the heat of the heating heat exchange medium efficiently. Alternatively, it may be possible to change the temperature of the heating heat exchange medium to match the working medium present in the apparatus.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">The apparatus disclosed in <patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="WO9830786A"><text>WO9830786</text></patcit> is susceptible to problems with sealing of the working medium, in particular at high pressures of the working medium (which may well be at 200 bar or higher), making the method less reliable.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004"><patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="US5916140A"><text>US5916140</text></patcit> discloses an apparatus according to the preamble of claim 1. In the thermal hydraulic engine disclosed, the temperature of a working fluid is changed, causing changes in volume without undergoing a phase change. The working fluid drives the piston of a cilinder in response to the expansion and contraction of the working fluid.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">The object of the present invention is to provide a method according to the preamble with reduced susceptibility to working medium sealing problems.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p><p id="p0006" num="0006">To this end, the invention according to the preamble is characterized in that
<ul><li>heat exchange medium having a second, low temperature is used for cooling working medium in a second chamber unit;</li><li>relatively cool heat exchange medium having a third temperature between the first and the second temperature is introduced via the inlet of a third chamber unit comprising relatively warm working medium to yield warmed-up heat exchange medium;</li><li>relatively warm heat exchange medium having a fourth temperature between the first and the second temperature is introduced via the inlet of a fourth chamber unit comprising relatively cool working medium to heat the working medium and drive the outgoing shaft;</li></ul>
wherein<br/>
after being heated by the heat exchange medium of the first temperature, the first chamber unit is used as a third chamber unit so as to extract thermal energy from said third chamber unit to result in warmed-up heat exchange medium;<br/>
after being cooled by the heat exchange medium of the second temperature, the second chamber unit is used as a fourth chamber unit to be warmed by relatively warm heat exchange medium of a fourth temperature;<br/>
after being cooled down by relatively cool heat exchange medium of a third temperature, the third chamber unit is used as a second chamber unit; and<br/>
after being warmed by relatively warm heat exchange medium of a fourth temperature the fourth chamber unit is used as the first chamber unit.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">This eliminates the need for moving working medium under high pressure from one chamber to another, thus significantly reducing the sealing problem. Thus, after a personal quest of over two decades, a method is provided that allows for both reliable and efficient conversion of thermal energy into mechanical energy for increased periods of time thanks to improved sealing. In the present application, the term "heat exchange medium" refers to any of heat exchange medium of the first, second, third and fourth temperature for exchange of heat with the working medium, but not to the working medium itself. The heat exchange medium will generally be water. Depending of its location in the apparatus, the heat exchange medium serves as a cooling<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> medium or a heating medium. The working medium is capable of flowing, at least at the upper end of the superexpansion range, and will generally be a liquid, including also suspensions and pastes. The term "outgoing shaft" means a shaft indirectly driven by expanding working medium. The outgoing shaft may be a shaft capable of reciprocating movement and/or a rotary movement. The adjectives "high" and "low" used in conjunction with temperature are relative, not absolute terms. The temperatures of relatively cool heat exchange medium of the third temperature and relatively warm heat exchange medium of the fourth temperature are somewhere between these high and low temperatures, and are relative to the temperature of working medium in the chamber unit the heat exchange medium is passing through and not relative to each other. In the method according to the invention, there will usually be at least two third chamber units between the first and the second chamber unit to extract as much thermal energy from the working medium in the third chamber units. Also, there will usually be at least two fourth chamber units between the second and the first chamber unit to transfer as much thermal energy from the working medium in the fourth chamber units. The use of multiple fourth chamber units contributes to a (mechanically) smooth operation.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008"><patcit id="pcit0005" dnum="US4283915A"><text>US4283915</text></patcit> discloses a thermal hydraulic engine in which two sources of water of different temperature flow alternately through heat exchanger tubes to expand and contract a working liquid that has a high coefficient of thermal expansion. The working cycle is carried out below the boiling point of the working liquid. Expansion and contraction of the working liquid provides a high pressure hydraulic output which may be used to drive a hydraulic motor. To provide substantially steady output flow, four banks of heat exchangers may be operated sequentially with hydraulic accumulator means smoothing out the flow pulsations.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">According to a preferred embodiment, there is at least one pair of fourth chamber units, the first of the pair of fourth chamber units comprising working medium at a relatively high temperature compared to the temperature of the working medium in the second of said pair of fourth chamber units, wherein the second of said pair of fourth chamber units is heated using heat exchange medium discharged from the first chamber unit after heat exchange with said first chamber<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> unit; and the first of said pair of fourth chamber units is heated using relatively warm heat exchange medium discharged from a third chamber unit that has a temperature of the working medium closest to the temperature of the working medium of the first chamber unit.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">This provides for a relatively large temperature difference between heat exchange medium and working medium, allowing the pistons to do a lot of work. This manner of operation is in particular advantageous if the thermal energy content of the heat exchange medium with respect to the temperature of the heat exchange medium of the second temperature is to be converted, as will be explained in more detail in the example section.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">According to a preferred embodiment, there is at least a second pair of fourth chamber units, the first chamber unit of said second pair of fourth chamber units comprising working medium at a relatively high temperature compared to the temperature of the working medium in the second chamber unit of said second pair of fourth chamber units, and cooled down heat exchange medium from the first chamber unit of the pair of fourth chamber units is used to heat the first chamber unit of said second pair of fourth chamber units and cooled down heat exchange medium from the second chamber unit of the first pair of fourth chamber units is used to heat the second chamber unit of said second pair of fourth chamber units.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">Despite the relatively large temperature difference between heat exchange medium and working medium, heat energy is converted to a larger extent into mechanical energy.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">According to a preferred embodiment, cooled-down heat exchange medium from the first chamber unit of the last pair of fourth chamber units is discharged from the apparatus and the loss of heat exchange medium being compensated by the heat exchange medium having the first temperature introduced in the first chamber unit; and cooled-down heat exchange medium from the second chamber unit of the last pair of fourth chamber units is used as relatively cool heat exchange medium to cool working medium in a third chamber unit having a working medium temperature closest to the working temperature of the second chamber unit.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">This method allows for the most extensive conversion of heat from the heating heat exchange medium to mechanical energy. If the<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> apparatus comprises a multitude of third chamber units, as will generally be the case, the cooled-down heat exchange medium from the first chamber of the last pair of fourth chamber unit will be used as relatively cool heat exchange medium to extract heat from the working medium present in the third chamber unit having the lowest temperature.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">According to a preferred embodiment, the outgoing shaft is connected to a generator for generating electricity.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">Thus very high-grade energy is obtained.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">According to a preferred embodiment, the apparatus comprises a second working medium, the working medium and the second working medium differing in super expansion range.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">This allows the apparatus to be used with a broader temperature range of heating heat exchange medium. The super expansion ranges of the working medium and the second working medium are different, but may still overlap. The different working media may be different waxes, such as different paraffins. It is feasible to have a single closed chamber contain different working media, for example if they are separated from each other by a second free moving piston. Alternatively, there are groups of two (or more) chamber units each group operated as described for a single chamber unit in the method according to the invention, the two (or more) chamber units of a group having different working media.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">According to a preferred embodiment, the heat exchange medium is heated using solar energy.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">This is a very important application of the method according to the present invention. Sunlight can be converted into heat using a solar collector very efficiently, and subsequently converted using the method according to the present invention quite efficiently. Another major advantage is that heat can be stored in a buffer, be it daily or for longer periods, such that mechanical energy but more importantly electricity can be generated even when no sunlight is available. Obviously this is not possible with (expensive) solar panels.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">Finally, the present invention relates to an apparatus for converting thermal energy into mechanical energy using a non-gaseous working medium, the apparatus comprising a plurality of heat exchangers and an outgoing shaft, wherein<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> -->
<ul><li>the apparatus comprises a multitude of chamber units, a chamber unit comprising an inlet for introducing heat exchange medium and an outlet for discharging said heat exchange medium after having undergone heat exchange as well as a closed chamber having a heat exchanger wall for exchanging heat between working medium inside the closed chamber and the heat exchange medium introduced into the chamber unit via said inlet for introducing heat exchange medium;</li><li>the closed chambers comprising a cylinder and a piston, the piston of a closed chamber being workably connected to the outgoing shaft via an organ capable of driving the outgoing shaft if the piston is moved from a first, relatively retracted position in the cylinder to a second, relatively protruding position for driving the outgoing shaft and allowing free movement of the outgoing shaft if said piston is moved from the second to the first position;</li><li>the apparatus comprises a device for distributing a heat exchange medium for passing said heat exchange medium along the heat exchanger walls via said inlets and outlets of the chamber units, the device being capable of providing a first chamber unit with heat exchange medium of a first high temperature and providing a second chamber unit with heat exchange medium with a second low temperature, providing a third chamber unit with heat exchange medium of a third temperature between the first and the second temperature and providing a fourth chamber unit with heat exchange medium of a fourth temperature between the first and the second temperature.</li></ul></p><p id="p0022" num="0022">Thus an apparatus has been provided that allows for the reliable and efficient conversion of thermal energy into mechanical energy for increased periods of time thanks to improved sealing. In practice, the chamber units of an apparatus according to the invention will be quite similar such as identical. The heat exchanger wall is generally part of a tube having a circular cross-section so as to withstand the forces that occur during operation when the working medium expands. The walls of the closed chamber are sufficiently rigid to ensure that pressure developing inside the closed chamber results in the piston being moved from a first retracted position to a second, extended position. Paraffin is a preferred working medium because its composition can be changed to suit the temperature of the heating heat exchange medium.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p><p id="p0023" num="0023">According to a preferred embodiment, the outgoing shaft is connected to a generator for generating electricity.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">Thus very high-grade energy is obtained.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">According to a preferred embodiment, the apparatus comprises a control device for starting and stopping the flow of heat exchange medium through at least one of the chamber units.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">The control device will be operated such that the flow of heat exchange medium is interrupted while the flow of heat exchange medium is switched between chamber unites. This makes the device for distributing heating heat exchange medium and cooling heat exchange medium less susceptible to leakage of heat exchange medium. As an alternative solution, a by-pass could be used but depending on the circumstances, this could result in a waste of thermal energy.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">According to a preferred embodiment, the organ comprises a freewheel.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">This allows for a convenient conversion of the reciprocating motion of a piston to a rotary motion of the shaft.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">According to a preferred embodiment, the piston of a chamber unit is provided with a sprocket, the apparatus comprises a frame and a chain, a first end of the chain being attached to the frame and the chain from that first end being passed over said sprocket and subsequently over the freewheel.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">When the piston moves from the first relatively retracted position in the cylinder to a second, relatively protruding position, the sprocket is pushed away from the cylinder, and the freewheel starts to drive the outgoing axis. If the chamber is cooled, the working medium contracts and the piston moves from the second, relatively protruding position to the first relatively retracted position in the cylinder. Then, the freewheel will move freely in the opposite direction and no work is done by the piston. The chain will be a heavy duty chain, such as of a motorcycle.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">According to a preferred embodiment, the piston of a third chamber unit is aligned opposite to a piston of a fourth chamber unit, the second, remaining end of the chain being attached to the frame as well and the third and fourth chamber units each having their own sprocket and freewheel but sharing the chain, the apparatus being provided with a tensioning organ for keeping the chain taut.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></p><p id="p0032" num="0032">The use of such a chain differential allows the number of tensioning organs to be reduced. The difference in phase for the opposite chamber units is preferably 180°. The tensioning organ may comprise a rubber band, a coil spring or any other means. The tensioning organ will be elongated in the process.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">According to a preferred embodiment, the device for distributing heat exchange medium over chamber units comprises a first member and a second member, the first member being rotatable relative to the second member around an axis of rotation in a first direction, the first member comprising a multitude of through channels, each of these through channels connecting two surface areas of said first member and suitable for passing heat exchange medium to and from chamber units and the second member comprising a conduit arrangement, wherein
<ul><li>for every chamber unit of the multitude of chamber units the first member comprises at least a first channel for passing heat exchange medium to a chamber unit and at least one second channel for heat exchange medium passed through said chamber unit; the first channel having an inlet end facing the second member and an outlet end not facing the second member; the second channel having an outlet end facing the second member and an inlet end not facing the second member, the inlet ends of the first channels being distributed evenly spaced over the circumference of a circle having its center on the axis of rotation and the outlet ends of the second channels being distributed evenly spaced over the circumference of a second circle having its center on the axis of rotation;</li><li>the conduit arrangement of the second member comprises a multitude of through channels, the through channels having
<ul><li># inlets for sealingly connecting to the outlets of second channels of the first member and to an inlet for heat exchange medium of the first high temperature and to an inlet for heat exchange medium of a second low temperature, and</li><li># outlets for sealingly connecting to the inlets of first channels of the first member, and an outlet for discharging heat exchange medium from the apparatus;</li></ul></li></ul>
said inlets of the second member being distributed over the first circle and said outlets of the second member being distributed over the second circle, and<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> -->the through channel of the second member being capable of connecting the outlet of a second channel of the first member connected to a particular chamber unit with the inlet of a first channel of the first member connected to a different chamber unit.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">The second member determines the path that the heat exchange medium should take to pass through the various chamber units. The term "evenly spaced" allows for deviations as long as the relative rotation results in the desired channels being connected without leakage of heat exchange medium. The first and second circle may have the same radius (as exemplified in the example discussed below).</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">The invention will now be explained in more detail with reference to the following drawings:
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1a</figref> shows in a cut-away view a chamber unit suitable for use in the method and in an apparatus according to the invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 1b</figref> shows a bottom view of the chamber unit of <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1a</figref>;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 2</figref> is a graph showing super expansion behaviour of a paraffin suitable for use in the method and in the apparatus according to the invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 2</figref> depicts a graph to illustrate super expansion of a working medium;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 3</figref> shows a chamber unit workably connected to an axle;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 4a-c</figref> show a schematic arrangement of 12 chamber units each at a different phase in a thermal heating/cooling cycle of working medium in the chamber units;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 5</figref> shows a schematic bottom view of the chamber units and the way in which they are connected for a first way of operating;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 6</figref> shows a detail of a realized embodiment of the apparatus according to the present invention (top view), with 4 ancillary axles;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 7</figref> shows a front view of the apparatus, ancillary axles being coupled via chains to drive an outgoing shaft;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0009">Fig. 8a</figref> shows a cross-sectional view through a multiway-valve for controlling the flow of heat exchange medium through an apparatus according to the invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0010">Fig. 8b</figref> shows a cross-sectional view through the multiway-valve of <figref idrefs="f0009 f0010">fig. 8</figref> along line VIII-VIII; and<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></li><li><figref idrefs="f0011">Fig. 9</figref> shows a variant of the schematic bottom view of the chamber units of <figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 5</figref> and the way in which they are connected for an alternative way of operating.</li></ul></p><p id="p0036" num="0036"><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1a</figref> shows a chamber unit 100 comprising three copper tubes 101 having a circular cross-section and having two common ends 102. The chamber unit 100 is provided with a cylinder 103 which is provided with a piston 104. <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 1b</figref> shows the chamber unit 100 of <figref idrefs="f0001">fig. 1a</figref> in a partially cut-away bottom view.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">The copper tubes 101 are enclosed in a second tube 106, here in the form of a plastic hose, having an inlet 107 for a heat exchange medium and an outlet 108 for said heat exchange medium. The heat exchange medium will generally be water, but may be of a different composition.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">The copper tubes 101, the cylinder 103 and the piston 104 define a closed chamber 105, which contains a working medium displaying super expansion. An example of a suitable working medium is paraffin VP858 (Sasol, Hamburg, Germany). To prevent the working medium from escaping from the closed chamber 105, sealing rings 176 are provided, Teflon sealing against the piston 104. <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 2</figref> shows the expansion behaviour of this paraffin depending on the temperature. It is clear that over a limited temperature range the paraffin displays an exceptionally large expansion, and this range is particularly suitable for converting thermal energy into mechanical energy.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">The copper tubes 101 will serve as a heat exchanging wall for transfer of heat between the heat exchange medium passed through the second tube 106 and the working medium present inside the closed chamber 105. Although it is feasible if one end 102 of a copper tube 101 is closed, for the best operation, both ends 102 of copper tube 101 open into the cylinder 103.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">It is noted that in use, the working medium inside the closed chamber 105 will be at a high pressure when heated, typically hundreds of bars. For this reason, it is preferred that the second tube 106 encompasses the first tube 101 instead of the other way around. While copper is a preferred material because it is a very good thermal conductor, it should be noted that the tube 101 is subjected to large forces. For this reason, in case use is made of copper for the tube 101, high grade copper will be used. Suitable copper tube is<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> commercially available, such as copper tube xyz available from Wieland (Ulm, Germany).</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">If the working medium inside the closed chamber 105 is relatively cold and the heat exchange medium passed through the second tube 106 is relatively warm, the piston 104 will move from a relatively retracted position inside the cylinder 103 (corresponding to the relatively retracted state shown in fig. la) to a relatively extended position. Very large forces can be exerted by the piston 104 during this movement. If the piston 104 moves in the opposite direction because the working medium is relatively warm and the heat exchange medium is relatively cold, the piston 104 is not capable of performing any useful work because it would result in a negative pressure inside the closed chamber 105.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042"><figref idrefs="f0004">Fig 3</figref> shows a frame 110 with two identical but facing chamber units 100, 100' (partially shown), and will be used to show how a force exerted by a piston 104 may be transferred to an ancillary axle 109. In <figref idrefs="f0004">fig. 3</figref>, parts of chamber unit 100 don't have an apostrophe, whereas their counterparts of chamber unit 100' do. The chamber units 100, 100' are attached to the frame 110. A chain 111 having two ends 112 and 113 respectively is connected with said ends 112, 113 to the frame 110. The piston 104 is provided at its distal (protruding) end with a sprocket 114 and the ancillary axle 109 is provided with a freewheel sprocket 115. The chain 111 passes over the sprocket 114 and the freewheel sprocket 115. If the piston 104 extends, the chain 111 drives the ancillary axle 109 in a first rotational direction, whereas if the piston 104 retracts, the freewheel sprocket 115 allows the chain to move with respect to the ancillary axle 109 without driving said ancillary axle 109 in a direction opposite to the first rotational direction.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">The linear movement of the piston 104 is thus converted into a rotational movement of the ancillary axle 109. If there were only one piston 104 to drive an ancillary axle 109, the conversion of thermal energy into mechanical energy would not result continuous output of mechanical energy. For this reason the method according to the invention makes use of a multitude of chamber units driven with a different phase, achieved by passing heat exchange medium of different temperatures through the chamber units at any given time. In <figref idrefs="f0004">fig. 3</figref>, the chamber unit 100' driving ancillary axle 109' is at a 180° difference<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> in phase with respect to chamber unit 100 driving ancillary axle 109, but particular ancillary axle will be driven with different (intermediate) phase differences as well. That is, a multitude of chamber units 100 operated with a different phase is used to drive ancillary axle 109, using respective pistons 104 with sprockets 114. Similarly, a multitude of chamber units 100' will be used to drive ancillary axle 109'.</p><p id="p0044" num="0044">It is noted that a peculiarity of the apparatus is that the pressure in closed chambers of chamber units actually driving a common ancillary axle will be the same, even though they don't have the same phase. The actual pressure is dependent on several factors, amongst which the load at the outgoing shaft. Because there will be multiple fourth chamber units, this results in smooth operation and a first chamber unit having extended its piston maximally can stop contributing mechanical energy and a second chamber unit can kick in as a fourth chamber unit without causing shock effects.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045">A spring 116 with a sprocket 117, the spring 116 being attached to the frame 110, is used to keep the chain 111 taut. In case of a phase difference of 180° between chamber units 100 and 100' (as is preferred), there will hardly be any movement of the sprocket 117 during continuous operation, and the spring 116 will serve mainly to keep the chain 111 taut from start-up (when the working medium in the chambers chamber units 100, 100' is cold and the distal ends of opposing pistons are further apart).</p><p id="p0046" num="0046">An important aspect of the present invention is that once working medium inside a chamber unit 100 is heated by heat exchange medium, this heat is recuperated to a large extent for subsequent heating of relatively cool working medium. This involves the use of a multitude of third chamber units 100, and the distribution of heat exchange medium through the second tubes 106 of said chamber units 100, as will be explained in greater detail below.</p><p id="p0047" num="0047"><figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 4a-c</figref> show a schematic arrangement of 24 chamber units 100 operated in 12 groups of 2 chamber units, each group at a different phase in a thermal heating/cooling cycle of working medium in the chamber units 100. Accordingly, the pistons 104 of the chamber units 100 extend from the cylinders 103 of the chamber units over different lengths. Arrows indicate the direction of movement of the pistons 104. Thus by using multiple chamber units operating at different<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> phases mechanical energy can be delivered in a continuous manner. It is remarked that of a group of 2 chamber units, one chamber unit could contain a first working medium and the other chamber unit could contain another working medium having a superexpansion range differing from but overlapping with the super expansion range of the first working unit. This allows for a larger working temperature range (albeit at the cost of reduced efficiency at converting heat into mechanical energy). <figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 4</figref> shows channels 803, inlets 804, 806 and outlets 804 which are discussed with reference to <figref idrefs="f0009">fig. 8a</figref> below.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048">Once the temperature of the working medium in a chamber unit is comparable to the temperature of the heat exchange medium with which it is exchanging heat, the flow of heat exchange medium through the chamber units is changed so as to cause the working medium to contract or expand.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">There are two major ways of operating, both of which will be explained below.</p><p id="p0050" num="0050">According to the first major way of operating, a relatively hot heat exchange medium, usually hot water, of a first temperature is introduced into the inlet 107 of a (first) chamber unit 100 to heat already relatively warm working medium. After heat exchange, the heat exchange medium is passed to another (fourth) chamber unit containing relatively cool working medium to heat that relatively cool working medium. This is preferably repeated one or more times, so the already somewhat cooler heat exchange medium is used to heat working medium of a (fourth) chamber unit 100 that is relatively cool. This results in heat exchange medium that has given off most of its thermal energy, and work has been performed by the respective (fourth) chamber units 100. The heat exchange medium that was cooled off is now used to recuperate thermal energy from working medium inside a (third) chamber unit 100 that is relatively warm compared to the heat exchange medium of a third temperature. Once warmed up a bit, the heat exchange medium is passed to yet another (third) chamber unit 100 etc, until the heat exchange medium is hot enough to heat working medium inside a fourth chamber 100, and preferably several fourth chambers having working medium of different temperatures so as to use the thermal energy of the heat exchange medium to perform work and to result in relatively cool heat exchange medium, which is subsequently discharged.<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></p><p id="p0051" num="0051">To make sure that heat exchange medium can heat working medium even if the heat exchange medium isn't very warm, the working medium inside one of the chamber units 100 (the second chamber unit) is cooled, and some thermal energy is lost here.</p><p id="p0052" num="0052">This embodiment is in particular suitable where it is desired to extract thermal energy to a large extent, e.g. in case a heat storage is present. A practical example is a building provided with solar panels for collecting heat during the day, storing the heat in a buffer and generating electricity at any desired time by depleting the buffer.</p><p id="p0053" num="0053">To explain the flow of heat exchange medium for a specific embodiment, reference is made to <figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 5</figref>, which is bottom view of an arrangement of 12 chamber units 100. A top view would show a similar arrangement of 12 chamber units 100'. The latter arrangement is operated similarly as will now discussed for the arrangement of chamber units 100. The temperatures of heat exchange medium (water) and working medium (paraffin) are merely given for explanatory purposes.</p><p id="p0054" num="0054"><figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 5</figref> shows one first chamber unit 501-1, six fourth chamber units 502-4 through 507-4, one second chamber unit 508-2 and four third chamber units 509-3 through 512-3. The fourth chamber units come in three pairs:
<ul><li>502-4 and 503-4 constitute the first pair;</li><li>504-4 and 505-4 constitute the second pair; and</li><li>506-4 and 507-4 constitute the third pair.</li></ul></p><p id="p0055" num="0055">Of the first pair, the working medium of 502-4 is warmer than the working medium of 503-4.</p><p id="p0056" num="0056">Of the second pair, the working medium of 504-4 is warmer than the working medium of 505-4.</p><p id="p0057" num="0057">Of the third pair, the working medium of 506-4 is warmer than the working medium of 507-4.</p><p id="p0058" num="0058">Hot heat exchange medium, e.g. hot water that would normally have to be disposed of, e.g. using a cooling tower, of a temperature of over 70°C is introduced into the first chamber unit 501-1. There it heats the working medium to the highest temperature working medium reaches in the thermal cycle described here, 70°C. During this heat exchange process, the heat exchange medium cools down a bit, and it is passed to the fourth chamber unit 503-4 where it heats the working medium to 50°C. Having given off more heat, the heat exchange medium<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> has become colder yet again and is now used to heat working medium of fourth chamber unit 505-4 to 30°C. From there, the heat exchange medium is passed to heat the working medium of fourth chamber unit 507-4. This working medium of fourth chamber unit 507-4 had previously been cooled using cold water of &lt;20° (when the fourth chamber unit currently designated 505-4 was second chamber unit 508-2).</p><p id="p0059" num="0059">Now the relatively cool heat exchange medium from unit 507-4 of a third low temperature is used to recuperate heat from third chamber units 509-3 through 512-3 consecutively, resulting in warmed up heat exchange medium that is passed to the fourth chamber unit 502-4 to heat its working medium. From the fourth chamber unit 502-4, the heat exchange medium is used to heat the working media of the fourth chamber units 504-4 and 506-4 respectively, before being discharged, for example in another buffer, or discharged on surface water. According to a highly preferred embodiment, however, the water is reheated, e.g. using solar energy or geothermal energy, to &gt;70° for heating the first chamber unit 501-1.</p><p id="p0060" num="0060">In the apparatus actually built a chamber unit as discussed above was actually composed of two chamber units a, b operated as a single chamber unit. The drawing reflects this, but the design choice was made because of the parts available to the inventor. The apparatus was able to convert heat into work with an efficiency of over 20%.</p><p id="p0061" num="0061"><figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 6</figref> schematically shows the actually realized embodiment of the present invention (top view), with 4 ancillary axles 109 for chamber units 100. The ancillary axles 109 are coupled via conical gear wheels 181. To allow <figref idrefs="f0007">fig. 6</figref> to show both the ancillary axles 109 of the lower half of the apparatus and the ancillary axles 109' of the upper half of the apparatus, the former have been drawn shorter.</p><p id="p0062" num="0062"><figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 7</figref> shows a front view of an apparatus according to the invention. Ancillary axles 109, 109' are workably linked to an outgoing shaft 119. <figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 7</figref> (where the chamber units are left out) shows the frame 110 and the ends of four, parallel ancillary axles 109, 109'. These ancillary axles 109, 109' are provided with sprockets 170 and drive the outgoing shaft 119, provided with two sprockets 171 (they are behind each other, so only one is indicated) via chains 161, 162 (one chain for each sprocket 171 of the outgoing shaft 119). Two ancillary<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> sprockets 181, 182 are provided for tensioning the chains 161, 162 respectively.</p><p id="p0063" num="0063">With the method and apparatus according to the present invention, the working medium is not moved from one chamber unit to another but remains where it is. The thermal cycle involves that chamber units have different roles at different times in the thermal cycle. They are first, third, second and fourth chamber units in turn. This requires the stream of heat exchange medium to be fed to a chamber unit to be controlled accordingly. According to a favourable embodiment, this may be done with a multiple-way valve as is shown in <figref idrefs="f0009">fig. 8a</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0010">8b</figref> in a cross-sectional view. A first circular section 801 is rotated with respect to a stationary section 802. The stationary section 802 contains a multitude of channels 803, 803' connected to the inlets 107 and outlets 108 of the chamber units via tubing 106 (visible in <figref idrefs="f0001">fig. 1a</figref>). The first circular section 801 defines a path that corresponds to the desired distribution pattern for heat exchange medium as shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">fig. 5</figref>. The first section 801 has an inlet 804 for hot heat exchange medium to be passed to first chamber unit 501-1 and an outlet 805 for discharging the exhausted heat exchange medium from fourth chamber unit 506-4. There is also an inlet 806 for passing cooling heat exchange medium through the second chamber unit 508-2 and an outlet 807 for discharging the cooling heat exchange medium. This may be in a closed loop, e.g. if a liquid-air heat exchanger is provided.</p><p id="p0064" num="0064">In operation, the first circular section is discontinuously rotated using a motor 847 (<figref idrefs="f0010">fig. 8b</figref>). During the actual rotation, the flow of heat exchange medium will be interrupted so as to reduce the likelihood of leakage of heat exchange medium. Once the inlets 804 and outlets 805 are aligned with the channels 803, 803', the feeding of heat exchange medium is resumed.</p><p id="p0065" num="0065">It should be noted that for the best performance, the flow of heat exchange medium through the chamber units 100 should be controlled with respect to volume and time. If the working medium doesn't heat up sufficiently, the duration and/or volume of heat exchange medium should be increased. If the energy conversion efficiency drops, the duration and/or volume of heat exchange medium should be reduced.<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></p><p id="p0066" num="0066">Again reference is made to <figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 4</figref> shows the channel arrangement of <figref idrefs="f0009">Fig. 8a</figref> in a schematic linear lay-out.</p><p id="p0067" num="0067">The second major way of operating uses heat exchange medium in a closed loop. Heat exchange medium is simply passed from one chamber unit to the next. However, between the chamber unit and the next, the heat exchange medium can be diverted to one of two heat exchangers. If the next chamber unit is to serve as a second chamber unit, the heat exchange medium is passed to a heat exchanger which is cooled. If the next chamber unit is to serve as a first chamber unit, the heat exchange medium is passed to a heat exchanger which is heated. To keep the heat exchange medium flowing, a pump will be provided.</p><p id="p0068" num="0068">Apart from the difference in heat exchange medium distribution indicated, the actual apparatus may otherwise be identical or substantially similar to the embodiment discussed in <figref idrefs="f0001">fig. 1a</figref>, <figref idrefs="f0002">1b</figref>, <figref idrefs="f0004">3</figref> , <figref idrefs="f0007">6</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0008">7</figref>, and does not require further elucidation.</p><p id="p0069" num="0069"><figref idrefs="f0011">Fig. 9</figref> shows a variant of the schematic bottom view of the chamber units of <figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 5</figref> and the way in which they are connected for an alternative way of operating. Cooled down heat exchange medium from the fourth chamber units 506-4 and 507-4 is discharged from these units, and may be passed to a heat exchanger (not shown) to be cooled, releasing the extracted heat to the environment, and resulting in fresh cooling heat exchange medium. The second chamber unit 508-2 is cooled with said fresh cooling heat exchange medium. The advantage of this method of operation is that it is easier to ensure that the non-gaseous working medium (paraffin) has contracted to the desired extent, allowing more work to be done in the fourth chamber units.</p><p id="p0070" num="0070">The invention may be varied within the scope of the enclosed independent claims. For example:
<ul><li>the cylinder of a chamber unit does not necessarily have to be at an end, but may for example be in the middle (T-shaped chamber). In fact, having multiple tubes connected to the chamber is an excellent opportunity to scale-up the apparatus according to the invention;</li><li>in the second major embodiment, the heat exchange medium itself may be subjected to heat exchange for heating and/or cooling, and passed to the first chamber unit and second chamber unit respectively before being passed to the fourth chamber unit and third chamber<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> unit respectively. This is most easily accomplished using a multiway-valve in which at one side of the first circular part there is a centrally located inlet for heated heat exchange medium and an outlet for heat exchange medium to be heated, and at the opposite side of the first circular part there is a centrally located inlet for cooled heat exchange medium and an outlet for heat exchange medium to be cooled. A pair of inlet and outlet may be concentrically placed. With a proper (insulating) choice of material and by keeping the parallel length short, this has little effect on the energy efficiency of the apparatus. The invention is also very suitable for the conversion of earth-derived heat (terrestrial heat/geothermal heat), which is currently financial less attractive because the length of the holes that have to be drilled in the earth is not primarily determined by the amount of heat that can be extracted but by the temperature level required to be of any use. Thanks to the device and method according to the present invention, a large saving can be realized because boreholes can be much shorter.</li></ul></p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56979080" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Verfahren zur Umwandlung von Wärmeenergie in mechanische Energie unter Verwendung eines nicht gasförmigen Arbeitsmediums, welches in einer Vorrichtung, die eine Mehrzahl von Wärmetauschern und eine abgehende Welle umfasst, vorhanden ist, wobei
<claim-text>- die Vorrichtung eine Vielzahl von Kammereinheiten (100, 100') umfasst, wobei eine Kammereinheit (100, 100') einen Einlass (107), um das Wärmeaustauschmedium einzubringen und einen Auslass (108) um das Wärmeaustauschmedium abzulassen sowie eine geschlossene Kammer (105), die eine Wärmetauscherwand (101) besitzt, um Wärme zwischen dem Arbeitsmedium innerhalb der geschlossenen Kammer (105) und dem Wärmeaustauschmedium, welches in die Kammereinheit eingebracht wird durch den besagten Einlass (107) um Wärmeaustauschmedium einzubringen, auszutauschen;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- die geschlossenen Kammern (105) der Kammereinheiten (100, 100') einen Zylinder (103) und einen Kolben (104) umfassen, wobei der Kolben (104) einer geschlossenen Kammer (105) mit der abgehenden Welle (119) wirkverbunden ist, die abgehende Welle (119) von dem Kolben (104) wirkverbunden angetrieben ist, wenn der Kolben (104) von einer ersten, relativ eingezogenen Position im Zylinder (103) in eine zweite, relativ herausragende Position bewegt wird und eine freie Bewegung der<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> abgehenden Welle (119) erlaubt wird, wenn der besagte Kolben (104) von der zweiten in die erste Position bewegt wird;<br/>
wobei</claim-text>
<claim-text>- das Wärmeaustauschmedium eine erste, hohe Temperatur hat, die verwendet wird, um das Arbeitsmedium, das in einer ersten Kammereinheit (501-1) anwesend ist, zu erhitzen, um die abgehende Welle (119) anzutreiben;<br/>
<b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>- das Wärmeaustauschmedium eine zweite, niedrige Temperatur, die verwendet wird um das Arbeitsmedium in einer zweiten Kammereinheit (508-2) zu kühlen, besitzt;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- das relativ kühle Wärmeaustauschmedium eine dritte Temperatur besitzt, die zwischen der ersten und der zweiten Temperatur liegt, durch den Einlass (107) einer dritten Kammereinheit (509-3), die relativ warmes Arbeitsmedium beinhaltet, eingebracht wird, um erwärmtes Wärmeaustauschmedium zu erhalten;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- das relativ warme Wärmeaustauschmedium eine vierte Temperatur besitzt, die zwischen der ersten und der zweiten Temperatur liegt, durch den Einlass (107) einer vierten Kammereinheit (502-4), die relativ kaltes Arbeitsmedium beinhaltet, eingebracht wird, um das Arbeitsmedium zu erhitzen und die abgehende Welle (119) anzutreiben;</claim-text>
wobei<br/>
die erste Kammereinheit (501-1), nachdem sie von dem Wärmeaustauschmedium mit der ersten Temperatur erhitzt wurde, als dritte Kammereinheit (512-3) benutzt wird, um Wärmeenergie aus besagter dritter Kammereinheit (512-3) zu gewinnen, um erwärmtes Wärmeaustauschmedium zu erhalten;<br/>
die zweite Kammereinheit (508-2), nachdem sie von dem Wärmeaustauschmedium mit der zweiten Temperatur gekühlt wurde, als vierte Kammereinheit (507-4) benutzt wird, um von relativ warmem Wärmeaustauschmedium mit der vierten Temperatur erwärmt zu werden; die dritte Kammereinheit (509-3), nachdem sie von dem relativ kalten Wärmeaustauschmedium mit der dritten Temperatur gekühlt wurde, als zweite Kammereinheit (508-2) benutzt wird; und<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> -->die vierte Kammereinheit (502-4), nachdem sie von dem relativ warmen Wärmeaustauschmedium mit der vierten Temperatur erwärmt wurde, als erste Kammereinheit (501-1) benutzt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, wobei wenigstens ein Paar von vierten Kammereinheiten (502-4 und 503-4) existiert, wobei die erste (502-4) des Paares von vierten Kammereinheiten (502-4 und 503-4) Arbeitsmedium mit einer relativ hohen Temperatur verglichen mit der Temperatur des Arbeitsmedium in der zweiten des Paars von vierten Kammereinheiten (502-4 und 503-4) umfasst, wobei die zweite des besagten Paares von vierten Kammereinheiten (502-4 und 503-4) erwärmt wird durch die Verwendung von Wärmeaustauschmedium, welches aus der ersten Kammereinheit (501-1) abgelassen wird, nach einem Wärmeaustausch mit besagter erster Kammereinheit (501-1); und die erste (502-4) des besagten Paares von vierten Kammereinheiten (502-4 und 503-4) wird erwärmt durch die Verwendung von relativ warmem Wärmeaustauschmedium, welches von einer dritten Kammereinheit (512-3) abgelassen wurde, welches eine Temperatur des Arbeitsmediums aufweist, welche der Temperatur des Arbeitsmedium in der ersten Kammereinheit (501-1) am nächsten kommt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 2, wobei wenigstens ein zweites Paar von vierten Kammereinheiten (504-4 und 505-4) vorhanden ist, wobei die erste Kammereinheit (504-4) des besagten zweiten Paares von vierten Kammereinheiten (504-4 und 505-4) Arbeitsmedium bei einer relativ hohen Temperatur verglichen mit der Temperatur des Arbeitsmediums in der zweiten Kammereinheit (505-4) des besagten zweiten Paares von vierten Kammereinheiten (504-4 und 505-4) umfasst und abgekühltes Wärmeaustauschmedium aus der ersten Kammereinheit (502-4) des Paares von vierten Kammereinheiten (502-4 und 503-4) verwendet wird um die erste Kammereinheit (504-4) des besagten zweiten Paares von vierten Kammereinheiten (504-4 und 505-4) zu erhitzen und abgekühltes Wärmeaustauschmedium aus der zweiten Kammereinheit (503-4) von dem ersten Paar von vierten Kammereinheiten (502-4 und 503-4) verwendet wird um die zweite Kammereinheit (505-4) des besagten zweiten Paares von vierten Kammereinheiten (504-4 und 505-4) zu erhitzen.<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 3, wobei abgekühltes Wärmeaustauschmedium aus der ersten Kammereinheit (507-4) des letzten Paares von vierten Kammereinheiten (506-4 und 507-4) aus der Vorrichtung abgelassen wird und der Verlust an Wärmeaustauschmedium dadurch kompensiert wird, dass Wärmeaustauschmedium mit der ersten Temperatur in die erste Kammereinheit (501-1) eingebracht wird; und abgekühltes Wärmeaustauschmedium aus der zweiten Kammereinheit (507-4) des letzten Paares von vierten Kammereinheiten (506-4 und 507-4) als relativ kaltes Wärmeaustauschmedium zum Abkühlen von Arbeitsmedium in einer dritten Kammereinheit (509-3) verwendet wird, wobei die Temperatur des Arbeitsmediums am nächsten an der Arbeitstemperatur der zweiten Kammereinheit (508-2) liegt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem oder mehreren der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei die abgehende Welle (119) mit einem Generator (661), zur Erzeugung von elektrischer Energie, verbunden ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem oder mehreren der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei die Vorrichtung ein zweites Arbeitsmedium umfasst, wobei sich die starke Volumenzunahme beim Erhitzen des Arbeitsmediums und des zweiten Arbeitsmediums unterscheiden.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem oder mehreren der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei das Wärmeaustauschmedium unter Verwendung von Solarenergie erwärmt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zur Umwandlung von Wärmeenergie in mechanische Energie unter Verwendung eines nicht gasförmigen Arbeitsmediums, wobei die Vorrichtung eine Vielzahl von Wärmetauschern und eine abgehende Welle (119) umfasst, wobei
<claim-text>- die Vorrichtung eine Vielzahl von Kammereinheiten (100, 100') umfasst, wobei eine Kammereinheit einen Einlass (107), um das Wärmeaustauschmedium einzubringen und einen Auslass (108), um besagtes Wärmeaustauschmedium, nachdem es einen Wärmeaustausch vollzogen hat, herauszuführen sowie eine geschlossene Kammer (105), die<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --> eine Wärmetauscherwand (101) besitzt, um Wärme zwischen dem Arbeitsmedium im Inneren der geschlossenen Kammer (105) und dem Wärmeaustauschermedium, welches durch den besagten Einlass (107) in die Kammer eingebracht wurde, um Wärmeaustauschmedium einzubringen, umfasst;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- die geschlossenen Kammern (105) einen Zylinder (103) und einen Kolben (104) umfassen, wobei der Kolben (104) einer geschlossenen Kammer (105) mit der abgehenden Welle (119) über ein Organ (115) wirkverbunden ist, welches dazu fähig ist die abgehende Welle (119) anzutreiben, wenn der Kolben (104) von einer ersten, relativ eingezogenen Position im Zylinder (103) in eine zweite, relativ herausragende Position bewegt wird, um die abgehende Welle (119) anzutreiben und eine freie Bewegung der abgehenden Welle (119) zu erlauben, wenn der besagte Kolben (104) von der zweiten in die erste Position bewegt wird;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- die Vorrichtung eine Einrichtung (800) um Wärmeaustauschmedium zu verteilen umfasst, um besagtes Wärmeaustauschmedium entlang der Wärmetauscherwände (101) über besagte Einlässe (107) und Auslässe (108) der Kammereinheiten (100, 100') zu verteilen, wobei die Einrichtung (800) dazu fähig ist, eine erste Kammereinheit (501-1) mit Wärmeaustauschmedium mit einer ersten hohen Temperatur zu versorgen, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die Einrichtung (800) dazu geeignet ist, eine zweite Kammereinheit (508-2) mit Wärmeaustauschmedium mit einer zweiten, niedrigen Temperatur zu versorgen, eine dritte Kammereinheit (509-3) mit Wärmeaustauschmedium mit einer dritten Temperatur, die zwischen der ersten und der zweiten Temperatur liegt, zu versorgen und eine vierte Kammereinheit (502-4) mit Wärmeaustauschmedium mit einer vierten Temperatur, die zwischen der ersten und der zweiten Temperatur liegt, zu versorgen.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Vorrichtung nach Anspruch 8, wobei die abgehende Welle (119) mit einem Generator (661) verbunden ist, um Elektrizität zu generieren.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Vorrichtung nach Anspruch 8 oder 9, wobei die Vorrichtung eine Kontrolleinrichtung (847) zum Starten und Stoppen des Flusses von<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --> Wärmeaustauschmittel durch wenigstens eine der Kammereinheiten (100, 100') umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Vorrichtung nach einem oder mehreren der Ansprüche 8 bis 10, wobei das Organ (115) einen Freilauf umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Vorrichtung nach Anspruch 11, wobei der Kolben (104) der Kammereinheit (100) mit einem Zahnrad (114) ausgestattet ist, die Vorrichtung ein Gehäuse (110) und eine Kette (111) umfasst, wobei ein erstes Ende (112) der Kette (111) mit dem Gehäuse (110) verbunden ist und die Kette (111) von diesem ersten Ende (112) aus über das besagte Zahnrad (114) und anschließend über den Freilauf (115) geführt ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Vorrichtung nach Anspruch 12, wobei der Kolben (104) einer dritten Kammereinheit (100') entgegengesetzt ausgerichtet ist zu einem Kolben (104) einer vierten Kammereinheit (100), das zweite verbleibende Ende (113) der Kette (111) ebenfalls an dem Gehäuse (110) befestigt ist und die dritten und vierten Kammereinheiten (100, 100') jeweils ein eigenes Zahnrad (114, 144') und einen eigenen Freilauf haben, aber sich eine Kette (111) teilen, wobei die Vorrichtung ein Spannorgan (116, 177) besitzt, welches die Kette (111) straff hält.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Vorrichtung nach einem oder mehreren der Ansprüche 8 bis 13, wobei die Einrichtung (800) um Wärmeaustauschmedium auf die Kammereinheiten (100, 100') zu verteilen ein erstes Glied (802) und ein zweites Glied (801) enthält, wobei das erste Glied (802) relativ zum zweiten Glied (801) um eine Rotationsachse in eine erste Richtung rotationsbeweglich ist, wobei das erste Glied (802) eine Vielzahl von Durchführungskanälen besitzt, wobei jeder dieser Durchführungskanäle zwei Oberflächenbereiche von besagtem erstem Glied (802) verbindet und geeignet ist Wärmeaustauschmedium zu den Kammereinheiten (100, 100') und von diesen weg zu leiten und das zweite Glied (801) eine Leitungsanordnung enthält, wobei
<claim-text>- für jede Kammereinheit der Vielzahl von Kammereinheiten (100, 100') umfasst das erste Glied (802) wenigstens einen ersten Kanal (803) um Wärmeaustauschmedium zu einer Kammereinheit zu leiten und<!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --> wenigstens einen zweiten Kanal (803') für Wärmeaustauschmedium, das durch besagte Kammereinheit hindurch geleitet wurde; der erste Kanal (803) ein Einlassende besitzt, welches dem zweiten Glied (801) zugewandt ist und ein Auslassende, welches nicht dem zweiten Glied (801) zugewandt ist; der zweite Kanal (803') ein Auslassende besitzt, welches dem zweiten Glied (801) zugewandt ist und ein Einlassende, welches nicht dem zweiten Glied (801) zugewandt ist, wobei die Einlassenden der ersten Kanäle (803) gleichmäßig über den Umfang eines Kreises, der seinen Mittelpunkt auf der Rotationsachse hat, verteilt sind und die Auslassenden der zweiten Kanäle (803') gleichmäßig über den Umfang eines zweiten Kreises, der seinen Mittelpunkt auf der Rotationsachse hat, verteilt sind;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- die Leitungsanordnung des zweiten Gliedes (801) eine Vielzahl von Durchführungskanälen besitzt, wobei die Durchführungskanäle umfassen
<claim-text># Einlässe, die versiegelnd mit den Auslässen der zweiten Kanäle (803') (803') des ersten Glieds (802) und mit einem Einlass für Wärmeaustauschmedium mit der ersten, hohen Temperatur und mit einem Einlass für Wärmeaustauschmedium mit einer zweiten, niedrigen Temperatur verbunden sind und</claim-text>
<claim-text># Auslässe, die versiegelnd mit den Einlässen der ersten Kanäle (803) des ersten Glieds (802) und mit einem Auslass, um Wärmeaustauschmedium aus der Vorrichtung abzulassen, verbunden sind;</claim-text>
besagte Einlässe des zweiten Glieds (801) über den ersten Kreis verteilt sind und besagte Auslässe des zweiten Glieds (801) über den zweiten Kreis verteilt sind und<br/>
der Durchführungskanal des zweiten Glieds (801) dazu fähig ist, den Auslass eines zweiten Kanals (803') eines ersten Glieds (802), der mit einer bestimmten Kammereinheit mit dem Einlass eines ersten Kanals (803) eines ersten Glieds (802), welches mit einer anderen Kammereinheit verbunden ist, zu verbinden.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56979081" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A method of converting thermal energy into mechanical energy using a non-gaseous working medium present in an apparatus comprising a plurality of heat exchangers and an outgoing shaft (119), wherein
<claim-text>- the apparatus comprises a multitude of chamber units (100, 100'), a chamber unit (100, 100') comprising an inlet (107) for introducing heat exchange medium and an outlet (108) for discharging heat exchange medium as well as a closed chamber (105) having a heat exchanger wall (101) for exchanging heat between working medium inside the closed chamber (105) and the heat exchange medium introduced into the chamber unit via said inlet (107) for introducing heat exchange medium;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- the closed chambers (105) of the chamber units (100, 100') comprise a cylinder (103) and a piston (104), wherein the piston (104) of a closed chamber (105) is workably connected to the outgoing shaft (119), the outgoing shaft (119) being workably driven by the piston (104) if the piston (104) is moved from a first, relatively retracted position in the cylinder (103) to a second, relatively protruding position and free movement of the outgoing shaft (119) is allowed if said piston (104) is moved from the second to the first position; wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>- heat exchange medium having a first, high temperature is used for heating working medium present in a first chamber unit (501-1) for driving the outgoing shaft (119);<br/>
<b>characterized in that</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>- heat exchange medium having a second, low temperature is used for cooling working medium in a second chamber unit (508-2);</claim-text>
<claim-text>- relatively cool heat exchange medium having a third temperature between the first and the second temperature is introduced via the inlet (107) of a third chamber unit (509-3) comprising relatively warm working medium to yield warmed-up heat exchange medium;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- relatively warm heat exchange medium having a fourth temperature between the first and the second temperature is introduced via the inlet (107) of a fourth chamber unit (502-4) comprising relatively<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> cool working medium to heat the working medium and drive the outgoing shaft (119);</claim-text>
wherein<br/>
after being heated by the heat exchange medium of the first temperature, the first chamber unit (501-1) is used as a third chamber unit (512-3) so as to extract thermal energy from said third chamber unit (512-3) to result in warmed-up heat exchange medium;<br/>
after being cooled by the heat exchange medium of the second temperature, the second chamber unit (508-2) is used as a fourth chamber unit (507-4) to be warmed by relatively warm heat exchange medium of a fourth temperature;<br/>
after being cooled down by relatively cool heat exchange medium of a third temperature, the third chamber unit (509-3) is used as a second chamber unit (508-2); and<br/>
after being warmed by relatively warm heat exchange medium of a fourth temperature the fourth chamber unit (502-4) is used as the first chamber unit (501-1).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The method according to claim 1, wherein there is at least one pair of fourth chamber units (502-4 and 503-4), the first (502-4) of the pair of fourth chamber units (502-4 and 503-4) comprising working medium at a relatively high temperature compared to the temperature of the working medium in the second of said pair of fourth chamber units (502-4 and 503-4), wherein the second of said pair of fourth chamber units (502-4 and 503-4) is heated using heat exchange medium discharged from the first chamber unit (501-1) after heat exchange with said first chamber unit (501-1); and the first (502-4) of said pair of fourth chamber units (502-4 and 503-4) is heated using relatively warm heat exchange medium discharged from a third chamber unit (512-3) that has a temperature of the working medium closest to the temperature of the working medium of the first chamber unit (501-1).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The method according to claim 2, wherein there is at least a second pair of fourth chamber units (504-4 and 505-4), the first chamber unit (504-4) of said second pair of fourth chamber units (504-4 and 505-4) comprising working medium at a relatively high temperature compared to the temperature of the working medium in the second chamber unit (505-4) of said second pair of fourth chamber units (504-4<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> and 505-4), and cooled down heat exchange medium from the first chamber unit (502-4) of the pair of fourth chamber units (502-4 and 503-4) is used to heat the first chamber unit (504-4) of said second pair of fourth chamber units (504-4 and 505-4) and cooled down heat exchange medium from the second chamber unit (503-4) of the first pair of fourth chamber units (502-4 and 503-4) is used to heat the second chamber unit (505-4) of said second pair of fourth chamber units (504-4 and 505-4).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The method according to claim 3, wherein cooled-down heat exchange medium from the first chamber unit (507-4) of the last pair of fourth chamber units (506-4 and 507-4) is discharged from the apparatus and the loss of heat exchange medium being compensated by the heat exchange medium having the first temperature introduced in the first chamber unit (501-1); and cooled-down heat exchange medium from the second chamber unit (507-4) of the last pair of fourth chamber units (506-4 and 507-4) is used as relatively cool heat exchange medium to cool working medium in a third chamber unit (509-3) having a working medium temperature closest to the working temperature of the second chamber unit (508-2).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The method according to any of the preceding claims, wherein the outgoing shaft (119) is connected to a generator (661) for generating electricity.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The method according to any of the preceding claims, wherein the apparatus comprises a second working medium, the working medium and the second working medium differing in super expansion range.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The method according to any of the preceding claims, wherein the heat exchange medium is heated using solar energy.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>An apparatus for converting thermal energy into mechanical energy using a non-gaseous working medium, the apparatus comprising a plurality of heat exchangers and an outgoing shaft (119), wherein
<claim-text>- the apparatus comprises a multitude of chamber units (100, 100'), a chamber unit comprising an inlet (107) for introducing heat exchange<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> medium and an outlet (108) for discharging said heat exchange medium after having undergone heat exchange as well as a closed chamber (105) having a heat exchanger wall (101) for exchanging heat between working medium inside the closed chamber (105) and the heat exchange medium introduced into the chamber unit via said inlet (107) for introducing heat exchange medium;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- the closed chambers (105) comprising a cylinder (103) and a piston (104), the piston (104) of a closed chamber (105) being workably connected to the outgoing shaft (119) via an organ (115) capable of driving the outgoing shaft (119) if the piston (104) is moved from a first, relatively retracted position in the cylinder (103) to a second, relatively protruding position for driving the outgoing shaft (119) and allowing free movement of the outgoing shaft (119) if said piston (104) is moved from the second to the first position;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- the apparatus comprises a device (800) for distributing a heat exchange medium for passing said heat exchange medium along the heat exchanger walls (101) via said inlets (107) and outlets (108) of the chamber units (100, 100'), the device (800) being capable of providing a first chamber unit (501-1) with heat exchange medium of a first high temperature, <b>characterized in that</b> the device (800) is capable of providing a second chamber unit (508-2) with heat exchange medium with a second low temperature, providing a third chamber unit (509-3) with heat exchange medium of a third temperature between the first and the second temperature and providing a fourth chamber unit (502-4) with heat exchange medium of a fourth temperature between the first and the second temperature.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The apparatus according to claim 8, wherein the outgoing shaft (119) is connected to a generator (661) for generating electricity.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The apparatus according to claim 8 or 9, wherein the apparatus comprises a control device (847) for starting and stopping the flow of heat exchange medium through at least one of the chamber units (100, 100').</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>The apparatus according to any of the claims 8 to 10, wherein the organ (115) comprises a freewheel.<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>The apparatus according to claim 11, wherein the piston (104) of a chamber unit (100) is provided with a sprocket (114), the apparatus comprises a frame (110) and a chain (111), a first end (112) of the chain (111) being attached to the frame (110) and the chain (111) from that first end (112) being passed over said sprocket (114) and subsequently over the freewheel (115).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>The apparatus according to claim 12, wherein the piston (104) of a third chamber unit (100') is aligned opposite to a piston (104) of a fourth chamber unit (100), the second, remaining end (113) of the chain (111) being attached to the frame (110) as well and the third and fourth chamber units (100, 100') each having their own sprocket (114, 114') and freewheel but sharing the chain (111), the apparatus being provided with a tensioning organ (116, 117) for keeping the chain (111) taut.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>The apparatus according to any of the claims 8 to 13, wherein the device (800) for distributing heat exchange medium over chamber units (100, 100') comprises a first member (802) and a second member (801), the first member (802) being rotatable relative to the second member (801) around an axis of rotation in a first direction, the first member (802) comprising a multitude of through channels, each of these through channels connecting two surface areas of said first member (802) and suitable for passing heat exchange medium to and from chamber units (100, 100') and the second member (801) comprising a conduit arrangement, wherein
<claim-text>- for every chamber unit of the multitude of chamber units (100, 100') the first member (802) comprises at least a first channel (803) for passing heat exchange medium to a chamber unit and at least one second channel (803') for heat exchange medium passed through said chamber unit; the first channel (803) having an inlet end facing the second member (801) and an outlet end not facing the second member (801); the second channel (803') having an outlet end facing the second member (801) and an inlet end not facing the second member (801), the inlet ends of the first channels (803) being distributed evenly spaced over the circumference of a circle having its center on the axis of rotation and the outlet ends of the second channels (803')<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --> (803') being distributed evenly spaced over the circumference of a second circle having its center on the axis of rotation;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- the conduit arrangement of the second member (801) comprises a multitude of through channels, the through channels having</claim-text>
# inlets for sealingly connecting to the outlets of second channels (803') (803') of the first member (802) and to an inlet for heat exchange medium of the first high temperature and to an inlet for heat exchange medium of a second low temperature, and<br/>
# outlets for sealingly connecting to the inlets of first channels (803) of the first member (802), and an outlet for discharging heat exchange medium from the apparatus;<br/>
said inlets of the second member (801) being distributed over the first circle and said outlets of the second member (801) being distributed over the second circle, and<br/>
the through channel of the second member (801) being capable of connecting the outlet of a second channel (803') of the first member (802) connected to a particular chamber unit with the inlet of a first channel (803) of the first member (802) connected to a different chamber unit.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56979082" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Un procédé de conversion d'énergie thermique en énergie mécanique en utilisant un fluide de travail non gazeux présent dans un appareil comprenant une pluralité d'échangeurs de chaleur et un arbre de sortie (119), dans lequel
<claim-text>- l'appareil comprend une multitude d'unités à chambres (100, 100'), une unité à chambre (100, 100') comprenant une entrée (107) pour introduire un fluide d'échange de chaleur et une sortie (108) pour évacuer le fluide d'échange de chaleur ainsi qu'une chambre fermée (105) ayant une paroi échangeuse de chaleur (101) pour échanger de la chaleur entre le fluide de travail à l'intérieur de la chambre fermée (105) et le fluide d'échange de chaleur introduit dans l'unité à chambre par ladite entrée (107) pour introduire un fluide d'échange de chaleur ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- les chambres fermées (105) des unités à chambres (100, 100') comprennent un cylindre (103) et un piston (104), dans lequel le piston (104) d'une chambre fermée (105) est relié à l'arbre de sortie (119), l'arbre de sortie (119) étant entraîné par le piston (104) si le piston (104) est déplacé depuis une première position comparativement rétractée dans le cylindre (103) vers une deuxième position comparativement en saillie, et un mouvement libre de l'arbre de sortie (119) est autorisé si ledit piston (104) est déplacé de la deuxième à la première position, dans lequel</claim-text>
<claim-text>- le fluide d'échange de chaleur ayant une première température, élevée, est utilisé pour chauffer le fluide de travail présent dans une première unité à chambre (501-1) en vue d'entraîner l'arbre de sortie (119) ;<br/>
<b>caractérisé en ce que</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>- le fluide d'échange de chaleur ayant une deuxième température, faible, est utilisé pour refroidir le fluide de travail dans une deuxième unité à chambre (508-2) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- le fluide d'échange de chaleur relativement froid, ayant une troisième température située entre la première et la deuxième température, est introduit par l'entrée (107) d'une troisième unité à chambre (509-3) comprenant un fluide de travail relativement chaud pour réchauffer le fluide d'échange de chaleur ;<!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>- le fluide d'échange de chaleur relativement chaud, ayant une quatrième température située entre la première et la deuxième température, est introduit par l'entrée (107) d'une quatrième unité à chambre (502-4) comprenant du fluide de travail relativement frais pour chauffer le fluide de travail et entraîner l'arbre de sortie (119) ;</claim-text>
dans lequel<br/>
après avoir été chauffée par le fluide d'échange de chaleur ayant la première température, la première unité à chambre (501-1) est utilisée en tant que une troisième unité à chambre (512-3) de manière à extraire de l'énergie thermique depuis ladite troisième unité à chambre (512-3), avec pour résultat un fluide d'échange de chaleur réchauffé ;<br/>
après avoir été refroidi par le fluide d'échange de chaleur ayant la deuxième température, la deuxième unité à chambre (508-2) est utilisée en tant que quatrième unité à chambre (507-4) pour être échauffée par un fluide d'échange de chaleur relativement chaud ayant une quatrième température ;<br/>
après avoir été refroidie par du fluide d'échange de chaleur relativement froid ayant une troisième température, la troisième unité à chambre (509-3) est utilisée en tant qu'une deuxième unité à chambre (508-2), et<br/>
après avoir été chauffée par du fluide d'échange de chaleur relativement chaud ayant une quatrième température, la quatrième unité à chambre (502-4) est utilisée en tant que la première unité à chambre (501-1).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Le procédé selon la revendication 1, dans lequel il y a au moins une paire de quatrièmes unités à chambres (502-4 et 503-4), la première (502-4) de la paire de quatrièmes unités à chambres (502-4 et 503-4) comprenant du fluide de travail à une température relativement élevée par rapport à la température du fluide de travail dans la deuxième de ladite paire de quatrièmes unités à chambres (502-4 et 503-4), la deuxième de ladite paire de quatrièmes unités à chambres (502-4 et 503-4) étant chauffée en utilisant un fluide d'échange thermique délivré par la première unité à chambre (501-1) après échange de chaleur avec ladite première unité à chambre (501-1) et la première (502-4) de ladite paire de quatrièmes unités à chambres (502-4 et 503-4) est chauffée en utilisant un fluide d'échange de chaleur relativement chaud<!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --> provenant d'une troisième unité à chambre (512-3), ayant une température du fluide de travail plus proche de la température du fluide de travail de la première unité à chambre (501-1).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Le procédé selon la revendication 2, dans lequel il y a au moins une deuxième paire de quatrièmes unités à chambres (504-4 et 505-4), la première unité à chambre (504-4) de ladite deuxième paire de quatrièmes unités à chambres (504-4 et 505-4) comprenant du fluide de travail à une température relativement élevée par rapport à la température du fluide de travail dans la deuxième unité à chambre (505-4) de ladite deuxième paire de quatrièmes unités à chambres (504-4 et 505-4), et du fluide d'échange de chaleur refroidi provenant de la première unité à chambre (502-4) de la paire de quatrièmes unités à chambres (502-4 et 503-4) est utilisé pour chauffer la première unité à chambre (504-4) de ladite deuxième paire de quatrièmes unités à chambres (504-4 et 505-4) et du fluide d'échange de chaleur refroidi provenant de la deuxième unité à chambre (503-4) de la première paire de quatrièmes unités à chambres (502-4 et 503-4) est utilisé pour chauffer la deuxième unité à chambre (505-4) de ladite deuxième paire de quatrièmes unités à chambres (504-4 et 505-4).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Le procédé selon la revendication 3, dans lequel du fluide d'échange de chaleur refroidi provenant de la première unité à chambre (507-4) de la dernière paire de quatrièmes unités à chambres (506-4 et 507-4) est évacué de l'appareil et la perte du fluide d'échange de chaleur est compensée par le fluide d'échange de chaleur ayant la première température introduite dans la première unité à chambre (501-1), et du fluide d'échange de chaleur refroidi provenant de la deuxième unité à chambre (507-4) de la dernière paire de quatrièmes unités à chambres (506-4 et 507-4) est utilisé en tant que fluide d'échange de chaleur relativement froid pour refroidir le fluide de travail dans une troisième unité à chambre (509-3) ayant une température de fluide de travail plus proche de la température de travail de la deuxième unité à chambre (508-2).<!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Le procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans lequel l'arbre de sortie (119) est relié à un générateur (661) pour générer de l'électricité.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Le procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans lequel l'appareil comprend un deuxième fluide de travail, le fluide de travail et le deuxième fluide de travail différant en ce qui concerne une gamme de super expansion.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Le procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans lequel le fluide d'échange de chaleur est chauffé par de l'énergie solaire.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Un appareil pour convertir de l'énergie thermique en énergie mécanique au moyen d'un fluide de travail non gazeux, le dispositif comprenant une pluralité d'échangeurs de chaleur et un arbre de sortie (119), dans lequel<br/>
l'appareil comprend une multitude d'unités à chambres (100, 100'), une unité à chambre comprenant une entrée (107) pour introduire du fluide d'échange de chaleur et une sortie (108) pour évacuer ledit fluide d'échange de chaleur après avoir subi un échange de chaleur, ainsi qu'une chambre fermée (105) ayant une paroi (101) formant échangeur de chaleur pour échanger de la chaleur entre le fluide de travail situé à l'intérieur de la chambre fermée (105) et le fluide d'échange de chaleur introduit dans l'unité à chambre par ladite entrée (107) qui permet d'introduire un fluide d'échange de chaleur ;
<claim-text>- les chambres fermées (105) comprennent un cylindre (103) et un piston (104), le piston (104) d'une chambre fermée (105) étant relié à l'arbre de sortie (119) par l'intermédiaire d'un organe (115) apte à entraîner l'arbre de sortie (119) si le piston (104) est déplacé depuis une première position, comparativement rétractée, dans le cylindre (103), vers une deuxième position, comparativement en saillie, pour entraîner l'arbre de sortie (119) et permettant le mouvement libre de l'arbre de sortie (119) si ledit piston (104) est déplacé de la deuxième à la première position ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- l'appareil comprend un dispositif (800) destiné à distribuer un fluide d'échange de chaleur de manière à faire passer ledit fluide d'échange de chaleur le long des<!-- EPO <DP n="36"> --> parois formant échangeur de chaleur (101) entre lesdits orifices d'entrée (107) et lesdites sorties (108) des unités à chambres (100, 100'), le dispositif (800) étant apte à fournir une première unité à chambre (501-1) avec du fluide d'échange thermique ayant une première température, élevée, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> le dispositif (800) est apte à fournir une deuxième unité à chambre (508-2) avec du fluide d'échange de chaleur ayant une deuxième température, basse, une troisième unité à chambre (509-3) avec un fluide d'échange de chaleur ayant une troisième température située entre la première et la deuxième températures, et une quatrième unité à chambre (502-4) avec un fluide d'échange de chaleur ayant une quatrième température située entre la première et la deuxième températures.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>L'appareil selon la revendication 8, dans lequel l'arbre de sortie (119) est relié à un générateur (661) pour générer de l'électricité.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>L'appareil selon la revendication 8 ou la revendication 9, dans lequel l'appareil comprend un dispositif de commande (847) pour libérer et arrêter l'écoulement de fluide d'échange de chaleur à travers au moins une des unités à chambres (100, 100').</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>L'appareil selon l'une quelconque des revendications 8 à 10, dans lequel l'organe (115) comprend une roue libre.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>L'appareil selon la revendication 11, dans lequel le piston (104) d'une unité à chambre (100) est pourvu d'une roue dentée (114), l'appareil comprend un châssis (110) et une chaîne (111), une première extrémité (112) de la chaîne (111) étant fixée au châssis (110) et la chaîne (111), à partir de cette première extrémité (112), étant passé au-dessus de ladite roue dentée (114) et ensuite sur la roue libre (115).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>L'appareil selon la revendication 12, dans lequel le piston (104) d'une troisième unité à chambre (100') est aligné en face d'un piston (104) d'une quatrième unité à chambre (100), la deuxième extrémité (313) restante de la chaîne (111) étant<!-- EPO <DP n="37"> --> également fixée au châssis (110), et les troisième et quatrième unités à chambres (100, 100') ayant chacune leur propre roue dentée (114, 114') et roue libre, mais partageant la chaîne (111), l'appareil étant muni d'un organe de mise en tension (116, 117) pour maintenir la chaîne (111) tendue.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>L'appareil selon l'une quelconque des revendications 8 à 13, dans lequel le dispositif (800) de distribution de fluide d'échange de chaleur vers des unités à chambres (100, 100') comprend un premier organe (802) et un deuxième organe (801), le premier organe (802) étant pate à tourner par rapport au deuxième organe (801) autour d'un axe de rotation dans un premier sens, le premier organe (802) comprenant une multitude de conduits traversants, chacun de ces conduits traversants reliant deux zones de surface dudit premier organe (802) et étant adapté pour permettre le passage de fluide d'échange de chaleur vers les unités à chambres (100, 100') et depuis ces unités, et le deuxième organe (801) comportant un agencement de conduits,
<claim-text>- pour chaque unité à chambre de la multitude d'unités à chambres (104, 100'), le premier organe (802) comprend au moins un premier conduit (803) pour permettre le passage du fluide d'échange de chaleur vers une unité à chambre et au moins un deuxième conduit (803') pour du fluide d'échange de chaleur ayant traversé ladite unité à chambre ; le premier conduit (803) ayant une extrémité d'entrée située en regard du deuxième organe (801) et une extrémité de sortie située non en regard du deuxième organe (801) ; le deuxième conduit (803') ayant une extrémité de sortie située en regard du deuxième organe (801) et une extrémité d'entrée située non en regard du deuxième organe (801), les extrémités d'entrée des premiers conduits (803) étant réparties de façon uniformément espacée sur la circonférence d'un cercle ayant son centre sur l'axe de rotation et les extrémités de sortie des deuxièmes conduits (803') étant répartis de façon uniformément espacée sur la circonférence d'un deuxième cercle ayant son centre situé sur l'axe de rotation ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- l'agencement de conduit du deuxième organe (801) comprend une multitude de conduits traversants, les conduits traversants ayant</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="38"> -->
# des entrées pour un raccordement étanche aux sorties des deuxièmes conduits (803') (803') du premier organe (802) et à une entrée pour du fluide d'échange de chaleur ayant la première température élevée et à une entrée pour le fluide d'échange de chaleur ayant une deuxième température, faible, et<br/>
# des sorties pour un raccordement étanche aux entrées des premiers conduits (803) du premier organe (802), et à une sortie pour évacuer du fluide d'échange de chaleur hors de l'appareil ;<br/>
lesdites entrées du deuxième organe (801) étant réparties sur le premier cercle et lesdites sorties du deuxième organe (801) étant réparties sur le deuxième cercle, et<br/>
le conduit traversant du deuxième organe (801) étant apte à relier la sortie d'un deuxième conduit (803') du premier organe (802) reliée à une unité à chambre déterminée à l'entrée d'un premier conduit (803) du premier organe (802) relié à une unité à chambre différente.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16668761" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="39"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1a"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="158" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="40"> --><figure id="f0002" num="1b"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="165" he="182" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="41"> --><figure id="f0003" num="2"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="125" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="42"> --><figure id="f0004" num="3"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="138" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="43"> --><figure id="f0005" num="4a,4b,4c"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="156" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="44"> --><figure id="f0006" num="5"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="165" he="183" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="45"> --><figure id="f0007" num="6"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="165" he="219" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="46"> --><figure id="f0008" num="7"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="165" he="185" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="47"> --><figure id="f0009" num="8a"><img id="if0009" file="imgf0009.tif" wi="164" he="203" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="48"> --><figure id="f0010" num="8b"><img id="if0010" file="imgf0010.tif" wi="165" he="183" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="49"> --><figure id="f0011" num="9"><img id="if0011" file="imgf0011.tif" wi="165" he="179" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
