<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2307201-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2307201" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="41203645" file-reference-id="315037" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146588643" ucid="EP-2307201-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2307201</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-09788954-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154850835" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>09788954</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20090720</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140556541" ucid="US-18352908-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>18352908</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20080731</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140549536" ucid="US-2009004198-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>2009004198</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20090720</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130718</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989326223" load-source="docdb">B41J   2/325       20060101AFI20100217BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989624777" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B41J   2/325       20130101 FI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370562" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">*</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370563" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">THERMALLY CONDUCTIVE, ELECTRICALLY ISOLATED PEEL MEMBER ASSEMBLY</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370564" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">ENSEMBLE ÉLÉMENT DE PELAGE THERMIQUEMENT CONDUCTEUR, ÉLECTRIQUEMENT ISOLÉ</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919504557" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>KODAK ALARIS INC</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919536644" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>KODAK ALARIS INC.</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919514814" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>MINDLER ROBERT FREDRIC</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919514687" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>MINDLER, ROBERT, FREDRIC</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919024047" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>MINDLER, ROBERT, FREDRIC</last-name><address><street>343 State Street</street><city>Rochester NY 14650</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919523231" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>ELLIS RICHARD HAROLD</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919531124" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>ELLIS, RICHARD, HAROLD</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919024048" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>ELLIS, RICHARD, HAROLD</last-name><address><street>343 State Street</street><city>Rochester NY 14650</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919516310" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>HILTON DAVID BRUCE</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919527755" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>HILTON, DAVID, BRUCE</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919024049" load-source="patent-office" sequence="3" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>HILTON, DAVID, BRUCE</last-name><address><street>1832 Kennedy Road</street><city>Webster, New York 14580</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919024051" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Kodak Alaris Inc.</last-name><iid>101421534</iid><address><street>2400 Mount Read Boulevard</street><city>Rochester, NY 14650</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919024050" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Wagner &amp; Geyer</last-name><iid>100061282</iid><address><street>Partnerschaft Patent- und Rechtsanwälte Gewürzmühlstrasse 5</street><city>80538 München</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="US-2009004198-W"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2009004198</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20090720</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2010014154-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2010014154</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20100204</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549878676" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549882357" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549895059" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549804580" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549872422" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549878677" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549882370" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549872423" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549872424" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549788750" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549895060" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549804581" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549882371" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549872425" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549882372" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549878682" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549924923" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549872430" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549804582" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549872431" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549895065" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549787519" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549895066" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549895067" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549787520" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS549787525" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549787526" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549804583" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549787527" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549924924" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549788751" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549787528" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549882373" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549804588" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549804589" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS549872432" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63961063" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001"><b>FIELD OF THE INVENTION</b></heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to thermal printers of type that apply material from a donor web to a receiver web in order to form images on the receiver web.</p><heading id="h0002"><b>BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</b></heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">In thermal printing, it is generally well known to render images by heating and pressing one or more donor materials such as a dye, colorant or other coating against a receiver web. The donor materials are provided in sized donor patches on a movable web known as a donor ribbon. The donor patches are organized on the ribbon into donor sets; each set containing all of the donor patches that are to be used to record an image on the receiver web. For full color images, multiple color dye patches can be used, such as yellow, magenta, and cyan donor dye patches. Arrangements of other color patches can be used in like fashion within a donor set. Additionally, each donor set can include an overcoat or sealant layer.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">Thermal printers offer a wide range of advantages in photographic printing including the provision of truly continuous tone scale variation and the ability to deposit, as a part of the printing process a protective overcoat layer to protect the images formed thereby from mechanical and environmental damage. Accordingly, the most popular photographic kiosks and home photo printers currently use thermal printing technology.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">Electrostatic charge can be generated in thermal printers by peeling donor media from receiver media. Electrostatic charge is a significant concern and problem for makers of thermal printers, because excess static charge leads to jamming and buckling of print media as the print media traverses through the thermal printer. Conventional approaches to addressing static charge focus on the media itself in that, ionic or nonionic anti-stats are added to the media; for example, the receiver media. This anti-static material is adjusted positionally to<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> reduce static charge. In other words, the anti-static material may be placed in multiple locations with varying effectiveness. The anti-stats may be placed in various layers of the receiver and donor media.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">Limitations of anti-stats include, for ionic anti-stats, their ineffectiveness in high humidity. Both ionic and non-ionic anti-stats are subject to great expense, and imprecise usage that is dependent upon the receiver media impacted with reduction of static charge. Another disadvantage associated with non-ionic anti-stats is an addition of unwanted color in white areas of a print.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="JP630147168A"><text>JP-A-630147168</text></patcit> shows the preamble of claim 1.</p><heading id="h0003"><b>SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</b></heading><p id="p0007" num="0007">One aspect of the present invention thermal printer according to claim 1.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">Another aspect of the invention provides a method for eliminating built-up electrical static charge in a thermally conductive peel member assembly according to claim 3.</p><heading id="h0004"><b>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</b></heading><p id="p0009" num="0009"><ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> shows a printer having one embodiment of the control system of the invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> shows a bottom view of one embodiment of a thermal printhead used in the printer of <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> shows a donor web;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 4</figref> shows a thermal printhead, platen, donor web, and receiver web during printing;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 5</figref> shows a thermal printhead, platen, donor web, and receiver web during printing;<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates an exemplary thermal printer system;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005 f0006">FIG. 7</figref> illustrates electrical isolation from ground of peel member assembly;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 8</figref> illustrates a triboelectric effect upon the peel member assembly;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 9</figref> illustrates no triboelectric effect upon the peel member assembly;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 10</figref> illustrates triboelectric effect at critical contact point for peel member, donor web, and receiver web;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0010">FIG. 11</figref> illustrates a prior art multi-headed printer; and</li><li><figref idrefs="f0011">FIG. 12</figref> shows an apparatus for measuring surface voltage on a sheet of receiver material.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0005"><b>DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</b></heading><p id="p0010" num="0010"><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> shows one exemplary embodiment a printer 18 of the invention. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, printer 18 has a controller 20 that causes thermal printhead 22 to record images on a receiver web 26 by applying heat and pressure to transfer material from a donor web 30 to receiver web 26. Controller 20 can include, but is not limited to: a programmable digital computer, a programmable microprocessor, a programmable logic controller, a series of electronic circuits, a series of electronic circuits reduced to the form of an integrated circuit, or a series of discrete components. In the embodiment of <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, controller 20 also controls a receiver web take-up roller 42, a receiver web supply roller 44, a donor web take-up roller 48, and a donor web supply roller 50; which are each motorized for rotation on command of the controller 20 to effect movement of receiver web 26 and donor web 30.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011"><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> shows a bottom view of an illustration of one embodiment of a conventional thermal printhead 22 with an array of thermal resistors 43 fabricated in a ceramic substrate 45. A heat sink 47, typically in the form of an aluminum backing plate, is fixed to a left side 49 of ceramic substrate 45. Heat sink 47 rapidly dissipates heat generated by the thermal resistors 43 during printing. In the embodiment shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>, thermal resistors 43 are arranged in<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> a linear array extending across platen roller 46 (shown in phantom). Such a linear arrangement of thermal resistors 43 is commonly known as a heat line or print line. However, other non-linear arrangements of thermal resistors 43 can be used. Further, it will be appreciated that there are a wide variety of other arrangements of thermal resistors 43 and thermal printheads 22 that can be used in conjunction with the present invention.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">Thermal resistors 43 are adapted to generate heat in proportion to an amount of electrical energy that passes through thermal resistors 43. During printing, controller 20 transmits signals to a circuit board 51 to which thermal resistors 43 are connected causing different amounts of electrical energy to be applied to thermal resistors 43 so as to selectively heat donor web 30 in a manner that is intended to cause donor material from donor patches 34, 36, 38, and 40 to be applied to receiver web 26 in a desirable manner.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">As is shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3</figref>, donor web 30 comprises a first donor patch set 32.1 having a yellow donor patch 34.1, a magenta donor patch 36.1, a cyan donor patch 38.1, a clear donor patch 40.1; and a second donor patch set 32.2 having a yellow donor patch 34.2, a magenta donor patch 36.2, a cyan donor patch 38.2, and a clear donor patch 40.2. Each donor patch set 32 has a leading edge L and a trailing edge T. In order to provide a full color image with a clear protective coating, the four patches of each set 32.1 and 32.2; etc., are printed, in registration with each other, onto a common image receiving area 52 of receiver web 26 shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 4</figref>. Circuit board 51 provides variable electrical signals to thermal resistors 43 in accordance with the signal from controller 20.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">A first color is printed in the conventional direction, from right to left as seen by the viewer in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGS. 1</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0003">3</figref>. During printing, controller 20 raises thermal printhead 22 and actuates donor web supply roller 50 and donor web take-up roller 48 to advance a leading edge L of a first donor patch set 32.1 to thermal printhead 22. In the embodiment illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0001 f0002 f0003">FIGS. 1 through 3</figref>, leading edge L for first donor patch set 32.1 is defined by a leading edge of a yellow donor patch 34.1. As will be discussed in greater detail below, the position of this leading edge L can be determined by using a position sensor to detect a marking indicia<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> on donor web 30 that has a known position relative to the leading edge of yellow donor patch 34.1 or by directly detecting leading edge of yellow donor patch 34.1 as will be discussed in greater detail below.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">Controller 20 also actuates receiver web take-up roller 42 and receiver web supply roller 44 so that image receiving area 52 of receiver web 26 is positioned with respect to the thermal printhead 22. In the embodiment illustrated, image receiving area 52 is defined by a leading edge LER and a trailing edge TER on receiver web 26. Donor web 30 and receiver web 26 are positioned so that leading edge LED of yellow donor patch 34.1 is registered at thermal printhead 22 with leading edge LER of image receiving area 52. Controller 20 then causes a motor or other conventional structure (not shown) to lower thermal printhead 22 so that a lower surface of donor web 30 engages receiver web 26 which is supported by platen roller 46. This creates a pressure holding donor web 30 against receiver web 26.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">Controller 20 then actuates receiver web take-up roller 42, receiver web supply roller 44, donor web take-up roller 48, and donor web supply roller 50 to move receiver web 26 and donor web 30 together past the thermal printhead 22. Concurrently, controller 20 selectively operates heater elements in thermal printhead 22 to transfer donor material yellow donor patch 34.1 to receiver web 26.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">As donor web 30 and receiver web 26 leave the thermal printhead 22, a stripping plate 54 separates donor web 30 from receiver web 26. Donor web 30 continues over idler roller 56 toward the donor web take-up roller 48. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 4</figref>, the trailing edge TER of image receiving area 52 of receiver web 26 remains on platen roller 46. Controller 20 then adjusts the position of donor web 30 and receiver web 26 using a predefined pattern of donor web movement so that a leading edge of each of the remaining donor patches 36.1, 38.1 and 40.1 in the first donor patch set 32.1 are brought into alignment with leading edge LER of image receiving area 52 and the printing process is repeated to transfer further material as desired to complete image format.<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></p><p id="p0018" num="0018">Controller 20 operates the printer 18 based upon input signals from a user input system 62, an output system 64, a memory 68, a communication system 74, and sensor system 80. User input system 62 can comprise any form of transducer or other device capable of receiving an input from a user and converting this input into a form that can be used by controller 20. For example, user input system 62 can comprise a touch screen input, a touch pad input, a 4-way switch, a 6-way switch, an 8-way switch, a stylus system, a trackball system, a joystick system, a voice recognition system, a gesture recognition system or other such systems. An output system 64, such as a display, is optionally provided and can be used by controller 20 to provide human perceptible signals for feedback, informational or other purposes.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">Data including, but not limited to, control programs, digital images and metadata can also be stored in memory 68. Memory 68 can take many forms and can include without limitation conventional memory devices including solid state, magnetic, optical or other data storage devices. In the embodiment of <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, memory 68 is shown having a removable memory interface 71 for communicating with removable memory (not shown) such as a magnetic, optical or magnetic disks. In the embodiment of <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, memory 68 is also shown having a hard drive 72 that is fixed with printer 18 and a remote memory 76 that is external to controller 20 such as a personal computer, computer network or other imaging system.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">In the embodiment shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, controller 20 has a communication system 74 for communicating external devices such as remote memory 76. Communication system 74 can be for example, an optical, radio frequency circuit or other transducer that converts electronic signals representing an image and other data into a form that can be conveyed to a separate device by way of an optical signal, radio frequency signal or other form of signal. Communication system 74 can also be used to receive a digital image and other information from a host computer or network (not shown). Controller 20 can also receive information and instructions from signals received by communication system 74.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p><p id="p0021" num="0021">Sensor system 80 includes circuits and systems that are adapted to detect conditions within printer 18 and, optionally, in the environment surrounding printer 18 and to convert this information into a form that can be used by controller 20 in governing printing operations. Sensor system 80 can take a wide variety of forms depending on the type of media therein and the operating environment in which printer 18 is to be used.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">In the embodiment of <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, sensor system 80 includes an optional donor position sensor 82 that is adapted to detect the position of donor web 30 and a receiver web position sensor 84. Controller 20 cooperates with donor position sensor 82 to monitor donor web 30 during movement thereof so that controller 20 can detect one or more conditions on donor web 30 that indicate a leading edge of a donor patch set. In this regard, a donor web 30 can be provided that has markings or other optically, magnetically or electronically sensible indicia between each donor patch set 32 and/or between donor patches 34, 36, 38, and 40. Where such markings or indicia are provided, donor position sensor 82 is provided to sense these markings or indicia and to provide signals to controller 20. Controller 20 can use these markings and indicia to determine when donor web 30 is positioned with the leading edge of the donor patch set at thermal printhead 22. In a similar way, controller 20 can use signals from receiver web position sensor 84 to monitor the position of the receiver web 26 to align receiver web 26 during printing. Receiver web position sensor 84 can be adapted to sense markings or other optically, magnetically or electronically sensible indicia between each image receiving area of receiver web 26.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">During a full image printing operation, controller 20 causes donor web 30 to be advanced in a predetermined pattern of distances so as to cause a leading edge of each of the first donor patches 34.1, 36.1, 38.1, and 40.1 to be properly positioned relative to the image receiving area 52 at the start each printing process. Controller 20 can optionally be adapted to achieve such positioning by precise control of the movement of donor web 30 using a stepper type motor for motorizing donor web take-up roller 48 or donor web supply roller 50 or by using a movement sensor 86 that can detect movement of donor web 30.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> In one example, an arrangement using a receiver web position sensor 84, a follower wheel 88 is provided that engages donor web 30 and moves therewith. Follower wheel 88 can have surface features that are optically, magnetically or electronically sensed by movement sensor 86. One example of this is a follower wheel 88 that has markings thereon indicative of an extent of movement of donor web 30 and a movement sensor 86 that has a light sensor that can sense light reflected by the markings. In other optional embodiments, perforations, cutouts or other routine and detectable indicia can be incorporated onto donor web 30 in a manner that enables movement sensor 84 to provide an indication of the extent of movement of the donor web 30.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">Alternatively, donor position sensor 82 can also optionally be adapted to sense the color of donor patches on donor web 30 and can provide color signals to controller 20. In this alternative, controller 20 is programmed or otherwise adapted to detect a color that is known to be found in the first donor patch, e.g., yellow donor patch 34.1 in a donor patch set such as first donor patch set 32.1. When the first color is detected, controller 20 can determine that donor web 30 is positioned proximate to the start of a donor patch set.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">An exemplary thermal printer schematic 400, shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 6</figref>, includes a donor supply spool 410 for distributing a donor web 415. A donor take-up spool 420 removes slack donor web 415. A receiver supply spool 440 distributes receiver web 445. Receiver web 445 and donor web 415 are merged together atop platen roller 450 and beneath a thermal ceramic printhead 460 that includes a grounded heat sink and a peel member 470. Subsequent to the thermal ceramic printhead 460 adhering donor material on the donor web 415 to receiver web 445, the peel member 470 separates the donor web 415 from the receiver web 445. Donor web 415 continues to travel on to the donor take-up spool 420, while the receiver web 445 travels between a pinch roller 480 and a micro-grip roller 485 that form a nip.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">In <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 7A</figref>, peel member 470 is metal and ungrounded, i.e., not electrically connected to the earth, yet thermally conductive. Hence, peel member 470 is electrically isolated from ground. The electrical isolation of the peel<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> member 470 from ground removes build-up of electrical charge static charge at a point on the peel member 470 where either one or both of the donor web 415 or the receiver web 445 contact peel member 470 (shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 5</figref>). Therefore, at contact point "A" there will be no apparent electrical static charge transfer as a result of either donor web 415 or receiver web 445 contacting peel member 470.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">In <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 7B</figref>, an alternative embodiment includes a resistance of at least one mega-ohm provided by a high resistance component 462 that substantially electrically isolates peel member 470 from thermal printhead 461 with heat sink 465.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">Peel member 470 can be a plate, a roller, or a bar. Alternatively, peel member 470 can be a combination of either - a plate, roller, or bar. Sources of resistance, that enable electrical isolation of peel member 470 from thermal printhead with heat sink 465 can include non-conductive tape and plastic washers.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">Conventional wisdom, involving electrical current and electrical conductive material, states that the electrical conductive material should be grounded. Applicants' novel approach reduces transfer of electrostatic charge, because peel member 470 is at least substantially electrically isolated. <figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 8</figref> illustrates a triboelectric effect (increased static charge) when the conductive surface of peel member 470 is grounded to the frame of a thermal printer. Electrostatic charge transfer to the peel member 470 creates an imbalance in electrostatic charge on a donor web or a receiver web that can cause buckling of print media, either a receiver sheet or a donor sheet. Most likely, the receiver sheet is more negatively impacted because the receiver sheet will have difficulty exiting the printer.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">In sharp contrast to <figref idrefs="f0007">FIG.8</figref>, <figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 9</figref> illustrates that there is minimal or substantially reduced electrostatic charge transferred to peel member 470 when peel member 470 is electrically isolated from ground. Elimination of, or greatly reduced electrostatic charge transfer to the peel member 470 (as shown in <figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 9</figref>), ensures substantially reduced migration of charge and keeps near balance of existing charges on both the non-polar surface of receiver web 445 and the non-polar surface of donor web 415.<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></p><p id="p0031" num="0031">A view of a triboelectric effect, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 10</figref>, illustrates that the donor web 415 and the receiver web 445, together at a contact point "A" on peel member 470 generates an electrostatic field. A grounded peel member 470 allows a portion of the static charge to go to ground, resulting in a polar charge on the receiver.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">A prior-art multi-headed printer is illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0010">FIG. 11</figref>. The present invention can be employed for a multi-headed printer as well. In this case, one or more peel plates would be used.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0010">FIG. 11</figref>, reference is to a single pass, multi-color thermal printer of the type described in <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="US5440328A"><text>U.S. Patent No. 5,440,328</text></patcit>. In such a printer, a print engine 1110 is provided that comprises a receiver transport system and three or more thermal printhead assemblies 1112, 1114 and 1116. Each of the printhead assemblies includes a respective re-loadable thermal ribbon cassette assembly which is loaded with a color transfer ribbon 1112c, 1114c, and 1116c. Each of the thermal printhead assemblies comprises a thermal printhead 1119a-d having a thermal print line. Each of the thermal printhead assemblies further has a counterpart platen roller 1113a-d with which a respective printhead forms a respective nip and through which a receiver 1111 passes in combination with the respective color ribbon of dye. The mounting assemblies allow the thermal printheads' positions to be adjusted so that the mounting assemblies can be pivoted towards and away from the respective platen rollers. In this regard, the mounting assemblies are pivotable between an "up" position, wherein the thermal printheads are disengaged from the platen rollers and a "down" position wherein the printheads are in biased engagement with the platen rollers.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">Each reloadable ribbon cassette assembly comprises a cassette body including a ribbon supply roll 1112a, 1114a or 1116a and a ribbon take-up roll 1112b, 1114b or 1116b. The ribbon cassette assemblies are loaded with one of three or more primary color ribbons 1112c, 1114c, and 1116c, which are used in conventional subtractive color printing. The supply and take-up rolls of each ribbon cassette assembly are coupled to individual ribbon drive sub-assemblies when the cassette assembly is loaded into the printer for printing images on the<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> receiver. In addition to an assembly for each of the color ribbons, there may also be provided a ribbon cassette assembly 1118 that is provided with a supply of transparent ribbon 1118c that can transfer an overcoat layer to the receiver after an image has been printed thereon. The transparent ribbon cassette assembly is similar in all respects to the other assemblies (including supply and take-up rolls 1118a and 1118b), and a separate printhead is used to transfer the overcoat layer to the now imaged receiver. Different types of transparent ribbon may be used to provide matt or glossy finish overcoats to the final print. Alternatively, the printhead associated with the transparent ribbon may have the respective recording elements suitably modulated to create different finish overcoats to the final print.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">Receiver 1111 having a coating thereon for receiving a thermal dye is supported as a continuous roll and threaded about platen rollers 1113a-d. The receiver is also threaded through a nip comprised of a capstan drive roller 1117 and a back-up roller 1117a. As the receiver is driven by the capstan drive roller the receiver passes by each thermal printhead assembly 1112, 1114, and 1116 a respective color dye image is transferred to the receiver sheet to form the multicolor image. For example, thermal printhead assembly 1112 may provide a yellow color separation image, thermal printhead assembly 1114 may provide a magenta color separation image, and thermal printhead assembly 1116 may provide a cyan color separation image to form a three color multicolor image on the receiver sheet. Fourth ribbon cassette assembly 1118 thermally transfers the transparent overcoat to protect the color image from for example fingerprints. At each of the four assemblies there is provided a thermal printhead 1119a-d that has recording elements selectively enabled in accordance with image information to selectively transfer color dye to the receiver or in the case of the transparent ribbon to transfer the overcoat layer to the now imaged receiver sheet. At each thermal print assembly, platen rollers 1113a-d, form a respective printing nip with the respective printhead 1119a-d. As the receiver is driven through each of the respective nips, the movement of the receiver advances corresponding primary color ribbon 1112c, 1114c, 1116c and 1118c through the respective nip as well.<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> After each multicolor image is formed, a cutter 1115 may be enabled to cut the receiver into a discrete sheet containing the multicolor image protected by the transparent overcoat layer.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036"><figref idrefs="f0011">FIG. 12</figref> shows an apparatus for measuring surface voltage including, an isolated metal surface plate 1205 having a plurality of vacuum holes 1210 on its surface. A black image sample 1215 on a sheet of receiver material has adhered to its surface dual volt meter probes 1220. These dual volt meter probes 1220 are capable of being positioned in different locations on the black image sample 1215. Sample voltage readings from volt meters 1230, 1240 when electrically connected to dual volt meter probes 1220 provide useful data on the amount of voltage difference between a grounded member and an isolated peel plate. Peel members can be plates.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">In addition, the following test procedure for measuring voltages on image side of a printed sheet of receiver material is included below:
<ul><li>A Kodak Ektatherm™ donor and receiver from media kit type 838-0370 was used in this test. Black imaged samples of receiver material are generated by an experimental printer which transfers yellow, magenta, and cyan dye patches and a protective laminate patch onto the surface of the receiver. Samples were produced with and without grounding of the printer peel member 1205, and were measured for surface voltage using the procedure described below.</li></ul></p><p id="p0038" num="0038">Probes from two Trek™ Model 347 Electrostatic Voltmeters are placed over an isolated metal plate (see <figref idrefs="f0011">FIG. 12</figref>) and calibrated to give zero response according to the manufacturer's procedure. A sheet of receiver material is placed on the metal plate with the imaged side uppermost. The metal plate contains holes connected to a vacuum pump to ensure intimate contact with the sheet of receiver material. The probes are moved over the surface of the sheet, maintaining a constant probe-sheet gap by using a supporting bar which slides across the metal plate. Surface voltage is recorded at selected positions along the sheet of receiver material.<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --></p><p id="p0039" num="0039">Readings from the two Trek™ Model 347 Electrostatic Voltmeters when the sheets of receiver material are mounted to the isolated metal surface plate:
<tables id="tabl0001" num="0001"><table frame="all"><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="37mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="55mm"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="52mm"/><thead><row><entry namest="col1" nameend="col3" align="center" valign="middle"><b>Image Side of Sheet of Receiver Material</b></entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">Voltage Reading Point</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">Grounded Peel Plate Test (Voltage)</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">Isolated Peel Plate Test (Voltage)</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">1</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">0</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">0</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">2</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">-210</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">15</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">3</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">-230</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">15</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">4</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">-230</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">15</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">5</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">-225</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">15</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">6</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">-220</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">15</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">7</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">-220</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">15</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">8</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">-175</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">15</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">9</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">-75</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">0</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">10</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">0</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">0</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></tables><!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></p><heading id="h0006"><b>PARTS LIST</b></heading><p id="p0040" num="0040"><dl id="dl0001" compact="compact"><dt>18</dt><dd>Printer</dd><dt>20</dt><dd>Controller</dd><dt>22</dt><dd>Thermal Printhead</dd><dt>26</dt><dd>Receiver Web</dd><dt>30</dt><dd>Donor Web</dd><dt>32</dt><dd>Donor Patch Set</dd><dt>32.1</dt><dd>First Donor Patch</dd><dt>32.2</dt><dd>Second Donor Patch</dd><dt>34</dt><dd>Donor Patch</dd><dt>34.1</dt><dd>Yellow Donor Patch</dd><dt>34.2</dt><dd>Yellow Donor Patch</dd><dt>36</dt><dd>Donor Patch</dd><dt>36.1</dt><dd>Magenta Donor Patch</dd><dt>36.2</dt><dd>Magenta Donor Patch</dd><dt>38</dt><dd>Donor Patch</dd><dt>38.1</dt><dd>Cyan Donor Patch</dd><dt>38.2</dt><dd>Cyan Donor Patch</dd><dt>40</dt><dd>Donor Patches</dd><dt>40.1</dt><dd>Clear Donor Patch</dd><dt>40.2</dt><dd>Clear Donor Patch</dd><dt>42</dt><dd>Receiver Web Take-Up Roller</dd><dt>43</dt><dd>Thermal Resistors</dd><dt>44</dt><dd>Receiver Web Supply Roller</dd><dt>45</dt><dd>Ceramic Substrate</dd><dt>46</dt><dd>Platen Roller</dd><dt>47</dt><dd>Heat Sink</dd><dt>48</dt><dd>Donor Web Take-Up Roller</dd><dt>49</dt><dd>Aluminum Backing Plate<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --></dd><dt>50</dt><dd>Donor Web Supply Roller</dd><dt>51</dt><dd>Circuit Board</dd><dt>52</dt><dd>Image Receiving Area</dd><dt>56</dt><dd>Idler Roller</dd><dt>62</dt><dd>Input System</dd><dt>64</dt><dd>Output System</dd><dt>68</dt><dd>Memory</dd><dt>71</dt><dd>Removable Memory Interface</dd><dt>72</dt><dd>Hard Drive</dd><dt>74</dt><dd>Communication System</dd><dt>76</dt><dd>Remote Memory</dd><dt>80</dt><dd>Sensor System</dd><dt>82</dt><dd>Donor Position Sensor</dd><dt>84</dt><dd>Receiver Web Position Sensor</dd><dt>86</dt><dd>Movement Sensor</dd><dt>88</dt><dd>Follower Wheel</dd><dt>400</dt><dd>Thermal Printer Schematic</dd><dt>410</dt><dd>Donor Supply Spool</dd><dt>415</dt><dd>Donor Web</dd><dt>420</dt><dd>Donor Take-Up Spool</dd><dt>440</dt><dd>Receiver Supply Spool</dd><dt>445</dt><dd>Receiver Web</dd><dt>450</dt><dd>Platen Roller</dd><dt>460</dt><dd>Thermal Ceramic Printhead</dd><dt>461</dt><dd>Thermal Printhead</dd><dt>462</dt><dd>High Resistance Component</dd><dt>465</dt><dd>Heat Sink</dd><dt>470</dt><dd>Peel Member</dd><dt>480</dt><dd>Pinch Roller</dd><dt>485</dt><dd>Micro-Grip Roller<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></dd><dt>1110</dt><dd>Print Engine</dd><dt>1111</dt><dd>Receiver</dd><dt>1112</dt><dd>Thermal Printhead Assembly</dd><dt>1112a</dt><dd>Ribbon Supply Roll</dd><dt>1112b</dt><dd>Ribbon Take-Up Roll</dd><dt>1112c</dt><dd>Primary Color Ribbon</dd><dt>1113a-d</dt><dd>Platen Roller</dd><dt>1114</dt><dd>Thermal Printhead Assembly</dd><dt>1114a</dt><dd>Ribbon Supply Roll</dd><dt>1114b</dt><dd>Ribbon Take-Up Roll</dd><dt>1114c</dt><dd>Primary Color Ribbon</dd><dt>1115</dt><dd>Cutter</dd><dt>1116</dt><dd>Thermal Printhead Assembly</dd><dt>1116a</dt><dd>Ribbon Supply Roll</dd><dt>1116b</dt><dd>Ribbon Take-Up Roll</dd><dt>1116c</dt><dd>Primary Color Ribbon</dd><dt>1117</dt><dd>Capstan Drive Roller</dd><dt>1117a</dt><dd>Back-Up Roller</dd><dt>1118</dt><dd>Ribbon Cassette Assembly</dd><dt>1118c</dt><dd>Transparent Ribbon</dd><dt>1119a-d</dt><dd>Thermal Printhead</dd><dt>1205</dt><dd>Metal Surface Plate</dd><dt>1210</dt><dd>Vacuum Holes</dd><dt>1215</dt><dd>Black Image Sample</dd><dt>1220</dt><dd>Dual Volt Meter Probes</dd><dt>1230</dt><dd>Volt Meters</dd><dt>1240</dt><dd>Volt Meters<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></dd><dt>A</dt><dd>Contact Point</dd><dt>L</dt><dd>Leading Edge</dd><dt>T</dt><dd>Trailing Edge</dd><dt>LED</dt><dd>Leading Edge</dd><dt>TED</dt><dd>Trailing Edge</dd><dt>LER</dt><dd>Leading Edge</dd><dt>TER</dt><dd>Trailing Edge</dd></dl></p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56985929" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Thermodrucker mit einer reduzierten elektrischen Ladung, die aufgebaut ist am Ablösungspunkt eines Geberbandes (415) von einem Empfängerband (445), aufgebaut wird, wobei der Thermodrucker folgendes aufweist:
<claim-text>a) mindestens einen Thermodruckkopf (460; 461);</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) mindestens eine Andruckwalze (450), wobei zwischen dem mindestens einen Thermodruckkopf und der mindestens einen Andruckwalze ein Spalt ausgebildet ist, durch den das Geberband und das Empfängerband gezogen werden können;</claim-text>
<claim-text>c) einen Kühlkörper, der an dem mindestens einen Thermodruckkopf befestigt ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>d) ein Trennelement (470), das stromabwärts vom Spalt angeordnet ist; <b>gekennzeichnet durch</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>e) eine elektrische Verbindung zwischen dem Trennelement (470) und Masse, wobei die elektrische Verbindung eine hochohmige Komponente (462) aufweist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Thermodrucker gemäß Anspruch 1, der eine Halterungsstruktur für das Trennelement aufweist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Thermodrucker gemäß Anspruch 1, wobei das Trennelement (470) gegenüber Masse elektrisch isoliert ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Thermodrucker gemäß Anspruch 1, wobei die Halterungsstruktur für das Trennelement (470) der Kühlkörper ist, welcher am mindestens einen Thermodruckkopf befestigt ist.<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Thermodrucker gemäß Anspruch 1, wobei das Trennelement (470) gegenüber dem Kühlkörper elektrisch isoliert ist, wenn der Kühlkörper selber mit Masse elektrisch verbunden ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Thermodrucker gemäß Anspruch 1, wobei die hochohmige Komponente (462) ein Widerstand von mindestens 500 Kilo-ohm ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Thermodrucker gemäß Anspruch 1, wobei die hochohmige Komponente (462) ein Luftspalt ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Thermodrucker gemäß Anspruch 1, wobei das Trennelement (470) eine Platte ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Thermodrucker gemäß Anspruch 1, wobei das Trennelement (470) eine sich nicht drehende Welle ist, die auf dem Gebiet der Bandförderung im Allgemeinen als "Schuh" bezeichnet wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Thermodrucker gemäß Anspruch 1, wobei das Trennelement (470) eine Walzeneinheit ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Thermodrucker gemäß Anspruch 1, wobei das Trennelement (470) in einem Druckergehäuse gelagert ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Thermodrucker gemäß Anspruch 5, wobei das Trennelement (470) vom Kühlkörper abgestützt und mittels eines dielektrischen Materials gegenüber einem direkten Kontakt mit dem Kühlkörper getrennt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Verfahren zum Eliminieren einer aufgebauten elektrischen, statischen Ladung in einer wärmeleitfähigen Trennelementeinheit, das die folgenden Schritte aufweist:
<claim-text>a) elektrisches Isolieren des wärmeleitfähigen Trennelements (470) gegenüber Masse; und<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>b) Aufrechterhalten eines physikalischen engen Kontakts zwischen dem wärmeleitfähigen Trennelement und einer Kühlkörpereinheit eines Thermodruckkopfes.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56985930" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A thermal printer having reduced electrical charge built at point of separation of a donor web (415) and a receiver web (445), comprising:
<claim-text>a) at least one thermal printhead (460; 461);</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) at least one platen roller (450) with a nip formed between the at least one thermal printhead and the at least one platen roller through which the donor web and the receiver web can be drawn;</claim-text>
<claim-text>c) a heat sink attached to the at least one thermal printhead; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>d) a peel member (470) located downstream of the nip; <b>characterised in that</b> it also comprises</claim-text>
<claim-text>e) an electrical connection from the peel member (470) to ground, the electrical connection including a high resistance component (462).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The thermal printer as recited in claim 1, further comprising a support structure for the peel member.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The thermal printer as recited in claim 1, wherein the peel member (470) is electrically isolated from ground.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The thermal printer as recited in claim 1, wherein the support structure for the peel member (470) is the heat sink attached to the at least one thermal printhead.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The thermal printer as recited in claim 1 wherein the peel member (470) is electrically isolated apart from the heat sink when the heat sink itself is electrically connected to ground.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The thermal printer as recited in claim 1, wherein the high resistance component (462) is a resistor of at least 500 kilo-ohms.<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The thermal printer as recited in claim 1, wherein the high resistance component (462) is an air gap.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The thermal printer as recited in claim 1, wherein the peel member (470) is a plate.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The thermal printer as recited in claim 1, wherein the peel member (470) is a non-rotating shaft, commonly referred to in web conveyance as a "shoe".</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The thermal printer as recited in claim 1, wherein the peel member (470) is a roller assembly.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>The thermal printer as recited in claim 1, wherein the peel member (470) is supported within a printer housing.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>The thermal printer as recited in claim 5, wherein the peel member (470) is supported from the heat sink and is separated from direct contact with the heat sink with a dielectric material.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>A method for eliminating built-up electrical static charge in a thermally conductive peel member assembly, comprising the steps of:
<claim-text>a) electrically isolating the thermal conductive peel member (470) from ground; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) maintaining the thermal conductive peel member's physical proximate contact with a heat sink assembly of a thermal printhead.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56985931" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Imprimante thermique ayant une accumulation réduite de charge électrique au niveau d'un point de séparation entre une bande donneuse (415) et une bande réceptrice (445), comprenant :
<claim-text>a) au moins une tête d'impression thermique (460 ; 461) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) au moins un cylindre d'impression (450) avec une ligne de contact formée entre ladite au moins une tête d'impression thermique est ledit au moins un cylindre d'impression, à travers lequel la bande donneuse et la bande réceptrice peuvent être tirées ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>c) un radiateur fixé à ladite au moins une tête d'impression ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>d) un élément de pelage (470) situé en aval de la ligne de contact ; <b>caractérisé en ce qu'</b>elle comprend en outre</claim-text>
<claim-text>e) une connexion électrique entre l'élément de pelage (470) et la masse, la connexion électrique comprenant un composant à résistance élevée (462).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Imprimante thermique selon la revendication 1, comprenant en outre une structure de support pour l'élément de pelage.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Imprimante thermique selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle l'élément de pelage (470) est isolé électriquement de la masse.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Imprimante thermique selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle la structure de support pour l'élément de pelage (470) est le radiateur fixé à ladite au moins une tête d'impression thermique.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Imprimante thermique selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle l'élément de pelage (470) est isolé électriquement du radiateur lorsque le radiateur lui-même est connecté électriquement à la masse.<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Imprimante thermique selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle le composant à résistance élevée (462) est une résistance d'au moins 500 kilo-ohms.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Imprimante thermique selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle le composant à résistance élevée (462) est un intervalle d'air.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Imprimante thermique selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle l'élément de pelage (470) est une plaque.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Imprimante thermique selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle l'élément de pelage (470) est un arbre non rotatif, appelé couramment dans le domaine du transport de bande une "chaussure".</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Imprimante thermique selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle l'élément de pelage (470) est un assemblage à rouleau.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Imprimante thermique selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle l'élément de pelage (470) est supporté dans un boîtier d'imprimante.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Imprimante thermique selon la revendication 5, dans laquelle l'élément de pelage (470) est supporté par le radiateur et est séparé d'un contact direct avec le radiateur par un matériau diélectrique.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Procédé pour éliminer une accumulation de charge électrique statique dans un assemblage d'élément de pelage conducteur thermiquement, comprenant les étapes suivantes :
<claim-text>a) isoler électriquement l'élément de pelage conducteur thermique (470) de la masse ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) maintenir le contact de proximité physique de l'élément de pelage conducteur thermique à l'aide d'un assemblage de radiateur d'une tête d'impression thermique.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16672305" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="165" he="204" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="137" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3,4,5"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="165" he="194" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --><figure id="f0004" num="6"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="126" he="209" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --><figure id="f0005" num="7A"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="142" he="189" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --><figure id="f0006" num="7B"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="153" he="182" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --><figure id="f0007" num="8"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="163" he="214" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --><figure id="f0008" num="9"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="165" he="190" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --><figure id="f0009" num="10"><img id="if0009" file="imgf0009.tif" wi="153" he="182" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --><figure id="f0010" num="11"><img id="if0010" file="imgf0010.tif" wi="155" he="162" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --><figure id="f0011" num="12"><img id="if0011" file="imgf0011.tif" wi="116" he="156" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
