<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2960094-A1" country="EP" doc-number="2960094" kind="A1" date="20151230" family-id="51389859" file-reference-id="245813" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="160452051" ucid="EP-2960094-A1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2960094</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20151230</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-14174112-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP193867070" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>14174112</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20140626</date><lang>IT</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP193867071" load-source="patent-office" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>14174112.4</doc-number><date>20140626</date><lang>IT</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC162032805" ucid="EP-14174112-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>14174112</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20140626</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1988521299" load-source="docdb">B60K  17/28        20060101AFI20141215BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1988523743" load-source="docdb">B28C   5/42        20060101ALI20141215BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1987765623" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B60K  17/28        20130101 FI20141211BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT165547619" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Drehmomentübertragungsvorrichtung für Lastkraftwagen mit abnehmbarem oder auswechselbaren Aufbauten</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT165547620" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Torque transmission device for trucks having demountable or interchangeable bodies</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT165547621" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Dispositif de transmission de couple pour camions possédant des corps interchangeables ou démontables</invention-title><citations><patent-citations><patcit mxw-id="PCIT335963127" load-source="docdb" ucid="DE-4314218-A1"><document-id format="epo"><country>DE</country><doc-number>4314218</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>19941103</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="X" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT335963129" load-source="docdb" ucid="EP-0490365-A1"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>0490365</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>19920617</date></document-id><sources><source name="APP" created-by-npl="N"/><source name="SEA" category="XD" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT335963130" load-source="docdb" ucid="EP-1916147-A1"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>1916147</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20080430</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="X" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit></patent-citations></citations></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR1103334189" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>PRIS MAG S R L</last-name><address><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR1103314277" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>PRIS-MAG S.R.L.</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR1101640328" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Pris-Mag S.r.l.</last-name><iid>101456406</iid><address><street>Via Villasanta, 17</street><city>20871 Vimercate (MB)</city><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1103312038" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>SALA ALESSANDRO</last-name><address><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1103326711" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>SALA, ALESSANDRO</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1101647862" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>SALA, ALESSANDRO</last-name><address><street>Via C.na Pignone, 1</street><city>20871 VIMERCATE MB</city><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1103340175" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>SALA PAOLO</last-name><address><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1103310736" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>SALA, PAOLO</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1101651550" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>SALA, PAOLO</last-name><address><street>Via C.na Pignone, 1</street><city>20871 VIMERCATE MB</city><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR1101642456" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Mittler, Enrico</last-name><suffix>et al</suffix><iid>100018997</iid><address><street>Mittler &amp; C. s.r.l. Viale Lombardia, 20</street><city>20131 Milano</city><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS660618733" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS660696128" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS660786352" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS660618310" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS660709533" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS660786353" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS660615897" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS660618739" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS660786354" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS660786355" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS660695040" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS660618319" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS660618320" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS660618740" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS660786356" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS660618741" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS660615898" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS660709534" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS660786357" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS660618321" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS660786358" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS660618742" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS660696129" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS660618322" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS660618331" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS660696130" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS660696135" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS660696136" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS660709551" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS660696137" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS660695041" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS660698743" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS660695042" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS660696138" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS660618752" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS660709552" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS660709553" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS660786359" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states><ep-extended-states><ep-extended-state-data><country>BA</country></ep-extended-state-data><ep-extended-state-data><country>ME</country></ep-extended-state-data></ep-extended-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA166480421" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p id="pa01" num="0001">A torque transmission device for trucks (5) with demountable or interchangeable bodies (40) is described; the device comprises torque transmission means (10) aboard the truck and torque reception means (20) aboard the body. The reception means and the transmission means each comprise a coupling member (11, 21) to transmit a rotary motion of the truck to the body; the transmission means and reception means each comprise supporting means (15, 24) for the coupling member (21); the supporting means for the coupling member of the reception means are provided with at least one bearing (26).
<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="165" he="93" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA166760233" lang="EN" source="EPO" load-source="docdb"><p>A torque transmission device for trucks (5) with demountable or interchangeable bodies (40) is described; the device comprises torque transmission means (10) aboard the truck and torque reception means (20) aboard the body. The reception means and the transmission means each comprise a coupling member (11, 21) to transmit a rotary motion of the truck to the body; the transmission means and reception means each comprise supporting means (15, 24) for the coupling member (21); the supporting means for the coupling member of the reception means are provided with at least one bearing (26).</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES98405122" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to a torque transmission device for trucks having demountable or interchangeable bodies, in particular to an automatic coupling device.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002">In the aforesaid technical field, "bodyworks" or bodies" or "superstructures" are structures attached to the chassis of a truck to be specialized for a particular type of transport or handling on site.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">Examples of trucks with different units may be: fixed bodies, dumper bodies, cranes, concrete mixers, diggers, drainage tanks and others. The aforesaid bodies may be fixed to the vehicle either permanently so as to limit it to a single use or temporarily for transporting them and for some particular purposes, and then the bodies can be removed leaving the vehicle ready for a different use.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">A truck built to carry demountable bodies can obviously offer a more versatile service than one which is not; furthermore, said truck is more versatile if the units are also interchangeable. The fact of making a truck suited to carry such interchangeable bodies results in the addition of hydraulic devices to the chassis of the truck with which the body is maneuvered, means for locking the body onto the chassis and means for releasing the body from the chassis; the means may be of different type, such as hydraulic, pneumatic or electric type.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">The use of torque transmission devices for trucks with demountable or interchangeable bodies is known, where a male member of the device is allocated aboard the truck and the female member is arranged aboard the body, or vice versa. The male member is usually connected to the power take-off of the truck and allows the transmission of the rotary motion to the female member aboard the body, or vice versa, as long as the parts can be<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> coupled to each other.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="EP0490365A"><text>EP 0490365</text></patcit> describes a truck with interchangeable concrete mixer, provided with a device for transmitting torque from the truck to the interchangeable body with automatic coupling/releasing means. The device particularly controls the hydraulic pump of a concrete mixer adapted to control the rotation of the mixing drum of a concrete mixer.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">The power take-off shaft is connected to the hydraulic pump by means of a transmission system comprising a transmission shaft with two Cardan joints, one of which is connected to the power take-off of the truck and the other is connected to a rotary motion transmission device and to a rotary motion reception device arranged on the concrete mixer. The Cardan shaft is inclined with respect to the resting plane of the truck and the rotary motion transmission and reception devices also have a rotation axis which is not parallel to the resting plane of the truck for the interchangeable body.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">Said apparatus however has some drawbacks. The transmission system cannot ensure a correct operation when the truck on which the concrete mixer is installed must operate under difficult operating conditions, such as on rough terrain or on slopes.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">Vibrations and oscillations may occur during the operation of the transmission system, which may damage the aforesaid system.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">Furthermore, the forces which are released during the coupling of the transmission member with the reception member may damage both members.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">In view of the described prior art, it is the object of the present invention to provide a torque transmission device for trucks having demountable or interchangeable bodies, in particular an automatic coupling device, which solves the problems set forth above.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">According to the present invention, such an object is achieved by a torque transmission device for trucks with demountable or interchangeable bodies, said device comprising torque transmission means aboard the truck<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> and torque reception means aboard the body, said torque reception and transmission means each comprising a coupling member to transmit a rotary motion from the truck to the body, said transmission means and said reception means each comprising supporting means for the coupling member, characterized in that said supporting means for the coupling member of said reception means are provided with at least one bearing.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">Again according to the present invention, such an object is achieved by a demountable or interchangeable body comprising rotary motion reception means which may be coupled to rotary motion transmission means of a truck, said reception means comprising a coupling member with the transmission means, said coupling member comprising supporting means, characterized in that said supporting means for the coupling member are provided with at least one bearing.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">The features and advantages of the present invention will become apparent from the following detailed description of a practical embodiment thereof, shown by way of non-limitative example in the accompanying drawings, in which:
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">figure 1</figref> is a diagrammatic view of the torque transmission device for trucks having demountable or interchangeable bodies according to the present invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">figure 2</figref> is a side view of a truck provided with a part of the torque transmission device for trucks having demountable or interchangeable bodies according to the present invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">figure 2A</figref> is a perspective view of a part of the truck in <figref idrefs="f0002">figure 2</figref>;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">figure 3</figref> is a view of a part of the demountable or interchangeable body provided with the other part of the torque transmission device for trucks having demountable or interchangeable bodies according to the present invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004 f0005 f0006">figures 4-6</figref> are exploded views of the parts of the torque transmission device in <figref idrefs="f0003">figure 3</figref>;<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></li><li><figref idrefs="f0007">figure 7</figref> is a front view of a part of the torque transmission device in <figref idrefs="f0004">figure 4</figref>;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0007">figure 8</figref> shows a translation device adapted to allow the automatic coupling of the two parts of the torque transmission device in <figref idrefs="f0001">figure 1</figref>.</li></ul></p><p id="p0015" num="0015"><figref idrefs="f0001 f0002 f0003 f0004 f0005 f0006 f0007">Figures 1-8</figref> show a torque transmission device 1 for trucks with demountable or interchangeable bodies, in particular an automatically coupling device, according to the present invention. Device 1 comprises a device 10 adapted to transmit a rotary motion to a device 20 adapted to receive the rotary motion of device 10.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">Means 30 are preferably provided aboard truck 5, being adapted to allow the automatic coupling of the two devices 10, 20; so the manual mechanical intervention of an operator is not needed. Truck 5 is provided with a chassis 2 which develops along the longitudinal axis X, and in particular the coupling means 30 for the devices 10 and 20 are means adapted to allow the translation of the demountable or interchangeable body 40 along the longitudinal axis X; said means 30, normally arranged in the chassis 2 of truck 5, may be represented by the translation device 30 described in <figref idrefs="f0007">figure 8</figref>. The means 30 comprise a hydraulic jack 31 for activating the translation device which is hinged by means of a hinge 31a to a crosspiece 3 which is integral with the chassis 2 of truck 5. The means 30 comprise a triangular cam 33, at a first vertex of which an end of the piston of the hydraulic jack 31 is hinged. A second vertex of cam 33 is hinged onto a transversal arm 32a, to which an end of a lateral reinforcing support 32 is also connected, the other end of said support being constrained to the crosspiece 3; a conical pin 34, which is free to rotate, is fixed to the third vertex of cam 33. As known, the conical pin engages two crosspieces of body 40 when the body is lowered on chassis 2 and the hydraulic jack 31 translates the body 40 on chassis 2 along the axis X to couple the devices 10 and 20, and preferably also to anchor body 40 onto truck 5.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">Truck 5 is provided with a power take-off shaft 4 having a rotation axis<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> preferably parallel to the support plane A of the body (<figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref>); the support plane A is defined by the chassis 2 of truck 5. The power take-off preferably depends on the engine of the truck and may be actuated when the vehicle is either stationary or traveling.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">The device 10, which has a coupling member 11 provided with cavities 12 delimited by segments 13 arranged circumferentially about the rotation axis X1 (<figref idrefs="f0002">figures 2</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0004 f0005 f0006 f0007">4-7</figref>), is connected to the power take-off shaft of the truck; device 10 preferably comprises four cavities 12 delimited by four segments 13 and by an annular protrusion 14 which surrounds the segments 13 and the cavities 12. Moreover, the annular protrusion 14 facilitates the coupling with the device 20, especially when the two devices are not well aligned. The rotation axis X1 is parallel to the support plane A of body 40 and is parallel to the translation axis X.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">The device 10 is fixed to the truck by means of a ring-shaped supporting bracket 15. The coupling member 11 comprises a hollow tubular protrusion 110 which may be coupled to another member 17 having a tubular protrusion 170 and connected to the power take-off 4 of the truck; the member 17 is adapted to transmit the rotary motion to the coupling member 11.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">The device 20 comprises a coupling member 21 provided with protrusions 22, preferably of the saw-tooth type and made of a very hard material, for example a thermally treated material, such as 39 NiCrMo4 or the like or with similar or better features. The protrusions 22 are adapted to engage the cavities 12 of device 10 to allow the rotary motion to be transmitted to a user of the body 40, preferably by means of a Cardan shaft 23 (<figref idrefs="f0003 f0004 f0005 f0006">Figures 3-6</figref>); the device 20 is fixed to body 40 by means of a ring-shaped supporting bracket 24. The coupling members 11 and 21, with the presence of the protrusions 22 which can be inserted into the cavities 12 and of the annular protrusion 14 in which the coupling member 21 can be inserted, are of the automatic coupling type, i.e. are structured to allow their<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> automatic coupling.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">The coupling member 21 comprises a longitudinally grooved shaft 210 which may be coupled to another member 27 having a tubular grooved cavity 270 configured to be coupled to the shaft 210. Member 27 is connected to the user of the body; member 27 is adapted to transmit the rotary motion to the user of the body. The device 20 comprises at least one bearing 26, but preferably two bearings 26, of the ring-shaped type and normally kept within the annular bracket 24 by means of a member 29; the bearings 26 are arranged about the outer part of the tubular cavity 270. In particular, the bearings are arranged about a sleeve 260, slidingly fitted in turn on the outer part of the tubular cavity 270. A spring 28 arranged within the tubular cavity 270 is also present; the spring 28 allows the translation of the coupling member 21 along the axis X1 to allow a correct, reliable coupling between the members 11, 21, thus ensuring a correct transmission of the mechanical power throughout the operation. Spring 28 has the function of always ensuring the correct coupling pressure, by relieving the reaction forces which are developed due to its compression caused by the coupling of the two members 11 on the bearings. The free end of the outer part of the tubular cavity 270 is threaded to be coupled to an annular member 25.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">The bearings 26 are adapted to absorb the forces which are developed during the operation of coupling the members 11 and 21. When coupling the members 11 and 21, member 21 translates along the axis X1 towards member 11; member 21 is carried preferably by the means 30 to obtain the automatic coupling of the members 11 and 21.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">When coupling member 11 to member 21, the bearings 26, kept within the annular bracket 24, are adapted to absorb the forces which are developed during the coupling operation; thereby, shocks to the user of body 40 which could even cause a failure of the user are avoided. When coupling the members 11 and 21, member 21 translates along the axis X1 towards body<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> 40 and may knock against the member 25 screwed onto the outer part of the tubular cavity 270 of member 27; the impact is absorbed within the annular bracket 24 by the bearings 26 without damaging member 27 and/or the user connected to member 27.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">Preferably, device 10 also comprises at least one bearing 16, but preferably two bearings 16, normally kept within the annular bracket 15 by means of a member 19. In particular, the bearings are arranged about a sleeve 160, slidingly fitted in turn on the outer part of the hollow tubular protrusion 110; the latter has a threaded free end to be coupled to an annular member.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">When coupling the members 11 and 21, member 21 rapidly translates along the axis X1 towards the cab of the truck; the impact of the members 11 and 21 caused by said translation is also absorbed within the annular bracket 15 of the bearings 16 without causing the impact of member 11 with bracket 15 and/or damaging member 17 and/or the power take-off connected to member 17.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">The bearings 16 provide a better absorption of the forces which are developed during the operation of coupling the members 11 and 21.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM90460078" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --><claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A torque transmission device for trucks with demountable or interchangeable bodies (40), said device comprising torque transmission means (10) aboard the truck (5) and torque reception means (20) aboard the body, said torque reception and transmission means each comprising a coupling member (11, 21) to transmit a rotary motion from the truck to the body, said transmission means and said reception means each comprising supporting means (15, 24) for the coupling member (21), <b>characterized in that</b> said supporting means for the coupling member of said reception means are provided with at least one bearing (26).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>A device according to claim 1, <b>characterized in that</b> said supporting means for the coupling member of said transmission means are provided with at least one bearing (16).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>A device according to claim 1, <b>characterized in that</b> the coupling members (11, 21) of said transmission and reception means are arranged so that the rotary motion transmitted by the truck and received by the body occurs about a rotation axis (X1) which is parallel to the support plane (A) of the truck on which the body is arranged.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>A device according to claim 1, <b>characterized in that</b> the coupling members (11, 21) of said transmission and reception means are of the automatic coupling type.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>A device according to claim 1, <b>characterized in that</b> said reception means comprise elastic means (28) adapted to allow the translation of the coupling member (21) of the reception means along a rotation axis (X1) which is parallel to the support plane (A) of the truck on which the body is arranged to allow a correct coupling between the coupling members (11, 21) of said transmission and reception means.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>A demountable or interchangeable body (4) comprising means (20) for receiving a rotary motion, which may be coupled to means (10) for transmitting the rotary motion of a truck (5), said reception means<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> comprising a coupling member (21) with the transmission means, said coupling member comprising supporting means, <b>characterized in that</b> said supporting means (24) of the coupling member are provided with at least one bearing (26).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>A body according to claim 6, <b>characterized in that</b> the coupling member (21) of said reception means is arranged so that the rotary motion is received about a rotation axis (X1) parallel to the support plane (A) of the truck on which the body is arranged.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>A body according to claim 6, <b>characterized in that</b> the coupling members (11, 21) of said transmission and reception means are of the automatic coupling type.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>A body according to claim 6, <b>characterized in that</b> said reception means comprise elastic means (28) adapted to allow the translation of the coupling member (21) of the reception means along a rotation axis (X1) which is parallel to the support plane (A) of the truck on which the body is arranged to allow a correct coupling between the coupling members (11, 21) of said transmission and reception means.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>A truck (5) comprising transmission means (10) of a rotary motion which may be coupled to the means (20) for receiving the rotary motion of a demountable or interchangeable body, said transmission means comprising a coupling member (11), said coupling member comprising supporting means, <b>characterized in that</b> said supporting means (15) of the coupling member are provided with at least one bearing (16).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>A truck according to claim 10, <b>characterized in that</b> the chassis (2) of the truck develops along a longitudinal axis (X) and defines a resting plane (A) for the body and the coupling member (11) of said transmission means is arranged so that the rotary motion is transmitted about a rotation axis (X1) parallel to the support plane (A) of the truck on which the body is arranged.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>A truck according to claim 10, <b>characterized in that</b> the coupling<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> members (11, 21) of said transmission and reception means are of the automatic coupling type, said truck comprising means (30) adapted to automatically couple the means (10) for transmitting the rotary motion to the means (20) for receiving the rotary motion of a demountable or interchangeable body.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>A truck according to claim 12, <b>characterized in that</b> the chassis (2) of the truck develops along a longitudinal axis (X) and defines a resting plane (A) for the body, and <b>in that</b> said means (30) for automatically coupling the means (10) for transmitting the rotary motion to the means (20) for receiving the rotary motion of a demountable or interchangeable body comprise translation means of the demountable or interchangeable body along a longitudinal axis (X) which is parallel to the support plane (A) of the demountable or interchangeable body.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>A combination of a truck (5) as defined in any of the claims 10-13 with a demountable or interchangeable body (40) as defined in any of the claims 6-9.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW20422762" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="135" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="111" he="193" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --><figure id="f0003" num="2a,3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="162" he="230" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --><figure id="f0004" num="4"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="132" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --><figure id="f0005" num="5"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="141" he="221" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --><figure id="f0006" num="6"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="141" he="231" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --><figure id="f0007" num="7,8"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="163" he="222" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><search-report-data><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="159" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="159" he="233" type="tif"/></search-report-data><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
