<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2492433-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2492433" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="43976287" file-reference-id="315081" date-produced="20180825" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146587865" ucid="EP-2492433-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2492433</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-12154940-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154850057" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12154940</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120210</date><lang>IT</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140554057" ucid="IT-PD20110055-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>IT</country><doc-number>PD20110055</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20110225</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130828</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989324122" load-source="ipcr">E06B   9/40        20060101AFI20120605BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989324123" load-source="ipcr">E06B   9/58        20060101ALI20120605BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989628096" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">E06B   9/581       20130101 LI20130921BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989649111" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">E06B   9/42        20130101 FI20130921BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989651592" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">E06B2009/588       20130101 LA20130921BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989651795" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">E06B   9/582       20130101 LA20130921BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132368228" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Abschrimvorrichtung mit Aufwicklung</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132368229" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Wind-up-screen</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132368230" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">DISPOSITIF D'ÉCRAN À ENROULEMENT</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919510279" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>GIBUS S P A</last-name><address><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919544746" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>GIBUS S.P.A.</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919511312" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>LAMON EDOARDO</last-name><address><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919521214" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>Lamon, Edoardo</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919020414" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Lamon, Edoardo</last-name><address><street>Via Musatti, 16</street><city>I-35136 Padova</city><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919534660" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>DELL AGLIO LUIGI</last-name><address><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919512761" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>Dell'aglio, Luigi</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919020413" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Dell'aglio, Luigi</last-name><address><street>Via Santa Maria Assunta, 46</street><city>I-35125 Padova</city><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919020415" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Gibus S.p.A.</last-name><iid>101402363</iid><address><street>Via Einaudi, 35</street><city>35030 Saccolongo (PD)</city><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919020412" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Gallo, Luca</last-name><iid>100960038</iid><address><street>Gallo &amp; Partners S.r.l. Via Rezzonico, 6</street><city>35131 Padova</city><country>IT</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549794626" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS549864700" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549779243" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549921607" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549862915" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549779244" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549778862" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549794627" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549779249" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549779250" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549886186" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549921608" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549921609" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549794628" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549779251" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549794641" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549778863" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549862916" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549779252" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549921610" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549779257" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549921611" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549864701" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549921612" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549921613" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549864714" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS549864715" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549864716" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549862917" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549864717" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549886187" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549867033" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549886188" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS549864722" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549794642" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549862922" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549862923" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS549779258" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63960299" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001"><u>Field of application</u></heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention regards a wind-up screen, according to the preamble of the main claim.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002">The wind-up screen of the present invention is intended to be advantageously used for covering, in an adjustable manner, the openings of buildings such as windows, doorways, skylights and the like or for closing balconies, porches or other spaces that require protection from the wind, from the sun and more generally from the outside environment. The aforesaid screen is preferably of fall type, i.e. intended to close the opening by sliding with vertical movement within guides starting from a winder placed at the top of the opening.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">It is therefore intended to be inserted in the industrial field of the production of home accessories, in the field of doors/windows/shutters and in the field of the production of sheets for sun protection, mosquito nets and similar applications.</p><heading id="h0002"><u>State of the art</u></heading><p id="p0004" num="0004">Wind-up screens are known on the market for the covering of doorways, windows or other similar openings of building, balconies or porches, provided with a cloth in flexible sheet form, which can be wound on a rotatable roller housed in a collection box arranged above the opening of the building.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">The sheet is usually made of fabric or of synthetic material and it can be transparent (e.g. made of transparent plastic material), e.g. in order to protect from the air, or dark, e.g. for screening part or all of the sunlight.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">More in detail, the sheet is fixed with its upper end to the rotatable roller, and with its lower end to a transverse bar for the user's grip.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p><p id="p0007" num="0007">Each side edge of the sheet carries a flexible thickening element associated therewith, usually obtained with a flexible toothing, which is able to slide within a longitudinal guide of a corresponding rail.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">More in detail, the wind-up screen is also known to comprise two vertical uprights, which are rigidly mounted on the inner walls of the opening, for example by means of screw means.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">Each upright has a cross section shaped substantially like a U, with its opening facing the other upright, and it houses a corresponding rail internally between its arms.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">The rail is usually retained in the upright by means of suitable removable listels, mechanically and fittedly connected to the arms of the U-shaped upright. The aforesaid listels simultaneously perform the function of retaining the rails and guiding the ends of the transverse grip bar.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">In practice, the wind-up screen of the type described above does not lack drawbacks. In particular, given the high number of components it is very complex to install and difficult to achieve.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">In order to overcome these drawbacks, a wind-up screen was recently developed composed of a very limited number of components, since the removable listels were substantially eliminated for the benefit of greater mounting convenience. Such screen, described in particular in the patent application <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="ITBO20040762A"><text>IT BO2004-A-000762</text></patcit>, comprises two lateral support uprights, each of which defining a half-shoulder for the rail and a first half-guide for the transverse bar, and two panels, each which being removably engageable with the respective upright and defining a second half-shoulder, complementary to the first, in order to retain the rail inside the profile of the upright and define the end stop abutment towards the outlet of the upright.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">The aforesaid wind-up screen also comprises a second half-guide, complementary to the<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> first, for the sliding of the transverse grip bar.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">By assembling the two above-indicated profiles of the L-shaped upright together with the two I-shaped panels, via suitable joining means, one obtains a structure that accomplishes the three required functionalities, i.e.: laterally retaining the rail in the guide; defining an end stop with shoulders facing the rail which prevents the outward exit thereof from the guide; guiding the terminals arranged at the ends of the transverse grip bar.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">Even if it has facilitated mounting, the aforesaid wind-up screen of known type has the drawback of not offering sufficient mechanical seal guarantees; it is also hard to maintain since in the case of wear of the grip guide bars or of the rail holding abutments, it is necessary to dismantle the entire frame formed by the aforesaid wall-fixed uprights and by the panels in order to substitute the worn parts with new ones.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">In addition, the fixing means between the upright and the panel necessarily allow clearances and displacements between the two parts, which involve an imprecise obtainment of the guides that they constitute.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">Also known, from the patent <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="AU2010100720"><text>AU 2010100720</text></patcit>, is a wind-up screen according to the preamble of claim 1, equipped with two vertical uprights; each upright has cross section shaped like a U and is equipped with two first arms, between which a corresponding rail is housed.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">The latter also has a cross section with U shape, and is equipped with two parallel second arms which together define, inside the rail, a seat in which a corresponding end terminal of the transverse bar of the wind-up screen is slidably inserted.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">In particular, the rail is perfectly inserted inside the corresponding upright, with each second arm of the rail arranged with its outer surface adhering to the inner surface of one of the first arms of the upright, in order to prevent transverse movements of the rail inside the same upright.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p><p id="p0020" num="0020">Also the latter wind-up screen of known type does not lack drawbacks. In particular, such wind-up screen is not capable of ensuring a firm retention of the rail in the corresponding upright due to tolerances of the dimensions of the upright and of the rail connected with the production process of the latter.</p><heading id="h0003"><u>Presentation of the invention</u></heading><p id="p0021" num="0021">In this situation, the problem underlying the present invention is to provide a wind-up screen which allows easy maintenance of its components that are most subjected to wear.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">Another object of the present invention is to provide a wind-up screen which is simple and quick to install.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">Another object of the present invention is to provide a wind-up screen which is structurally simple to achieve and fully reliable operationally.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">These and still other objects are all attained by the wind-up screen according to the enclosed claims.</p><heading id="h0004"><u>Brief description of the drawings</u></heading><p id="p0025" num="0025">The technical characteristics of the finding, according to the aforesaid objects, are clearly described in the contents of the claims reported below, and the advantages of the same will be more clearly evident in the following detailed description, given with reference to the enclosed drawings, which represent two merely exemplifying and nonlimiting embodiments thereof, in which:
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figures 1, 2 and 3</figref> show wind-up screen, object of the present invention, in a perspective view with the sheet respectively completely extended, completely wound and partially extended to close the opening.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 4</figref> shows a detail of the wind-up screen, object of the present invention, according to a section view achieved at a lateral upright thereof, with different parts<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> seen in exploded view, i.e. with the wind-up screen in mounting step;</li></ul>
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 5</figref> shows the detail of the wind-up screen of <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 4</figref> with the different parts assembled together;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 6</figref> shows the detail of the wind-up screen of <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 4</figref> in accordance with an embodiment variant of the coupling means of the sheet, and with the different parts in exploded view;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 7</figref> shows the detail of the wind-up screen of <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 6</figref> with the different parts assembled together;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Figures 8 and 9</figref> illustrate two perspective views of the detail of <figref idrefs="f0002 f0003">Figures 4-6</figref> according to the two abovementioned embodiment variants of the sheet coupling means;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005">Figure 10</figref> is a perspective view of a detail of the wind-up screen according to the present invention relative to an upright and to the components associated therewith in accordance with the embodiment of <figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 9</figref>, partially exploded and with some parts removed in order to better emphasize other parts.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0005"><u>Detailed description of a preferred embodiment</u></heading><p id="p0026" num="0026">With reference to the enclosed drawings, the wind-up screen that is the object of the present invention is indicated in its entirety with 1.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">The present wind-up screen 1 is intended to carry out the closure, in an adjustable manner, of an opening A, such as in particular a doorway, a window or the like, obtained on a building wall or on another load-bearing structure, e.g. a porch, a veranda, a terrace or other similar structures.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">It comprises, in a <i>per se</i> fully conventional manner, a flexible sheet 2, made of fabric or plastic material, of dark or transparent type, depending on the function that the flexible sheet 2 is intended to perform, such as for example for protecting an area from the sun and/or from the wind and/or, more generally, from the atmospheric conditions of the<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> outside environment.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">The opening A is defined by two side walls, e.g. masonry, by an upper wall and a lower wall, such as a windowsill; otherwise the opening can be defined as a function of the specific application of the wind-up screen 1, also by columns, uprights or crossbars of a metal framework.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">Above the opening A, for example on the upper wall of the masonry, a roller is mounted (not illustrated), rotatably housed inside a collection box 3. The roller is able to wind-up and unwind the flexible sheet 2, allowing its extension to a different extent in an adjustable manner, for the partial or total closure of the opening A.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">For such purpose, the roller can be driven to rotate by means of a motor or manually, e.g. through the use of a command rod engaged through an articulated joint to the roller shaft.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">With the term "flexible sheet" 2, it is intended below an element in the form of a flexible sheet, able to be wound on the roller and unwound from the roller.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">The flexible sheet 2 has a preferably rectangular shape and is provided, in a manner <i>per se</i> known to the man skilled in the art, with an upper end mechanically associated with the roller; with a lower end 4 mechanically associated with a transverse bar 5; and two side edges 6 guided to slide at the side walls of the opening A as will be specified below.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">More in detail, the transverse bar 5 is obtained with an extruded profile, preferably made of aluminum, equipped with a longitudinal slot parallel to the extension of the same transverse bar 5, open towards the outside by means of a longitudinal slit suitable to receive a thickening prearranged at the lower end 4 of the flexible sheet 2. Advantageously, such thickening is obtained with a pocket made at the aforesaid lower end 4, at whose interior a rod is housed with diameter slightly less than the slot; in such<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> a manner, the rod can be inserted inside the slot once it is inserted in the pocket, with the flexible sheet 2 arranged to cross through the aforesaid slit of the slot.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">At the lateral ends of the transverse bar 5, two terminals 7 are mounted, for example by means of screws or other analogous fixing means, which are able to close the ends of the transverse bar 5, and in particular of the aluminum extrusion, and slide in a guided manner along the side walls of the opening A, as will be better specified below.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">Each of the side edges 6 of the flexible sheet 2 is in turn provided with a flexible flap 8 capable of sliding in a guided manner along the side walls of the opening A, as will be better specified below.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">The wind-up screen 1 also comprises two uprights 9, which are intended to be vertically fixed starting from the collection box 3, on the side walls that define the opening A covered by the sheet 2 and in positions facing each other.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">Each upright 9 has a rail 10 mechanically associated thereto, and such rail defines a longitudinal groove 11 having a slit 17. The longitudinal groove 11 is capable of slidably receiving, at its interior, the flexible flap 8 of one of the two side edges 6 of the sheet 2 with the latter arranged to cross through the slit 17.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">According to the idea underlying the present invention, the wind-up screen 1 also comprises two guide profiles 12, each of which mechanically fixed to a corresponding upright 9 through first fixing means 13, e.g. constituted by screws or dowels as indicated in the enclosed figures. Each guide profile 12 is also obtained in a single body, preferably via extrusion in aluminum, and has a cross section shaped substantially as a U. Such shape of the guide profile 12 is obtained with two substantially parallel arms 12A, 12B, connected to each other by a bottom 12C. The two arms 12A, 12B define at their free ends, on the side opposite the bottom 12C, a through opening 14 of the flexible sheet 2. This latter opening 14 faces that of the other guide profile 12 fixed to<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> the facing upright 9 in order to maintain the planarity of the flexible sheet 2.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">In addition, according to the present invention, each guide profile 12 defines, by means of the outer surfaces of its aforesaid arms 12A, 12B, a track 15, in which a terminal 7 of the transverse bar 5 is slidably engaged. Each guide profile 12 also internally defines a seat 16, which is partially closed at its through opening for the sheet 14 and in which the corresponding rail 10 is housed in a holding relationship.</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">Advantageously, the two terminals 7 are provided with two guide wings 30, parallel to each other, laterally projecting as an extension of the transverse bar 5, and able to be employed outside the arms 12A and 12B of the guide profile 12. For such purpose, the distance D1 between the inner surfaces of the aforesaid two guide wings 30 is slightly greater than that between the outer faces D2 of the two arms 12A and 12B (in order to define the sliding clearance).</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">The guide profile 12 presents the through opening for the sheet 14 with a reduced width D3 with respect to the distance D4 between the inner faces of the two arms 12A, 12B (internal width of the seat 16). This in order to retain the rail 10 inside its seat 16 in a holding relationship, such rail 10 having size greater than the opening 14 but less than the seat 16.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">Advantageously, such through opening for the sheet 14 has reduced width by means of the two terminal portions 12A' and 12B' of the arms 12A, 12B folded inwardly, as is clearly seen in <figref idrefs="f0002 f0003">figures 4-7</figref> enclosed with the present description.</p><p id="p0044" num="0044">The rail 10 is then advantageously mounted in the seat 16 of the guide profile 12, by making it slide starting from one end thereof as can be inferred from the embodiment of <figref idrefs="f0005">figure 10</figref>.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045">The width D5 of the rail 10 is advantageously slightly less than the width D4 of the seat 16 in order to limit the forward/backward movements of the rail 10 orthogonal to the<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> surface of the sheet 2, allowing the seat 16 to maintain the rail 10 with the flexible sheet 2 in a substantially median and centered position with respect to the opening 14 of the guide profile 12.</p><p id="p0046" num="0046">Such rail 10 can assume different forms, so that it can be coupled in a sliding relationship with different embodiments of flexible flaps 8, available on the market, fixed to the side edges 6 of the flexible sheet 2.</p><p id="p0047" num="0047">In accordance with a first embodiment illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0002">figures 4, 5</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0004">8</figref>, flap 8 of the sheet 2 is obtained with a flexible toothing 8' laterally projecting from the side edges 6 of the sheet 2 suitably reinforced with a support tape. Correspondingly, the rail 10 is shaped in the form of an elongated box-like body, advantageously obtained via extrusion in plastic material, e.g. with quadrangular shape section, which internally defines the groove 11 open towards the outside due to the aforesaid slit 17 for the passage of the sheet 2. In this case, the rail 10 is provided with at least two lateral wings 10', which are intended to come into abutment against the terminal portions 12A', 12B' of the arms 12A, 12B in order to prevent the rail 10 from exiting outward from the seat 16 of the guide profile 12. Advantageously, between the lateral wings 10' of the rail 10 and the terminal portions 12A', 12B' of the arms 12A, 12B, damping dowels 18 are interposed, advantageously obtained with spongy bodies, adapted to prevent the wind from transmitting impulsive stress to the teeth engaged in the rail 10 constrained in the seat 16 of the guide profile 12. Such stress is usually due to the action of the wind on the sheet 2; it can have excessive force capable of causing the breakage of the teeth or the tearing of the sheet 2.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048">Such damping dowels 18 at the same time allow compensating for possible shrinkage of the sheet 2.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">In accordance with a different second embodiment illustrated in the enclosed <figref idrefs="f0003">figures 6,<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> 7</figref>, <figref idrefs="f0004">9</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0005">10</figref>, the flap 8 of the sheet 2 is obtained with a flexible strap 8", preferably made of plastic material, laterally projecting from the side edges of the sheet 2, comprising a connection portion 8A, fixed with a first longitudinal margin thereof to the sheet 2, e.g. via gluing, and an engagement portion 8B having one free margin and one margin fixed to the second longitudinal margin of the connection portion 8A with an acute angle. Correspondingly, the rail 10 is shaped in the form of an elongated listel, advantageously obtained via extrusion and in plastic material, substantially having a C shape with two opposite cavities separated by the slit 17 crossing the sheet 2, having a width D6 less than the width D7 of the aforesaid flexible strip 8" in order to retain the latter constrained to the rail 10 in a slidable relationship.</p><p id="p0050" num="0050">The two guide profiles 12 thus advantageously define a seat 16, which is shaped such to receive at its interior different types of rails 10, in turn shaped to be connected in a slidable engagement relationship with different corresponding flexible flaps 8.</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">Such versatility is achieved by means of a guide profile 12 according to the present invention, which does not require internal tabs or other means for the composition of the guides of the rail or for its fixing to the upright, as is instead provided in the solutions of the prior art. The guide profile 12 can thus act as a connector element, of substantially multipurpose type, between the different types of rails 10 and the upright 9, defining seats 16 capable of housing different types of rails 10.</p><p id="p0052" num="0052">As is clearly explained above, the mechanical connection of the guide profiles 12 to the uprights 9 indeed occurs, according to an advantageous embodiment of the present invention, by means of tabs 19, 20 and with first fixing means 13 which are outside the seat.</p><p id="p0053" num="0053">Advantageously, the seat 16 of the two guide profiles 12 is defined by the inner faces of the two arms 12A, 12B which have flat and parallel surfaces. Due to such<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> characteristics, the seats are able to receive different types of rails 10, conferring to the guide profiles 12, and thus to the wind-up screen object of the present invention, a versatility of use that cannot be found in any other wind-up screen known up to now. For such purpose, the inner faces of the two arms 12A, 12B are extended in flat form for at least a majority section of the height L1 of the two arms 12A, 12B and preferably also of the height L2 of the connection wall 9A of the upright 9.</p><p id="p0054" num="0054">Preferably, the inner faces of the two arms 12A, 12B are flat for their entire extension. The seat 16 is thus defined, as indicated above, by a bottom 12C orthogonal to the two arms 12A, 12B, it too having a flat inner surface.</p><p id="p0055" num="0055">In accordance with a preferred embodiment of the present invention, each upright 9 is provided with a cross section shaped substantially as an L. Such L shape is obtained with a connection wall 9A, intended to be anchored, with its inner face, parallel on the outer face of the first arm 12A of the guide profile 12, and with a base wall 9B, which is obtained in a single body with the connection wall 9A. On the latter wall 9B, the through holes of the screws 40 are advantageously obtained, such screws aimed to fix the upright 9 to the side wall that defines the opening A to be covered.</p><p id="p0056" num="0056">The anchorage between the parallel opposite faces of the connection wall 9A of the upright 9 and the first arm 12A of the guide profile 12 is obtained by means of coupling between the first and second tabs 19 and 20 obtained on the aforesaid opposite faces. Preferably, the first fixing means 13 comprise a third tab 21, extended as a projection from the base wall 9B and shaped with the free end folded towards the same base wall 9B in order to define an abutment portion 21'; the means 13 also comprise a fourth shaped tab 22, extended outside the guide profile 12 at its bottom 12C (i.e. preferably, and more precisely, at an edge between the bottom 12C and the second arm 12B) and able to define with the base wall 9B at least one recess 23 for the insertion of a fixing<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> dowel 24 suitable for locking the guide profile 12 to the upright 9, with the connection wall 9A anchored to the first arm 12A.</p><p id="p0057" num="0057">More in detail, the aforesaid fourth shaped tab 22 of the guide profile 12 is provided with a foot 22', able to abut against the abutment portion 21' of the third tab 21 of the base wall 9B when the fixing dowel 24 is inserted under pressure inside the recess 23, so as to firmly anchor the guide profile 12 to the upright 9.</p><p id="p0058" num="0058">Advantageously, the aforesaid fixing dowel 24 is obtained by means of a seal made of elastically deformable material, inserted along the entire extension of the recess 23 which is equal to the extension of the upright 9.</p><p id="p0059" num="0059">In accordance with a preferred embodiment of the present invention, the wind-up screen 1 also comprises a coating cover 25, advantageously obtained with a further aluminum extrusion, intended to be anchored with its inner face parallel to the outer face of the second arm 12B of the guide profile 12.</p><p id="p0060" num="0060">The anchorage between the parallel opposite faces of the coating cover 25 and of the second arm 12B of the guide profile 12 is obtained by means of the coupling between fifth and sixth tabs 26 and 27 obtained on the aforesaid opposite faces.</p><p id="p0061" num="0061">Preferably, the coating cover 25 is provided with a seventh shaped tab 28, which is interposed between the fixing dowel 24 and the fourth tab 22 of the guide profile 12. In this manner, the insertion of the fixing dowel 24 in the recess 23 causes the fixing not only of the guide profile 12 on the upright 9, with the connection wall 9A anchored to the first arm 12A, but also the fixing of the coating cover 25 on the second arm 12B of the guide profile 12.</p><p id="p0062" num="0062">For the mounting of the wind-up screen 1 at an opening A, it is necessary to first fix the uprights 9, below the collection box 3 on the side walls that define the opening A that one wishes to close with the sheet 2.<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --></p><p id="p0063" num="0063">Previously, the ends of the uprights 9 were closed with suitable plugs, preferably made of plastic.</p><p id="p0064" num="0064">The plug 31 intended to be fixed below the collection box 3 is provided with a slit 32 for allowing the passage of the side edge 6 of the flexible sheet 2 and with alignment abutments 33 (e.g. shaped as projections) able to be coupled in form relationship with corresponding abutments (e.g. shaped as recesses) obtained below the collection box 3 in order to allow the positioning of the upright 9 in the correct position on the side wall that defines the opening A.</p><p id="p0065" num="0065">Furthermore, the upright 9 is mounted with its base wall 9B aligned with the side wall of the collection box 3 in order to also ensure a correct lateral positioning of the upright 9.</p><p id="p0066" num="0066">Therefore, the flexible sheet 2 is defined in its final position due to the correct positioning of the uprights 9 and without the need for any adjustment thereof.</p><p id="p0067" num="0067">Once the uprights 9 are centered below the collection box 3, they are fixed by means of screws or dowels to the side wall.</p><p id="p0068" num="0068">The rail 10 is then inserted in the seat 16 of the guide profile 12, and the flexible sheet 2 is then partly lowered, with the transverse bar 5 mounted on its lower end 4, moving it from the vertical in order to allow its facilitated insertion in the longitudinal groove 11 of the rail 10.</p><p id="p0069" num="0069">At this point, the guide profile 12 is positioned on the upright 9 with its first arm 12A anchored on the inner face of the wall 9A of the upright 9. The two parts are fixed together by inserting the fixing dowel 24 in the recess 23 and in such a manner locking the guide profile 12 to the upright 9.</p><p id="p0070" num="0070">Advantageously, before inserting the fixing dowel 24 in the recess 23, it is possible to also arrange the coating cover 25 by anchoring it on the outer face of the second arm<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> 12B of the guide profile 12, such that the insertion of the dowel 24 causes the fixing not only of the guide profile 12 on the upright 9 but also the fixing of the coating cover 25 on the second arm 12B of the guide profile 12.</p><p id="p0071" num="0071">The wind-up screen 1, object of the present invention, allows through a single component constituted by the guide profile 12 to limit the movements of the rail 10 and hence of the sheet 2, in particular achieving the abutment end stop for the movements of the rail 10 towards the opening 14 of the guide profile 12, as well as achieving the guide for the terminals 7 of the transverse bar 5.</p><p id="p0072" num="0072">Unlike the wind-up awnings/curtains of known type which require assembling the guides for the transverse bar and for the sheet, according to the present invention such guides are obtained without any assembly of parts, with the single component constituted by the guide profile 12. Since the latter is made of a single body, there is no risk of clearances between its parts, which could compromise the precision of its guides. In addition, the wind-up screen 1 that is the object of the present invention is particularly simple to assemble, since the flexible sheet 2 is easily inserted in the rail 10 in turn inserted in the seat 16 of the guide profile 12 which, being a rigid section, can be easily fit on the upright 9 and then be easily fixed with the fixing dowel 24.</p><p id="p0073" num="0073">The finding thus conceived therefore attains the pre-established objects.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56983634" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Abschirmvorrichtung mit Aufwicklung zum Schließen einer Öffnung (A), insbesondere einer Tür, eines Fensters oder Ähnlichem, die Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>- eine flexible Leinwand (2);</claim-text>
<claim-text>- eine drehbar in einem Kasten (3) gelagerte Rolle die über der genannten Öffnung (A) positioniert ist und die genannte flexible Leinwand (2) aufwickeln kann; wobei die genannte flexible Leinwand (2) mit Folgendem ausgestattet ist: mit einem oberen Ende, das mechanisch mit der genannten Rolle verbunden ist; mit einem unteren Ende (4), das mechanisch mit einer Querstange (5) verbunden ist, an deren Enden sich zwei Endstücke (7) befinden; und mit zwei seitlichen Rändern (6), von denen jeder mit einem flexiblen Verbindungsstreifen (8) ausgestattet ist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- mindestens zwei Streben (9), die dazu bestimmt sind, in einander gegenüber liegenden Position an den Seitenwänden der genannten Öffnung (A) befestigt zu werden;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- mindestens zwei Schienen (10), von denen jede mechanisch mit einer der genannten entsprechenden Streben (9) verbunden und mit einer Längsnut (11) versehen ist, in der der flexible Streifen (8) eines genannten Seitenrands (6) der genannten Leinwand (2) verschiebbar eingesetzt werden kann;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- zwei Führungsprofile (12), von denen jedes mechanisch an einer entsprechenden Strebe (9) mit ersten Befestigungsvorrichtungen (13) befestigt ist und aus einem einzigem Körper mit im Wesentlichen U-förmigem Querschnitt besteht, der durch zwei Ausleger (12A, 12B) erzielt wird, die im Wesentlichen parallel sind und durch einen Boden (12C) verbunden werden und eine Durchgangsöffnung der Leinwand (14) begrenzen, die der des Führungsprofils (12) gegenüberliegt, das an der anderen Strebe (9) befestigt ist;</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> -->
wobei jedes der genannten Führungsprofile (12) intern einen Sitz (16) definiert, der auf der genannten Durchgangsöffnung der Leinwand (14) teilweise geschlossen ist, in dem in einem Halteverhältnis die genannte Schiene (10) untergebracht ist; <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> jedes genannte Führungsprofil (12) über die genannten Ausleger (12A, 12B) außen eine Bahn (15) definiert, in der sich ein Endstück (7) der genannten Querstrebe (5) verschiebbar im Eingriff befindet.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Abschirmvorrichtung mit Aufwicklung nach Anspruch 1, <b>gekennzeichnet dadurch, dass</b> jede der genannten Streben (9) mit einem im Wesentlichen L-förmigen Querabschnitt mit einer Verbindungswand (9A) ausgestattet ist, die dazu bestimmt ist, parallel mit seiner Innenseite an der Außenseite des ersten Auslegers (12A) des genannten Führungsprofil (12) verankert zu werden und mit einer Grundwand (9B), die insbesondere dazu bestimmt ist, an der Seitenwand zur Begrenzung der genannten Öffnung (A) befestigt zu werden, die aus einem einzigen Körper mit der genannten Verbindungswand (9A) besteht.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Abschirmvorrichtung mit Aufwicklung nach Anspruch 2, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b>: die Verbindungswand (9A) der genannten Strebe (9) mit ersten Flügeln (19) ausgestattet ist; der erste Ausleger (12A) des genannten Führungsprofils (12) ist mit zweiten Flügeln (20) versehen; wobei die genannten ersten und zweiten Flügel (19, 20) untereinander mit der genannten Verbindungswand (9A) verankert werden können, die im Wesentlichen zum ersten Ausleger (12A) des genannten Führungsprofils (12) parallel ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Abschirmvorrichtung mit Aufwicklung nach Anspruch 2, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die genannten ersten Befestigungsvorrichtungen (13) Folgendes umfassen:
<claim-text>- mindestens einen dritten profilierten Flügel (21), der vorstehend von der genannten<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> Grundwand (9B) verläuft;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- mindestens einen vierten profilierten Flügel (22), der von dem genannten Führungsprofil (12) zur Außenseite seines Sitzes (16) auf seinem Boden (12C) verläuft und geeignet ist, mit der genannten Grundwand (9B) mindestens eine Nische (23) zu bilden, um einen Befestigungsdübel (24) einzusetzen, der geeignet ist, das genannte Führungsprofil (12) an der genannten Strebe (9) mit der Verbindungswand (9A) zu blockieren, die am ersten Ausleger (12A) verankert ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Abschirmvorrichtung mit Aufwicklung nach Anspruch 1, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> sie eine Verkleidungsabdeckung (25) umfasst, die dazu bestimmt ist, sich mit ihrer Innenseite parallel auf der Außenseite eines zweiten Auslegers (12B) des genannten Führungsprofils (12) zu verankern.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Abschirmvorrichtung mit Aufwicklung nach den Ansprüchen 4 und 5, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die genannte Verkleidungsabdeckung (25) mit mindestens einem siebten profilierten Flügel (28) ausgestattet ist, der zwischen dem genannten Befestigungsdübel (24) und dem vierten Flügel (22) des genannten Führungsprofils (12) eingesetzt wird, um die genannte Verkleidungsabdeckung (25) auf dem zweiten Ausleger (9B) des genannten Führungsprofils (12) zu blockieren.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Abschirmvorrichtung mit Aufwicklung nach Anspruch 5, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b>: die Verkleidungsabdeckung (25) mit fünften Flügeln (26) ausgestattet ist; der zweite Ausleger (12B) des genannten Führungsprofils (12) ist mit sechsten Flügeln (27) versehen; wobei die genannten fünften und sechsten Flügel (26, 27) untereinander mit der genannten Verkleidungsabdeckung (25) verankert werden können, die im Wesentlichen zum zweiten Ausleger (12B) des genannten Führungsprofils (12) parallel ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Abschirmvorrichtung mit Aufwicklung nach Anspruch 1, <b>dadurch<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> gekennzeichnet, dass</b> jedes Endstück (7) der genannten Querstrebe (5) mit zwei Führungsflügeln (30) ausgestattet ist, die zueinander parallel sind und als Verlängerung über die genannte Querstrebe (5) hinausragen und außen mit den Auslegern (12A, 12B) des genannten Führungsprofils (12) verbunden werden können.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Abschirmvorrichtung mit Aufwicklung nach Anspruch 1, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> der Abstand (D4) zwischen den Innenseiten der Ausleger (12A, 12B) des genannten Führungsprofils (12) die Verschiebungen der genannten Schiene (10) rechtwinklig zur Ebene der flexiblen Plane (2) begrenzt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Abschirmvorrichtung mit Aufwicklung nach Anspruch 1, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> das genannte Führungsprofil (12) so geformt ist, um in seinem Sitz (16) unterschiedliche Schienenformen (10) aufzunehmen, die geeignet sind, sich verschiebbar mit entsprechenden unterschiedlichen flexiblen Streifen (8) zu verbinden.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Abschirmvorrichtung mit Aufwicklung nach Anspruch 1, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die Innenseiten der beiden Ausleger (12A, 12B) der genannten Führungsprofile (12), die den genannten Sitz (16) begrenzen, flache und mindestens für einen Abschnitt parallele Flächen aufweisen, der größer als ihre Höhe (L1) ist und insbesondere auf der ganzen Ausdehnung ihrer Länge (L1).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Abschirmvorrichtung mit Aufwicklung nach Anspruch 11, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die Innenflächen der beiden Ausleger (12A, 12B) der genannten Führungsprofile (12) untereinander vom Boden (12C) her rechtwinklig miteinander verbunden sind.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56983635" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Wind-up screen for closing an opening (A), in particular a doorway, a window or the like, which comprises:
<claim-text>- a flexible sheet (2);</claim-text>
<claim-text>- a roller rotatably housed in a collection box (3) arranged above said opening (A) and able to wind up said flexible sheet (2); said flexible sheet (2) being provided: with an upper end mechanically associated with said roller; with a lower end (4) mechanically associated with a transverse bar (5) carrying two terminals (7) mounted at the ends; and with two side edges (6), each equipped with a flexible engagement flap (8);</claim-text>
<claim-text>- at least two uprights (9), intended to be fixed in a position facing one another at the side walls of said opening (A);</claim-text>
<claim-text>- at least two rails (10), each mechanically associated with one said corresponding upright (9) and provided with a longitudinal groove (11) suitable for slidably receiving the flexible flap (8) of one said side edge (6) of said sheet (2);</claim-text>
two guide profiles (12), each of which mechanically fixed to a corresponding upright (9) through first fixing means (13), made in a single body with cross section substantially shaped like a U, obtained with two substantially parallel arms (12A, 12B), joined by a bottom (12C) and defining a through opening for the sheet (14) facing that of the guide profile (12) fixed to the other upright (9); each of said guide profiles (12) defining internally a seat (16), partially closed at said through opening for the sheet (14), in which said rail (10) is housed in a holding relationship <b>characterized in that</b> each of said guide profiles (12) defining: on the outside through said arms (12A, 12B), a track (15), in which a terminal (7) of said transverse bar (5) is slidably engaged.<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Wind-up screen according to claim 1, <b>characterized in that</b> each of said uprights (9) is provided with a cross section substantially shaped like an L with a connection wall (9A), intended to be anchored with its inner face parallel to the outer face of a first arm (12A) of said guide profile (12), and with a base wall (9B), in particular intended to be fixed to the side wall defining said opening (A) made in a single body with said connection wall (9A).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Wind-up screen according to claim 2, <b>characterized in that</b>: the connection wall (9A) of said upright (9) is provided with first tabs (19); the first arm (12A) of said guide profile (12) is provided with second tabs (20); said first and second tabs (19, 20) being able to be anchored together with said connection wall (9A) substantially parallel to the first arm (12A) of said guide profile (12).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Wind-up screen according to claim 2, <b>characterized in that</b> said first fixing means (13) comprise:
<claim-text>- at least one third shaped tab (21) extended as a projection from said base wall (9B);</claim-text>
<claim-text>- at least one fourth shaped tab (22) extended from said guide profile (12) towards the outside of its seat (16), at its bottom (12C) and able to define, with said base wall (9B), at least one recess (23) for the insertion of a fixing dowel (24) suitable for locking said guide profile (12) to said upright (9) with the connection wall (9A) anchored to the first arm (12A).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Wind-up screen according to claim 1, <b>characterized in that</b> it comprises a coating cover (25) intended to be anchored with its inner face parallel on the outer face of a second arm (12b) of said guide profile (12).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Wind-up screen according to claims 4 and 5, <b>characterized in that</b> said coating cover (25) is provided with at least one seventh shaped tab (28) that is arranged between said fixing dowel (24) and the fourth tab (22) of said guide profile (12) in order to lock<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> said coating cover (25) on the second arm (9B) of said guide profile (12).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Wind-up screen according to claim 5, <b>characterized in that</b>: the coating cover (25) is provided with fifth tabs (26); the second arm (12B) of said guide profile (12) is provided with sixth tabs (27); said fifth and sixth tabs (26, 27) being able to be anchored together with said coating cover (25) substantially parallel to the second arm (12B) of said guide profile (12).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Wind-up screen according to claim 1, <b>characterized in that</b> each terminal (7) of said transverse bar (5) is provided with two guide wings (30), parallel to one another and projecting as an extension of said transverse bar (5), and able to be engaged outside the arms (12A, 12B) of said guide profile (12).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Wind-up screen according to claim 1, <b>characterized in that</b> the distance (D4) between the inner faces of the arms (12A, 12B) of said guide profile (12) limits the movements of said rail (10) perpendicular to the plane of the flexible sheet (2).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Wind-up screen according to claim 1, <b>characterized in that</b> said guide profile (12) is shaped to receive in its seat (16) different forms of rails (10), suitable for being connected in a slidable engagement relationship with corresponding different flexible flaps (8).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Wind-up screen according to claim 1, <b>characterized in that</b> the inner faces of the two arms (12A, 12B) of said guide profiles (12), which define said seat (16), have surfaces that are flat and parallel for at least a majority section of their height (L1), and in particular for the entire extension of their height (L1).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Wind-up screen according to claim 11, <b>characterized in that</b> the inner faces of the two arms (12A, 12B) of said guide profiles (12) are joined together by the bottom (12C) in a perpendicular manner.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56983636" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Dispositif d'écran à enroulement pour la fermeture d'une ouverture (A), en particulier d'une porte, d'une fenêtre ou similaires, comprenant :
<claim-text>- une toile flexible (2) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- un rouleau logé de façon tournante dans un coffre de logement (3) situé au-dessus de ladite ouverture (A) et susceptible d'enrouler ladite toile flexible (2) ; ladite toile flexible (2) étant pourvue : d'une extrémité supérieure mécaniquement associée audit rouleau ; d'une extrémité inférieure (4) mécaniquement associée à une barre transversale (5) portante montées en bout de deux pièces d'extrémité (7) ; et de deux rebords latéraux (6) chacun pourvu d'un bord d'engagement flexible (8) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- au moins deux montants (9), destinés à être fixés en position face à face entre eux aux parois latérales de ladite ouverture (A) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- au moins deux rails (10), chacun mécaniquement associé à un dit montant (9) correspondant et pourvu d'une rainure longitudinale (11) apte à recevoir de façon coulissante le bord flexible (8) dudit rebord latéral (6) de ladite toile (2) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- deux profils de guidage (12), chacun desquels est mécaniquement fixé à un montant (9) correspondant moyennant des premiers moyens de fixation (13) et réalisé en corps unique avec section transversale façonnée essentiellement en forme de U, obtenue au moyen de deux bras (12A, 12B) essentiellement parallèles, raccordés par un fond (12C) et délimitant une ouverture de passage de la toile (14) située en face de celle du profil de guidage (12) fixé à l'autre montant (9) ;</claim-text>
chacun desdits profils de guidage (12) définissant à l'intérieur un logement (16) partiellement fermé au niveau de ladite ouverture de passage de la toile (14) dans lequel est logé en rapport de retenue, ledit rail (10) ; <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> chacun desdits profils de guidage (12) définissant à l'extérieur moyennant lesdits bras (12A, 12B), une<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> piste (15) dans laquelle est engagée de façon coulissante une pièce d'extrémité (7) de ladite barre transversale (5).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Dispositif d'écran à enroulement, selon la revendication 1, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> chacun desdits montants (9) est pourvu d'une section transversale essentiellement façonnée en forme de L avec une paroi de raccordement (9A), destinée à s'ancrer de façon parallèle avec sa face interne à la face externe d'un premier bras (12A) dudit profil de guidage (12) et avec une paroi de base (9B), destinée notamment à être fixée à la paroi latérale de délimitation de ladite ouverture (A), réalisée en un corps unique avec ladite paroi de raccordement (9A).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Dispositif d'écran à enroulement, selon la revendication 2, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b>:
<claim-text>la paroi de raccordement (9A) dudit montant (9) est pourvue de premières ailettes (19) ; le premier bras (12A) dudit profil de guidage (12) est pourvu de deuxièmes ailettes (20) ; lesdites premières et deuxièmes ailettes (19, 20) étant ancrables entre elles avec ladite paroi de raccordement (9A) essentiellement parallèle au premier bras (12A) dudit profil de guidage (12).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Dispositif d'écran à enroulement, selon la revendication 2, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> lesdits premiers moyens de fixation (13) comprennent :
<claim-text>- au moins une troisième ailette (21) façonnée s'étendant en saillie de ladite paroi de base (9B) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- au moins une quatrième ailette (22) façonnée s'étendant dudit profil de guidage (12) vers l'extérieur de son logement (16), au niveau de son fond (12C) et susceptible de définir avec ladite paroi de base (9B) au moins une niche (23) pour l'introduction d'une cheville de fixation (24) apte à bloquer ledit profil de guidage (12) audit montant (9) avec la paroi de raccordement (9A) ancrée au premier bras (12A).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Dispositif d'écran à enroulement, selon la revendication 1, <b>caractérisé en ce qu'</b>il<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --> comprend un couvercle de revêtement (25) destiné à s'ancrer avec sa face interne parallèlement sur la face externe d'un second bras (12B) dudit profil de guidage (12).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Dispositif d'écran à enroulement, selon les revendications 4 et 5, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> ledit couvercle de revêtement (25) est pourvu d'au moins une septième ailette (28) façonnée laquelle s'interpose entre ladite cheville de fixation (24) et la quatrième ailette (22) dudit profil de guidage (12) pour bloquer ledit couvercle de revêtement (25) sur le second bras (9B) dudit profil de guidage (12).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Dispositif d'écran à enroulement, selon la revendication 5, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> le couvercle de revêtement (25) est pourvu de cinquièmes ailettes (26) ; le second bras (12B) dudit profil de guidage (12) est pourvu de sixièmes ailettes (27) ; lesdites cinquièmes et sixièmes ailettes (26, 27) étant ancrables entre elles audit couvercle de revêtement (25) essentiellement parallèle au second bras (12B) dudit profil de guidage (12).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Dispositif d'écran à enroulement, selon la revendication 1, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> chacune des pièces d'extrémité (7) de ladite barre transversale (5) est pourvue de deux ailes de guidage (30), parallèles entre elles, en saillie, en prolongement de ladite barre transversale (5) et susceptibles de s'engager extérieurement aux bras (12A, 12B) dudit profil de guidage (12).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Dispositif d'écran à enroulement, selon la revendication 1, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> la distance (D4) entre les faces internes des bras (12A, 12B) dudit profil de guidage (12) limite les déplacements dudit rail (10) orthogonalement au plan de la toile flexible (2).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Dispositif d'écran à enroulement, selon la revendication 1, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> ledit profil de guidage (12) est façonné pour recevoir dans son logement (16) différentes formes de rails (10), aptes à se raccorder dans un rapport d'engagement coulissant avec différents bords flexibles (8) correspondants.<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Dispositif d'écran à enroulement, selon la revendication 1, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> les faces internes des deux bras (12A, 12B) desdits profils de guidage (12), qui délimitent ledit logement (16), ont des surfaces planes et parallèles pour au moins un tronçon majoritaire de leur hauteur (L1), et notamment pour toute l'extension de leur hauteur (L1).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Dispositif d'écran à enroulement, selon la revendication 11, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> les faces internes des deux bras (12A, 12B) desdits profils de guidage (12) sont raccordées entre elles par le fond (12C) de façon orthogonale.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16671607" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1,2,3"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="165" he="213" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --><figure id="f0002" num="4,5"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="165" he="220" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --><figure id="f0003" num="6,7"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="165" he="220" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --><figure id="f0004" num="8,9"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="165" he="220" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --><figure id="f0005" num="10"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="165" he="220" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
