<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2352642-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2352642" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="42129882" file-reference-id="318274" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146588570" ucid="EP-2352642-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2352642</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-09825324-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154850762" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>09825324</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20091104</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140556583" ucid="US-2009063216-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>2009063216</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20091104</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140554559" ucid="US-29094008-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>29094008</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20081105</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130806</date></intention-to-grant-date><search-report-dispatch-date><date>20120619</date></search-report-dispatch-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989326004" load-source="ipcr">B41F   7/08        20060101ALI20130712BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989326005" load-source="ipcr">B41F  13/004       20060101AFI20130712BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989326006" load-source="ipcr">B41M   1/06        20060101ALI20130712BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989631945" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B41F  13/0045      20130101 LI20131203BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989640513" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B41F   7/08        20130101 FI20131203BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989641350" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B41P2213/734       20130101 LA20131203BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370343" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">GEMEINSAMER GUMMITUCHZYLINDER FÜR DRUCKMASCHINE MIT VARIABLER ABSCHALTUNG UND DRUCKVERFAHREN MIT VARIABLER ABSCHALTUNG</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370344" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">VARIABLE CUTOFF PRINTING PRESS WITH COMMON BLANKET CYLINDER AND METHOD OF VARIABLE CUTOFF PRINTING</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370345" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">PRESSE D'IMPRESSION À COUPURE VARIABLE AVEC CYLINDRE DE BLANCHET COMMUN ET PROCÉDÉ D'IMPRESSION À COUPURE VARIABLE</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919538739" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>GOSS INT AMERICAS INC</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919538048" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>GOSS INTERNATIONAL AMERICAS, INC.</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919543870" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>RICHARDS JOHN SHERIDAN</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919545076" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>RICHARDS, JOHN, SHERIDAN</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919023722" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>RICHARDS, JOHN, SHERIDAN</last-name><address><street>3 Hall Road</street><city>Barrington NH 03825</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919023724" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Goss International Americas, Inc.</last-name><iid>101096703</iid><address><street>121 Technology Drive</street><city>Durham, NH 03824</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919023723" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Kling, Simone</last-name><iid>101170679</iid><address><street>Lavoix Munich Bayerstrasse 83</street><city>80335 München</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="US-2009063216-W"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2009063216</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20091104</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2010053947-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2010053947</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20100514</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549881526" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549803931" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549787614" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549871633" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549924608" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549881527" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549786842" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549803936" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549924609" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549877389" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549787615" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549787616" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549786843" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549803937" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549803938" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549924610" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549871638" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549803939" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549787629" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549924611" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549786844" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549881528" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549786849" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549786850" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549894304" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS549894309" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549803944" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549787630" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549803945" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549787631" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549803946" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549803947" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549871639" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549786851" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549786852" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS549924612" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63960990" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001">BACKGROUND OF INVENTION</heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates generally to a printing press and more specifically to a variable cut off printing apparatus and method.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US5950536A"><text>U.S. Pat. No. 5,950,536</text></patcit> discloses a variable cutoff offset press unit wherein a fixed cutoff press is adapted to a variable cutoff press while maintaining the size of the blanket cylinders. A plate cylinder sleeve has a variable outer diameter, whereby a length of an image to be printed is varied proportionally to a variable outer diameter while maintaining an outer diameter of the gapless blanket cylinder sleeve constant. The size of a plate cylinder is changed by using a sleeve mounted over the plate cylinder or adding packing under a plate to increase the diameter of the plate cylinder.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003"><patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="US6327975B"><text>U.S. Pat. No. 6,327,975</text></patcit> discloses a method and apparatus for printing elongate images on a web. A first printing unit prints a first image portion on the web at prescribed spacings, by moving the impression cylinder away from the blanket cylinder each time one first image portion is printed. A second printing unit prints a second image portion on the spacings left on the web by the first printing unit, also by moving the impression cylinder away from the blanket cylinder each time one second image portion is printed. A variable speed motor rotates each blanket cylinder, while each time the associated impression cylinder is held away to create a space on the web for causing printing of the first or the second printing portion at required spacings.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004"><patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="US7066088B"><text>U.S. Pat. No. 7,066,088</text></patcit> discloses a variable cut-off offset press system and method of operation which utilizes a continuous image transfer belt. The offset printing system comprises at least two plate cylinders adapted to have thereon respective printing sleeves. Each of the printing sleeves is adapted to receive colored ink from a respective ink source. The system further comprises at least a impression cylinder, wherein the image transfer belt is positioned to contact each of the printing sleeves at respective nips formed between respective ones of the plate cylinders and the at least one impression cylinder.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005"><patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="DE888247C"><text>DE 888 247 C</text></patcit> relates to a perfecting printing press with inter-mediate cylinders made of hard material.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p><heading id="h0002">BRIEF SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading><p id="p0006" num="0006">According to the invention a variable cutoff web printing press is provided including a first plate cylinder for printing a first color of first and second images and a second plate cylinder for printing a second color of the first and the second images. The printing press also includes a common blanket cylinder. The first and second plate cylinders contact the common blanket cylinder and transfer the first and second images to the common blanket cylinder. The printing press also includes a first transfer body for receiving the first image from the common blanket cylinder and transferring the first image to a web and a second transfer body for receiving the second image from the common blanket cylinder and transferring the second image to the web.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">A method of variable cutoff web printing is also provided. The steps include transferring a first first image and a second first image to a common blanket cylinder, transferring the first first image from the common blanket cylinder to a first circumferential section movable with respect to a second circumferential section having a same rotational axis as the first circumferential section, printing the first first image on a web using the first circumferential section, transferring the second first image from the common blanket cylinder to the second circumferential section, and printing the second first image on the web using the second circumferential section.</p><heading id="h0003">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading><p id="p0008" num="0008">The present invention is described below by reference to the following drawings, in which:
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> shows a schematic side view of a perfecting printing press according to an embodiment of the present invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2a</figref> shows a schematic side view of a nonperfecting printing press according to an embodiment of the present invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 2b</figref> shows a schematic side view of the nonperfecting printing press shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2a</figref>;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 2c</figref> shows a schematic side view of the nonperfecting printing press shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Figs. 2a</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0003">2b</figref>; and<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></li><li><figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 3</figref> shows a schematic front view of a transfer body shown in <figref idrefs="f0002 f0003 f0004">Figs. 2a to 2c</figref>.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0004">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading><p id="p0009" num="0009">Variable cutoff printing presses have been developed to allow for printing products of different sizes on the same printing press without having to change plate and blanket cylinders. Changing plate and blanket cylinders to correspond to the cutoff of the image that needs to be printed can be a time consuming and difficult process. It also may require purchasing and storing cylinders of multiple sizes.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010"><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> shows a schematic side view of a perfecting printing press 30 according to an embodiment of the present invention. Printing press 30 includes two print units 10 and 20 printing on opposite sides of a passing web 12. Print unit 10 includes plate cylinders 14, 15, 16, 17, transfer bodies 135, 136 and common blanket cylinder 18. Transfer bodies 135, 136 include circumferential sections 31, 32, 33, 34 and support cylinders 35, 36, respectively. In a preferred embodiment plate cylinders 14, 15, 16, 17 may include two printing plates disposed about the surface of each plate cylinder 14, 15, 16, 17. Each plate cylinder 14, 15, 16, 17 is inked with a different colored ink and each plate cylinder 14, 15, 16, 17 rotates clockwise about a respective axis during a printing mode. The ink colors may be black, cyan, yellow and magenta, respectively, for example. Inked images are passed from each plate cylinder 14, 15, 16, 17 to common blanket cylinder 18, which then passes the images to circumferential blanket sections 31, 32, 33, 34, respectively. In turn, circumferential blanket sections 31, 32, 33, 34, which are rotating clockwise about respective support cylinders 35, 36 during the printing mode, print the images on the web. The images need to be reverse images so that the double transfer of images, first through common blanket cylinder 18, then through the respective circumferential blanket sections 31, 32, 33, 34, will be right-reading.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">During the printing mode, plate cylinders 14, 15, 16, 17 act together to print a first four color image on common blanket cylinder 18. Each plate cylinder 14, 15, 16, 17 is phased to print an inked image of one color so that the four different colored images printed respectively by plate cylinders 14, 15, 16, 17 are aligned to form a first four color image on common blanket cylinder 18. Plate cylinder 17 rotates and a first plate on plate cylinder 17 prints an inked image of a first color on rotating common blanket cylinder 18. When the inked image of the first color<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> approaches a nip formed between plate cylinder 16 and common blanket cylinder 18, a first plate on plate cylinder 16 prints an inked image of a second color on rotating common blanket cylinder 18, directly overprinting the inked image printed by the first plate of plate cylinder 17. When the overprinted inked images printed by respective first plates on cylinders 16, 17 approach a nip formed between plate cylinder 15 and common blanket cylinder 18, a first plate on plate cylinder 15 prints an inked image of a third color on rotating common blanket cylinder 18, directly overprinting the respective first images printed by respective first plates on plate cylinders 16, 17. When the overprinted inked images printed by respective first plates on plate cylinders 15, 16, 17 approach a nip formed between plate cylinder 14 and common blanket cylinder 18, a first plate on plate cylinder 14 prints an inked image of a fourth color on common blanket cylinder 18, at a position on common blanket cylinder 18 so that the image printed by the first plate on plate cylinder 14 overprints the respective images printed by the first plates on plate cylinders 15, 16, 17. Thus, the first plate on plate cylinder 14 completes a first four color image on common blanket cylinder 18.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">Common blanket cylinder 18 transfers the first four color image printed by plate cylinders 14, 15, 16, 17 to one of circumferential sections 31, 32, depending on the phasing of circumferential sections 31, 32. Whichever circumferential section 31, 32 receives the first four color image printed by plate cylinders 14, 15, 16, 17 from common blanket cylinder 18 then prints the first four color image on web 12. Plate cylinders 14, 15, 16, 17, during operation, should be in constant contact with common blanket cylinder 18. In a preferred embodiment, the surfaces of plate cylinders 14, 15, 16, 17 and common blanket cylinder 18 are traveling at a substantially equal constant velocity.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">After plate cylinders 14, 15, 16, 17 print a first four color image on common blanket cylinder 18, respective second plates on plate cylinders 14, 15, 16, 17 print a second four color image on common blanket cylinder 18. The second four color image should be printed similar to the first four color image, with second plates on plate cylinders 14, 15, 16, 17 overprinting in a manner similar to how first plates of plate cylinders 14, 15, 15, 17 printed the first four color image.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></p><p id="p0014" num="0014">The second four color image printed by plate cylinders 14, 15, 16, 17 is then transferred from common blanket cylinder 18 to either circumferential section 33, 34, depending on the phasing of circumferential sections 33, 34, which rotate clockwise about support cylinder 36 during operation. Whichever circumferential section 33, 34 receives the second four color image printed by plate cylinders 14, 15, 16, 17 from common blanket cylinder 18 then prints the second four color image on web 12.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">Plate cylinders 14, 15, 16, 17, common blanket cylinder 18, and circumferential sections 31, 32, 33, 34 are appropriately configured and phased so that circumferential sections 31, 32 print first four color images on web 12 printed by the respective first plates of plate cylinders 14, 15, 16, 17 on common blanket cylinder 18 and circumferential sections 33, 34 print second four color images on web 12 printed by the respective second plates of plate cylinders 14, 15, 16, 17 on common blanket cylinder 18. Circumferential sections 31, 32, 33, 34 are also appropriately configured and phased so that circumferential sections 31, 32 print every other four color image on web 12, while circumferential sections 33, 34 print intervening four color images. In a preferred embodiment, there should not be any unprinted space between the first four color images printed by circumferential sections 31, 32 and adjacent second four color images printed by circumferential sections 33, 34.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">Print unit 20 includes plate cylinders 24, 25, 26, 27 and transfer bodies 145, 146. Transfer bodies 145, 146 may include support cylinders 45, 46 and circumferential sections 41, 42, 43, 44 similar to support cylinders 35, 36 and circumferential sections 31, 32, 33, 34 of transfer bodies 135, 136, respectively. Two plates are disposed about the surface of each plate cylinder 24, 25, 26, 27. Each plate cylinder 24, 25, 26, 27 is inked with a different color ink and rotates counterclockwise about a respective axis during operation. Plate cylinders 24, 25, 26, 27 may print four color images on common blanket cylinder 28, which are transferred to circumferential sections 41, 42, 43, 44, with print unit 20 printing in a manner similar to how print unit 10 prints.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">Surfaces of circumferential sections 31, 32, 33, 34, 41, 42, 43, 44 are raised above surfaces of support cylinders 35, 36, 45, 46 so that each circumferential section 31, 32, 33, 34, 41, 42, 43, 44 contacts respective common blanket cylinder 18, 28 and web 12 during a single<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> revolution about the axis of transfer bodies 135, 136, 145, 146, respectively. Surfaces of support cylinders 35, 36, 45, 46, which can be defined as not raised, do not come into contact with web 12 or respective common blanket cylinders 18, 28. This configuration allows circumferential sections 31, 32, 33, 34, 41, 42, 43, 44 to accelerate or decelerate while not in contact with web 12 or respective common blanket cylinders 18, 28 without smearing the respective four color images on common blanket cylinders 18, 28 and web 12. In a preferred embodiment, circumferential sections 31, 32, 33, 34, 41, 42, 43, 44 are driven independently of one another, allowing each circumferential section 31, 32, 33, 34, 41, 42, 43, 44 to independently accelerate and decelerate. For example, circumferential section 31 may be driven independently of circumferential section 32, and therefore circumferential section 32 can be accelerated while circumferential section 31 is printing an image on web 12 without causing the image being printed by circumferential section 31 to be smeared.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">Circumferential sections 31, 32, 33, 34, 41, 42, 43, 44 may need to accelerate, decelerate, or simply travel at constant velocities depending on the positioning of the transfer bodies 135, 136, 145, 146 in relation to the respective common blanket cylinders 18, 28, the velocity of web 12 in relation to the velocity of respective common blanket cylinders 18, 28, and the length of the images on the respective first and second plates of plate cylinders 14, 15, 16, 17, 24, 25, 26, 27.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">Surfaces of circumferential sections 31, 32, 33, 34, 41, 42, 43, 44 run at substantially the same velocity as respective common blanket cylinders 18, 28 as circumferential sections 31, 32, 33, 34, 41, 42, 43, 44 contact respective common blanket cylinders 18, 28 and run at substantially the same velocity as web 12 as circumferential sections 31, 32, 33, 34, 41, 42, 43, 44 contact web 12. Thus, when web 12 travels at a different rate than the surface of common blanket cylinders 18, 28, circumferential sections 31, 32, 33, 34, 41, 42, 43, 44 have to accelerate and decelerate when rotating between web 12 and respective common blanket cylinders 18, 28, and when rotating between respective common blanket cylinders 18, 28 and web 12.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">In alternative embodiments, plate cylinders 14, 15, 16, 17 each may include one printing plate including one or more images or printing plates may not be required, with one or more images directly imaged on plate cylinders 14, 15, 16, 17. In these embodiments, respective<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> circumferential sections 31, 32, 41, 42 may receive a first portion of images from respective common blanket cylinder 18, 28 and print the first portion of the images on web 12 and respective circumferential sections 33, 34, 43, 44 will receive second portions of the images from common blanket cylinder 18, 28 and print the second portion of the image on web 12.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021"><figref idrefs="f0002 f0003 f0004">Figs. 2a to 2c</figref> show schematic side views of a nonperfecting printing press 50 according to an embodiment of the present invention printing on web 52. <figref idrefs="f0002 f0003 f0004">Figs. 2a to 2c</figref> show an example of how, according to an embodiment of the present invention, plate cylinders 54, 55, 56, 57 print four color images on common blanket cylinder 58, which are transferred to circumferential sections 61, 62, 63, 64 and printed on web 52, in a manner similar to how printing units 10, 20 print.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">Each plate cylinder 54, 55, 56, 57 is driven by a respective motor 101, 102, 103, 104. In an alternative embodiment, one or more plate cylinders 54, 55, 56, 57 can be driven by a common motor. Each plate cylinder 54, 55, 56, 57 includes a first plate 70, 72, 74, 76, respectively, and a second plate 71, 73, 75, 77, respectively. Each plate cylinder 54, 55, 56, 57 is inked with a different colored ink and rotates clockwise about a respective axis during operation. Plate cylinders 54, 55, 56, 57, during printing mode, are in constant contact, via respective plates 70, 71, 72, 73, 74, 75, 76, 77 with a common blanket cylinder 58, which is rotated counterclockwise about an axis by a motor 110. In an alternative embodiment, a common motor can rotate plate cylinders 54, 55, 56, 57 and common blanket cylinder 58. Surfaces of plates 70, 71, 72, 73, 74, 75, 76, 77 and the surface of common blanket cylinder 58 may travel at substantially equal velocities.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">Plates 70, 71, 72, 73, 74, 75, 76, 77 of plate cylinders 54, 55, 56, 57 carry formed images 80, 81, 82, 83, 84, 85, 86, 87. Each plate cylinder 54, 55, 56, 57 is provided with a different colored ink. First inked images, corresponding to respective formed images 80, 82, 84, 86, are printed on common blanket cylinder 58 by first plates 70, 72, 74, 76 on plate cylinders 54, 55, 56, 57, respectively. Second inked images, corresponding to respective formed images 81, 83, 85, 87, are printed on common blanket cylinder 58 by second plates 71, 73, 75, 77 on plate cylinders 54, 55, 56, 57, respectively. First inked images are printed on top of one another on common blanket cylinder 58 to form first four color images 180, 182, 184, 186, 188, which are<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> shown schematically in <figref idrefs="f0002 f0003 f0004">Figs. 2a to 2c</figref> by shading. Second inked images printed by second plates 71, 73, 75, 77 are printed on top of one another on common blanket cylinder 58 to form second four color images 181, 183, 185, 187, 189, 191, 193, which are shown schematically in <figref idrefs="f0002 f0003 f0004">Figs. 2a to 2c</figref> by stripes.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">First four color images 180, 182, 184, 186, 188 are transferred from common blanket cylinder 58 to circumferential sections 61, 62, respectively, which print first four color images 180, 182, 184, 186, 188 on passing web 52. Second four color images 181, 183, 185, 187, 189, 191, 193 are transferred from common blanket cylinder 58 to circumferential sections 63, 64, respectively, which print second four color images on passing web 52. Circumferential sections 61, 62, 63, 64 may be rotated about respective support cylinders 65, 66 by motors 105, 106, 107, 108, respectively. Formed images 80, 81, 82, 83, 84, 85, 86, 87 on plates 70, 71, 72, 73, 74, 75, 76, 77, respectively, need to be reverse images so that the double transfer of images, first through common blanket cylinder 58, then through the respective circumferential sections 61, 62, 63, 64, will be right-reading.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">Motors 101, 102, 103, 104, 105, 106, 107, 108, 110 may be controlled by a controller 200. Controller 200 ensures cylinders 54, 55, 56, 57, 58, and circumferential sections 61, 62, 63, 64 are properly phased and positioned so four color images are printed on web 52 in a proper alignment.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">As shown in the embodiment in <figref idrefs="f0002 f0003 f0004">Figs. 2a to 2c</figref>, images 80, 81, 82, 83, 84, 85, 86, 87 on plates 70, 71, 72, 73, 74, 75, 76, 77, respectively, do not take up the entire length of respective plates 70, 71, 72, 73, 74, 75, 76, 77. In this embodiment, plates 70, 71, 72, 73, 74, 75, 76, 77 are all of equal length. Images 80, 81, 82, 83, 84, 85, 86, 87 also are all of equal length. Thus, plates 70, 71, 72, 73, 74, 75, 76, 77 have portions that are prepared as non-print area. Web 52 travels a distance substantially equal to the length of one of images 80, 81, 82, 83, 84, 85, 86, 87 in a time each plate cylinder 54, 55, 56, 57 performs one half of a revolution. Therefore, printing surfaces of plates 70, 71, 72, 73, 74, 75, 76, 77 may travel at a greater velocity than web 52. For example, if each plate cylinder 54, 55, 56, 57, including corresponding plates 70, 71, 72, 73, 74, 75, 76, 77 has a permanent circumference of 50 inches, and plates 70, 71, 72, 73, 74, 75, 76, 77 are each 25 inches long but each printing an image that is only 21 inches long, then web 17 may<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> travel 16% [(50 - (2)*(21))/50 = 8/50 = 0.16] more slowly than the printing surfaces of plate cylinders 54, 55, 56, 57.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">When plates 70, 71, 72, 73, 74, 75, 76, 77 have portions of non-print area, there will be corresponding non-printed spaces between first four color images and second four color images printed on common blanket cylinder 58 by plates 70, 71, 72, 73, 74, 75, 76, 77. If a length of a circumference of common blanket 58 is equal to an integer multiple of the length of the circumference of each plate cylinder 54, 55, 56, 57, then the non-printed spaces on common blanket cylinder 58 will not vary with each revolution of blanket cylinder 58. In the schematic embodiment shown in <figref idrefs="f0002 f0003 f0004">Figs. 2a to 2c</figref>, the length of the circumference of common blanket cylinder 58 is assumed to be substantially equal to three times the surface of each plate cylinder 54, 55, 56, 57. Accordingly, common blanket cylinder 58 is schematically shown divided into six equal sections for illustrative purposes. Each section includes an image transferring portion 102, which has a surface length equal to the length of each formed image 80, 81, 82, 83, 84, 85, 86, 87, and a non-printed space 100, which has a surface length equal to the portions of non-print area on each plate 70, 71, 72, 73, 74, 75, 76, 77. Image transferring portion 102 and non-printed space 100 demonstrate where inked images of formed images 80, 81, 82, 83, 84, 85, 86, 87 may be printed on common blanket cylinder 58 and where portions of non-print area of plates 70, 71, 72, 73, 74, 75, 76, 77 may contact the surface of common blanket cylinder 58.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">In a preferred embodiment each first four color image forms one continuous image with an adjacent second four color image. A cutoff length of each continuous image equals a length of each first four color image plus the length of each second four color image. To vary the cutoff of the continuous images printed by printing press 50 the plates 70, 71, 72, 73, 74, 75, 76, 77 could be replaced with respective replacement plates having images that vary in length from images 80, 81, 82, 83, 84, 85, 86, 87.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029"><figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 3</figref> shows a schematic front view of an embodiment of transfer body 165 shown in <figref idrefs="f0002 f0003 f0004">Figs. 2a to 2c</figref>. Transfer body 165 has a support shaft 91, which can attach to a frame or other supporting device to stabilize support cylinder 65 and circumferential sections 61, 62. In this embodiment, circumferential sections 61, 62 independently rotate about support cylinder 65. Circumferential sections 61, 62 are attached to support arms 94, 95, respectively. Support arms<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> 94, 95 are attached to respective bearings 92, 93 that are rotatably attached to support shaft 91. Bearings 92, 93 are rotated by respective motors 105, 106 about support shaft 91, thereby driving circumferential sections 61, 62, respectively, about support cylinder 65. Transfer body 166 (<figref idrefs="f0002 f0003 f0004">Figs. 2a to 2c</figref>) and transfer bodies 135, 136, 145, 146 (<figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>) may be similarly configured.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">In alternative embodiments circumferential sections 31, 32, 33, 34, 41, 42, 43, 44, 61, 62, 63, 64 may, respectively, be circumferential sections on common axes with no respective support cylinders 35, 36, 45, 46, 65, 66. For example, support cylinder 65 would be absent, with circumferential sections 61 and 62 independently rotating about a common axis to receive four color images from common blanket cylinder 58 and print those images on web 52.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56985710" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Rollendruckmaschine (50) mit variablem Abschnitt, umfassend:
<claim-text>einen ersten Plattenzylinder (54) zum Druck einer ersten Farbe eines ersten (180) und eines zweiten (181) Bildes;</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen zweiten Plattenzylinder (55) zum Druck einer zweiten Farbe des ersten (180) und des zweiten (181) Bildes;</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen gemeinsamen Gummituchzylinder (58);</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen ersten Übertragungskörper (165); und</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen zweiten Übertragungskörper (166);</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b>:
<claim-text>der erste und der zweite Plattenzylinder mit dem gemeinsamen Gummituchzylinder in Kontakt kommen und das erste (180) und das zweite (181) Bild an den gemeinsamen Gummituchzylinder übertragen;</claim-text><claim-text>der erste Übertragungskörper (165) ausgelegt ist, um das erste Bild (180) vom gemeinsamen Gummituchzylinder zu empfangen und das erste Bild auf eine Bahn (52) zu übertragen; und</claim-text><claim-text>der zweite Übertragungskörper (165) ausgelegt ist, um das zweite Bild (181) vom gemeinsamen Gummituchzylinder zu empfangen und das zweite Bild auf die Bahn (52) zu übertragen.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Rollendruckmaschine (50) mit variablem Abschnitt nach Anspruch 1, wobei der erste Übertragungskörper (165) einen ersten Umfangsabschnitt (61) umfasst, der mit Bezug auf einen zweiten Umfangsabschnitt (62) beweglich ist, und der zweite Übertragungskörper (166) einen dritten Umfangsabschnitt (63) umfasst, der mit Bezug auf einen vierten Umfangsabschnitt (64) beweglich ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Rollendruckmaschine (50) mit variablem Abschnitt nach Anspruch 2, wobei der erste Übertragungskörper (165) einen ersten Stützzylinder (65) umfasst, der den ersten und den zweiten Umfangsabschnitt stützt, und der zweite Übertragungskörper (166) einen zweiten Stützzylinder (66) umfasst, der den dritten und den vierten Umfangsabschnitt stützt.<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Rollendruckmaschine (50) mit variablem Abschnitt nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 3, weiter umfassend einen dritten Plattenzylinder (56) zum Druck einer dritten Farbe des ersten (180) und des zweiten (181) Bildes auf dem gemeinsamen Gummituchzylinder (58).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Rollendruckmaschine (50) mit variablem Abschnitt nach Anspruch 4, weiter umfassend einen vierten Plattenzylinder (57) zum Druck einer vierten Farbe des ersten (180) und des zweiten (181) Bildes auf dem gemeinsamen Gummituchzylinder (58), wobei der erste, der zweite, der dritte und der vierte Plattenzylinder zusammen arbeiten, um die ersten (180) und zweiten (181) Vierfarbbilder auf dem gemeinsamen Gummituchzylinder zu drucken, wobei der gemeinsame Gummituchzylinder (58) das erste Vierfarbbild (180) an den ersten Übertragungsköper (165) überträgt, und das zweite Vierfarbbild (181) an den zweiten Übertragungskörper (166).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Rollendruckmaschine (50) mit variablem Abschnitt nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 5, wobei der erste Plattenzylinder (54) mindestens eine erste Platte (70) umfasst, die die erste Farbe des ersten Bildes (180) und die erste Farbe des zweiten Bildes (181) trägt, und der zweite Plattenzylinder (55) mindestens eine zweite Platte (72) umfasst, die die zweite Farbe des ersten Bildes (180) und die zweite Farbe des zweiten Bildes (181) trägt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Rollendruckmaschine (50) mit variablem Abschnitt nach Anspruch 6, wobei das erste Bild (180) und das zweite Bild (181) ein ununterbrochenes Bild mit einer Abschnittslänge umfassen, und die mindestens eine erste Platte (70) entfernt und durch mindestens eine erste Ersatzplatte ersetzt werden kann, und die mindestens eine zweite Platte (72) entfernt und durch mindestens eine zweite Ersatzplatte ersetzt werden kann,<br/>
wobei die mindestens eine erste Ersatzplatte und die mindestens eine zweite Ersatzplatte ein erstes Ersatzbild und ein zweites Ersatzbild auf dem gemeinsamen Gummituchzylinder (58) drucken, wobei das erste Ersatzbild und das zweite Ersatzbild ein ununterbrochenes Ersatzbild mit einer Ersatzabschnittslänge bilden;<br/>
wobei die Ersatzabschnittslänge verschieden von der Abschnittslänge ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Rollendruckmaschine (50) mit variablem Abschnitt nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 7,<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> weiter umfassend einen ersten Druckzylinder (67) und einen zweiten Druckzylinder (68), wobei der erste Übertragungskörper (165) während des Druckmodus über die Bahn (52) mit dem ersten Druckzylinder in Kontakt kommt und der zweite Übertragungskörper (166) während des Druckmodus über die Bahn mit dem zweiten Druckzylinder in Kontakt kommt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Rollendruckmaschine mit variablem Abschnitt nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 8, wobei der gemeinsame Gummituchzylinder (58) einen Umfang aufweist, der ein ganzzahliges Vielfaches einer Summe eines Umfangs des ersten Plattenzylinders (54) ist und eines Umfangs des zweiten Plattenzylinders (55).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Verfahren zum Bedrucken einer Bahn mit variablem Abschnitt, umfassend die folgenden Schritte:
<claim-text>Übertragen eines ersten ersten Bildes (180) und eines zweiten ersten Bildes (182) an einen gemeinsamen Gummituchzylinder (58);</claim-text>
<claim-text>Übertragen des ersten ersten Bildes (180) von dem gemeinsamen Gummituchzylinder an einen ersten Umfangsabschnitt (61), der mit Bezug auf einen zweiten Umfangsabschnitt (62) beweglich ist, der die gleiche Drehachse wie der erste Umfangsabschnitt aufweist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Drucken des ersten ersten Bildes (180) auf eine Bahn (52) unter Verwendung des ersten Umfangsabschnitts (61);</claim-text>
<claim-text>Übertragen des zweiten ersten Bildes (182) von dem gemeinsamen Gummituchzylinder an den zweiten Umfangsabschnitt (62); und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Drucken des zweiten ersten Bildes (180) auf die Bahn unter Verwendung des zweiten Umfangsabschnitts.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Druckverfahren nach Anspruch 10, wobei das erste und das zweite Bild Vierfarbenbilder sind.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Druckverfahren nach Anspruch 10 oder 11, weiter umfassend Drehung des ersten Umfangsabschnitts (61) mit einer variierenden Geschwindigkeit, nachdem das erste erste Bild (180) unter Verwendung des ersten Umfangsabschnitts auf eine Bahn gedruckt ist.<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Druckverfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 10 bis 12, weiter umfassend:
<claim-text>Übertragung eines ersten zweiten Bildes (181) und eines zweiten zweiten Bildes (183) auf den gemeinsamen Gummituchzylinder(58);</claim-text>
<claim-text>Übertragung des ersten zweiten Bildes (181) von dem gemeinsamen Gummituchzylinder an einen dritten Umfangsabschnitt (63), der mit Bezug auf einen vierten Umfangsabschnitt (64) beweglich ist, der die gleiche Drehachse wie der dritte Umfangsabschnitt aufweist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Drucken des ersten zweiten Bildes (181) auf die Bahn zwischen dem ersten (180) und dem zweiten (182) ersten Bild unter Verwendung des dritten Umfangsabschnitts;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Übertragung des zweiten zweiten Bildes (183) von dem gemeinsamen Gummituchzylinder an den vierten Umfangsabschnitt (64); und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Drucken des zweiten zweiten Bildes (183) nach dem zweiten ersten Bild (182) auf die Bahn (52) unter Verwendung des vierten Umfangsabschnitts (64).</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56985711" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A variable cutoff web printing press (50) comprising:
<claim-text>a first plate cylinder (54) for printing a first color of first (180) and second (181) images;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second plate cylinder (55) for printing a second color of the first (180) and the second (181) images;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a common blanket cylinder (58);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first transfer body (165); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second transfer body (166),</claim-text>
<b>characterized in that</b>:
<claim-text>the first and second plate cylinders contact the common blanket cylinder and transfer the first (180) and second (181) images to the common blanket cylinder;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the first transfer body (165) is adapted for receiving the first image (180) from the common blanket cylinder and transferring the first image to a web (52); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the second transfer body (165) is adapted for receiving the second image (181) from the common blanket cylinder and transferring the second image to the web (52).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The variable cutoff web printing press (50) recited in claim 1 wherein the first transfer body (165) includes a first circumferential section (61) movable with respect to a second circumferential section (62) and the second transfer body (166) includes a third circumferential section (63) movable with respect to a fourth circumferential section (64).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The variable cutoff web printing press (50) recited in claim 2 wherein the first transfer body (165) includes a first supporting cylinder (65) supporting the first and second circumferential sections and the second transfer body (166) includes a second support cylinder (66) supporting the third and fourth circumferential sections.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The variable cutoff web printing press (50) as recited in anyone of claims 1 to 3 further comprising a third plate cylinder (56) for printing a third color of the first (180) and the second (181) images on the common blanket cylinder (58).<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The variable cutoff web printing press (50) as recited in claim 4 further comprising a fourth plate cylinder (57) for printing a fourth color of the first (180) and the second (181) images on the common blanket cylinder (58), the first, second, third and fourth plate cylinders acting together to print first (180) and second (181) four color images on the common blanket cylinder, the common blanket cylinder (58) transferring the first four color image (180) to the first transfer body (165) and the second four color image (181) to the second transfer body (166).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The variable cutoff web printing press (50) as recited in anyone of claims 1 to 5 wherein the first plate cylinder (54) includes at least one first plate (70) carrying the first color of the first image (180) and the first color of the second image (181) and the second plate cylinder (55) includes at least one second plate (72) carrying the second color of the first image (180) and the second color of the second image (181).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The variable cutoff web printing press (50) as recited in claim 6 wherein the first image (180) and the second image (181) form a continuous image having a cutoff length, and the at least one first plate (70) can be removed and replaced with at least one first replacement plate and the at least one second plate (72) can be removed and replaced with at least one second replacement plate;<br/>
wherein the at least one first replacement plate and the at least one second replacement plate print a first replacement image and a second replacement image on the common blanket cylinder (58), the first replacement image and the second replacement image forming a replacement continuous image having a replacement cutoff length;<br/>
wherein the replacement cutoff length varies from the cutoff length.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The variable cutoff web printing press (50) recited in anyone of claims 1 to 7 further comprising a first impression cylinder (67) and a second impression cylinder (68) wherein the first transfer body (165) contacts the first impression cylinder via the web (52) during the printing mode and the second transfer body (166) contacts the second impression cylinder via the web during the printing mode.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The variable cutoff web printing press recited in anyone of claims 1 to 8 wherein the common blanket cylinder (58) has a circumference that is an integer multiple of a sum of a<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> circumference of the first plate cylinder (54) and a circumference of the second plate cylinder (55).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>A method of variable cutoff web printing comprising the steps of:
<claim-text>transferring a first first image (180) and a second first image (182) to a common blanket cylinder (58);</claim-text>
<claim-text>transferring the first first image (180) from the common blanket cylinder to a first circumferential section (61) movable with respect to a second circumferential section (62) having a same rotational axis as the first circumferential section;</claim-text>
<claim-text>printing the first first image (180) on a web (52) using the first circumferential section (61);</claim-text>
<claim-text>transferring the second first image (182) from the common blanket cylinder to the second circumferential section (62); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>printing the second first image (182) on the web using the second circumferential section.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>The method of printing as recited in claim 10 wherein the first and the second first images are four color images.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>The method of printing as recited in claim 10 or 11 further comprising rotating the first circumferential section (61) at a varying velocity after the first first image (180) is printed on the web using the first circumferential section.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>The method of printing as recited in anyone of claims 10 to 12 further comprising:
<claim-text>transferring a first second image (181) and a second second image (183) to the common blanket cylinder (58);</claim-text>
<claim-text>transferring the first second image (181) from the common blanket cylinder to a third circumferential section (63) movable with respect to a fourth circumferential section (64) having a same rotational axis as the third circumferential section;</claim-text>
<claim-text>printing the first second image (181) on the web between the first (180) and the second (182) first images using the third circumferential section;</claim-text>
<claim-text>transferring the second second image (183) from the common blanket cylinder to the fourth circumferential section (64); and<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>printing the second second image (183) on the web (52) following the second first image (182) using the fourth circumferential section (64).</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56985712" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Presse d'impression sur bande à coupe variable (50) comprenant :
<claim-text>un premier cylindre porte-plaque (54) pour imprimer une première couleur de première (180) et seconde (181) images ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un deuxième cylindre porte-plaque (55) pour imprimer une seconde couleur des première (180) et seconde (181) images ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un cylindre porte-blanchet commun (58) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un premier corps de transfert (165) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un second corps de transfert (166),</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>caractérisée en ce que</b> :
<claim-text>les premier et deuxième cylindres porte-plaque viennent en contact avec le cylindre porte-blanchet commun et transfèrent les première (180) et seconde (181) images sur le cylindre porte-blanchet commun ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>le premier corps de transfert (165) est conçu pour recevoir la première image (180) du cylindre porte-blanchet commun et transférer la première image sur une bande (52) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>le second corps de transfert (165) est conçu pour recevoir la seconde image (181) du cylindre porte-blanchet commun et transférer la seconde image sur la bande (52).</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Presse d'impression sur bande à coupe variable (50) selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle le premier corps de transfert (165) comporte une première section circonférentielle (61) mobile par rapport à une deuxième section circonférentielle (62) et le second corps de transfert (166) comporte une troisième section circonférentielle (63) mobile par rapport à une quatrième section circonférentielle (64).<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Presse d'impression sur bande à coupe variable (50) selon la revendication 2, dans laquelle le premier corps de transfert (165) comporte un premier cylindre de support (65) supportant les première et deuxième sections circonférentielles et le second corps de transfert (166) comporte un second cylindre de support (66) supportant les troisième et quatrième sections circonférentielles.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Presse d'impression sur bande à coupe variable (50) selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 3, comprenant en outre un troisième cylindre porte-plaque (56) pour imprimer une troisième couleur des première (180) et seconde (181) images sur le cylindre porte-blanchet commun (58).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Presse d'impression sur bande à coupe variable (50) selon la revendication 4, comprenant en outre un quatrième cylindre porte-plaque (57) pour imprimer une quatrième couleur des première (180) et seconde (181) images sur le cylindre porte-blanchet commun (58), les premier, deuxième, troisième et quatrième cylindre porte-plaque agissant conjointement pour imprimer les première (180) et seconde (181) images en quadrichromie sur le cylindre porte-blanchet commun, le cylindre porte-blanchet commun (58) transférant la première image en quadrichromie (180) sur le premier corps de transfert (165) et la seconde image en quadrichromie (181) sur le second corps de transfert (166).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Presse d'impression sur bande à coupe variable (50) selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 5, dans laquelle le premier cylindre porte-plaque (54) comprend au moins une première plaque (70) portant la première couleur de la première image (180) et la première couleur de la seconde image (181) et le deuxième cylindre porte-plaque (55) comprend au moins une seconde plaque (72) portant la deuxième couleur<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> de la première image (180) et la deuxième couleur de la seconde image (181).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Presse d'impression sur bande à coupe variable (50) selon la revendication 6, dans laquelle la première image (180) et la seconde image (181) forment une image continue ayant une longueur de coupe, et l'au moins une première plaque (70) peut être retirée et remplacée par au moins une première plaque de remplacement et l'au moins une seconde plaque (72) peut être retirée et remplacée par au moins une seconde plaque de remplacement ;<br/>
dans laquelle l'au moins une première plaque de remplacement et l'au moins une seconde plaque de remplacement impriment une première image de remplacement et une seconde image de remplacement sur le cylindre porte-blanchet commun (58), la première image de remplacement et la seconde image de remplacement formant une image continue de remplacement ayant une longueur de coupe de remplacement ;<br/>
dans laquelle la longueur de coupe de remplacement varie par rapport à la longueur de coupe.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Presse d'impression sur bande à coupe variable (50) selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 7, comprenant en outre un premier cylindre d'impression (67) et un second cylindre d'impression (68), dans laquelle le premier corps de transfert (165) vient en contact avec le premier cylindre d'impression via la bande (52) en mode d'impression et le second corps de transfert (166) vient en contact avec le second cylindre d'impression via la bande en mode d'impression.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Presse d'impression sur bande à coupe variable selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 8, dans laquelle le cylindre porte-blanchet commun (58) a une circonférence qui est un entier multiple d'une somme d'une circonférence du premier<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> cylindre porte-plaque (54) et d'une circonférence du second cylindre porte-plaque (55).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Procédé d'impression de bande à coupe variable comprenant les étapes suivantes :
<claim-text>le transfert d'une première première image (180) et d'une seconde première image (182) sur un cylindre porte-blanchet commun (58) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>le transfert de la première première image (180) du cylindre porte-blanchet commun sur une première section circonférentielle (61) mobile par rapport à une deuxième section circonférentielle (62) ayant un même axe de rotation que la première section circonférentielle ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'impression de la première première image (180) sur une bande (52) au moyen de la première section circonférentielle (61) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>le transfert de la seconde première image (182) du cylindre porte-blanchet commun sur la deuxième section circonférentielle (62) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'impression de la seconde première image (182) sur la bande au moyen de la deuxième section circonférentielle.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Procédé d'impression selon la revendication 10, dans lequel les première et seconde premières images sont des images en quadrichromie.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Procédé d'impression selon la revendication 10 ou 11, comprenant en outre la rotation de la première section circonférentielle (61) à une vitesse variable une fois que la première première image (180) est imprimée sur la bande au moyen de la première section circonférentielle.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Procédé d'impression selon l'une quelconque des revendications 10 à 12, comprenant en outre :<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> -->
<claim-text>le transfert d'une première seconde image (181) et d'une seconde seconde image (183) sur le cylindre porte-blanchet commun (58) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>le transfert de la première seconde image (181) du cylindre porte-blanchet commun sur une troisième section circonférentielle (63) mobile par rapport à une quatrième section circonférentielle (64) ayant un même axe de rotation que la troisième section circonférentielle ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'impression de la première seconde image (181) sur la bande entre la première (180) et la seconde (182) première image au moyen de la troisième section circonférentielle ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>le transfert de la seconde seconde image (183) du cylindre porte-blanchet commun sur la quatrième section circonférentielle (64) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'impression de la seconde seconde image (183) sur la bande (52) à la suite de la seconde première image (182) au moyen de la quatrième section circonférentielle (64).</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16672239" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="165" he="164" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2A"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="165" he="219" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --><figure id="f0003" num="2B"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="165" he="219" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --><figure id="f0004" num="2C"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="165" he="219" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --><figure id="f0005" num="3"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="150" he="226" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
