<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-1435641-B1" country="EP" doc-number="1435641" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="32505932" file-reference-id="290026" date-produced="20180823" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146589213" ucid="EP-1435641-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>1435641</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-03027274-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154851405" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>03027274</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20031128</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP219826046" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>03027274.4</doc-number><date>20031128</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140551654" ucid="US-31637002-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>31637002</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20021211</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130709</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989327951" load-source="docdb">A61L   2/10        20060101ALI20130514BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989327952" load-source="docdb">A61L   9/20        20060101ALI20130514BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989327953" load-source="docdb">C02F   1/32        20060101ALI20130514BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989327954" load-source="docdb">H01J  61/04        20060101AFI20130514BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989327955" load-source="docdb">H01J  61/10        20060101ALI20130514BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989327956" load-source="docdb">H01J  61/72        20060101ALI20130514BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989641408" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01J  61/04        20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989651881" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01J  61/10        20130101 FI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132372272" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Gasentladungslampe mit einem Kathodenschutzschild, eine eine solche Gasentladungslampe enthaltende keimtötende Lampe und Verfahren zur Desinfektion von verschmutztem Wasser oder Behandlung von Abwasser und Erhöhung der Stromlast in einer Gasentladungslampe</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132372273" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Gas discharge lamp with a cathode shield, germicidal lamp comprising the same and method of disinfecting contaminated water or treating wastewater and increasing current load in a gas discharge lamp</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132372274" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Lampe à décharge gazeuse avec un écran cathodique, lampe germicide la comprenant et procédé pour désinfecter de l'eau pollué ou traiter de l'eaux usées et augmenter la charge de courant dans une lampe à décharge gazeuse</invention-title><citations><patent-citations><patcit mxw-id="PCIT369950731" load-source="docdb" ucid="US-6193894-B1"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>6193894</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20010227</date></document-id><sources><source name="EXA" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit></patent-citations></citations></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919533766" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>LIGHT SOURCES INC</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919532645" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>LIGHT SOURCES, INC.</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919512681" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>PIROVIC ARPAD</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919524973" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>PIROVIC, ARPAD</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919026882" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>PIROVIC, ARPAD</last-name><address><street>34 Ox Bow Lane</street><city>Woodbridge, Connecticut 06525</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919026884" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Light Sources, Inc.</last-name><iid>100167032</iid><address><street>37 Robinson Boulevard</street><city>Orange, CT 06477</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919026883" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Grünecker, Kinkeldey, Stockmair &amp; Schwanhäusser Anwaltssozietät</last-name><iid>100060488</iid><address><street>Leopoldstrasse 4</street><city>80802 München</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549899976" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549885080" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549891209" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549885081" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549794220" load-source="docdb">NL</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63961623" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001"><b>FIELD OF THE INVENTION</b></heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates in general to improving the current load of a gas discharge lamp, and particularly to a predetermined size shield for an electrode or cathode for improving performance.</p><heading id="h0002"><b>BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</b></heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">Low pressure gas discharge lamps, such as fluorescent lamps and germicidal lamps, have been known for many years. Gas discharge lamps usually have an envelope or a vessel enclosing electrodes that function as a cathode and anode. Ionized gas between the cathode and anode create an electromagnetic radiation discharge. In a fluorescent lamp, this discharge is converted to visible light. In a<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> germicidal lamp, the ultraviolet radiation is used to disinfect materials such as wastewater.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">While cathode shields of different structures have been utilized in the past to limit the loss of emission material from the cathode caused by ion bombardment and vaporization, prior cathode shields have not improved current load without changing discharge characteristics of the lamp. Prior cathode shield structures have increased the service life of a fluorescent lamp and have reduced the blacking of the inside of the lamp. However, these prior cathode shields may also increase the starting voltage of the fluorescent lamp. Therefore, there is a need for a cathode shield for use in a gas discharge lamp that can improve the current load without changing discharge characteristics.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p><p id="p0004" num="0004"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="WO8101344A"><text>WO 81/01344</text></patcit> relates to a cathode unit for a fluorescent tube and it discloses all of the features in the preamble of claim 1.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005"><patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="WO03088307A"><text>WO 03/088307</text></patcit> relates to a homogenous cathode unit and it discloses a cathode screen having a central opening. The central opening has a diameter of between 3-8 mm. This size is the most efficient size for narrow fluorescent tubes with a diameter of 16 mm.</p><heading id="h0003"><b>SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</b></heading><p id="p0006" num="0006">The above problems are solved by a gas discharge lamp as set forth in claim 1, a germicidal lamp as set forth in claim 9 and a method of disinfecting contaminated water or treatment of wastewater as set forth in claim 11. The present invention comprises a cathode shield for use in a gas discharge lamp that has predetermined openings proportional to the size of the lamp and shield resulting in improved current load without changing discharge characteristics of the gas discharge lamp, as well as<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> improving lamp life. A gas discharge lamp has a quartz envelope or vessel having a predetermined diameter. An electrode placed within the envelope or vessel has a cup shaped shield placed around the electrode or filament. The cup shaped shield has a large opening adjacent the end of the gas discharge lamp. A cover placed on the cup shaped shield has a hole therein. The diameter of the hole in the cover has a proportional relationship to the diameter of the envelope or vessel and the diameter of the cup shaped shield. Specifically, the ratio of the diameter of the envelope or vessel to the diameter of the hole in the cover is between 3.5 and 4.5, and the ratio of the diameter of the cup to the diameter of the hole in the cover is between 2.0 and 3.0. These proportional relationships have been found to reduce the cross sectional area of the arc at the anode or electrode, thereby increasing ion and electron current density and effectively cooling the anode. This allows for increased current load. The temperature cooling effect of the present invention also decreases the evaporation rate of cathode emission material, resulting in less consumption of emission material and longer cathode life.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></p><p id="p0007" num="0007">Accordingly, it is an object of the present invention to improve current load without changing discharge characteristics of a gas discharge lamp.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">It is a further object of the present invention to improve lamp life.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">It is an advantage of the present invention that heat is dissipated.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">It is another advantage of the present invention that lower temperature operation may be obtained and anode fall is reduced.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">It is a feature of the present invention that a hole in a cover of a shield is sized in proportion to the lamp envelope and cup shaped shield.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">It is a further feature of the present invention that a hole is placed in the cup shaped shield opposite the cover so that amalgam placed on the stem of the lamp becomes accessible.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">These and other objects, advantages, and features will become more readily apparent in view of the following detailed description.<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></p><heading id="h0004">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading><p id="p0014" num="0014"><ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> schematically illustrates a gas discharge lamp.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2</figref> is a partial cross section illustrating an electrode assembly of one end of a gas discharge lamp.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 3</figref> is an elevational view illustrating the electrode assembly</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 4</figref> is an elevational view illustrating another embodiment of an electrode assembly.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 5</figref> schematically illustrates the diameters in the shield structure used in the proportional relationships.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 6</figref> schematically illustrates showing a germicidal water treatment system embodiment of the present invention.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0005"><b>DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</b></heading><p id="p0015" num="0015"><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> schematically illustrates a gas discharge lamp 10. The gas discharge lamp 10 comprises electrode assemblies 12 on either end of a cylindrical quartz envelope or vessel 14. The gas discharge lamp 10 may be any low pressure gas discharge lamp, such as a germicidal lamp or a fluorescent lamp.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016"><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2</figref> illustrates an electrode assembly 12 from one end of the gas discharge lamp 10 illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> Placed within the quartz envelope or vessel 14 is a stem 16. The stem 16 is made of the same material as the glass envelope 14 and may be formed within the glass envelope or vessel 14 or pressed from the glass envelope or vessel 14. Formed within the stem 16 are wire leads 18. The leads 18 support a filament 20, which functions as a cathode or anode for the gas discharge lamp. The filament 20 has an emissive coating 22 thereon. Formed around the filament 20 is a cup shaped shield 26. The cup or shield 26 is attached to one of the leads 18 with a bracket 24. The cup shaped shield 26 has a relatively large bottom hole 28 formed therein adjacent the stem 16. On the stem 16 may be placed amalgam 34. The bottom hole 28 in the cup or shield 26 should be of sufficient size so as to make the amalgam 34 accessible. The cup shaped shield 26 is preferably made of a conductive material. The cup or shield 26 is illustrated as being attached to lead 18. If the bracket 24 is conductive, the cup or shield 26 is considered live. If the bracket 24 is an insulator or if the bracket 24 is connected to the stem 16 and not the lead 18, the cup or shield is considered to be dead or is not electrically connected to the lead 18.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></p><p id="p0017" num="0017">Covering the cup or shield 26 is cover 30. Within cover 30 is a hole 32. The cover 30 is preferably made of a non-conducting material, such as mica, having a thickness from between 0.003 and 0.005 inches.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018"><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 3</figref> illustrates the electrode assembly 12. The filament or cathode 20 held by the lead 18 is shielded by cup shaped shield 26 and cover 30. However, adjacent the electrode or filament 20 is hole 32. The hole 32 has a predetermined diameter. The predetermined diameter of hole 32 has a relationship with the diameter of the cup shaped shield 26 and the diameter of the envelope or vessel 14, illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figs. 1 and 2</figref>. In this embodiment the lead 18 is attached to the cup shaped shield 26 by bracket 24. Therefore, the electrode is considered live because it is electrically connected to the lead 18.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019"><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 4</figref> illustrates another electrode assembly 12'. In the electrode assembly 12' the cup shaped shield 26 is held by bracket 24' which is placed within stem 16'. In this embodiment the electrode is considered dead because it is not electrically connected to the lead 18.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020"><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 5</figref> schematically illustrates the different diameters of the envelope, cup shaped shield, and the hole in the cover used in the gas discharge lamp. Element 114<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> represents the inside of the envelope or vessel and has a diameter d<sub>v</sub>. Element 130 represents the cup shaped shield and has a diameter d<sub>c</sub>. Element 132 represents the hole in the cover and has a diameter d<sub>H</sub>.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">It has been discovered that improved current load is obtained without changing the discharge characteristics of the lamp if specific or predetermined proportional relationships are maintained between the different diameters d<sub>v</sub>, d<sub>c</sub> and d<sub>H</sub>. The preferred proportional relationship is particularly advantageous for providing low temperature operation and starting of a gas discharge lamp. The present invention is particularly applicable to lamps used in cold or cooler weather, or that are submerged in a relatively cool fluid such as use in germicidal applications. For example, germicidal lamps are often submerged in wastewater to disinfect the wastewater prior to discharge. Usually, this wastewater is relatively cool, and therefore the lamp must operate in a relatively cool environment. It has been determined that improved service life and low temperature operating and starting is achieved when the ratio of d<sub>v</sub> to d<sub>h</sub> ranges between 3.5 and 4.5 and the ratio of d<sub>c</sub> to d<sub>H</sub> ranges between 2.0 and 3.0.<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></p><p id="p0022" num="0022">For example, the table below illustrates preferred dimensions for the different diameters.
<tables id="tabl0001" num="0001"><table frame="all"><tgroup cols="5"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="14mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="14mm"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="14mm"/><colspec colnum="4" colname="col4" colwidth="14mm"/><colspec colnum="5" colname="col5" colwidth="14mm"/><thead valign="top"><row><entry align="center"><b>d<sub>H</sub></b></entry><entry align="center"><b>d<sub>C</sub></b></entry><entry align="center"><b>d<sub>V</sub></b></entry><entry align="center"><b>d<sub>V</sub>/d<sub>H</sub></b></entry><entry align="center"><b>d<sub>C</sub>/d<sub>H</sub></b></entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry align="char" char="." charoff="13">0.375</entry><entry align="char" char="." charoff="13">0.875</entry><entry align="char" char="." charoff="13">1.500</entry><entry align="char" char="." charoff="13">4.00</entry><entry align="char" char="." charoff="13">2.33</entry></row><row><entry align="char" char="." charoff="13">0.250</entry><entry align="char" char="." charoff="13">0.750</entry><entry align="char" char="." charoff="13">1.000</entry><entry align="char" char="." charoff="13">4.00</entry><entry align="char" char="." charoff="13">3.00</entry></row><row><entry align="char" char="." charoff="13">0.188</entry><entry align="char" char="." charoff="13">0.500</entry><entry align="char" char="." charoff="13">0.750</entry><entry align="char" char="." charoff="13">3.98</entry><entry align="char" char="." charoff="13">2.65</entry></row><row><entry align="char" char="." charoff="13">0.156</entry><entry align="char" char="." charoff="13">0.138</entry><entry align="char" char="." charoff="13">0.625</entry><entry align="char" char="." charoff="13">4.01</entry><entry align="char" char="." charoff="13">2.80</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></tables>
Where,
<dl id="dl0001" compact="compact"><dt>d<sub>H</sub> =</dt><dd>the diameter of the hole in the cover;</dd><dt>d<sub>C</sub> =</dt><dd>the diameter of the cup shaped shield; and</dd><dt>d<sub>V</sub> =</dt><dd>the diameter of the envelope or vessel.</dd></dl></p><p id="p0023" num="0023">The above units of the different diameters are expressed in inches, but any units may be used as it is the ratio that is of interest in determining the proportional relationships of the diameters.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">Accordingly, the present invention is a new cathode design with an improved disintegration shield. This shield and cover reduce the cross section area of the arc at the anode, thereby increasing ion and electron current density and effectively cooling the anode. The temperature<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> controlling effect of this electrode design decreases the evaporation rate of cathode emission material. This results in less consumption of emission material and longer cathode life. The present invention helps to dissipate heat and dissipates an electron cloud around the filament to help cooling. Increased current loads may be achieved without changing discharge characteristics. Additionally, lower temperature operations may be maintained with reduced anode fall. This conserves emission material placed on the filament and increases service life. Additionally, amalgam placed on the stem may be better accessed. Therefore, the present invention, in providing specific proportional relationships between the different diameters of the electrode assembly greatly improves lamp operation.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025"><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 6</figref> schematically illustrates a germicidal application for disinfecting contaminated water or the treatment of wastewater. A water treatment system 236 comprises a conduit 238 containing water 240 for germicidal treatment. The water 240 has a direction of flow represented by arrow 242. Ultraviolet germicidal lamp 210 has an electrode construction as illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0001 f0002">Figs. 2-4</figref> and is controlled by lamp control 244. The germicidal lamp 210 is submerged in the water 240 being treated. The<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> electrode construction illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0001 f0002">Figs 2-4</figref> permits the germicidal lamp 210 to operate at lower operating temperatures with improved service life. This is beneficial due to the lower operation temperatures typically encountered as a result of the temperature of the water 240 being treated. The germicidal lamp 210 has improved starting and longer service life.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">While the preferred embodiments have been illustrated and described, it will be appreciated by those skilled in the art that various modifications may be made without departing from the scope of this invention.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56987609" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Gasentladungslampe (10, 210), die Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>eine Hülle (14) mit einem ersten Durchmesser (d<sub>v</sub>);</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Glühdraht (20), der in der Hülle (14) platziert ist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine becherförmige Abschirmung (26) mit einem zweiten Durchmesser (d<sub>c</sub>) und einem Bodenloch (28), die um den Glühdraht (20) platziert ist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Deckel (30) mit einem Loch (32) mit einem dritten Durchmesser (d<sub>h</sub>), der die becherförmige Abschirmung (26) gegenüber dem Bodenloch (28) bedeckt; wobei der dritte Durchmesser (d<sub>h</sub>) des Lochs (32) in dem Deckel (30) eine vorbestimmte Größe aufweist, die ein erstes Verhältnis relativ zu dem ersten Durchmesser (d<sub>v</sub>) der Hülle (14) und ein zweites Verhältnis relativ zu dem zweiten Durchmesser (d<sub>c</sub>) der becherförmigen Abschirmung (26) bildet, so dass eine Querschnittsfläche einer Entladung reduziert wird,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei sich die Ionen- und Stromdichte erhöht;</claim-text>
<claim-text>und</claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Verhältnis des ersten Durchmessers (d<sub>v</sub>) zu dem dritten Durchmesser (d<sub>h</sub>) zwischen 3,5</claim-text>
<claim-text>und 4,5 ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Verhältnis des zweiten Durchmessers (d<sub>c</sub>) zu dem dritten Durchmesser (d<sub>h</sub>) zwischen 2,0 und 3,0 ist, so dass die Stromlast erhöht werden kann, um die Entladungscharakteristiken zu ändern.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Gasentladungslampe (10, 210) nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Gasentladungslampe eine keimtötende Lampe ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Gasentladungslampe (10, 210) nach Anspruch 1, die weiterhin umfasst:
<claim-text>Amalgam, das neben dem Bodenloch (28) angeordnet ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei das Bodenloch (28) eine Größe aufweist, die ausgelegt ist, um an das Amalgam zu gelangen.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Gasentladungslampe (10, 210) nach Anspruch 1, die weiterhin umfasst:
<claim-text>einen Pfropfen (16), der ein Ende der Hülle (14) abdichtet;</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Leitungsdraht (18), der in dem Pfropfen (16) platziert ist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei der Heizdraht (22) auf dem Leitungsdraht (18) platziert ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei die becherförmige Abschirmung (26) das Bodenloch (28) darin über dem Pfropfen (16) aufweist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei man einen Betrieb bei niedrigerer Temperatur erreicht, ohne die Entladungscharakteristiken der Gasentladungslampe (10) zu ändern.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Gasentladungslampe (10, 210) nach Anspruch 4, wobei die becherförmige Abschirmung (26) ein Leiter ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Gasentladungslampe (10, 210) nach Anspruch 4, wobei der Deckel (30) ein Isolator ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Gasentladungslampe (10, 210) nach Anspruch 4, wobei: die becherförmige Abschirmung (26) elektrisch mit dem Leitungsdraht (18) verbunden ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Gasentladungslampe (10, 210) nach Anspruch 4, wobei: die becherförmige Abschirmung (26) elektrisch von dem Leitungsdraht (18) isoliert ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Keimtötende Lampe zur Verwendung in der Wasseraufbereitung, die Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>eine Gasentladungslampe (210) nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 8, und</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Lampensteuerung (244), die mit einem Leitungsdraht (18) der Gasentladungslampe (210) verbunden ist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei die keimtötende Lampe (210) ausgelegt ist, in einer Leitung (238) eines Wasseraufbereitungssystems (236) untergetaucht zu werden.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Keimtötende Lampe zur Verwendung in der Wasseraufbereitung nach Anspruch 9, die weiterhin umfasst:
<claim-text>Amalgam, das neben dem Bodenloch (28) platziert ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei das Bodenloch (28) eine Größe aufweist, die ausgelegt ist, um an das Amalgam zu gelangen.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Verfahren zum Desinfizieren von verschmutztem Wasser (240) oder zum Aufbereiten von Abwasser (240) und zur Erhöhung der Stromlast in einer Gasentladungslampe (210), die bei einer niedrigen Temperatur des verschmutzten Wassers (240) oder des Abwassers (240) betrieben wird, wobei die Gasentladungslampe (210) eine Hülle (14) mit einem ersten Durchmesser (d<sub>v</sub>) aufweist,<br/>
<b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> das Verfahren Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>Platzieren eines Bechers (26) mit einem zweiten Durchmesser (d<sub>c</sub>) um einen Heizdraht (22) der Gasentladungslampe (210);</claim-text>
<claim-text>Bedecken des Bechers (26) mit einem Deckel (30) mit einem Loch (32) mit einem dritten Durchmesser (d<sub>h</sub>); und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Untertauchen der Gasentladungslampe (210) in dem verschmutzten Wasser (240) oder</claim-text>
<claim-text>dem Abwasser (240);</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei das Verhältnis des ersten Durchmessers (d<sub>v</sub>) und des dritten Durchmessers (d<sub>h</sub>) im Bereich zwischen 3,5 und 4,5 liegt, und das Verhältnis des zweiten Durchmesser (d<sub>c</sub>) und</claim-text>
<claim-text>des dritten Durchmessers (d<sub>h</sub>) im Bereich zwischen 2,0 und 3,0 liegt,</claim-text>
<claim-text>so dass man eine erhöhte Stromlast und einen Betrieb bei niedrigen Temperaturen erreicht, ohne die Entladungscharakteristiken der Gasentladungslampe zu verändern.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56987610" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A gas discharge lamp (10, 210) comprising:
<claim-text>an envelope (14) having a first diameter (d<sub>v</sub>);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a filament (20) placed within said envelope (14);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cup shaped shield (26) having a second diameter (d<sub>c</sub>) and a bottom hole (28) placed around said filament (20);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cover (30) having a hole (32) with a third diameter (d<sub>h</sub>) covering said cup shaped shield (26) opposite the bottom hole (28); wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>the third diameter (d<sub>h</sub>) of the hole (32) in said cover (30) has a predetermined size forming a first proportion relative to the first diameter (d<sub>v</sub>) of said envelope (14) and a second proportion relative to the second diameter (d<sub>c</sub>) of said cup shaped shield (26) so that a cross section area of an arc is reduced increasing ion and current density;</claim-text>
<claim-text>and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a ratio of the first diameter (d<sub>v</sub>) to the third diameter (d<sub>h</sub>) is between 3.5 and 4.5; and</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>characterized in that</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>a ratio of the second diameter (d<sub>c</sub>) to the third diameter (d<sub>h</sub>) is between 2.0 and 3.0,</claim-text>
<claim-text>so that current load may be increased without changing discharge characteristics.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>A gas discharge lamp (10, 210) as in claim 1 wherein the gas discharge lamp is a germicidal lamp.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>A gas discharge lamp (10, 210) as in claim 1 further comprising:
<claim-text>amalgam placed adjacent the bottom hole (28); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the bottom hole (28) has a size adapted to access said amalgam.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>A gas discharge lamp (10, 210) according to claim 1, further comprising:
<claim-text>a stem (16) sealing an end of said envelope (14);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a lead wire (18) placed within said stem (16);</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the filament (22) placed on said lead wire (18); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said cup shaped shield (26) has said bottom hole (28) therein over said stem (16);</claim-text>
<claim-text>whereby low temperature operation is obtained without changing discharge characteristics of the gas discharge lamp(10).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>A gas discharge lamp (10, 210) as in claim 4 wherein said cup shaped shield (26) is a conductor.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>A gas discharge lamp (10, 210) as in claim 4 wherein said cover (30) is an insulator.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>A gas discharge lamp (10, 210) as in claim 4 wherein: said cup shaped shield (26) is electrically connected to said lead wire (18).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>A gas discharge lamp (10, 210) as in claim 4 wherein: said cup shaped shield (26) is electrically insulated from said lead wire (18).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>A germicidal lamp for use in water treatment comprising:
<claim-text>a gas discharge lamp (210) according to any one of the claims 1 - 8, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a lamp control (244) connected to a lead wire (18) of the gas discharge lamp (210);</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the germicidal lamp (210) is adapted to be submerged in water (240) in a conduit (238) of a water treatment system (236).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>A germicidal lamp for use in water treatment as in claim 9 further comprising:
<claim-text>amalgam placed adjacent the bottom hole (28); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the bottom hole (28) has a size adapted to access said amalgam.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>A method for disinfecting contaminated water (240) or the treatment of wastewater (240) and for increasing current load in a gas discharge lamp (210) operated at the low temperature of the contaminated water (240) or the wastewater (240), the gas discharge lamp (210) having an envelope (14) of a first diameter (d<sub>v</sub>),<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --><b>characterized in that</b> the method comprises:
<claim-text>placing a cup (26) having a second diameter (d<sub>c</sub>) around a filament (22) of the gas discharge lamp (210);</claim-text>
<claim-text>covering the cup (26) with a cover (30) having a hole (32) with a third diameter (d<sub>h</sub>);</claim-text>
<claim-text>and</claim-text>
<claim-text>submerging the gas discharge lamp (210) in the contaminated water (240) or the wastewater (240);</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the ratio of the first diameter (d<sub>v</sub>) and the third diameter (d<sub>h</sub>) ranges between 3.5 and 4.5 and the ratio of the second diameter (d<sub>c</sub>) and the third diameter (d<sub>h</sub>) ranges between 2.0 and 3.0,</claim-text>
<claim-text>so that increased current load and low temperature operation is obtained without changing discharge characteristics of the gas discharge lamp.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56987611" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Lampe à décharge de gaz (10, 210) comprenant :
<claim-text>une enveloppe (14) ayant un premier diamètre (d<sub>v</sub>) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un filament (20) placé à l'intérieur de ladite enveloppe (14) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une coupelle de protection (26) ayant un deuxième diamètre (d<sub>c</sub>) et un trou inférieur (28) placé autour dudit filament (20) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un couvercle (30) comportant un trou (32) avec un troisième diamètre (d<sub>n</sub>) recouvrant ladite coupelle de protection (26) à l'opposé du trou inférieur (28) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans laquelle</claim-text>
<claim-text>le troisième diamètre (d<sub>n</sub>) du trou (32) dans ledit couvercle (30) possède une taille prédéterminée formant une première proportion par rapport au premier diamètre (d<sub>v</sub>) de ladite enveloppe (14) et une seconde proportion par rapport au deuxième diamètre (de) de ladite coupelle de protection (26) de façon à diminuer la section d'un arc, ce qui augmente la densité des ions et du courant ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>le rapport du premier diamètre (d<sub>v</sub>) sur le troisième diamètre (d<sub>n</sub>) est compris entre 3,5 et 4,5 ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>caractérisée en ce que</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>le rapport du deuxième diamètre (d<sub>c</sub>) sur le troisième diamètre (d<sub>n</sub>) est compris entre 2,0 et 3,0,</claim-text>
<claim-text>de sorte que la charge de courant peut être accrue sans modifier les caractéristiques de décharge.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Lampe à décharge de gaz (10, 210) selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle la lampe à décharge de gaz est une lampe germicide.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Lampe à décharge de gaz (10, 210) selon la revendication 1, comprenant en outré :
<claim-text>un amalgame disposé de manière adjacente au trou inférieur (28) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel le trou inférieur (28) possède une taille adaptée à l'accès audit amalgame.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Lampe à décharge de gaz (10, 210) selon la revendication 1, comprenant en outré :
<claim-text>un pied (16) fermant hermétiquement une extrémité de ladite enveloppe (14) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un fil conducteur (18) placé à l'intérieur dudit pied (16) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel le filament (22) est placé sur ledit fil conducteur (18) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel ledit trou inférieur (28) situé à l'intérieur de ladite coupelle de protection (26) se trouve au-dessus dudit pied (16) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>de sorte qu'un fonctionnement à basse température est obtenu sans modifier les caractéristiques de décharge de la lampe à décharge de gaz (10).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Lampe à décharge de gaz (10, 210) selon la revendication 4, dans laquelle ladite coupelle de protection (26) est un conducteur.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Lampe à décharge de gaz (10, 210) selon la revendication 4, dans laquelle ledit couvercle (30) est un isolant.<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Lampe à décharge de gaz (10, 210) selon la revendication 4, dans laquelle ladite coupelle de protection (26) est connectée électriquement audit fil conducteur (18).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Lampe à décharge de gaz (10, 210) selon la revendication 4, dans laquelle ladite coupelle de protection (26) est isolée électriquement dudit fil conducteur (18).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Lampe germicide destinée à être utilisée dans le traitement de l'eau comprenant :
<claim-text>une lampe à décharge de gaz (210) selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 8, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>une commande de lampe (244) connectée à un fil conducteur (18) de la lampe à décharge de gaz (210) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans laquelle la lampe germicide (210) est adaptée à être immergée dans l'eau (240) dans une conduite (238) d'un système de traitement de l'eau (236).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Lampe germicide destinée à être utilisée dans le traitement de l'eau selon la revendication 9, comprenant en outré :
<claim-text>un amalgame disposé de manière adjacente au trou inférieur (28) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel le trou inférieur (28) possède une taille adaptée à l'accès audit amalgame.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Procédé de désinfection d'eau contaminée (240) ou de traitement des eaux usées (240) et d'augmentation de la charge de courant dans une lampe à décharge de gaz (210) fonctionnant à la température basse de l'eau contaminée (240) ou des eaux usées (240), la lampe à<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> décharge de gaz (210) comportant une enveloppe (14) d'un premier diamètre (d<sub>v</sub>) ;<br/>
<b>caractérisé en ce que</b> le procédé comprend :
<claim-text>la disposition d'une coupelle (26) ayant un deuxième diamètre (de) autour d'un filament (22) de la lampe à décharge de gaz (210) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>le recouvrement de la coupelle (26) avec un couvercle (30) comportant un trou (32) avec un troisième diamètre (d<sub>n</sub>) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'immersion de la lampe à décharge de gaz (210) dans l'eau contaminée (240) ou dans les eaux usées (240) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans laquelle le rapport du premier diamètre (d<sub>v</sub>) sur le troisième diamètre (d<sub>n</sub>) est compris entre 3,5 et 4,5 et le rapport du deuxième diamètre (d<sub>c</sub>) sur le troisième diamètre (d<sub>n</sub>) est compris entre 2,0 et 3,0,</claim-text>
<claim-text>de sorte que la charge de courant accrue et la température basse de fonctionnement sont obtenues sans modifier les caractéristiques de décharge de la lampe à décharge de gaz.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16672798" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1,2"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="134" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --><figure id="f0002" num="3,4"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="96" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --><figure id="f0003" num="5,6"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="146" he="221" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
