<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2468013-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2468013" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="41171264" file-reference-id="315038" date-produced="20180825" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146587920" ucid="EP-2468013-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2468013</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-09761819-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154850112" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>09761819</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20090817</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140556047" ucid="EP-2009060632-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>2009060632</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20090817</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130821</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989324252" load-source="docdb">H04R  25/00        20060101AFI20130628BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989324253" load-source="docdb">F16B  31/02        20060101ALN20130628BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989324254" load-source="docdb">F16B  35/06        20060101ALI20130628BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989624360" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F16B  31/02        20130101 LA20130321BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989632081" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F16B  35/06        20130101 LI20130321BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2097024444" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04R  25/65        20130101 FI20140716BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2097025109" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04R2225/63        20130101 LA20140716BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2097025563" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04R2225/021       20130101 LA20140715BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2097029165" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04R  25/60        20130101 LI20140716BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132368393" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Befestigung eines Hakens zu einem Hörgerät</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132368394" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Attachment of a hook to a hearing device</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132368395" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Fixation d'un crochet à un dispositif auditif</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919537581" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>PHONAK AG</last-name><address><country>CH</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919527805" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>PHONAK AG</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919516625" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>GABATHULER BRUNO</last-name><address><country>CH</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919539186" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>GABATHULER, BRUNO</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919020654" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>GABATHULER, BRUNO</last-name><address><street>Huebbrunnenstrasse 2</street><city>CH-8627 Grüningen</city><country>CH</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919532307" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>PORTMANN PAUL</last-name><address><country>CH</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919530669" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>PORTMANN, PAUL</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919020655" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>PORTMANN, PAUL</last-name><address><street>Wollerauerstrasse 49</street><city>CH-8834 Schindellegi</city><country>CH</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919513898" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>DITTLI ERICH</last-name><address><country>CH</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919522634" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>DITTLI, ERICH</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919020656" load-source="patent-office" sequence="3" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>DITTLI, ERICH</last-name><address><street>Bahnhofstrasse 15e</street><city>CH-8864 Reichenburg</city><country>CH</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919020657" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Phonak AG</last-name><iid>100752602</iid><address><street>Laubisrütistrasse 28</street><city>8712 Stäfa</city><country>CH</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919020658" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Troesch Scheidegger Werner AG</last-name><iid>100060727</iid><address><street>Schwäntenmos 14</street><city>8126 Zumikon</city><country>CH</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="EP-2009060632-W"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2009060632</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20090817</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2009150258-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2009150258</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20091217</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549921873" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549886765" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549863612" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549865233" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549795452" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549921874" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549886770" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549795461" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549795462" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549867657" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549863613" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549865238" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549886771" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549795463" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549886772" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549921875" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549867662" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549795464" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549865239" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549795481" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549863618" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549779451" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549863619" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549863620" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549779452" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS549779461" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549795482" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549886773" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549795483" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549863621" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549921876" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549795484" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549865240" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549886778" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549886779" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS549779462" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63960353" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention refers to a hearing device with a connecting portion for the connection of a hook or an acoustic tube according the introduction of claim 1.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002">Usually for an air or acoustic transmission hearing devices comprise connecting portions for the attachment of a so called hook or an acoustic or air tube. E.g. such hooks or tubes are provided for the connection to a further acoustic tube to the otoplastic for the transmission of acoustic signals to the entrance of an ear canal.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">Hooks or connection tubes usually are connected to the hearing device by means of an inside thread or snap connection which is attached on a respective thread or plug nipple at the connection portion of the hearing device.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">The disadvantage of such connections is that the wall surrounding the inside thread is relatively thin and in addition the protruding threads or nipples at the hearing device housing are protruding relatively widely out of the housing. In case, when attaching the hook or tube to the hearing device that to much force is applied there exists the danger that the thread portion at the hearing device is breaking away or the thread connection is over winded so that as a result the connection is not anymore airtight.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> Within the <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="EP0108734A"><text>EP 0 108 734</text></patcit> a bayonet connection between a tube and a hearing device hook is described, which means, no thread at all is used.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">In a similar way within the <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="DE3720591A"><text>DE 3 720 591</text></patcit> a so called all locking system is described for the connection of a hook to a hearing device casing.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">Within the <patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="NL1020904A"><text>NL 1020904</text></patcit> a hearing apparatus is described which fits behind an ear and which has a housing and a screw thread connectable to the housing to create the sound connection between the hearing apparatus and a hook shaped component.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">The object of the present invention is to provide a connecting arrangement which overcomes the above mentioned disadvantages.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">According the invention a hearing device is proposed with a connecting portion for the connection of a hook or an acoustic tube at which the connecting portion comprises an inside thread or internal thread portion intended for the attachment of a hook or acoustic tube.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">Furthermore, the connecting portion comprises a stopper portion which is arranged such that a respective further stopper portion arranged at the respective thread of the hook or acoustic tube by abutting at the stopper portion avoids an over winding. With other words, it is proposed that a stopper portion is arranged at the connecting portion, which is radially effective.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --><!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p><p id="p0010" num="0010">The stopper portion at the connecting portion could be arranged e.g. at the front end of the internal thread portion and the further stopper portion at the back end of the respective thread of the hook or acoustic tube. Of course the arrangement of the stopper portion and the further stopper portion could be vice versa.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">The connecting portion may further comprise a soundproof enabling connecting portion so that a soundproof connection is achievable when connecting the hook or acoustic tube to the hearing device. Vice versa a respective soundproof enabling portion could be arranged at the thread of the hook or acoustic tube. In addition at the connecting portion as well as at the thread respective soundproof enabling portions could be arranged. E.g. the end portion of the connecting portion away from the hearing device casing or the surface at the end portion could be such, that a soundproof connection is achievable or in an analogous way a respective sealing portion can be arranged at the backside end of the respective thread at the hook or acoustic tube to achieve a soundproof connection.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">The end portion or surface at the end portion of the connecting portion of the hearing device as well as the sealing portion can be made out of an elastic material such as an elastomeric polymer.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">A great advantage of the inventive connection is, that in case of applying draw forces the hook is destroyed at breaking away and not the hearing device.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></p><p id="p0014" num="0014">The invention shall be described in more details with reference to the attached figures. In the figures
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> shows a hook thread with an radially stopper portion,</li><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 2</figref> shows a thin tube thread with a radial stopper portion,</li><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 3</figref> shows the respective inside thread at the connecting portion of the hearing device again with a radially effective stopper portion,</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 4</figref> shows the attached hook to the hearing device casing, and</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 5</figref> shows a length cut through the connection between a connecting portion and the tread of a hook.</li></ul></p><p id="p0015" num="0015"><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> shows in a perspective view the end portion 3 of a hook 1,10 comprising an end thread 5 provided to be thread into a respective inside thread at the connecting portion of a hearing device casing. This hook is attachable to a hearing device, e.g. as an intersection for an acoustic tube for the connection of the hearing device with a<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> respective so called otoplastic at the entrance of an ear canal. At the base of the thread 5 a radially effective stopper 7 is arranged, the function of which shall be explained in more details later with respect to <figref idrefs="f0002">figure 5</figref>. Finally, at the backside portion of the thread 5, a sealing surface 9 is arranged to achieve a soundproof connection to the hearing device casing.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">In equivalence to <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1, Figure 2</figref> shows in a perspective view the end portion 6 of a thin tube 2 comprising an end thread 5 provided to be thread into a respective inside thread connecting portion of a hearing device casing. Due to the flexibility of the thin tube 2 it might be advisable to arrange a holding portion 4 between the thin tube 2 and the end portion 6 comprising the end thread 5.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017"><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 3</figref> shows in a perspective view the respective connecting portion 15 at a hearing device casing. For the connection to the thread as shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">figure 1</figref> an inside thread or internal thread 21 is arranged, which of course corresponds with the geometry of the respective thread at the hook or thin tube. Furthermore, again a radially effective stopper portion 22 is arranged, the function of which shall be explained later on with respect to <figref idrefs="f0002">figure 5</figref>. Finally, again to achieve a soundproof connection to the hook or thin tube a sealing surface 23 is arranged at the end portion of the connecting portion.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">The sealing surface at the thread of the hook or thin tube<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> as well as the sealing surface 23 at the connecting portion 15 can be made out of an elastic material such as an elastomeric polymer.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019"><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 4</figref> shows in perspective view the hook 1 or thin tube 2 being attached with its end portion 10 to the connecting portion 15 of a hearing device casing. A great advantage of the connection as shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">figure 4</figref> is that no protruding parts at the hearing device as well as no nipple or thread at the hook or thin tube is visible. For the connection of an acoustic tube for the interconnection to an otoplastic the hook 1 or thin tube 2 comprises at its other end a respective further connecting portion 12.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">The function of the two radially effective stopper portions, mentioned in <figref idrefs="f0001">figures 1 to 3</figref>, shall be explained with respect to <figref idrefs="f0002">figure 5</figref>. In <figref idrefs="f0002">figure 5</figref> a cut is shown lengthwise through the connection of a hook or thin tube to the hearing device casing. As it can be seen very clearly the two portions 7 and 22 will come into engagement, when the thread 5 is completely screwed into the respective inside thread 21 of the connecting portion 15 of the hearing device casing. When stopper end 7 abuts at stopper portion 22 no further screw movement is possible, so that an over winding is impossible.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">The arrangement as shown with respect to <figref idrefs="f0001 f0002">figure 1 to figure 5</figref> only shows examples for the better understanding of the present invention. It is of course possible to modify or to<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> vary parts of this arrangement as well as it is possible to add further features. Important is that first of all, at the connecting end portion of the hearing device casing a so called inside or internal thread is arranged for the introduction of a respective thread, arranged at the end portion of a hook or thin tube. In addition, means are arranged to avoid the over winding at the screw movement, which means are provided as radially effective stopper portions.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56983796" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Hörgerät mit einem Anschlussstück (15) für den Anschluss eines Hakens oder Akustikschlauches (1,2), wobei das Anschlussstück ein inneres Gewinde (21) oder einen internen Gewindeabschnitt aufweist, vorgesehen für den Anschluss eines Hakens oder Akustikschlauches, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> am Anschlussstück ein radial wirkungsvoller Anschlag (22) angeordnet ist, derart, dass ein entsprechender weiterer radial wirkender Anschlag (7), angeordnet am Gewinde (5) des Hakens oder Akustikschlauches durch Anstossen am Anschlag ein Überdrehen verhindert.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Hörgerät nach Anspruch 1, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> der Anschlag (22) am Anschlussstück (15) am Front-öffnungsende angeordnet ist, derart, dass der entsprechende weitere Anschlag (7) angeordnet am rückseitigen Ende des Gewindes (5) des Hakens oder Akustikschlauches durch Anstossen am Anschlag ein Überdrehen verhindert.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Hörgerät nach einem der Ansprüche 1 oder 2, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> der Endabschnitt oder die Oberfläche des Anschlussstückes derart ist, dass eine schalldichte isolierte Verbindung erhalten wird, wenn der Haken oder Akustikschlauch am Hörgerät angeschlossen ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Hörgerät nach Anspruch 3, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> der Endabschnitt oder die Endoberfläche beschichtet<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> oder überdeckt oder bestehend ist mit bzw. aus einem elastischen Material wie einem Elastomehrpolymer.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Anordnung für das Anschliessen eines Hörgerätes an eine Otoplastik am Eingang des Ohrkanales enthaltend ein Hörgerät gemäss einem der Ansprüche 1 - 4 und einen Haken oder einen Schlauch aufweisend einen Endabschnitt für das Anschliessen an das Hörgerät enthaltend einen Gewindeabschnitt und einen radial wirkenden Anschlag, um ein Überdrehen beim Anschliessen dessen Gewindes an den entsprechenden internen Gewindeabschnitt am Hörgerät zu verhindern.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Anordnung nach Anspruch 5, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> am Endabschnitt des Hakens oder dünnen Schlauches ein Dichtabschnitt angeordnet ist, um einen schalldichten Anschluss zwischen dem Haken oder dünnen Schlauch und dem Anschlussstück des Hörgerätes zu erzielen.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56983797" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Hearing device with a connecting portion (15) for the connection of a hook or acoustic tube (1,2), the connecting portion comprises an inside thread (21) or internal thread portion intended for the attachment of a hook or acoustic tube, <b>characterized in that</b> at the connecting portion a radially effective stopper portion (22) is arranged such that a respective further radially effective stopper portion (7), arranged at the thread (5) of the hook or acoustic tube, by abutting at the stopper portion avoids an over winding.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Hearing device according claim 1, <b>characterized in that</b> the stopper portion (22) at the connecting portion (15) is arranged at the front opening end, such that the respective further stopper portion (7) arranged at the back end of the thread (5) of the hook or acoustic tube, by abutting at the stopper portion avoids an over winding.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Hearing device according of the claims 1 to 2 <b>characterized in that</b> the end portion or surface at the connecting portion is such, that a soundproof connection is achievable when connecting the hook<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> or acoustic tube to the hearing device.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Hearing device according to claim 3 <b>characterized in that</b> the end portion or end surface is coated or covered with or made out of an elastic material such as an elastomeric polymer.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Arrangement for connecting a hearing device with an otoplastic at the entrance of an ear canal comprising a hearing device according to one of the claims 1 to 4 and a hook or thin tube, comprising an end portion for being connected to the hearing device comprising a thread portion and a radially effective stopper portion to avoid an over winding when connected by its thread to the respective internal thread portion at the hearing device.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Arrangement according to claim 5, <b>characterized in that</b> at the end portion of the hook or thin tube a sealing portion is arranged to achieve a sound proof connection between the hook or thin tube and the connecting portion of the hearing device.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56983798" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Dispositif auditif doté d'une portion de raccordement (15) pour lé raccordement d'un crochet ou tube acoustique (1, 2), la portion de raccordement comprenant un filetage interne (21) ou une portion de filetage interne destinée à fixer un crochet ou un tube acoustique, <b>caractérisé en ce qu'</b>au niveau de la portion de raccordement, une portion de butée radialement efficace (22) est agencée de sorte qu'une portion de butée radialement efficace supplémentaire respective (7), agencée au niveau du filetage (5) du crochet ou du tube acoustique, en butant au niveau de la portion de butée évite un enroulement excessif.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Dispositif auditif selon la revendication 1, <b>caractérisée en ce que</b> la portion de butée (22) au niveau de la portion de raccordement (15) est agencée au niveau de l'extrémité d'ouverture avant, de sorte que la portion de butée supplémentaire respective (7) agencée au niveau de l'extrémité arrière du filetage (5) du crochet ou du tube acoustique, en butant au niveau de la portion de butée évite un enroulement excessif.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Dispositif auditif selon l'une des revendications 1 à 2, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> la portion ou surface d'extrémité au niveau de la portion de raccordement est telle qu'un raccordement insonore peut être réalisé lors du raccordement du crochet ou du tube acoustique au dispositif auditif.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Dispositif auditif selon la revendication 3, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> la portion d'extrémité ou la surface d'extrémité est revêtue ou couverte ou<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> constituée d'un matériau élastique tel qu'un polymère élastomérique.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Agencement permettant de raccorder un dispositif auditif à un otoplastique au niveau de l'entrée d'un conduit auditif comprenant un dispositif auditif selon l'une des revendications 1 à 4 et un crochet ou un tube fin, comprenant une portion d'extrémité permettant d'être raccordée au dispositif auditif comprenant une portion de filetage et une portion de butée radialement efficace afin d'éviter un enroulement excessif lors du raccordement par son filetage à la portion de filetage interne respective au niveau du dispositif auditif.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Agencement selon la revendication 5, <b>caractérisé en ce qu'</b>au niveau de la portion d'extrémité du crochet ou du tube fin, une portion d'étanchéité est agencée afin de réaliser un raccordement insonore entre le crochet ou le tube fin et la portion de raccordement du dispositif auditif.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16671658" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1,2,3"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="149" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --><figure id="f0002" num="4,5"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="132" he="191" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
