<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2355866-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2355866" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="41393644" file-reference-id="315040" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146588561" ucid="EP-2355866-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2355866</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-09744094-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154850753" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>09744094</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20090930</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140554536" ucid="EP-2009062650-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>2009062650</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20090930</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140550101" ucid="SE-0850026-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>SE</country><doc-number>0850026</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20081001</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130729</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989325984" load-source="ipcr">A61M   5/20        20060101ALI20130612BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989325985" load-source="ipcr">A61M   5/24        20060101ALI20130612BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989325986" load-source="ipcr">A61M   5/315       20060101AFI20130612BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989325987" load-source="ipcr">F16F   1/08        20060101ALI20130612BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989633996" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61M2005/31518     20130101 LA20130612BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989637878" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61M2005/2407      20130101 LA20130906BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989638599" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61M   5/24        20130101 LA20130906BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989641368" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61M   5/2033      20130101 FI20130906BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989646737" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61M2005/2073      20130101 LA20130906BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989650127" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61M   5/31515     20130101 LI20130612BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370316" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">AUTOMATISCHER INJEKTOR MIT EVOLUTFEDER</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370317" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">MEDICAMENT DELIVERY DEVICE POWERED BY VOLUTE SPRING</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370318" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">DISPOSITIF D'INJECTION AVEC RESSORT EN VOLUTE</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919539289" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>SHL GROUP AB</last-name><address><country>SE</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919518176" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>SHL GROUP AB</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919520031" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>HOLMQVIST ANDERS</last-name><address><country>SE</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919508006" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>HOLMQVIST, ANDERS</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919023689" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>HOLMQVIST, ANDERS</last-name><address><street>Björnstigen 4</street><city>S-139 40 Värmdö</city><country>SE</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919023690" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>SHL Group AB</last-name><iid>101076321</iid><address><street>Box 1240 Augustendalsvägen 19</street><city>131 28 Nacka Strand</city><country>SE</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="EP-2009062650-W"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2009062650</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20090930</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2010037759-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2010037759</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20100408</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549877310" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549787447" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549803855" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549924568" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549871537" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549877311" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549787448" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549871542" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549871543" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549881404" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549803860" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549803861" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549787457" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549871544" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549787458" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549877312" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549924569" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549787459" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549803862" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549871545" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549786745" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549877313" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549786746" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549786747" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549894239" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS549894240" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549881405" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549803863" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549894245" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549924570" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549881422" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549881423" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549924571" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549894246" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549894247" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS549871558" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63960981" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001">TECHNICAL AREA</heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to a medicament delivery device capable of delivering doses of medicament in liquid form, and in particular injection medicament delivery devices.</p><heading id="h0002">TECHNICAL BACKGROUND</heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">Medicament delivery devices developed for self-administration have become very popular because it allows for the users to provide medicament without the need for visiting a hospital, a clinic or the like in order to receive an injection of medicament.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">The devices for self-administration that have been developed contain different degrees of functionality depending e.g. on the application, type of drug and intended user. The different functions may include automatic penetration, injection, mixing, priming, withdrawal from injection site, needle shields, to mention a few.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">The majority of injection devices on the market are arranged with elongated, generally tubular medicament containers having one end where an injection needle can be attached, and provided with a movable wall at the other end, such as a rubber stopper. It is further very common to have some sort of elongated driver acting on said stopper, such as a plunger rod. The driver is also often connected to a power source such as compression springs, leaf springs, and the like for urging the plunger rod against the stopper for expelling medicament through the injection needle.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">The use of plunger rods is very well developed and they be moved forward by the power source either linearly or rotatingly. A general desire from many users is to have as small devices as possible in order that they shall not attract too much attention, especially when the devices sometimes are to be used in the public. A problem with the above mentioned use of plunger rods is that the device has to be at least somewhat longer than the length of the medicament container plus the length of the plunger rod. The length problem becomes even more pronounced when functionality is added to the injector, such as dose setting buttons, needle shields extending from the injector, to mention some. The problem is also more<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> pronounced the longer the plunger has to move inside the medicament container, either that the doses are large or that the injector is designed to deliver a number of doses before the container is emptied.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">A few attempts have been made to solve this problem. One such solution is shown in document <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US6641566B"><text>US 6,641,566</text></patcit> where the power source is placed parallel to the medicament container. Here the plunger rod is designed flexibly bendable around a wheel in order that the power source can act on the container via the plunger rod. However, even if the device becomes shorter, by necessity it becomes thicker and also obtains a shape that is more difficult to hold for a user. This means that the device is not as discrete as desired. Further, many patients have by now gotten used to injectors having a general pen-shape and are thus reluctant to adapt to other shapes.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">Another solution is shown in <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="EP1647292A1"><text>EP 1 647 292 A1</text></patcit> wherein the activation mechanism requires a rather complex design.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008"><patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="WO2005018720A"><text>WO 2005/018720</text></patcit> shows a needleless injector using several volute springs as a power unit, and <patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="WO9834659A"><text>WO 9834659</text></patcit> as well as <patcit id="pcit0005" dnum="US6626868B"><text>US 6626868</text></patcit> show buffer, volute and conical springs for needle retraction and corresponding locking mechanisms.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">There is thus room for improvement regarding the size and design of injector.</p><heading id="h0003">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading><p id="p0010" num="0010">The aim of the present invention is to provide a medicament injector having dimensions that renders it as slim and compact as possible, and yet simple and robust to use.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">This aim is obtained by an injector with the features according to the independent patent claim. Preferable embodiments form the subject of the dependent patent claims.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p><p id="p0012" num="0012">According to a preferred embodiment, the activation means is fixedly connected to the cover and rotationally operable in relation to the housing between a non-activation position wherein the activation button is in contact with a circumferential ledge of the housing for avoiding the activation button to be depressed, and an activation position wherein the activation button is in front of a cut-out on the circumferential ledge the housing for allowing the activation button to be depressed.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">According to a preferred embodiment, the activation means comprises an activation button operationally connected to said deformable ring-shaped member, such that when the cover is rotated from the non-activation position to the activation position, the deformable ring-shaped member is changed from the oval shape to a round shape, allowing the annular ledge to pass through the ring-shaped member and thereby releasing the volute spring from the tensioned state.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">There are a number of advantages with the present invention. The use of a volute spring provides several features that conventional medical delivery devices do not provide. A major feature is that a plunger rod can be completely disposed of, which in conventional devices adds to the length. The use of a volute spring thus enables the device to be made much shorter; it is only the width of the band forming the volute spring that adds to the length. Because of its design the volute spring stays stable, i.e. does not buckle or twist, when it is extended, which is the case for conventional spiral springs. Thus the volute spring both acts as a force means and a "plunger rod" when extended. The width of the band forming the<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> volute spring and the number of turns as well as choice of material may be modified in many ways in order to obtain the appropriate force, stability and stroke depending on application. In that respect, some sort of lubrication or friction reducing means may be applied on the band forming the spring in order to minimize friction when the spring extends.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">With the present invention, a very simple but yet robust design with very few components is obtained for the spring locking means. The round shape of the volute spring can be used to hold the spring in the tensioned, non-extended state by using a ring-shaped member that in an unaffected state is somewhat oval. This ovality prevents the spring from extending. When the ring-shaped member is acted upon by manually operation, becoming circular, it enables the volute spring to expand through the member. Further, the present invention preferably includes a safety lock of the spring locking means, which reduces the risk of unintentional activation of the medicament delivery device.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">These and other aspects of and advantages with the present invention will become apparent from the following detailed description and from the accompanying drawings.</p><heading id="h0004">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading><p id="p0017" num="0017">In the following detailed description of the invention, reference will be made to the accompanying drawings, of which
<dl id="dl0001" compact="compact"><dt>Fig. 1</dt><dd>is a perspective view of a medicament delivery device according to the present invention,</dd><dt>Fig. 2</dt><dd>is an exploded view of the medicament delivery device of <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, and</dd><dt>Figs. 3, 4</dt><dd>are cross-sectional side views of the device of <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>.</dd></dl></p><heading id="h0005">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading><p id="p0018" num="0018">The medicament delivery device shown in the drawings comprises an elongated, generally tubular housing 10. When the device is delivered to the user, the front part of the housing is covered by a detachable protective cover 12, <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>. The front end of the housing 10, to the right in the figures, is provided with a threaded neck 14 onto which a medicament dispensing means in the form of an injection needle<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> can attached. Inside the housing, a medicament container 16 is placed. The front end of the container is placed in the neck 14 of the housing. In the rear part of the medicament container a stopper 18 is arranged, <figref idrefs="f0003">Figs. 3</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0004">4</figref>. The container 16 is visible through openings or windows 20 in the housing.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">The rear part of the medicament delivery device is arranged with a power unit 22. It comprises a cover 24, a volute spring 26 arranged within said cover and that is wound with a number turns, and a pressure member 28 having a pressure pad 30 in contact with the stopper 18, a guide rod 34 extending into the volute spring and an annular ledge 32 in contact with the edges of the volute spring. The volute spring has a certain width as will be described below.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">The device further comprises an activation means 36 mechanically connected to the cover (24) and to the housing (10). In the embodiment of the figures the activation means 36 is fixedly connected to the cover 24 and rotationally operable in relation to the housing 10 between a non-activation position wherein the activation button 38 is in contact with a circumferential ledge of the housing for avoiding the activation button to be depressed, and an activation position wherein the activation button is in front of a cut-out on the circumferential ledge of the housing for allowing the activation button to be depressed. The activation means comprises an activation button 38 which can be operated by a user. The activation button is in turn operationally connected to a spring locking means 39 which comprises a deformable ring-shaped member 40 having an inner diameter somewhat larger than the annular ledge 32 of the pressure member, such that said ring-shaped member 40 presents an oval shape when it is in contact with the annular ledge 12 for locking the volute spring in a tensioned state.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">The activation button 38 is operationally connected to said deformable ring-shaped member 40, such that when the cover 24 is rotated from the non-activation position to the activation position, the deformable ring-shaped member 40 is changed from the oval shape to a round shape, allowing the annular ledge 32 to pass through the ring-shaped member and thereby releasing the volute spring from the tensioned state.<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></p><p id="p0022" num="0022">The medicament delivery device according to the present invention is intended to function as follows. When the patient is to administer a dose of medicament, a medicament container 16 is placed in the housing and the cover part 24 is attached to the housing. As an alternative, the device may be delivered to the user with a medicament container already in place in the housing.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">Now a medicament dispensing means is attached to the neck 14 of the housing 10 by appropriate fastening means such as threads or bayonet fittings. In order to make the device ready for medicament delivery the cover and thereby the activation means are turned from the non-activation position to the activation position. The device is after this positioned at the medicament delivery site, such as penetration of an injection needle at the injection place. The activation button 38 is now pressed by the user whereby the deformable ring-shaped member 40 is changed from the oval shape to the round shape. The change of shape causes the deformable ring-shaped member 40 to move out of contact with the circumferential ledge 32 of the pressure member 28, which enables the pressure member 28 and the volute spring 26 to move through the deformable ring-shaped member 40 and to extend in the longitudinal direction of the device, where the pressure pad 30 acts on the stopper of the medicament container 16. The force of the volute spring 26 now pushes the stopper 18 towards the front end of the medicament container 16 whereby the dose of medicament in the container is expelled through the medicament delivery means and into the delivery site. Due to the width of the band forming the volute spring 26, it becomes stable enough to exert a force on the stopper 18 through the whole injection phase without the risk of buckling or twisting, <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4</figref>.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">When the delivery operation is completed, the user removes the medicament delivery device. The user preferably covers the needle with the needle sheath. The needle can then be removed and discarded. The injector may be used again by replacing the empty container with a new and by replacing the used power unit 22 with a new for a subsequent use or the injector may be designed as a single use injector and discarded after completed injection.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56985683" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Medizinische Injektionsvorrichtung, umfassend:
<claim-text>- ein Gehäuse (10);</claim-text>
<claim-text>- einen Medikamentenbehälter (16), der so angeordnet ist, dass er in dem Gehäuse platziert ist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- einen Stopfen (18), der in dem Behälter (16) bewegbar ist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- ein Medikamentenabgabemittel, das an dem Gehäuse und an dem Behälter anbringbar ist, durch das ein Medikament ausgestoßen werden kann, wobei es sich bei dem Medikamentenabgabemittel um eine Injektionsnadel handelt;</claim-text>
<b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die Vorrichtung ferner Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>- eine Antriebseinheit (22), die eine Abdeckung (24), eine einzelne Evolutfeder (26), die in der Abdeckung angeordnet ist und im gestreckten Zustand sowohl als Kraftmittel als auch als Druckstange dient, und ein Druckelement (28) umfasst, das eine Druckfläche (30) im Kontakt mit dem Stopfen (18), eine Führungsstange (34), die in die Evolutfeder hinein verläuft, und einen ringförmigen Absatz (32) aufweist, der die Ränder der Evolutfeder berührt;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- ein Betätigungsmittel (36), das mechanisch mit der Abdeckung (24) und dem Gehäuse (10) verbunden ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>- ein Federarretiermittel (39), das mechanisch mit dem Betätigungsmittel verbunden ist, wobei das Federarretiermittel ein verformbares ringförmiges Element (40) umfasst, das einen Innendurchmesser aufweist, der etwas größer als der ringförmige Absatz (32) ist, sodass das ringförmige Element (40) eine ovale Form aufweist, wenn es den ringförmigen Absatz (32) berührt, um die Evolutfeder in einem gespannten Zustand zu arretieren, und wenn auf das ringförmige Element (40) durch eine manuelle Betätigung eingewirkt wird, wodurch es kreisförmig wird, ermöglicht es, dass sich die Evolutfeder (26) durch das Element hindurch entspannt.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Medizinische Injektionsvorrichtung nach Anspruch 1, wobei das Betätigungsmittel (36) fest mit der Abdeckung (24) verbunden ist und bezogen auf das Gehäuse (10) drehend bedienbar ist zwischen einer Nichtbetätigungsstellung, in der ein Betätigungsknopf (38) eine umlaufende Kante des Gehäuses berührt, um zu verhindern, dass der Betätigungsknopf heruntergedrückt wird, und einer Betätigungsstellung, in der sich der Betätigungsknopf vor einem Ausschnitt an der umlaufenden Kante des Gehäuses befindet, um zu ermöglichen, dass der Betätigungsknopf heruntergedrückt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Medizinische Injektionsvorrichtung nach Anspruch 2, wobei das Betätigungsmittel (36) einen Betätigungsknopf (38) umfasst, der mit dem verformbaren ringförmigen Element (40) wirkverbunden ist, sodass, wenn die Abdeckung (24) aus der Nichtbetätigungsstellung in die Betätigungsstellung gedreht wird, das verformbare ringförmige Element (40) aus der ovalen Form in eine runde Form umgewandelt wird, wodurch ermöglicht wird, dass sich der ringförmige Absatz (32) durch das ringförmige Element bewegt und dadurch die Evolutfeder aus dem gespannten Zustand entspannt wird.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56985684" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Medical injection device comprising:
<claim-text>- a housing (10);</claim-text>
<claim-text>- a medicament container (16) arranged to be placed in said housing;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- a stopper (18) movable within said container (16):</claim-text>
<claim-text>- a medicament dispensing means attachable to said housing and to said container through which medicament can be expelled, wherein said medicament dispensing means is an injection needle;</claim-text>
<b>characterized in that</b> the device further comprises
<claim-text>- a power unit (22) comprising a cover (24), a single volute spring (26) arranged within said cover and acting both as a force means and as a plunger rod when extended, and a pressure member (28) having a pressure pad (30) in contact with the stopper (18), a guide rod (34) extending into the volute spring and an annular ledge (32) in contact with the edges of the volute spring;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- activation means (36) mechanically connected to the cover (24) and to the housing (10); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>- a spring locking means (39) mechanically connected to said activation means, wherein said spring locking means comprises a deformable ringshaped member (40) having an inner diameter somewhat larger than the annular ledge (32), such that said ring-shaped member (40) presents an oval shape when it is in contact with the annular ledge (32) for locking the volute spring in a tensioned state, and when said ringshaped member (40) is acted upon by manually operation, becoming circular, it enables the volute spring (26) to expand through the member.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Medical injection device according to claim 1, wherein the activation means (36) is fixedly connected to the cover (24) and rotationally operable in relation to the housing (10) between a non-activation position wherein an activation button (38) is in contact with a circumferential ledge of the housing for avoiding the activation button to be depressed, and an activation position wherein the activation button is in front of a cut-out on the circumferential ledge the housing for allowing the activation button to be depressed.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Medical injection device according to claim 2, wherein the activation means (36) comprises an activation button (38) operationally connected to said deformable ring-shaped member (40), such that when the cover (24) is rotated from the non-activation position to the activation position, the deformable ringshaped member (40) is changed from the oval shape to a round shape, allowing the annular ledge (32) to pass through the ring-shaped member and thereby releasing the volute spring from the tensioned state.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56985685" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Dispositif médical d'injection comprenant :
<claim-text>- un boîtier (10) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- un réservoir à médicament (16) agencé pour être placé dans ledit boîtier ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- un bouchon (18) mobile dans ledit récipient (16) :</claim-text>
<claim-text>- un moyen de distribution de médicament pouvant être fixé audit boîtier et audit réservoir à travers lequel le médicament peut être expulsé, dans lequel ledit moyen de distribution de médicament est une aiguille d'injection ;</claim-text>
<b>caractérisé en ce que</b> le dispositif comprend en outre
<claim-text>- une unité de puissance (22) comprenant un couvercle (24), un unique ressort en volute (26) agencé dans ledit couvercle et agissant comme un moyen de force ainsi que comme une tige de piston quand il est étendu, et un élément de pression (28) présentant un tampon de pression (30) en contact avec le bouchon (18), une tige de guidage (34) s'étendant dans le ressort en volute et un rebord annulaire (32) en contact avec les bords du ressort en volute ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>- des moyens d'activation (36) reliés mécaniquement au couvercle (24) et au boîtier (10) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>- un moyen de blocage de ressort (39) relié mécaniquement auxdits moyens d'activation, dans lequel ledit moyen de blocage de ressort comprend un élément de forme annulaire déformable (40) présentant un diamètre intérieur légèrement plus grand que le rebord annulaire (32), de sorte que ledit élément de forme annulaire (40) présente une forme ovale quand il est en contact avec le rebord annulaire (32) pour bloquer le ressort en volute dans un état bandé, et quand ledit élément de forme annulaire (40) est soumis à une action par actionnement manuel, devenant circulaire, il permet au ressort en volute (26) de s'étendre à travers l'élément.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Dispositif médical d'injection selon la revendication 1, dans lequel le moyen d'activation (36) est relié fixement au couvercle (24) et peut être actionné<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> en rotation par rapport au boîtier (10) entre une position de non activation dans laquelle un bouton d'activation (38) est en contact avec un rebord circonférentiel du boîtier pour empêcher le bouton d'activation d'être enfoncé, et une position d'activation dans laquelle le bouton d'activation est devant une découpe sur le rebord circonférentiel du boîtier pour permettre au bouton d'activation d'être enfoncé.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Dispositif médical d'injection selon la revendication 2, dans lequel le moyen d'activation (36) comprend un bouton d'activation (38) relié de manière fonctionnelle audit élément de forme annulaire déformable (40), de sorte que quand le couvercle (24) est tourné de la position de non activation à la position d'activation, l'élément de forme annulaire déformable (40) passe d'une forme ovale à une forme ronde, permettant au rebord annulaire (32) de passer à travers l'élément de forme annulaire et libérant ainsi le ressort en volute de l'état bandé.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16672231" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="165" he="195" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="157" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="102" he="232" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --><figure id="f0004" num="4"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="102" he="232" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
