<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-1343879-B1" country="EP" doc-number="1343879" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="21741971" file-reference-id="299923" date-produced="20180823" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146589224" ucid="EP-1343879-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>1343879</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-00977013-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154851416" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>00977013</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20001107</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140549721" ucid="US-0030587-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>0030587</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20001107</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130624</date></intention-to-grant-date><search-report-dispatch-date><date>20060131</date></search-report-dispatch-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989327992" load-source="ipcr">C07K  14/47        20060101ALI20050818BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989327993" load-source="ipcr">C12N   9/00        20060101AFI20050818BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989627348" load-source="ipcr">C12N  15/09        20060101AFI20051220RMJP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989649620" load-source="ipcr">C12N   5/10        20060101ALI20051220RMJP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989637539" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">C07K  14/47        20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989645770" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">C12N   9/00        20130101 FI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132372305" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">VERFAHREN ZUR ISOLIERUNG NEUER ANTIMIKROBIELLER AGENTIEN AUS HYPERMUTIERBAREN SÄUGERZELLEN</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132372306" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">METHODS FOR ISOLATING NOVEL ANTIMICROBIAL AGENTS FROM HYPERMUTABLE MAMMALIAN CELLS</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132372307" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">PROCEDES POUR ISOLER DE NOUVEAUX AGENTS ANTIMICROBIENS A PARTIR DE CELLULES MAMMIFERES HYPERMUTABLES</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919542443" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>MORPHOTEK INC</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919528108" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>MORPHOTEK, INC.</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919511838" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>GRASSO LUIGI</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919529441" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>GRASSO, LUIGI</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919026933" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>GRASSO, LUIGI</last-name><address><street>403 Barbara Lane</street><city>Bryn Mawr, PA 19010</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919541157" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>NICOLAIDES NICHOLAS C</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919524163" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>NICOLAIDES, NICHOLAS, C.</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919026934" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>NICOLAIDES, NICHOLAS, C.</last-name><address><street>66 Mount Aire Farm Road</street><city>Glenn Mills, PA 19342</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919516701" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>SASS PHILIP M</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919530202" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>SASS, PHILIP, M.</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919026935" load-source="patent-office" sequence="3" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>SASS, PHILIP, M.</last-name><address><street>1903 Blackhawk Circle</street><city>Audubon, PA 19403</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919026937" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Morphotek, Inc.</last-name><iid>100181576</iid><address><street>210 Welsh Pool Road</street><city>Exton, PA 19341</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919026936" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>W.P. Thompson &amp; Co.</last-name><iid>100060697</iid><address><street>55 Drury Lane</street><city>London WC2B 5SQ</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="US-0030587-W"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>0030587</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20001107</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2002038750-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2002038750</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20020516</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549926647" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549900085" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549885112" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549807411" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549900086" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549807412" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549791720" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549891244" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549876107" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549900087" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549807413" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549885113" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549876108" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549807414" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549794261" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549891253" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549926648" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549891254" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549807415" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549794262" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63961634" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001"><b>FIELD OF THE INVENTION</b></heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention is related to the area of antimicrobial agents and cellular production of those agents. In particular, it is related to the field of identification of novel antimicrobial agents by placing mammalian cells under selection in the presence of the microbe.</p><heading id="h0002"><b>BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</b></heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">For as long as man has shared the planet with microorganisms there have been widespread outbreaks of infectious disease and subsequent widespread mortality associated with it. Although microorganisms and man frequently share a symbiotic relationship, microorganisms can, under some conditions, lead to sickness and death. The discovery, wide use and dissemination of antibiotics to treat microbial infection in both human and animal populations over the last one hundred or so years has done much to control, and in some instances, eradicate some microbes and associated infectious disease. However, microbes have a strong propensity to evolve and alter their genetic makeup when confronted with toxic substances that place them under life and death selective pressures. Therefore, emerging infectious diseases currently pose an important public health problem in both developed as well as developing countries. Not only have microbes evolved to evade and defeat current antibiotic therapeutics, but also there are novel and previously unrecognized and/or characterized bacterial, fungal, viral, and parasitic diseases that have emerged within the past two decades. <nplcit id="ncit0001" npl-type="s"><text>Sass, Curr. Opin. in Drug Discov. &amp; Develop. 2000, 3(5):646-654</text></nplcit>.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">Since the accidental discovery of a penicillin-producing mold by Fleming there has been steady progress in synthesizing, isolating and characterizing new and more effective beta-lactam antibiotics. In addition to the great success of the beta-lactam family of antibiotics, the newer fluoroquinolones have a broad-spectrum of bactericidal activity as well as excellent oral bio-availability, tissue penetration and favorable safety and tolerability profiles. <nplcit id="ncit0002" npl-type="s"><text>King et al., Am. Fam. Physician, 2000, 61, 2741-2748</text></nplcit>. A newly devised four-generation classification of the quinolone drugs accounts for the expanded antimicrobial spectrum of the more recently introduced fluoroquinolones and their clinical<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> indications. The so-called first generation drugs, which include nalidixic acid, are capable of achieving minimal serum levels. The second-generation quinolones, such as ciprofloxacin, have an increased gram-negative and systemic activity. The third-generation drugs comprise pharmaceuticals such as levofloxacin and are have significant and expanded action against gram-positive bacteria and atypical pathogens. Finally, the fourth-generation quinolone drugs, which, to date, only includes trovofloxacin, are highly active against anaerobes in addition to the activity described for the third-generation drugs. Furthermore, the quinolone class of anti-microbial drugs can be divided based on their pharmacokinetic properties and bioavailability.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">Mammalian epithelial surfaces are remarkable for their ability to provide critical physiologic functions in the face of frequent microbial challenges. The fact that these mucosal surfaces remain infection-free in the normal host suggests that highly effective mechanisms of host defense have evolved to protect these environmentally exposed tissues. Throughout the animal and plant kingdoms, endogenous genetically encoded antimicrobial peptides have been shown to be key elements in the response to epithelial compromise and microbial invasion. <nplcit id="ncit0003" npl-type="s"><text>Zasloff, Curr. Opin. Immunol., 1992, 4, 3-7</text></nplcit>; and <nplcit id="ncit0004" npl-type="s"><text>Bevins, Ciba Found. Symp., 1994, 186, 250-69</text></nplcit>. In mammals, a variety of such peptides have been identified, including the well-characterized defensins and cathelicidins and others (andropin, magainin, tracheal antimicrobial peptide, and PR-39; see <nplcit id="ncit0005" npl-type="s"><text>Bevins, Ciba Found. Symp., 1994, 186, 250-69 </text></nplcit>and references therein). A major source of these host defense molecules is circulating phagocytic leukocytes. However, more recently, it has been shown that resident epithelial cells of the skin and respiratory, alimentary, and genitourinary tracts also synthesize and release antimicrobial peptides. Both <i>in vitro</i> and <i>in vivo</i> data support the hypothesis that these molecules are important contributors to intrinsic mucosal immunity. Alterations in their level of expression or biologic activity can predispose the organism to microbial infection. <nplcit id="ncit0006" npl-type="s"><text>Huttner et al., Pediatr. Res., 1999, 45, 785-94</text></nplcit>.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">Across the evolutionary scale species from insects to mammals to plants defend themselves against invading pathogenic microorganisms by utilizing cationic antimicrobial peptides that rapidly kill microbes without exerting toxicity to the host. Physicochemical peptide-lipid interactions provide attractive mechanisms for innate immunity as discussed below. Many of these peptides form cationic amphipathic secondary structures, typically alpha-helices and beta-sheets, which can selectively interact with anionic bacterial<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> membranes via electrostatic interactions. Rapid, peptide-induced membrane permeabilization and subsequent cellular lysis is the result. <nplcit id="ncit0007" npl-type="s"><text>Matsuzaki, Biochim. Biophys. Acta, 1999, 1462, 1-10</text></nplcit>.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">The primary structures of a large number of these host-defense peptides have been determined. While there is no primary structure homology, the peptides are characterized by a preponderance of cationic and hydrophobic amino acids. The secondary structures of many of the host-defense peptides have been determined by a variety of techniques. <nplcit id="ncit0008" npl-type="s"><text>Sitaram et al., Biochim, Biophys. Acta, 1999, 1462, 29-54</text></nplcit>. The acyclic peptides tend to adopt helical conformation, especially in media of low dielectric constant, whereas peptides with more than one disulfide bridge adopt beta-structures.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">As described above, one reason for the rise in microbial drug resistance to the first line antimicrobial therapies in standard use today is the inappropriate and over-use of prescription antibiotics. Although bacteria are the most common organisms to develop drug-resistance, there are numerous examples of demonstrated resistance in fungi, viruses, and parasites. The development of a resistant phenotype is a complex phenomenon that involves an interaction of the microorganism, the environment, and the patient, separately as well as in combination. <nplcit id="ncit0009" npl-type="s"><text>Sitaram et al., Biochim. Biophys. Acta, 1999, 1462, 29-54</text></nplcit>. The microorganism in question may develop resistance while under antibiotic selection or it may be a characteristic of the microbe prior to exposure to a given agent. There are a number of mechanisms of resistance to antibiotics that have been described, including genes that encode antibiotic resistance enzymes that are harbored on extrachromosomal plasmids as well as DNA elements (e.g. transposable elements) that can reside either extra-chromosomally or within the host genome.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">Due to the ability of microorganisms to acquire the ability to develop resistance to antibiotics there is a need to continually develop novel antibiotics. Traditional methods to develop novel antibiotics have included medicinal chemistry approaches to modify existing antibiotics (<nplcit id="ncit0010" npl-type="s"><text>Kang et al., Bioorg. Med. Chem. Lett., 2000, 10, 95-99</text></nplcit>) as well as isolation of antibiotics from new organisms (<nplcit id="ncit0011" npl-type="s"><text>Alderson et al., Res. Microbiol., 1993, 144, 665-72</text></nplcit>). Each of these methods, however, has limitations. The traditional medicinal chemistry approach entails modification of an existing molecule to impart a more effective activity. The chemist makes a "best guess" as to which parts of the molecule to alter, must then devise a synthetic strategy, synthesize the molecule, and then have it tested. This approach is laborious, requires large numbers of medicinal chemists and frequently results<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> in a molecule that is lower in activity than the original antibiotic. The second approach, isolation of novel antimicrobial agents, requires screening large numbers of diverse organisms for novel antimicrobial activity. Then, the activity must be isolated from the microorganism. This is not a small task, and frequently takes many years of hard work to isolate the active molecule. Even after the molecule is identified, it may not be possible for medicinal chemists to effectively devise a synthetic strategy due to the complexity of the molecule. Furthermore, the synthetic strategy must allow for a cost-effective synthesis.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="CA2240609"><text>CA2240609</text></patcit> discloses dominant negative alleles of human mismatch repair genes, that can be used to generate hypermutable cells and organisms. By introducing these genes into cells and transgenic animals, new cell lines and animal varieties with novel and useful properties were prepared more efficiently than relying on the natural rate of mutation. <nplcit id="ncit0012" npl-type="s"><text>Papadopoulos et al. ("Mutation of mutL homolog in hereditary colon cancer ", Science, American Association for the Advancement of Science, US, 263, 18 March 1994, pages 1625-1629</text></nplcit><i>)</i> discloses that some cases of hereditary colorectal cancer are due to alterations in a mutS-related mismatch repair gene. The authors carried out a search of a large database of expressed sequence tags derived from random complimentary DNA clones, which revealed three additional human mismatch repair genes, all related to the bacterial mutL gene. <nplcit id="ncit0013" npl-type="s"><text>Nicolaides et al. ("Mutations of two PMS homologues in hereditary nonpolyposis colon cancer", Nature, London, GB, 371, 1 September 1994, pages 75-80</text></nplcit><i>)</i> discloses the nucleotide sequence, chromosome localization and mutational analysis of hPMS1 and hPMS2, two additional homologues of the prokaryotic mutL gene, both of which were found to be mutated in the germ line of colorectal cancer patients. <nplcit id="ncit0014" npl-type="s"><text>Winter et al. ("Altered spectra of hypermutation in antibodies from mice deficient for the DNA mismatch repair protein PMS2 ", Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of USA, Washington, DC, US, 95 (12), 9 June 1998, pages 6953-6958</text></nplcit><i>)</i> studied hypermutation in mice deficient for either the DNA nucleotide excision repair gene <i>Xpa</i> or the mismatch repair gene <i>Pms2.</i> High levels of mutation were found in variable genes from XPA-deficient and PMS2-deficient mice, indicating that neither nucleotide excision repair nor mismatch repair pathways generate hypermutation. The authors also confirm that tandem mispairs were repaired by wild-type cells but not by <i>Pms2</i><sup><i>-</i>/<i>-</i></sup> human or murine cells.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></p><p id="p0010" num="0010">Therefore, a method that would allow for creation of more effective antibiotics from existing molecules or allow rapid isolation of novel antimicrobial agents is needed to combat the ever-growing list of antibiotic resistant organisms. The present invention described herein is directed to the use of random genetic mutation of a cell to produce novel antibiotics by blocking the endogenous mismatch repair activity of a host cell. The cell can be a mammalian cell that produces an antimicrobial agent naturally, or a cell that is placed under selective pressure to obtain a novel antimicrobial molecule that attacks a specific microbe. Moreover, the invention describes methods for obtaining enhanced antimicrobial activity of a cell line that produces an antimicrobial activity due to recombinant expression or as part of the innate capacity of the cell to harbor such activity.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">In addition, the generation of genetically altered host cells that are capable of secreting an antimicrobial activity, which can be protein or non-protein based, will be valuable reagents for manufacturing the entity for clinical studies. An embodiment of the invention described herein is directed to the creation of genetically altered host cells with novel and/or increased antimicrobial production that are generated by a method that interferes with the highly ubiquitous and phylogenetically conserved process of mismatch repair.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">The present invention facilitates the generation of novel antimicrobial agents and the production of cell lines that express elevated levels of antimicrobial activity. Advantages of the present invention are further described in the examples and figures described herein.</p><heading id="h0003"><b>SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</b></heading><p id="p0013" num="0013">One aspect of the invention provides a method for obtaining a mammalian cell that is resistant to a selected microbe, comprising: growing a culture of mammalian cells wherein said cells comprise <i>hPMS2-134</i>; exposing said cells to said selected microbe; and selecting said mammalian cell that is resistant to said selected microbe.<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></p><p id="p0014" num="0014">A further aspect provides a method for obtaining a cell that comprises a mutation in a gene encoding microbial resistance, comprising: growing a culture of mammalian cells comprising said gene encoding said microbial resistance and <i>hPMS2-134</i>; selecting a cell having said microbial resistance; and determining whether said gene comprises a mutation.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">The ability of the cell to correct natural defects that occur in the DNA during the process of DNA replication is therefore altered.<br/>
Interference with this process, called mismatch repair, leads to genetically dissimilar sibling cells. These genetically dissimilar cells contain mutations, ranging from one mutation/genome to two or more mutations/genome, offer a rich population of cells from which to select for specific output traits, such as the novel ability to resist microbial insult. The genetically altered cell generated by manipulation of the mismatch repair process is then incubated with a microbe that is normally toxic to cells. Most of the cells will rapidly lose viability and die; however, a subset of resistant cells will have the capacity to resist the microbial insult. These cells express a molecule, protein or non-protein in structure, that imbues an antimicrobial activity to the newly selected mammalian clones. These newly created cells can be expanded <i>in vitro</i> and the new molecule isolated and characterized by standard methods that are well described it the art. The novel molecule(s) are then tested for their ability to kill or inhibit the growth of the microbe by standard microbial assays that are well described in the art. Finally, the novel cell line generated serves as an additional resource for large-scale production of the novel antimicrobial agent for use in clinical studies. The processes described herein are applicable to any mammalian cell and any microbe for which an antibiotic agent is sought.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">In one embodiment of the invention, the step of selecting for microbial resistance comprises isolating and testing culture medium from said cell.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">In another embodiment of the invention, the cell is selected for resistance to a bacterium. Alternatively, the cell is selected for resistance to a fungus.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">A further embodiment of the present invention provides a method as disclosed above, wherein said step of selecting a cell having said microbial resistance comprises isolating and testing culture medium from said cell.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">In another embodiment of the invention, the step of determining whether the gene comprises a mutation comprises analysing a nucleotide sequence of said gene. Alternatively, mRNA transcribed from said gene can be analysed. In a related embodiment, a protein encoded by said gene can be analysed. Alternatively, a phenotypic trait determined by said gene can be analysed.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p><heading id="h0004"><b>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</b></heading><p id="p0020" num="0020"><ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001"><b>Figure 1</b></figref> is a representative <i>in situ</i> β-galactosidase staining of TK-hPMS2-134 or TKvect cells to measure for cells containing genetically altered β-galactosidase genes; arrows indicate Blue (β-galactosidase positive) cells.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002"><b>Figure 2</b></figref> is a schematic representation of sequence of alterations of the β-galactosidase gene produced by expression of TK-hPMS2-134 host cells in TK cells.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003"><b>Figures 3A, 3B</b> and <b>3C</b></figref> show a representative immunoprecipitation of <i>in vitro</i> translated hPMS2 and hMLH1 proteins.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004"><b>Figure 4</b></figref> shows representative complementation of MMR activity in transduced SH cells.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005"><b>Figure 5</b></figref> is a representative photograph of Syrian hamster TK-ts13 cells transfected with a eukaryotic expression vector that produces a novel anti-microbial polypeptide.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0006"><b>Figure 6</b></figref> is a representative graph showing TK-hPMS-134 transfected TK cells can suppress the growth of bacteria <i>in vitro.</i></li></ul></p><p id="p0021" num="0021">Mismatched repair process is described in several references. <nplcit id="ncit0015" npl-type="s"><text>Baker et. al., Cell, 1995, 82, 309-319</text></nplcit>; <nplcit id="ncit0016" npl-type="s"><text>Bronner et. al., Nature, 1994, 368, 258-261</text></nplcit>; <nplcit id="ncit0017" npl-type="s"><text>de Wind et. al., Cell, 1995, 82, 321-330</text></nplcit>; and <nplcit id="ncit0018" npl-type="s"><text>Drummond et. al., Science, 1995, 268, 1909-1912</text></nplcit>. Dominant negative alleles of such genes, when introduced into cells or transgenic animals, increase the rate of spontaneous mutations by reducing the effectiveness of DNA repair and thereby render the cells or animals hypermutable. Hypermutable cells or animals can then be utilized to develop new mutations in a gene of interest or in a gene whose function has not been previously described. Blocking mismatch repair in cells such as, for example, mammalian cells or mammalian cells transfected with genes encoding for specific antimicrobial peptides or non-peptide based antimicrobials, can enhance the rate of mutation within these cells leading to clones that have novel or enhanced antimicrobial activity or production and/or cells that contain genetically altered antimicrobials with<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> enhanced biochemical activity against a range of opportunistic microbes.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">The process of mismatch repair, also called mismatch proofreading, is carried out by protein complexes in cells ranging from bacteria to mammalian cells. <nplcit id="ncit0019" npl-type="s"><text>Modrich, Science, 1994, 266, 1959-1960</text></nplcit>. A mismatch repair gene is a gene that encodes for one of the proteins of such a mismatch repair complex. <nplcit id="ncit0020" npl-type="s"><text>Baker et. al., Cell, 1995, 82, 309-319</text></nplcit>; <nplcit id="ncit0021" npl-type="s"><text>Bronner et. al., Nature, 1994, 368, 258-261</text></nplcit>; <nplcit id="ncit0022" npl-type="s"><text>de Wind et. al., Cell, 1995, 82, 321-330</text></nplcit>; <nplcit id="ncit0023" npl-type="s"><text>Drummond et. al., Science, 1995, 268, 1909-1912</text></nplcit>; and <nplcit id="ncit0024" npl-type="s"><text>Modrich, Science, 1994, 266, 1959-1960</text></nplcit>. Although not wanting to be bound by any particular theory of mechanism of action, a mismatch repair complex is believed to detect distortions of the DNA helix resulting from non-complementary pairing of nucleotide bases. The non-complementary base on the newer DNA strand is excised, and the excised base is replaced with the appropriate base that is complementary to the older DNA strand. In this way, cells eliminate many mutations, which occur as a result of mistakes in DNA replication.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">Dominant negative alleles cause a mismatch repair defective phenotype even in the presence of a wild-type allele in the same cell. An example of a dominant negative allele of a mismatch repair gene is the human gene <i>hP MS2-134,</i> which carries a truncation mutation at codon 134. <nplcit id="ncit0025" npl-type="s"><text>Nicolaides et. al., Mol. Cell. Biol., 1998, 18, 1635-1641</text></nplcit>. The mutation causes the product of this gene to abnormally terminate at the position of the 134th amino acid, resulting in a shortened polypeptide containing the N-terminal 133 amino acids. Such a mutation causes an increase in the rate of mutations that accumulate in cells after DNA replication. Expression of a dominant negative allele of a mismatch repair gene results in impairment of mismatch repair activity, even in the presence of the wild-type allele. Any allele, which produces such effect, can be used in this invention.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">Dominant negative alleles of a mismatch repair gene can be obtained from the cells of humans, animals, yeast, bacteria, or other organisms. <nplcit id="ncit0026" npl-type="s"><text>Prolla et. al., Science, 1994, 264, 1091-1093</text></nplcit>;<nplcit id="ncit0027" npl-type="s"><text> Strand et. al., Nature, 1993, 365, 274-276</text></nplcit>; and <nplcit id="ncit0028" npl-type="s"><text>Su et al., J. Biol. Chem., 1988, 263, 6829-6835</text></nplcit>. Screening cells for defective mismatch repair activity can identity such alleles. Cells from animals or humans with cancer can be screened for defective mismatch repair. Cells from colon cancer patients may be particularly useful. <nplcit id="ncit0029" npl-type="s"><text>Parsons et. al., Cell, 1993, 75, 1227-1236</text></nplcit>; and <nplcit id="ncit0030" npl-type="s"><text>Papadopoulos et. al., Science, 1993, 263, 1625-1629</text></nplcit>. Genomic DNA, cDNA, or mRNA from any cell encoding a mismatch repair protein can be analyzed for variations from the wild type sequence. <nplcit id="ncit0031" npl-type="s"><text>Perucho, Biol. Chem., 1996, 377, 675-684</text></nplcit>. Dominant negative alleles of a mismatch repair gene can also be created<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> artificially, for example, by producing variants of the <i>hP MS2-134</i> allele or other mismatch repair genes. Various techniques of site-directed mutagenesis can be used. The suitability of such alleles, whether natural or artificial, for use in generating hypermutable cells or animals can be evaluated by testing the mismatch repair activity caused by the allele in the presence of one or more wild-type alleles, to determine if it is a dominant negative allele.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">A cell or an animal into which a dominant negative allele of a mismatch repair gene has been introduced will become hypermutable. This means that the spontaneous mutation rate of such cells or animals is elevated compared to cells or animals without such alleles. The degree of elevation of the spontaneous mutation rate can be at least 2-fold, 5-fold, 10-fold, 20-fold, 50-fold, 100-fold, 200-fold, 500-fold, or 1000-fold that of the normal cell or animal.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">According to one aspect of the invention, a method for obtaining a mammalian cell that is resistant to a selected microbe, comprising: growing a culture of mammalian cells wherein said cells comprise <i>hP MS2-134</i>; exposing said cells to said selected microbe; and selecting said mammalian cell that is resistant to said selected microbe is provided. The dominant negative allele <i>hPMS2-134</i> can be naturally occurring or made in the laboratory.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">A polynucleotide including the dominant negative allele can be cloned into an expression vector containing a constitutively active promoter segment (such as but not limited to CMV, SV40, Elongation Factor or LTR sequences) or to inducible promoter sequences such as the steroid inducible pIND vector (In vitrogen), where the expression of the dominant negative mismatch repair gene can be regulated. The polynucleotide can be introduced into the cell by transfection.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">Transfection is any process whereby a polynucleotide is introduced into a cell. The process of transfection can be carried out in a living animal, <i>e.g</i>., using a vector for gene therapy, or it can be carried out <i>in vitro</i>, <i>e.g.,</i> using a suspension of one or more isolated cells in culture. The cell can be any type of eukaryotic cell, including, for example, cells isolated from humans or other primates, mammals or other vertebrates, invertebrates, and single celled organisms such as protozoa, yeast, or bacteria.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">In general, transfection will be carried out using a suspension of cells, or a single cell, but other methods can also be applied as long as a sufficient fraction of the treated cells or tissue incorporates the polynucleotide so as to allow transfected cells to be grown and utilized. The protein product of the polynucleotide may be transiently or stably expressed in the cell. Techniques for transfection are well known and available techniques<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> for introducing polynucleotides include but are not limited to electroporation, transduction, cell fusion, the use of calcium chloride, and packaging of the polynucleotide together with lipid for fusion with the cells of interest. Once a cell has been transfected with the mismatch repair gene, the cell can be grown and reproduced in culture. If the transfection is stable, such that the gene is expressed at a consistent level for many cell generations, then a cell line results.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">An isolated cell is a cell obtained from a tissue of humans or animals by mechanically separating out individual cells and transferring them to a suitable cell culture medium, either with or without pretreatment of the tissue with enzymes, <i>e.g</i>., collagenase or trypsin. Such isolated cells are typically cultured in the absence of other types of cells. Cells selected for the introduction of a dominant negative allele of a mismatch repair gene may be derived from a eukaryotic organism in the form of a primary cell culture or an immortalized cell line, or may be derived from suspensions of single-celled organisms.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">The imethod described herein is useful for creating microbial-resistant mammalian cells that secrete new antimicrobial biochemical agents, either protein or non-protein in nature. Furthermore, the method can be applied to cell lines that express known antimicrobial agents as a means to enhance the biochemical activity of the antimicrobial agent</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">Once a transfected cell line has been produced, it can be used to generate new mutations in one or more gene(s) of interest or in genes that have not been previously described. A gene of interest can be any gene naturally possessed by the cell line or introduced into the cell line by standard methods known in the art. An advantage of using transfected cells or to induce mutation(s) in a gene or genes of interest that encode antimicrobial activity is that the cell need not be exposed to mutagenic chemicals or radiation, which may have secondary harmful effects, both on the object of the exposure and on the workers. Furthermore, it has been demonstrate that chemical and physical mutagens are base pair specific in the way they alter the structure of DNA; the invention described herein results in mutations that are not dependent upon the specific nucleotide or a specific string of nucleotides and is a truly random genetic approach. Therefore, use of the present invention to obtain mutations in novel or known antimicrobial genes will be much more efficient and have a higher likelihood of success in contrast to conventional mutagenesis with chemical or irradiation. Once a new antimicrobial trait is identified in a sibling cell, the dominant negative allele can be removed from the cell by a variety of<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> standard methods known in the art. For example, the gene can be directly knocked out the allele by technologies used by those skilled in the art or use of a inducible expression system; the dominant-negative allele is driven by a standard promoter that is regulated by inclusion of an inducer, withdrawal of the inducer results in attenuation of the expression of the dominant negative mismatch repair mutant and a normal DNA repair process will ensue.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">New antimicrobial agents are selected from cells that have been exposed to the dominant negative mismatch repair process followed by incubating the mutant cells in the presence of the microbe for which an novel antimicrobial agent is sought The novel antimicrobial agent is purified by standard methods known to those skilled in the art and characterized. The antimicrobial agents are re-screened to determine the specific activity of the novel antimicrobial as well as tested against a broad range of microbes to determine spectrum of activity. The gene(s) that encode the novel antimicrobial are isolated by standard well known methods to those in the art. The mutations can be detected by analyzing for alterations in the genotype of the cells by examining the sequence of genomic DNA, cDNA, messenger RNA, or amino acids associated with the gene of interest. A mutant polypeptide can be detected by identifying alterations in electrophoretic mobility, spectroscopic properties, or other physical or structural characteristics of a protein encoded by a mutant gene when the cell that has undergone alteration encodes a known antimicrobial that is altered by the means described in the current invention to obtain a more efficacious antimicrobial.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">Examples of mismatch repair proteins and nucleic acid sequences include the following:
<ul><li>PMS2 (mouse) (SEQ ID NO:7)
<img id="ib0001" file="imgb0001.tif" wi="151" he="56" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></li><li>PMS2 (mouse cDNA) (SEQ ID NO:8)
<img id="ib0002" file="imgb0002.tif" wi="151" he="185" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></li><li>PMS2 (human) (SEQ ID NO:9)
<img id="ib0003" file="imgb0003.tif" wi="151" he="44" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="13"> -->
<img id="ib0004" file="imgb0004.tif" wi="147" he="11" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></li><li>PMS2 (human cDNA) (SEQ ID NO: 10)
<img id="ib0005" file="imgb0005.tif" wi="150" he="169" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></li><li>PMS1 (human) (SEQ ID NO:11)
<img id="ib0006" file="imgb0006.tif" wi="148" he="48" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="14"> -->
<img id="ib0007" file="imgb0007.tif" wi="148" he="11" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></li><li>PMS1 (human) (SEQ ID NO:12)
<img id="ib0008" file="imgb0008.tif" wi="156" he="189" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></li><li>MSH2 (human) (SEQ ID NO:13)
<img id="ib0009" file="imgb0009.tif" wi="148" he="19" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> -->
<img id="ib0010" file="imgb0010.tif" wi="148" he="41" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></li><li>MSH2 (human cDNA) (SEQ ID NO:14)
<img id="ib0011" file="imgb0011.tif" wi="159" he="191" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></li><li>MLH1 (human) (SEQ ID NO:15)
<img id="ib0012" file="imgb0012.tif" wi="151" he="52" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></li><li>MLH1 (human) (SEQ ID NO:16)
<img id="ib0013" file="imgb0013.tif" wi="155" he="155" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></li><li>hPMS2-134 (human) (SEQ ID NO:17)
<img id="ib0014" file="imgb0014.tif" wi="147" he="11" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></li><li>hPMS2-134 (human cDNA) (SEQ ID NO:18)
<img id="ib0015" file="imgb0015.tif" wi="147" he="29" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></li></ul></p><p id="p0035" num="0035">The above disclosure generally describes the present invention. A more complete understanding can be obtained by reference to the following specific examples, which are provided herein for purposes of illustration only, and are not intended to limit the scope of the invention.</p><heading id="h0005"><b>EXAMPLES</b></heading><heading id="h0006"><b>Example 1: <i>hPMS2-134</i> Encodes a Dominant Negative Mismatch Repair Protein</b></heading><p id="p0036" num="0036">A profound defect in MMR was found in the normal cells of two HNPCC patients. That this defect was operative <i>in vivo</i> was demonstrated by the widespread presence of microsatellite instability in non-neoplastic cells of such patients. One of the two patients had a germ-line truncating mutation of the <i>hP MS2</i> gene at codon 134 (the <i>hP MS2-134</i> mutation), while the other patient had a small germ-line deletion within the <i>hMLH1</i> gene. <nplcit id="ncit0032" npl-type="s"><text>Leach et al., Cell, 1993, 75, 1215-1225</text></nplcit>. These data contradicted the two-hit model generally believed to explain the biochemical and biological features of HNPCC patients. The basis for this MMR deficiency in the normal cells of these patients was unclear, and several potential explanations were offered. For example, it was possible that the second allele of the relevant MMR gene was inactivated in the germ-line of these patients through an undiscovered mechanism, or that unknown mutations of other genes involved in the MMR process were present that cooperated with the known germ-line mutation. It is clear from knock-out experiments in mice that MMR-deficiency is compatible with normal growth and development, supporting these possibilities. <nplcit id="ncit0033" npl-type="s"><text>Edelmann et al., Cell, 1996, 85, 1125-1134</text></nplcit>. Alternatively, it was possible that the mutant alleles exerted a dominant-negative effect, resulting in MMR deficiency even in the presence of the wild-type allele of the corresponding MMR gene and all other genes involved in the<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> MMR process. To distinguish between these possibilities, the truncated polypeptide encoded by the <i>hP MS2-134</i> mutation was expressed in an MMR proficient cell line its affect on MMR activity was analyzed. The results showed that this mutant could indeed exert a dominant-negative effect, resulting in biochemical and genetic manifestations of MMR deficiency. One embodiment of the present invention is demonstrated in Table 1, where a Syrian hamster fibroblast cell line (TK) was transfected with an expression vector containing the hPMS2-134 (TK-PMS2-134) or the empty expression vector (TKvect), which also contains the NEO gene as a selectable marker. TK-PMS2-134 cells were determined to be stably expressing the gene via western blot analysis (data not shown). Nuclear lysates from hPMS2-134 and control cells were measured for the ability to correct mismatched DNA substrates. As shown in Table 1, TK-PMS2-134 cells had a dramatic decrease in repair activity while TKvect control cells were able to repair mismatched DNA duplexes at a rate of ∼4.0 fmol/15 minutes (p&lt;.01).
<tables id="tabl0001" num="0001"><table frame="none"><title><b>Table 1: Relative endogenous MMR activity of MMR-proficient cells expressing an ectopicaliy expressed morphogene or an empty expression vector</b></title><tgroup cols="2" colsep="0"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="82mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="84mm"/><thead><row><entry valign="top">Cell Lines</entry><entry valign="top">5' DNA Repair activity of G/T mismatch (fmol/15 minutes)</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry>TKvect</entry><entry/></row><row><entry>1</entry><entry>3.5</entry></row><row><entry>2</entry><entry>2.9</entry></row><row><entry>3</entry><entry>5.5</entry></row><row><entry>TK-PMS2-134</entry><entry/></row><row><entry>1</entry><entry>0</entry></row><row><entry>2</entry><entry>0</entry></row><row><entry>3</entry><entry>0.5</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></tables></p><p id="p0037" num="0037">These data show that the expression of the TK-PMS2-134 results in suppressed MMR of a host organism and allows for an enhanced mutation rate of genetic loci with each mitosis.</p><heading id="h0007"><b>Example 2: <i>hPMS2-134</i> Can Alter Genes <i>In Vivo</i></b></heading><p id="p0038" num="0038">An example of the ability to alter mismatch repair comes from experiments using manipulation of mismatch repair TK cells (described above) that expressed the TK-hPMS2-134 mutant were used by transfection of the mammalian expression construct containing a defective β-galactosidase gene (referred to as pCAR-OF) which was<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> transfected into TK-hPMS2-134 or TKvect cells as described above. The pCAR-OF vector consists of a β-galactosidase gene containing a 29-basepair poly-CA tract inserted at the 5' end of its coding region, which causes the wild-type reading frame to shift out-of-frame. This chimeric gene is cloned into the pCEP4, which contains the constitutively active cytomegalovirus (CMV) promoter upstream of the cloning site and also contains the hygromycin-resistance gene that allows for selection of cells containing this vector. The pCAR-OF reporter cannot generate β-galactosidase activity unless a frame-restoring mutation (i.e., insertion or deletion) arises following transfection into a host Another reporter vector called pCAR-IF contains a β-galactosidase in which a 27-bp poly-CA repeat was cloned into the same site as the pCAR-OF gene, but it is biologically active because the removal of a single repeat restores the open reading frame and produces a functional chimeric β-galactosidase polypeptide (not shown). In these experiments, TK-hPMS2-134 and TKvect cells were transfected with the pCAR-OF reporter vector and selected for 17 days in neomycin plus hygromycin selection medium. After the 17 days, resistant colonies were stained for β-galactosidase production to determine the number of clones containing a genetically altered β-galactosidase gene. All conditions produced a relatively equal number of neomycin/hygromycin resistant cells, however, only the cells expressing the TK-hPMS2-134 contained a subset of clones that were positive for β-galactosidase activity. Representative results are shown in Table 2, which shows the data from these experiments where cell colonies were stained <i>in situ</i> for β-galactosidase activity and scored-for activity. Cells were scored positive if the colonies turned blue in the presence of X-gal substrate and scored negative if colonies remained white. Analysis of triplicate experiments showed that a significant increase in the number of functional β-galactosidase positive cells was found in the TK-hPMS2-134 cultures, while no β-galactosidase positive cells were seen in the control TKvect cells.
<tables id="tabl0002" num="0002"><table frame="none"><title><b>Table 2. Number of TKmorph and TKvect cells containing functional β-galactosidase activity</b></title><tgroup cols="4" colsep="0"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="38mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="35mm"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="35mm"/><colspec colnum="4" colname="col4" colwidth="34mm"/><thead><row><entry valign="top">Cells B-gal</entry><entry valign="top">White Colonies</entry><entry valign="top">Blue Colonies</entry><entry valign="top">% Clones with altered</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry>Tkvect</entry><entry>65 +/- 9</entry><entry align="center">0</entry><entry>0/65 = 0%</entry></row><row><entry>TK-PMS2-134</entry><entry>40+/-12</entry><entry align="center">28 +/- 4</entry><entry>28/68 = 41%</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></tables><!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --></p><p id="p0039" num="0039">TK-PMS2-134/pCAR-OF clones that were pooled and expanded also showed a number of cells that contained a functional β-galactosidase gene. No β-galactosidase positive cells were observed in TKvect cells transfected with the pCAR-OF vector. These data are shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> where the dark staining in panel B represent β-galactosidase positive cells present in the TK-PMS2-134/pCAR-OF cultures while none are found in the TKvect cells grown under similar conditions (panel A). These data demonstrate the ability of the mutant mismatch repair gene, hPMS2-134, to generate gene alterations <i>in vivo,</i> which allows for the rapid screening of clones with altered polypeptides exhibiting new biochemical features.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">To confirm that alterations within the nucleotide sequences of the β-galactosidase gene was indeed responsible for the <i>in vivo</i> β-galactosidase activity present in TK-hPMS2-134 clones, RNA was isolated from TK-hPMS2-134/pCAR OF and TKvect/pCAR-OF and the β-galactosidase mRNA primary structure was examined by reverse transcriptase polymerase chain reaction (RT-PCR) amplification and sequencing. Sequence analysis of β-galactosidase message from TKvect cells found no structural alterations in the input gene sequence. Analysis of the β-galactosidase message from TK-hPMS-134 cells found several changes within the coding sequences of the gene. These sequence alterations included insertion and deletions of the poly CA tract in the amino terminus as expected. Other alterations included insertions of sequences outside of the polyCA repeat as well as a series of single base alterations contained throughout the length of the gene.</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">A summary of the genetic alterations are given in <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref> where a schematic representation of the β-galactosidase gene is shown with the regions and types of genetic alterations depicted below.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042"><i>Plasmids.</i> The full-length wild-type <i>hPMS2</i> cDNA was obtained from a human Hela cDNA library as described in <nplcit id="ncit0034" npl-type="s"><text>Strand et. al., Nature, 1993, 365, 274-276</text></nplcit>.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">An <i>hPMS2</i> cDNA containing a termination codon at amino acid 134 was obtained via RT-PCR from the patient in which the mutation was discovered. <nplcit id="ncit0035" npl-type="s"><text>Nicolaides et. al., Mol. Cell. Biol., 1998, 18, 1635-1641</text></nplcit>.</p><p id="p0044" num="0044">The cDNA fragments were cloned into the BamHI site into the pSG5 vector, which contains an SV40 promoter followed by an SV40 polyadenylation signal. <nplcit id="ncit0036" npl-type="s"><text>Nicolaides et al., Genomics, 1995, 29, 329-334</text></nplcit>. The pCAR reporter vectors described in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> were constructed as described in <nplcit id="ncit0037" npl-type="s"><text>Palombo et al., Nature,<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> 1994, 36, 417</text></nplcit>.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045"><i>β-galactosidase assay.</i> Seventeen days following transfection with pCAR, β-galactosidase assays were performed using 20 µg of protein in 45 mM 2-mercaptoethanol, 1 mM MgCl<sub>2</sub>, 0.1 M NaPO<sub>4</sub> and 0.6 mg/ml Chlorophenol red-β-D-galatopyranoside (CPRG, Boehringer Mannheim). Reactions were incubated for 1 hour, terminated by the addition of 0.5 M Na<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub>, and analyzed by spectrophotometry at 576 nm. <nplcit id="ncit0038" npl-type="s"><text>Nicolaides et. al., Mol. Cell. Biol., 1998, 18, 1635-1641</text></nplcit>. For <i>in situ</i> β-galactosidase staining, cells were fixed in 1% glutaraldehyde in PBS and incubated in 0.15 M NaCl, 1 mM MgCl<sub>2</sub>, 3.3 mM K<sub>4</sub>Fe(CN)<sub>6</sub>, 3.3 mM K<sub>3</sub>Fe(CN)<sub>6</sub>, 0.2% X-Gal for 2 hours at 37°C. Example 3: hPMS2-134 Causes a Defect in MMR Activity</p><p id="p0046" num="0046">The differences in β-galactosidase activity between <i>PMS2-WT</i> and <i>PMS2-134</i> transfected cells can be due to the PMS2-134 protein disturbing MMR activity resulting in a higher frequency of mutation within the pCAR-OF reporter and re-establishing the ORF. To directly test whether MMR was altered, a biochemical assay for MMR with the individual clones described in Example 1 was employed. Nuclear extracts were prepared from the clones and incubated with heteroduplex substrates containing either a /CA\ insertion-deletion or a G/T mismatch under conditions described previously. The /CA\ and G/T heteroduplexes were used to test repair from the 3' and 5' directions, respectively. There was a dramatic difference between the <i>PMS2-134</i> expressing clones and the other clones in these assays (Table 3).
<tables id="tabl0003" num="0003"><table frame="topbot"><title><b>Table 3. MMR activity of nuclear extracts from SH clones or pooled cultures<i><sup><u>a</u></sup></i></b></title><tgroup cols="7" colsep="0"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="16mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="21mm"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="16mm"/><colspec colnum="4" colname="col4" colwidth="22mm"/><colspec colnum="5" colname="col5" colwidth="22mm"/><colspec colnum="6" colname="col6" colwidth="22mm"/><colspec colnum="7" colname="col7" colwidth="22mm"/><thead><row><entry namest="col1" nameend="col2" morerows="1" align="left" valign="middle">Cell line</entry><entry namest="col3" nameend="col7" align="left" valign="top">Amt of repaired substrate (fmol/15 min)</entry></row><row><entry valign="top">3' /CA\</entry><entry valign="top">3' G/T</entry><entry valign="top">5' G/T</entry><entry valign="top">3' /CTG\</entry><entry valign="top">5' /CTG\</entry></row><row><entry namest="col1" nameend="col2" align="left" valign="top">SH clones<i><sup><u>b</u></sup></i></entry><entry valign="top"/><entry valign="top"/><entry valign="top"/><entry valign="top"/><entry valign="top"/></row><row><entry namest="col1" nameend="col2" align="left" valign="top">PMS2-NOT</entry><entry valign="top"/><entry valign="top"/><entry valign="top"/><entry valign="top"/><entry valign="top"/></row></thead><tbody><row><entry namest="col1" nameend="col2" align="center">Clone A</entry><entry align="char" char=".">10.2</entry><entry/><entry align="char" char="." charoff="9">3.5</entry><entry/><entry/></row><row><entry namest="col1" nameend="col2" align="center">Clone B</entry><entry align="char" char=".">12.7</entry><entry/><entry align="char" char="." charoff="9">2.9</entry><entry/><entry/></row><row><entry namest="col1" nameend="col2" align="center">Clone C</entry><entry align="char" char=".">13.5</entry><entry/><entry align="char" char="." charoff="9">5.5</entry><entry/><entry/></row></tbody></tgroup><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --><tgroup cols="7" colsep="0" rowsep="0"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="16mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="21mm"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="16mm"/><colspec colnum="4" colname="col4" colwidth="22mm"/><colspec colnum="5" colname="col5" colwidth="22mm"/><colspec colnum="6" colname="col6" colwidth="22mm"/><colspec colnum="7" colname="col7" colwidth="22mm"/><thead><row><entry namest="col1" nameend="col2" align="left" valign="top">PMS2-WT</entry><entry valign="top"/><entry valign="top"/><entry valign="top"/><entry valign="top"/><entry valign="top"/></row></thead><tbody><row><entry/><entry align="center">Clone A</entry><entry align="char" char=".">2.8</entry><entry/><entry align="char" char="." charoff="9">2.2</entry><entry/><entry/></row><row><entry/><entry align="center">Clone B</entry><entry align="char" char=".">5.7</entry><entry/><entry align="char" char="." charoff="9">4.8</entry><entry/><entry/></row><row><entry/><entry align="center">Clone c</entry><entry align="char" char=".">4.7</entry><entry/><entry align="char" char="." charoff="9">2.9</entry><entry/><entry/></row></tbody></tgroup><tgroup cols="7" colsep="0" rowsep="0"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="16mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="21mm"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="16mm"/><colspec colnum="4" colname="col4" colwidth="22mm"/><colspec colnum="5" colname="col5" colwidth="22mm"/><colspec colnum="6" colname="col6" colwidth="22mm"/><colspec colnum="7" colname="col7" colwidth="22mm"/><thead><row><entry namest="col1" nameend="col2" align="left" valign="top">PMS2-134</entry><entry valign="top" align="char" char="."/><entry valign="top"/><entry valign="top"/><entry valign="top"/><entry valign="top"/></row></thead><tbody><row><entry/><entry align="center">Clone A</entry><entry align="char" char=".">2.5</entry><entry/><entry align="char" char="." charoff="9">0.0</entry><entry/><entry/></row><row><entry/><entry align="center">Clone B</entry><entry align="char" char=".">2.4</entry><entry/><entry align="char" char="." charoff="9">0.0</entry><entry/><entry/></row><row><entry/><entry align="center">Clone C</entry><entry align="char" char=".">5.0</entry><entry/><entry align="char" char="." charoff="9">0.5</entry><entry/><entry/></row></tbody></tgroup><tgroup cols="7" colsep="0" rowsep="0"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="16mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="21mm"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="16mm"/><colspec colnum="4" colname="col4" colwidth="22mm"/><colspec colnum="5" colname="col5" colwidth="22mm"/><colspec colnum="6" colname="col6" colwidth="22mm"/><colspec colnum="7" colname="col7" colwidth="22mm"/><thead><row><entry namest="col1" nameend="col2" align="left" valign="top">Pooled cultures</entry><entry valign="top"/><entry valign="top"/><entry valign="top"/><entry valign="top"/><entry valign="top"/></row></thead><tbody><row><entry/><entry>PMS2-NOT</entry><entry/><entry>2.07 ± 0.09</entry><entry>2.37 ± 0.37</entry><entry>3.45 ± 1.35</entry><entry>2.77 ± 1.37</entry></row><row><entry/><entry>PMS2-WT</entry><entry/><entry>1.65 ± 0.94</entry><entry>1.86 ± 0.57</entry><entry>1.13 ± 0.23</entry><entry>1.23 ± 0.65</entry></row><row><entry/><entry>PMS2-134</entry><entry/><entry>0.14 ± 0.2</entry><entry>0.0 ± 0.0</entry><entry>1.31 ± 0.66</entry><entry>0.0 ± 0.0</entry></row></tbody></tgroup><tgroup cols="7" rowsep="0"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="16mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="21mm"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="16mm"/><colspec colnum="4" colname="col4" colwidth="22mm"/><colspec colnum="5" colname="col5" colwidth="22mm"/><colspec colnum="6" colname="col6" colwidth="22mm"/><colspec colnum="7" colname="col7" colwidth="22mm"/><tbody><row><entry namest="col1" nameend="col7" align="justify"><i><sup>a</sup></i> The extracts were tested for MMR activity with 24 fmol of heteroduplex.<br/>
<i><sup>b</sup></i> These data represent similar results derived from more than five independent experiments.</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></tables></p><p id="p0047" num="0047">While all clones repaired substrates from the 3' direction (/CA\ heteroduplex), cells expressing the PMS2-134 polypeptide had very little 5' repair activity. A similar directional defect in mismatch repair was evident with pooled clones resulting from <i>PMS2-134</i> transfection, or when the heteroduplex contained a 2-4 base pair loop, examples of which are shown in Table 3. A small decrease in MMR activity was observed in the 3' /CA\ PMS2-WT repair assays, perhaps a result of interference in the biochemical assays by over-expression of the PMS2 protein. No significant activity was caused by <i>PMS2-WT</i> in the <i>in situ</i> β-galactosidase assays, a result more likely to reflect the <i>in vivo</i> condition.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048"><i>Biochemical assays for mismatch repair.</i> MMR activity in nuclear extracts was performed as described, using 24 fmol of substrate, in <nplcit id="ncit0039" npl-type="s"><text>Bronner et. al., Nature, 1994, 368, 258-261</text></nplcit> and <nplcit id="ncit0040" npl-type="s"><text>Nicolaides et. al., Mol. Cell. Biol., 1998, 18, 1635-1641</text></nplcit>.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">Complementation assays were done by adding ∼ 100 ng of purified MutLα or MutSα components to 100 µg of nuclear extract, adjusting the final KCl concentration to 100 mM. <nplcit id="ncit0041" npl-type="s"><text>Bevins, Ciba Found Symp., 1994, 186, 250-69</text></nplcit> and <nplcit id="ncit0042" npl-type="s"><text>Alderson et al., Res. Microbial., 1993, 144, 665-72</text></nplcit>. The substrates used in<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> these experiments contain a strand break 181 nucleotides 5' or 125 nucleotides 3' to the mismatch. Values represent experiments performed at least in duplicate.</p><heading id="h0008"><b>Example 4: C-Terminus of hPMS2 Mediates Interaction Between hPMS2 and hMLH1</b></heading><p id="p0050" num="0050">To elucidate the mechanism by which hPMS2-134 affected MMR, the interaction between hPMS2 and hMLH1 was analyzed. Previous studies have shown that these two proteins dimerize to form a functionally active complex. <nplcit id="ncit0043" npl-type="s"><text>Bronner et. al., Nature, 1994, 368, 258-261</text></nplcit>. Proteins were synthesized <i>in vitro</i> using reticulocyte lysates, employing RNA generated from cloned templates. The full-length hMLH1 and hPMS2 proteins bound to each other and were co-precipitated with antibodies to either protein, as expected (data not shown). To determine the domain of hPMS2 that bound to hMLH1, the amino terminus (codons 1-134), containing the most highly conserved domain among mutL proteins (<nplcit id="ncit0044" npl-type="s"><text>Su et al., J. Biol. Chem., 1988, 263, 6829-6835</text></nplcit> and <nplcit id="ncit0045" npl-type="s"><text>Edelmann et al., Cell, 1996, 85, 1125-1134</text></nplcit>), and the carboxyl terminus (codons 135-862) were separately cloned and proteins produced <i>in vitro</i> in coupled transcription-translation reactions. <figref idrefs="f0003">Figures 3A, 3B, and 3C</figref> show a representative immunoprecipitation of <i>in vitro</i>-translated hPMS2 and hMLH1 proteins. <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3A</figref> shows labeled (indicated by an asterisk) or unlabelled proteins incubated with an antibody to the C-terminus of hPMS2 in lanes 1 to 3 and to hMLH1 in lanes 4 to 6. Lane 7 contains a nonprogrammed reticulocyte lysate. PMS2-135 contains codons 135 to 862 of hPMS2. The major translation products of hPMS2 and hMLH1 are indicated. <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3B</figref> shows labeled hPMS2-134 (containing codons 1-134 of hPMS2) incubated in the presence or absence of unlabelled hMLH1 plus an antibody to hMLH1 (lanes 1 and 2, respectively). Lane 3 contains lysate from a nonprogrammed reticulolysate. <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3C</figref> shows labeled proteins incubated with an antibody to the N terminus of hPMS2. Lane 6 contains a nonprogrammed reticulocyte lysate. In both panels A and B, autoradiographs of immunoprecipitated products are shown. When a <sup>35</sup>S-labelled, full-length hMLH1 protein (<figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3A</figref>, lane 5) was mixed with the unlabelled carboxyl terminal hPMS2 polypeptide, a monoclonal antibody (mAb) to the carboxyl terminus of hPMS2 efficiently immunoprecipitated the labeled hMLH1 protein (lane 1). No hMLH1 protein was precipitated in the absence of hPMS2 (lane 2). Conversely, when the <sup>35</sup>S-labelled carboxyl-terminus of hPMS2 (lane 3) was incubated with unlabelled, full-length hMLH1 protein, an and-hMLH1 mAb precipitated the hPMS2<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --> polypeptide (lane 4). In the absence of the unlabelled hMLH1 protein, no hPMS2 protein was precipitated by this mAb (lane 6). The same antibody failed to immunoprecipitate the amino-terminus of hPMS2 (amino acids 1-134) when mixed with unlabelled MLH1 protein (<figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3B</figref>, lane 1). This finding was corroborated by the converse experiment in which radiolabelled hPMS2-134 (<figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3C</figref>, lane 1) was unable to coprecipitate radiolabelled MLH1 when precipitations were done using an N-terminal hPMS2 antibody (<figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3C</figref>, lane 2) while this antibody was shown to be able to coprecipitate MLH1 when mixed with wild-type hPMS2 (<figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3C</figref>, lane 4).</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">The initial steps of MMR are dependent on two protein complexes, called MutSα and MutLα. <nplcit id="ncit0046" npl-type="s"><text>Drummond et. al., Science, 1995, 268, 1909-1912</text></nplcit>. As the amino terminus of hPMS2 did not mediate binding of hPMS2 to hMLH1, it was of interest to determine whether it might instead mediate the interaction between the MutLα complex (comprised of HULH1 and hPMS2) and the MutSα complex (comprised of MSH2 and GTBP). Because previous studies have demonstrated that MSH2 and the MutLα components do not associate in solution, direct hPMS2-134:MutSα interaction was unable to be assayed. A different approach was used to address this issue, and attempted to complement nuclear extracts from the various SH cell lines with MutSα or MutLα. If the truncated protein present in the PMS2-134 expressing SH cells was binding to MutSα and lowering its effective concentration in the extract, then adding intact MutSα should rescue the MMR defect in such extracts. <figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 4</figref> shows complementation of MMR activity in transduced SH cells. Lysates from pooled clones stably transduced with PMS2-NOT, PMS2-WT, or PMS2-134 were complemented with purified MutSα or MutLα MMR components by using the 5' G/T heteroduplex substrate. The values are presented as the percentage of repair activity in each case compared to that in lysates complemented with both purified MutLα and MutSα components to normalize for repair efficiency in the different lysate backgrounds. The values shown represent the average of at least three different determinations. Purified MutSα added to such extracts had no effect (<figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 4</figref>). In contrast, addition of intact MutLα to the extract completely restored directional repair to the extracts from PMS2-134 cells (<figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 4</figref>).</p><p id="p0052" num="0052">The results described above lead to several conclusions. First, expression of the amino-terminus of hPMS2 results in an increase in microsatellite instability, consistent with a replication error (RER) phenotype. That this elevated microsatellite instability is due to MMR deficiency was proven by evaluation of extracts from stably transduced cells.<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --> Interestingly, the expression of PMS2-134 resulted in a polar defect in MMR, which was only observed using heteroduplexes designed to test repair from the 5' direction (no significant defect in repair from the 3' direction was observed in the same extracts). Interestingly, cells deficient in hMLH1 also have a polar defect in MMR, but in this case preferentially affecting repair from the 3' direction. <nplcit id="ncit0047" npl-type="s"><text>Huttner et al., Pediatr. Res., 1999, 45, 785-94</text></nplcit>. It is known from previous studies in both prokaryotes and eukaryotes that the separate enzymatic components mediate repair from the two different directions. Our results indicate a model in which 5' repair is primarily dependent on hPMS2 while 3' repair is primarily dependent on hMLH1. It is easy to envision how the dimeric complex between PMS2 and MLH1 might set up this directionality. The combined results also demonstrate that a defect in directional MMR is sufficient to produce a RER+ phenotype.</p><p id="p0053" num="0053">The dominant-negative function of the PMS2-134 polypeptide can result from its binding to MLH1 and consequent inhibition of MutLα function. This is based in part on the fact that the most highly conserved domain of the <i>PMS2</i> gene is located in its amino terminus, and the only known biochemical partner for PMS2 is MLH1. The binding studies revealed, however, that the carboxyl terminus-of PMS2, rather than the highly conserved amino terminus, actually mediated binding to MLH1. This result is consistent with those recently obtained in <i>S. cerevisciae,</i> in which the MLH1-interacting domain of PMS1 (the yeast homolog of human PMS2) was localized to its carboxyl-terminus. <nplcit id="ncit0048" npl-type="s"><text>Leach et al., Cell, 1993, 75, 1215-1225</text></nplcit>. The add-back experiments additionally showed that the hPMS2-134 mutant was not likely to mediate an interaction with the MutSα complex (<figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 4</figref>). The bPMS2-134 polypeptide does not inhibit the initial steps in MMR, but rather interacts with and inhibits a downstream component of the pathway, perhaps a nuclease required for repair from the 5' direction.</p><p id="p0054" num="0054">The demonstration that the hPMS2-134 mutation can confer a dominant-negative MMR defect to transfected cells helps to explain the phenotype of the kindred in which this mutant was discovered. Three individuals from this kindred were found to carry the mutation, a father and his two children. Both children exhibited microsatellite instability in their normal tissues and both developed tumors at an early age, while the father had no evidence of microsatellite instability in his normal cells and was completely healthy at age 35. The only difference known to us with respect to the MMR genes in this family is that the father's mutant allele was expressed at lower levels than the wild-type allele as assessed by sequencing of RT-PCR products of RNA from lymphocytes. The children<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> expressed both alleles at approximately equal levels. The dominant negative attribute of the <i>hPMS2-134</i> mutant may only be manifest when it is present at sufficient concentrations (at least equimolar) thus, explaining the absence of MMR deficiency in the father. The reason for the differential expression of the <i>hPMS2-134</i> allele in this kindred is not clear, though imprinting is a possibility. Ascertainment of additional, larger kindreds with such mutations will facilitate the investigation of this issue.</p><p id="p0055" num="0055"><i>Western blots.</i> Equal number of cells were lysed directly in lysis buffer (60 mM Tris, pH 6.8, 2% SDS, 10% glycerol, 0.1 M 2-mercaptoethanol, 0.001% bromophenol blue) and boiled for 5 minutes. Lysate proteins were separated by electrophoresis on 4-12% Tris-glycine gels (for analysis of full-length hPMS2) or 4-20% Tris-glycine gels (for analysis of hPMS2-134). Gels were electroblotted onto Immobilon-P (Millipore) in 48 mM Tris base, 40 mM glycine, 0.0375% SDS, 20% methanol and blocked overnight at 4°C in Tris-buffered saline plus 0.05% Tween-20 and 5% condensed milk. Filters were probed with a polyclonal antibody generated against residues 2-20 of hPMS2 (Santa Cruz Biotechnology, Inc.) and a horseradish peroxidase conjugated goat anti-rabbit secondary antibody, using chemiluminescence for detection (Pierce).</p><p id="p0056" num="0056"><i>In vitro translation.</i> Linear DNA fragments containing <i>hPMS2</i> and <i>hMLH1</i> cDNA sequences were prepared by PCR, incorporating sequences for <i>in vitro</i> transcription and translation in the sense primer. A full-length <i>hMLH1</i> fragment was prepared using the sense primer 5'-ggatcctaatacgactcactatagggaga ccaccatgtcgttcgtggcaggg-3' (SEQ ID NO:1) (codons 1-6) and the antisense primer 5'-taagtcttaagtgctaccaaa-3' (SEQ ID NO:2) (located in the 3' untranslated region, nt 2411-2433), using a wild-type hMLH1 cDNA clone as template. A full-length <i>hPMS2</i> fragment was prepared with the sense primer 5'-ggatcctaatacgactcactatagggag accaccatggaacaattgcctgcgg-3' (SEQ ID NO:3) (codons 1- 6) and the antisense primer 5'-aggttagtgaagactctgtc-3' (SEQ ID NO:4) (located in 3' untranslated region, nt 2670-2690) using a cloned <i>hPMS2</i> cDNA as template. A fragment encoding the amino-terminal 134 amino acids of hPMS2 was prepared using the same sense primer and the antisense primer 5'-agtcgagttccaaccttcg-3' (SEQ ID NO:5). A fragment containing codons 135-862 of <i>hPMS135</i> was generated using the sense primer 5 '-ggatcetaatacgactcactatagggagaccaccatgatgtttgatcacaat gg-3' (SEQ ID NO:6) (codons 135-141) and the same antisense primer as that used for the full-length <i>hPMS2</i> protein. These fragments were used to produce proteins via the coupled<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --> transcription-translation system (Promega). The reactions were supplemented with <sup>35</sup>S-labelled methionine or unlabelled methionine, as indicated in the text. The PMS135 and hMLH1 proteins could not be simultaneously radiolabelled and immunoprecipitated because of their similar molecular weights precluded resolution. Lower molecular weight bands are presumed to be degradation products and/or polypeptides translated from alternative internal methionines.</p><p id="p0057" num="0057"><i>Immunoprecipitation</i>. Immunoprecipitations were performed on <i>in vitro</i> translated proteins by mixing the translation reactions with 1 µg of the MLH1 specific monoclonal antibody (mAB) MLH14 (Oncogene Science, Inc.), a polyclonal antibody generated to codons 2-20 of hPMS2 described above, or a polyclonal antibody generated to codons 843-862 of hPMS2 (Santa Cruz Biotechnology, Inc.) in 400 µl of EBC buffer (50 mM Tris, pH 7.5, 0.1 M NaCl, 0.5% NP40). After incubation for 1 hour at 4°C, protein A sepharose (Sigma) was added to a final concentration of 10% and reactions were incubated at 4°C for 1 hour. Proteins bound to protein A were washed five times in EBC and separated by electrophoresis on 4-20% Tris-glycine gels, which were then dried and autoradiographed.</p><heading id="h0009"><b>Example 5: Syrian hamster Tk-ts-13 Cells Produce a Novel Anti-Microbial Polypeptide Can Suppress the Growth of <i>Bacillus subtilis</i></b></heading><p id="p0058" num="0058">The feasibility of creating microbial-resistant mammalian cells is demonstrated as follows. Syrian Hamster TK fibroblasts were transfected with a mammalian expression vector containing a novel anti-microbial polypeptide called mlg1 or the empty expression vector called psg. When cells expressing the mlg polypeptide (referred to as TK-mlg1) were grown in the presence of <i>Bacillus subtilis,</i> these cells were able to suppress the growth of the microbes and allow the TK host to remain viable in contrast to TK cells transfected with the empty vector (TK=psg), which all died from the toxic effects that <i>Bacillus subtilis</i> has on mammalian cells. <figref idrefs="f0005">Figure 5</figref> shows a photograph of TK-mlg1 and TK=psg cultures grown in the presence of <i>Bacillus</i> for 4 days. Syrian hamster Tk-ts 13 cells were transfected with a eukaryotic expression vector that produces a novel antimicrobial polypeptide referred to as mlg1 (Panel A) or the expression vector lacking an inserted cDNA for expression (TK=psg, Panel B). Cells were plated at a density of 5x10<sup>5</sup> cells/ml in a 10 cm falcon pyrogenic-free petri dish in growth medium for 24 hours and then inoculated with 10 µl of an exponentially growing culture of <i>Bacillus subtilis.</i><!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --> Cultures were then incubated for 4 days at which time <i>Bacilli</i> grow and begin to lyse the Tk-ts13 parental culture as shown in panel B (indicated by arrows), while cells expressing the anti-microbial mlg1 polypeptide (Panel A) remain viable in the presence of <i>Bacillus</i> (small granular structures present in panels A and B). These data demonstrate the feasibility of cells to survive in the presence of <i>Bacillus</i> contamination when they produce an anti-microbial agent These data show that antimicrobial producing mammalian cells are capable of growing and surviving in the presence of toxic microbes.</p><p id="p0059" num="0059"><i>Cell lines and trarrsfection.</i> Syrian Hamster fibroblast Tk-ts13 cells were obtained from ATCC and cultured as described. <nplcit id="ncit0049" npl-type="s"><text>Modrich, Science, 1994, 266, 1959-1960</text></nplcit>. Stably transfected cell lines expressing <i>hPMS2</i> were created by cotransfection of the <i>PMS2</i> expression vectors and the pLHL4 plasmid encoding the hygromycin resistance gene at a ratio of 3:1 (pCAR:pLHL4) and selected with hygromycin. Stably transfected cell lines containing pCAR reporters were generated by co-transfection of pCAR vectors together with either pNTK plasmid encoding the neomycin resistance plasmid or with pLHL4. All transfections were performed using calcium phosphate as previously described in <nplcit id="ncit0050" npl-type="s"><text>Modrich, Science, 1994, 266, 1959-1960</text></nplcit>.</p><heading id="h0010"><b>Example 6: TK-hPMS2-134 Cells Can Suppress the Growth of <i>Escherichia coli in vitro</i></b></heading><p id="p0060" num="0060">While TK-hPMS2-134 TK-ts13 cells have been previously shown to be capable of altering genes <i>in vivo</i> (refer to Table 2 and <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>), the ability to generate "naturally microbial-resistant" clones has not been reported in the literature. To generate microbial-resistant TK cells, TK-ts13 cells constitutively expressing the a dominant-negative mismatch repair gene, TK-hPMS2-134 or the empty vector (TKvect) that have been in culture for &gt;3 months (∼60 passages) were seeded at 5x10<sup>5</sup> cells/ml in Dulbelcco's Modified Eagles Medium (DMEM) plus 10% fetal bovine serum (FBS) and plated into 10 cm dishes (Falcon) in duplicate. These cells were grown overnight at 37°C in 5%CO<sub>2</sub> to allow cells to adhere to the plastic. The next day, TK cultures were inoculated with 10 µl of an exponentially growing culture of <i>Escherichia coli.</i> Cultures were then grown at 37°C in 5%CO<sub>2</sub> and observed on day 7 and 14 for microbial-resistant cell clones; these cells appear as clones of cells surrounded by "cleared" areas on the plate. At day 7, all cells in the control transfected TKvect culture were dead, while a subset of cells were viable in the<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --> TK-hPMS2-134 transfected cultures. At day 14, there were no clones in the control transfected TKvect cultures, while there were 34 and 40 <i>Escherichia coli</i>-resistant colonies formed in the TK-hPMS2-134 transfected cultures. Growing clones from each dish were then pooled as individual cultures and grown to confluence. These cultures were named TK-hPMS2-134 (R1) and TK-hPMS2-134 (R2). Cultures were cured of <i>Escherichia coli</i> by the addition of 1 mg/ml G418, in which the TK-hPMS2-134 cells are resistant due to expression of the neomycin-resistance gene contained on the mammalian expression vector used to generate the cells.</p><p id="p0061" num="0061">TKvect, TK-hPMS2-134 (R1) and TK-hPMS2-134 (R2) cells were plated at 5x10<sup>5</sup> cell/ml in 10 mls and plated into 10 cm dishes in duplicate. The next day, 10 µl of a logarithmic stage <i>Escherichia coli</i> culture was added to each TK culture and cultures were grown for 48 hours at 37°C in 5%CO<sub>2</sub>. An aliquot of supernatant from each culture was harvested immediately after inoculation to establish a baseline density of bacteria for each culture. After 48 hours, 2 ml of supernatant were harvested from each culture as well as from uninfected TK cultures. One ml of each supernatant was then analyzed by a spectrophotometer at an OD<sub>600</sub> to measure for bacterial density. Supernatants from uninfected cultures were used as a blank to correct for background. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">Figure 6</figref>, bacterial growth was significantly suppressed in TK-hPMS2-134 (R1) and TK-hPMS2-134 (R2) cultures in contrast to TKvect control cells. These data demonstrate the feasibility of using a dominant-negative mismatch repair mutant hPMS2-134 on mammalian cells to produce genetically altered clones capable of producing a molecule(s) that can suppress microbial growth.</p><p id="p0062" num="0062">As those skilled in the art will appreciate, numerous changes and modifications may be made to the preferred embodiments of the invention,<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --></p><heading id="h0011">SEQUENCE LISTING</heading><p id="p0063" num="0063"><ul><li>&lt;110&gt; Nicolaides, Nicholas C<br/>
Grasso, Luigi<br/>
Sass, Philip M</li><li>&lt;120&gt; METHODS FOR ISOLATING NOVEL ANTIMICROBIAL AGENTS FROM<br/>
HYPERMUTABLE CELLS</li><li>&lt;130&gt; MOR0006</li><li>&lt;140&gt; 00/000,000<br/>
&lt;141&gt; 2000-11-07</li><li>&lt;160&gt; 16</li><li>&lt;170&gt; PatentIn Ver. 2.1</li><li>&lt;210&gt; 1<br/>
&lt;211&gt; 52<br/>
&lt;212&gt; DNA<br/>
&lt;213&gt; Artificial Sequence</li><li>&lt;220&gt;<br/>
&lt;223&gt; Description of Artificial Sequence:oligonucleotide primer</li><li>&lt;400&gt; 1<br/>
ggatcctaat acgactcact atagggagac caccatgtcg ttcgtggcag gg    52</li><li>&lt;210&gt; 2<br/>
&lt;211&gt; 21<br/>
&lt;212&gt; DNA<br/>
&lt;213&gt; Artificial Sequence</li><li>&lt;220&gt;<br/>
&lt;223&gt; Description of Artificial Sequence:oligonucleotide primer</li><li>&lt;400&gt; 2<br/>
taagtcttaa gtgctaccaa c    21</li><li>&lt;210&gt; 3<br/>
&lt;211&gt; 53<br/>
&lt;212&gt; DNA<br/>
&lt;213&gt; Artificial Sequence<!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --></li><li>&lt;220&gt;<br/>
&lt;223&gt; Description of Artificial Sequence:oligonucleotide primer</li><li>&lt;400&gt; 3<br/>
ggatcctaat acgactcact atagggagac caccatggaa caattgcctg cgg    53</li><li>&lt;210&gt; 4<br/>
&lt;211&gt; 20<br/>
&lt;212&gt; DNA<br/>
&lt;213&gt; Artificial Sequence</li><li>&lt;220&gt;<br/>
&lt;223&gt; Description of Artificial Sequence:oligonucleotide primer</li><li>&lt;400&gt; 4<br/>
aggttagtga agactctgtc    20</li><li>&lt;210&gt; 5<br/>
&lt;211&gt; 19<br/>
&lt;212&gt; DNA<br/>
&lt;213&gt; Artificial Sequence</li><li>&lt;220&gt;<br/>
&lt;223&gt; Description of Artificial Sequence:primer</li><li>&lt;400&gt; 5<br/>
agtcgagttc caaccttcg    19</li><li>&lt;210&gt; 6<br/>
&lt;211&gt; 54<br/>
&lt;212&gt; DNA<br/>
&lt;213&gt; Artificial Sequence</li><li>&lt;220&gt;<br/>
&lt;223&gt; Description of Artificial Sequence:primer</li><li>&lt;400&gt; 6<br/>
ggatcctaat acgactcact atagggagac caccatgatg tttgatcaca atgg    54</li><li>&lt;210&gt; 7<br/>
&lt;211&gt; 859<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="32"> -->&lt;212&gt; PRT<br/>
&lt;213&gt; Mus musculus</li><li>&lt;400&gt; 7
<img id="ib0016" file="imgb0016.tif" wi="138" he="211" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="33"> -->
<img id="ib0017" file="imgb0017.tif" wi="139" he="225" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="34"> -->
<img id="ib0018" file="imgb0018.tif" wi="138" he="225" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="35"> -->
<img id="ib0019" file="imgb0019.tif" wi="138" he="95" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></li><li>&lt;210&gt; 8<br/>
&lt;211&gt; 3056<br/>
&lt;212&gt; DNA<br/>
&lt;213&gt; Mus musculus</li><li>&lt;400&gt; 8
<img id="ib0020" file="imgb0020.tif" wi="153" he="91" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="36"> -->
<img id="ib0021" file="imgb0021.tif" wi="153" he="153" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></li><li>&lt;210&gt; 9<br/>
&lt;211&gt; 862<br/>
&lt;212&gt; PRT<br/>
&lt;213&gt; Homo sapiens</li><li>&lt;400&gt; 9
<img id="ib0022" file="imgb0022.tif" wi="138" he="38" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="37"> -->
<img id="ib0023" file="imgb0023.tif" wi="139" he="225" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="38"> -->
<img id="ib0024" file="imgb0024.tif" wi="138" he="225" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="39"> -->
<img id="ib0025" file="imgb0025.tif" wi="139" he="225" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="40"> -->
<img id="ib0026" file="imgb0026.tif" wi="138" he="38" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></li><li>&lt;210&gt; 10<br/>
&lt;211&gt; 2771<br/>
&lt;212&gt; DNA<br/>
&lt;213&gt; Homo sapiens</li><li>&lt;400&gt; 10
<img id="ib0027" file="imgb0027.tif" wi="153" he="149" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="41"> -->
<img id="ib0028" file="imgb0028.tif" wi="153" he="76" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></li><li>&lt;210&gt; 11<br/>
&lt;211&gt; 932<br/>
&lt;212&gt; PRT<br/>
&lt;213&gt; Homo sapiens</li><li>&lt;400&gt; 11
<img id="ib0029" file="imgb0029.tif" wi="139" he="109" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="42"> -->
<img id="ib0030" file="imgb0030.tif" wi="139" he="225" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="43"> -->
<img id="ib0031" file="imgb0031.tif" wi="139" he="225" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="44"> -->
<img id="ib0032" file="imgb0032.tif" wi="138" he="225" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="45"> -->
<img id="ib0033" file="imgb0033.tif" wi="153" he="38" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></li><li>&lt;210&gt; 12<br/>
&lt;211&gt; 3063<br/>
&lt;212&gt; DNA<br/>
&lt;213&gt; Homo sapiens</li><li>&lt;400&gt; 12
<img id="ib0034" file="imgb0034.tif" wi="154" he="153" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="46"> -->
<img id="ib0035" file="imgb0035.tif" wi="153" he="95" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></li><li>&lt;210&gt; 13<br/>
&lt;211&gt; 934<br/>
&lt;212&gt; PRT<br/>
&lt;213&gt; Homo sapiens</li><li>&lt;400&gt; 13
<img id="ib0036" file="imgb0036.tif" wi="138" he="95" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="47"> -->
<img id="ib0037" file="imgb0037.tif" wi="138" he="225" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="48"> -->
<img id="ib0038" file="imgb0038.tif" wi="138" he="225" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="49"> -->
<img id="ib0039" file="imgb0039.tif" wi="138" he="225" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="50"> -->
<img id="ib0040" file="imgb0040.tif" wi="138" he="52" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></li><li>&lt;210&gt; 14<br/>
&lt;211&gt; 3145<br/>
&lt;212&gt; DNA<br/>
&lt;213&gt; Homo sapiens</li><li>&lt;400&gt; 14
<img id="ib0041" file="imgb0041.tif" wi="153" he="134" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="51"> -->
<img id="ib0042" file="imgb0042.tif" wi="153" he="121" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></li><li>&lt;210&gt; 15<br/>
&lt;211&gt; 756<br/>
&lt;212&gt; PRT<br/>
&lt;213&gt; Homo sapiens</li><li>&lt;400&gt; 15
<img id="ib0043" file="imgb0043.tif" wi="138" he="66" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="52"> -->
<img id="ib0044" file="imgb0044.tif" wi="139" he="225" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="53"> -->
<img id="ib0045" file="imgb0045.tif" wi="138" he="225" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="54"> -->
<img id="ib0046" file="imgb0046.tif" wi="141" he="154" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></li><li>&lt;210&gt; 16<br/>
&lt;211&gt; 2484<br/>
&lt;212&gt; DNA<br/>
&lt;213&gt; Homo sapiens</li><li>&lt;400&gt; 16
<img id="ib0047" file="imgb0047.tif" wi="151" he="38" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></li></ul></p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56987642" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="58"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Verfahren zur Gewinnung einer Säugerzelle, die gegenüber einer ausgewählten Mikrobe resistent ist, das Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>Wachsen einer Kultur von Säugerzellen, worin die genannten Zellen hPMS2-134 umfassen;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Exponieren der genannten Zellen gegenüber der genannten ausgewählten Mikrobe; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Auswählen der genannten Säugerzelle, die gegenüber der genannten ausgewählten Mikrobe resistent ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, worin der genannte Schritt des Auswählens nach mikrobieller Resistenz das Isolieren und Testen des Kulturmediums aus der genannten Zelle umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Verfahren zur Gewinnung einer Zelle, die eine Mutation in einem Gen umfasst, das mikrobielle Resistenz kodiert, das Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>Wachsen einer Kultur von Säugerzellen, die das genannte Gen, das die genannte mikrobielle Resistenz kodiert, und hPMS2-134 umfassen;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Auswählen einer Zelle, die die genannte mikrobielle Resistenz aufweist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Bestimmen, ob das genannte Gen eine Mutation umfasst.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1 oder 3, worin die genannte Zelle nach Resistenz gegenüber einem Bakterium ausgewählt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1 oder 3, worin die genannte Zelle nach Resistenz gegenüber einem Pilz ausgewählt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 3, worin der genannte Schritt des Auswählens einer Zelle, die die genannte mikrobielle Resistenz aufweist, das Isolieren und Testen des Kulturmediums aus der genannten Zelle umfasst.<!-- EPO <DP n="59"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 3, worin der genannte Schritt des Bestimmens, ob das genannte Gen eine Mutation umfasst, das Analysieren einer Nukleotidsequenz des genannten Gens umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 3, worin der genannte Schritt des Bestimmens, ob das genannte Gen eine Mutation umfasst, das Analysieren von mRNA, die von dem genannten Gen transkribiert wird, umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 3, worin der genannte Schritt des Bestimmens, ob das genannte Gen eine Mutation umfasst, das Analysieren eines Proteins, das von dem genannten Gen kodiert wird, umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 3, worin der genannte Schritt des Bestimmens, ob das genannte Gen eine Mutation umfasst, das Analysieren eines phänotypischen Merkmals, das von dem genannten Gen bestimmt wird, umfasst.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56987643" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="55"> --><!-- EPO <DP n="56"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A method for obtaining a mammalian cell that is resistant to a selected microbe, comprising:
<claim-text>growing a culture of mammalian cells wherein said cells comprise hPMS2-134;</claim-text>
<claim-text>exposing said cells to said selected microbe; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>selecting said mammalian cell that is resistant to said selected microbe.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>A method according to claim 1, wherein said step of selecting for microbial resistance comprises isolating and testing culture medium from said cell.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>A method for obtaining a cell that comprises a mutation in a gene encoding microbial resistance, comprising:
<claim-text>growing a culture of mammalian cells comprising said gene encoding said microbial resistance and hPMS2-134;</claim-text>
<claim-text>selecting a cell having said microbial resistance; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining whether said gene comprises a mutation.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>A method according to claim 1 or 3, wherein said cell is selected for resistance to a bacterium.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>A method according to claim 1 or 3, wherein said cell is selected for resistance to a fungus.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>A method according to claim 3, wherein said step of selecting a cell having said microbial resistance comprises isolating and testing culture medium from said cell.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>A method according to claim 3, wherein said step of determining whether said gene comprises a mutation comprises analyzing a nucleotide sequence of said gene.<!-- EPO <DP n="57"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>A method according to claim 3, wherein said step of determining whether said gene comprises a mutation comprises analyzing mRNA transcribed from said gene.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>A method according to claim 3, wherein said step of determining whether said gene comprises a mutation comprises analyzing a protein encoded by said gene.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>A method according to claim 3, wherein said step of determining whether said gene comprises a mutation comprises analyzing a phenotypic trait determined by said gene.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56987644" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="60"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Méthode d'obtention d'une cellule mammalienne qui est résistante à un microbe sélectionné, comprenant :
<claim-text>le développement d'une culture de cellules mammaliennes, où lesdites cellules comprennent hPMS2-134 ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'exposition desdites cellules audit microbe sélectionné ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>la sélection de ladite cellule mammalienne qui est résistante audit microbe sélectionné.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Méthode selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle ladite étape de sélection pour une résistance microbienne comprend l'isolement et l'analyse du milieu de culture à partir de ladite cellule.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Méthode d'obtention d'une cellule qui comprend une mutation dans un gène codant pour une résistance microbienne, comprenant :
<claim-text>le développement d'une culture de cellules mammaliennes comprenant ledit gène codant pour ladite résistance microbienne et hPMS2-134 ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>la sélection d'une cellule ayant ladite résistance microbienne ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>la détermination du fait que ledit gène comprend ou non une mutation.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Méthode selon la revendication 1 ou 3, dans laquelle ladite cellule est sélectionnée pour une résistance vis-à-vis d'une bactérie.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Méthode selon la revendication 1 ou 3, dans laquelle ladite cellule est sélectionnée pour une résistance vis-à-vis d'un champignon.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Méthode selon la revendication 3, dans laquelle ladite étape de sélection d'une cellule ayant ladite résistance microbienne comprend l'isolement et l'analyse du milieu de culture à partir de ladite cellule.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Méthode selon la revendication 3, dans laquelle ladite étape de détermination du fait que ledit gène comprend ou non une mutation, comprend l'analyse d'une séquence nucléotidique dudit gène.<!-- EPO <DP n="61"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Méthode selon la revendication 3, dans laquelle ladite étape de détermination du fait que ledit gène comprend ou non une mutation, comprend l'analyse d'ARNm transcrit à partir dudit gène.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Méthode selon la revendication 3, dans laquelle ladite étape de détermination du fait que ledit gène comprend ou non une mutation, comprend l'analyse d'une protéine codée par ledit gène.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Méthode selon la revendication 3, dans laquelle ladite étape de détermination du fait que ledit gène comprend ou non une mutation, comprend l'analyse d'un caractère phénotypique déterminé par ledit gène.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16672808" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="62"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="137" he="198" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="63"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="149" he="190" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="64"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3A,3B,3C"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="165" he="110" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="65"> --><figure id="f0004" num="4"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="134" he="138" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="66"> --><figure id="f0005" num="5A,5B"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="165" he="96" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="67"> --><figure id="f0006" num="6"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="131" he="108" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
