<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2287087-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2287087" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="29734490" file-reference-id="315726" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146588675" ucid="EP-2287087-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2287087</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-10075430-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154850867" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>10075430</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20030620</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP173221574" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>10075430.8</doc-number><date>20030620</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140548923" ucid="EP-03761151-A" linkage-type="3" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>03761151</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20030620</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140551550" ucid="US-17778602-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>17778602</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20020620</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130807</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989326324" load-source="docdb">B65D  83/04        20060101AFI20120910BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989621614" load-source="docdb">G01F  11/18        20060101A I20051008RMEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989643936" load-source="docdb">A61J   1/00        20060101ALI20060310RMJP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2056049060" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G01F  11/18        20130101 LI20150509BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2056057191" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B65D2583/0481      20130101 LA20150509BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2056060161" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B65D  83/0409      20130101 FI20150509BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2059353605" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y02W  30/807       20150501 LA20150507BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370658" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Spender für Festobjekte</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370659" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Dispenser for solid objects</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370660" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Distributeur d'objets solides</invention-title></technical-data><related-documents><relation type="division"><child-doc ucid="EP-10075430-A"><document-id load-source="patent-office" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>10075430</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20030620</date></document-id></child-doc><parent-doc ucid="EP-03761151.4"><document-id load-source="patent-office" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>03761151.4</doc-number><date>20030620</date></document-id></parent-doc></relation></related-documents><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919509488" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>CSP TECHNOLOGIES INC</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919516018" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>CSP TECHNOLOGIES, INC.</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919545856" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>GIRAUD JEAN-PIERRE</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919504337" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>GIRAUD, JEAN-PIERRE</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919024214" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>GIRAUD, JEAN-PIERRE</last-name><address><street>3576 Ridgeview Court Auburn</street><city>Alabama 36830</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919024215" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>CSP Technologies, Inc.</last-name><iid>100105397</iid><address><street>1030 Riverfront Center P.O. Box 710</street><city>Amsterdam New York 12010</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919024216" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Potter Clarkson LLP</last-name><iid>101340609</iid><address><street>The Belgrave Centre Talbot Street</street><city>Nottingham NG1 5GG</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549787791" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549872677" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549895389" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549804846" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549879150" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549879151" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549882847" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549872682" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549872683" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549925049" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549895390" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549895391" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549882848" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549872684" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549879152" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549804847" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549895392" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549872685" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549787792" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549882849" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549787797" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549925050" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549789176" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549787798" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549882854" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549804852" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549872690" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63961094" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001"><b><u>FIELD OF THE INVENTION</u></b></heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention is directed to dispensers for solid objects. In one embodiment, the dispenser can be used as a dispenser for pieces of candy. In another embodiment, the dispenser can be used to dispense tablets that, for example, deliver therapeutic substances. The dispenser is moisture tight for a desired period (e.g. dispenser's use life, solid objects shelf-stability life).</p><heading id="h0002"><b><u>BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</u></b></heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">Tablet dispensers are typically employed in the nutritional and candy industries in order to retain and dispense tablets. These dispensers may be designed for specific tablets, such as the Pez dispenser for Pez candy. Because conventional tablet dispensers are not moisture-tight during use life, they are not typically used in the industries such as the pharmaceutical industry for moisture sensitive products. Instead, moisture tight tablet packaging has typically been provided by "blister" packs. For "blister packs", the tablet is pushed through a frangible barrier material in order to separate it from the packaging.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="DE8412693U"><text>DE-U-8412693</text></patcit> discloses a tablet dispenser comprising a reservoir for the tablets and having an outlet that is sealed when not in operation.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004"><patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="WO8300319A"><text>WO 83/00319</text></patcit> relates to a tablet dispenser for dispensing a solid tablet or a predetermined number of tablets of a substantially uniform size from a storage area containing a relatively large number of tablets into a dispensing orifice upon operation of an external actuating mechanism.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005"><patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="AT348406B"><text>AT-B-348406</text></patcit> discloses a device in the form of a pen for dispensing tablets or powdered materials.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006"><patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="DE1213567B"><text>DE-B-1213567</text></patcit> describes a container with a dispensing device for the metered delivery of solid material, in particular pills or the like, consisting of an axial dispensing aperture having an elongated sleeve.</p><heading id="h0003"><b><u>SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</u></b></heading><p id="p0007" num="0007">The present invention is directed to a moisture tight dispenser as defined in the appended claim 1. In one example, the design is suited for pharmaceutical applications, particularly where moisture-sensitivity of the tablet is a consideration.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">The present invention is directed to dispensers for dispensing tablets. The dispenser maintains a moisture tight seal both during shelf life and during use life. The dispenser provides a reservoir for holding a number of tablets, such as, for example, 50 to 100 tablets. The dispenser may be provided with a housing that is constructed in part of plastic material of a substantially water impermeable material, such as polypropylene ("PP") or polyethylene ("PE"), while other parts of the housing are constructed of an elastomeric material of a substantially water impermeable material such as an ethylene propylene diene terpolymers (EPDM).<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --><!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p><p id="p0009" num="0009">For purposes of the present invention, a dispenser of the present invention is "moisture tight" in accordance with the test protocols set forth in USP 671. In one embodiment, the dispenser is considered "moisture tight" where not more than one of the 10 test dispenser exceeds 100 mg per day, per liter, in moisture permeability. Testing for USP 671 is conducted on sealed containers and on containers that have been opened and then resealed. The testing consists of a desiccant of set quantity 4-8 mesh, anhydrous calcium chloride being first dried at 110°C for one hour then cooled in a desiccator. Then 12 containers of uniform size are selected and opened and closed 30 times each. Torque is applied to the closures as specified in the USP monograph. Desiccant is then added to 10 of the packages labeled test containers. These are then filled to within 13mm of the opening on containers larger than 20ml and to two-thirds full on containers smaller than 20ml. The closures are then applied to the torque specified in the monograph. Weight is recorded to the nearest 0.1mg for containers smaller than 20ml, to the nearest mg for 20ml to 200ml, or to the nearest centigram if the container is larger than 200ml. The containers are stored at 75 percent, plus or minus three percent, relative humidity at a temperature of 23°C, plus or minus two degrees. After 36 hours, plus or minus one hour, the weight is recorded, with the moisture permeability calculated in mg per day, per liter.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">Elastomeric materials of the present invention should be sufficiently deformable to allow them to be sufficiently deformed when a force is applied to them so that the solid object can pass through the desired exit location. The elastomeric material is used to construct the lip seal. The lip seal remains moisture tight when the seal is closed, and is opened only for the time needed to pass a tablet through the opening. The elastomeric material is also used to encase the trigger mechanism that is used to eject the tablets.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p><p id="p0011" num="0011">The dispenser may be sized so that the housing interiors are sized only as thick as one tablet. The dispenser may maintain a moisture-tight seal within the tablet reservoir throughout the dispenser use life. A desiccant, such as a desiccant entrained plastic may be used in at least a portion.</p><heading id="h0004"><b><u>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</u></b></heading><p id="p0012" num="0012"><ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> is a cross sectional view of an embodiment of a dispenser of the invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 2</figref> is a cross sectional view, as shown from the dispensing side of the dispenser shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 3</figref> is a is a cross sectional view, as shown from the pusher side of the dispenser shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 4</figref> is a first perspective view of the dispenser embodiment;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 5</figref> is a first perspective view of the dispenser embodiment;<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 6</figref> is a perspective view of another embodiment not according to the present invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 7</figref> is a side elevational view of an aspect of the embodiment shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 6</figref>;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 8</figref> is an exploded view of the embodiment shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 6</figref>;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 9</figref> is a bottom plan view of the embodiment shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 6</figref>; and</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 10</figref> is a cross sectional view of another embodiment not acording to the present invention.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0005"><b><u>DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</u></b></heading><p id="p0013" num="0013"><figref idrefs="f0001 f0002">Figures 1-5</figref> illustrate an embodiment of a dispenser produced in accordance with the invention. <figref idrefs="f0002">Figures 4 and 5</figref> show perspective views of the components that house the tablets and dispenser mechanism. Generally, dispenser 10 is provided with a lower housing 12, upper housing 14, a cover 16, a seal 18 that joins the lower and upper housings, and a cover 20 of an elastomer that covers the portions of the lower housing<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> where the dispensing mechanism is located. A lip seal 22 is provided in the elastomer through which a tablet is dispensed.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">For purpose of the present invention, a "lip seal" is formed by two lip sides that converge at the thin, slit like opening. In one example, the "lip seal" is formed by molding the two lip sides that converge at a thin slit-like opening. In another example, the "lip seal" is formed by molding a membrane and then cutting a slit in the membrane. The lip seal is designed so that it is opened for a sufficient time needed to pass an item through it as a sufficient ejecting force is applied to the item.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">In one embodiment, the housing components of the dispenser may be provided with long sides that have a slight curvature and endwalls 31, 31' joined to the sidewalls by corners which are squared or rounded. The housing components are hollow in their interior and house the tablets and the dispensing mechanism. In another embodiment, the interior width dimension of the housing components may be only slightly greater than the width of a singular tablet that would be housed in the dispenser. This arrangement of a tablet reservoir provides for the housing and storage of the tablets in a single-thickness arrangement.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">The housing components are formed of an injection molded plastic (e.g. clarified polypropylene or polyethylene). If a clarified plastic is used, the tablets contained in the dispenser are visible from outside the housing. In one embodiment, the outer surface of the upper housing may be made of a sufficiently water impermeable plastic (e.g. PP or PE) and at least a portion of the inner surface may be overmolded with a desiccant plastic, such as the desiccant plastic formulations disclosed in <patcit id="pcit0005" dnum="US5911937A"><text>U.S. patent Nos. 5,911,937</text></patcit>, <patcit id="pcit0006" dnum="US6130263A"><text>6,130,263</text></patcit>,<patcit id="pcit0007" dnum="US6080350A"><text> 6,080,350</text></patcit>, <patcit id="pcit0008" dnum="US6174952B"><text>6,174,952</text></patcit>, and <patcit id="pcit0009" dnum="US6486231B"><text>6,486,231</text></patcit>.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017"><figref idrefs="f0001">Figures 1-3</figref> illustrate one embodiment of the internal components of the dispenser. Cover 16 is joined to the upper housing via seal 24. Seal 24 is provided with a downwardly extending tab 26 that terminates in a horizontally extending portion that locks into undercut 28 on the upper housing 14. Seal 24 can be any conventional sealing mechanism such as compression or interference fit. Alternatively, an elastomeric<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> material can be overmolded over the region to be sealed in accordance with the principles discussed elsewhere in this disclosure.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">In a further embodiment, the upper housing 14 is provided with ribs 30 that line the interior of the upper housing, which extend into the interior thereof. The ribs 30 help maintain the tablets in single-tablet thickness.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">In the embodiment, the lower housing 12 is joined to the upper housing 14 via seal 18, formed of LDPE or other suitable material. The seal 18 can be any type of seal that results in a moisture tight sealing arrangements for container and cap assemblies. Alternatively, an elastomeric material can be overmolded over the region to be sealed in accordance with the principles discussed elsewhere in this disclosure.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">In the embodiment, the interior of the lower housing 14 is provided with guidepiece 32 that directs the tablet toward the dispensing zone 34. For example, guidepiece 32 gradually reduces the area in which a tablet can reside as the tablet moves downward through the housing and approaches the dispensing zone 34. In one specific embodiment, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>, the guidepiece has four regions: a first region 32a in which the guidepiece extends horizontally from an endwall 31 to a location in the lower housing, a second region 32b in which the guidepiece extends vertically above the dispensing zone for a preselected distance, and a sloped region 32c wherein the guidepiece slopes downward as it traverses the horizontal direction from the second region 32b to just above the dispensing zone 34. The guidepiece terminates in a fourth region 32d which extends vertically and may contact the upper surface of the tablet ejector 36. A second guidepiece 33 is provided. Guidepiece 33 extends from endwall 31' in three regions 33a, 33b, and 33c.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">Due to the configuration of the guidepiece as just described, and the assistance of gravity, the tablets follow a path as they descend through a region having a gradually decreasing area, to a point where a tablet T2 is positioned just above the dispensing zone.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">In the embodiment 2 tablet T1 in the dispensing zone is at rest on platform 35, placing it between ejector 36 and lip seal 22. The tablet ejector 36 is positioned below the guidepiece 32. The tablet ejector has a length dimension that extends from the endwall 31 where the ejector 36 is activated to the dispensing zone 34. A spring 40 is formed unitary with the ejector 36, and extends vertically away from the<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> ejector, from a location near the endwall 31 to a location where the spring contacts the second region 32b of the guidepiece 32. Also, a trigger guide 42 that rises from the bottom wall 38 of the lower housing 12 is provided. The trigger guide may be provided with a slot that resides between two prongs 42a (not shown), or, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 3</figref>, the ejector may be provided with a forked bottom that receives the blade of the trigger guide. In any event, the trigger guide maintains the ejector in a straight path as it travels from the rest position to the eject position.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">In the embodiment, the lower housing 12 is formed of two regions: a substantially moisture impermeable plastic region and an elastomeric region 20, such as EPDM, (e.g. commercially available under the trade name Santoprene). For example, the lower housing may be over-molded either in a two-shot injection molding machine or made in two injection molding processes (that is, injection mold the plastic in mold 1, then over-mold the elastomeric material in mold 2). In the embodiment shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Figures 4 and 5</figref>, the elastomeric region 20 covers the sidewalls at the end where the ejector is activated, and at the opposite end where the slit 22 is located. The elastomeric material is sufficiently deformable so that the user.can impart a sufficient force to the ejector so as to activate it and thus, the tablet can then be moved through the slit and be ejected.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">For operating the dispenser of the present invention, a user presses on the endwall 31 of the lower housing 12 where the ejector is located. A force is transmitted through the elastomer 20, and the ejector 36 is moved into the dispensing zone 34, where it contacts a tablet and forces it out of the slit 22 in the elastomeric material 20 on the opposite endwall 31'. At this time, the ejector is in the extended position and prevents any other tablet from entering the dispensing zone. As the ejector is moved into the dispensing zone 34, the spring 40, which is unitary with the ejector, goes into compression and stores energy. Once the user ceases to apply a dispensing force, the spring 40 pushes against the second portion 32b of the guidepiece 32, releasing its energy and returning the spring to the original position. When the ejector is retracted, a tablet drops into the dispensing zone for the next dispense cycle.<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --></p><p id="p0025" num="0025">In yet another embodiment, the ejector may be provided with 2 vertically extending positive stop 41 that can provide an impediment to further travel of the ejector when it comes into contact with stop 32e that extends from the guidepiece 32.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">In another embodiment not according to the invention, shown in <figref idrefs="f0003 f0004">Figures 6-9</figref>, a housing 12' has a major portion 14' and a sidewall 16', which assembles to the major portion in the same manner in which the cover 16 assembles to the upper housing 14, as discussed in relation to <figref idrefs="f0001 f0002">Figures 1-5</figref>.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">In yet another embodiment not according to the present invention, the interior of the dispenser of this embodiment is the same as the interior for <figref idrefs="f0001 f0002">Figures 1-5</figref>. A region of deformable, moisture tight material (e.g. elastomer) covers the portion of the ejector where the ejector is actuated. The ejector button 37' is provided with a bulbous shape.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">As shown in the embodiment of <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 7</figref>, the sidewall 16' has a wall portion 17' provided with horizontally extending end portions 19' that extend along the inner walls of the major portion 14' of the housing 12', when the sidewall 16' is assembled in the housing 12'. The ends of the horizontally extending portions 19' are covered with elastomer 21' to provide a seal with the inner walls of the major portion 14'. The wall portion 17' is provided with the lip seal 22' through which the tablet is dispensed. The wall portion 17' is joined to the horizontally extending portions 19' at 2 point along the horizontally extending portions 19' that is between the ends of said portions. Thus, when the sidewall 16' is assembled to the major portion 14', the wall portion is recessed, residing within the volume defined by the major portion. Further, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 8</figref>, the recessed portion is provided-with tapered walls 27' that reduce the area of the recess into which the tablet is dispensed.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029"><figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 10</figref> shows another embodiment not according to the present invention for an ejector assembly that can be substituted for the ejector assembly shown in the embodiments of <figref idrefs="f0001 f0002">Figures 1-5</figref>. Here, ejector 36' is maintained in a compartment that may not be moisture tight, that is defined in part by the guidepiece. A vertically extending guidepiece portion 32b' having a deformable membrane 35 is positioned between the ejector 36' and the dispensing zone<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> 34". The elastomeric membrane is deformable when the ejector is actuated and contacts the tablet and pushes the tablet out of the dispenser.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56986022" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Feuchtigkeitsdichter Spender (10) zum Spenden von Tafeln (T1, T2), gebildet aus:
<claim-text>einem Gehäuse (12, 14, 16, 18), das mit Wänden versehen ist, die einen hohlen Innenabschnitt definieren; wobei ein Führungsstück (32) innerhalb eines unteren Abschnitts des Gehäuses und über einer Spendezone (34) angeordnet ist; wobei das Führungsstück (32) den Bereich verringert, in dem sich die Tafeln befinden können, wenn sie sich der Spendezone (34) nähern;</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Tafelauswurf (36), der unter dem Führungsstück (32) angeordnet ist, wobei der Auswurf (36) ferner mit einer Vorspannfeder (40) versehen ist, die vom Auswurf (36) weg verläuft und eine Fläche berührt, um eine Kraft vorzusehen, die der Kraft entgegengesetzt ist, welche zum Betätigen des Auswurfs (36) ausgeübt ist; <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die Spendezone (34) einer Lippendichtung (22) benachbart angeordnet ist, durch die die Tafel gespendet wird; der Tafelauswurf (36) eine Längenabmessung aufweist, die von einer ersten Stelle an einer Wand (31), wo der Auswurf (36) betätigt wird, zu einer zweiten, der Spendezone (34) benachbarten Stelle verläuft; und ein Elastomermaterial (20) die Abschnitte des Gehäuses abdeckt, wo sich der Tafelauswurf (36) befindet, und die Lippendichtung (22) in dem Elastomermaterial (20) vorgesehen ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Spender nach Anspruch 1, wobei das Gehäuse ein unteres Gehäuse (12), ein oberes Gehäuse (14), eine Abdeckung (16) und eine erste Dichtung (18) umfasst, die das untere (12) und obere (14) Gehäuse verbindet, wobei die Abdeckung (16) mit dem oberen Gehäuse (14) mit einer zweiten Dichtung (24) verbunden ist, die mit einer nach unten verlaufenden Zunge (26) versehen ist, welche in einem horizontal verlaufenden Abschnitt endet, der sich in einem Unterschnitt (28) am oberen Gehäuse (14) verriegelt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Spender nach Anspruch 1, wobei das Führungsstück (32) verbundene erste, zweite, dritte und vierte Bereiche (32a, 32b, 32c, 32d) aufweist,<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> wobei der erste Bereich (32a) des Führungsstücks (32) horizontal von der Wand (31) zu einer Stelle im unteren Gehäuse (12) verläuft, der zweite Bereich (32b) des Führungsstücks (32) vertikal über der Spendezone (34) über einen vorausgewählten Abstand hinweg verläuft, und der dritte Bereich (32c) des Führungsstücks (32) schräg abfällt, wenn er die horizontale Richtung vom zweiten Bereich (32b) zu einem Punkt über der Spendezone (34) durchquert, und der vierte Bereich (32d) vertikal zu einem Punkt über dem Tafelauswurf (36) verläuft.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Spender nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Spendezone (34) ferner aus einer Plattform (35) gebildet ist, auf der eine Tafel in der Spendezone (34) ruhen kann, wobei die Höhe der Plattform (35) zum Anordnen einer Tafel in der Spendezone (34) auf derselben Höhe wie der Auswurf (36) und die Lippendichtung (22) ausgewählt ist.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56986023" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A moisture tight dispenser (10) for dispensing tablets (T<sub>1</sub>,T<sub>2</sub>) comprised of:
<claim-text>a housing (12,14,16,18) provided with walls defining an interior hollow portion; a guidepiece (32) positioned within a lower portion of the interior of the housing and above a dispensing zone (34); the guidepiece (32) decreasing the area in which tablets can reside as they approach the dispensing zone (34);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a tablet ejector (36) positioned below the guidepiece (32), the ejector (36) further provided with a biasing spring (40) that extends away from the ejector (36) and contacts a surface to provide a force in opposition to the force applied to activate the ejector (36); <b>characterised in that</b> the dispensing zone (34) is positioned adjacent a lip seal (22) through which the tablet is dispensed; the tablet ejector (36) has a length dimension that extends from a first location on a wall (31) where the ejector (36) is activated to a second location adjacent the dispensing zone (34); and an elastomeric material (20) covers the portions of the housing where the tablet ejector (36) is located, and the lip seal (22) is provided in the elastomeric material (20).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The dispenser of Claim 1 wherein the housing comprises a lower housing (12), an upper housing (14), a cover (16), and a first seal (18) that joins the lower (12) and upper (14) housings wherein the cover (16) is joined to the upper housing (14) with a second seal (24) provided with a downwardly extending tab (26) that terminates in a horizontally extending portion that locks into an undercut (28) on the upper housing (14).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The dispenser of Claim 1 wherein the guidepiece (32) has connected first, second, third and fourth regions (32a, 32b, 32c, 32d), wherein the first region (32a) of the guidepiece (32) extends horizontally from the wall (31) to a location in the lower portion of the housing (12), the second region (32b) of the guidepiece (32) extends vertically above the dispensing zone (34) for a preselected distance, and the third region (32c) of the guidepiece (32) slopes downward as it traverses the horizontal direction from the second region (32b) to a point above the dispensing zone (34), and the fourth region (32d) extends vertically to a point above the tablet ejector (36).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The dispenser of Claim 1 wherein the dispensing zone (34) is further comprised of a platform (35) on which a tablet in the dispensing zone (34) can rest, the height of the platform (35) selected to place a tablet in the dispensing zone (34) at the same height as the ejector (36) and the lip seal (22).</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56986024" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Distributeur étanche à l'humidité (10) pour la distribution de comprimés (T1, T2) composé :
<claim-text>d'un logement (12, 14, 16, 18) pourvu de parois définissant une portion creuse intérieure ; d'une pièce de guidage (32) positionnée à l'intérieur d'une portion inférieure de l'intérieur du logement et au-dessus d'une zone de distribution (34) ; la pièce de guidage (32) diminuant la zone dans laquelle les comprimés peuvent se trouver lorsqu'ils s'approchent de la zone de distribution (34) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>d'un éjecteur de comprimés (36) positionné sous la pièce de guidage (32), l'éjecteur (36) étant en outre pourvu d'un ressort de sollicitation (40) qui s'étend en éloignement de l'éjecteur (36) et entre en contact avec une surface afin de fournir une force en opposition à la force appliquée pour activer l'éjecteur (36) ; <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> la zone de distribution (34) est positionnée adjacente à un joint à lèvre (22) à travers lequel le comprimé est distribué ; l'éjecteur de comprimés (36) a une dimension de longueur qui s'étend d'un premier emplacement sur une paroi (31) où l'éjecteur (36) est activé vers un second emplacement adjacent à la zone de distribution (34) ; et un matériau élastomérique (20) recouvre les portions du logement où l'éjecteur de comprimés (36) est situé, et le joint à lèvre (22) est prévu dans le matériau élastomérique (20).</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Distributeur selon la revendication 1, dans lequel le logement comprend un logement inférieur (12), un logement supérieur (14), un couvercle (16) et un premier joint (18) qui relie les logements inférieur (12) et supérieur (14), où le couvercle (16) est relié au logement supérieur (14) par un second joint (24) pourvu d'une languette s'étendant vers le bas (26) qui se termine en une portion s'étendant horizontalement qui se verrouille dans une gorge (28) sur le logement supérieur (14).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Distributeur selon la revendication 1, dans lequel la pièce de guidage (32) comporte des première, deuxième, troisième et quatrième régions (32a, 32b, 32c, 32d) raccordées, où la première région (32a) de la pièce de guidage (32) s'étend horizontalement depuis la paroi (31) vers un emplacement dans la portion inférieure du logement (12), la deuxième région (32b) de la pièce de guidage (32) s'étend verticalement au-dessus de la zone de distribution (34) sur une distance présélectionnée, et la troisième région (32c) de la pièce de guidage (32) s'incline vers le bas lorsqu'elle traverse la direction horizontale depuis la deuxième région (32b) vers un point au-dessus de la zone de distribution (34), et la quatrième région (32d) s'étend verticalement vers un point au-dessus de l'éjecteur de comprimé (36).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Distributeur selon la revendication 1, dans lequel la zone de distribution (34) est en outre composée d'une plateforme (35) sur laquelle un comprimé<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> dans la zone de distribution (34) peut reposer, la hauteur de la plateforme (35) étant choisie pour placer un comprimé dans la zone de distribution (34) à la même hauteur que l'éjecteur (36) et le joint à lèvre (22).</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16672330" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1,2,3"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="142" he="189" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --><figure id="f0002" num="4,5"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="128" he="202" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --><figure id="f0003" num="6,7,8"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="109" he="187" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --><figure id="f0004" num="9,10"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="122" he="198" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
