<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2326435-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2326435" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="41105229" file-reference-id="315036" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146588609" ucid="EP-2326435-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2326435</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-09788854-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154850801" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>09788854</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20090630</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP220334718" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>09788854.9</doc-number><date>20090630</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140555026" ucid="US-13424608-P" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>13424608</doc-number><kind>P</kind><date>20080708</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140552256" ucid="US-2009003884-W" linkage-type="W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>2009003884</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20090630</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20131028</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989326120" load-source="docdb">B01J  41/04        20060101ALI20100129BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989326121" load-source="docdb">B08B   3/08        20060101AFI20100129BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989326122" load-source="docdb">B08B   3/14        20060101ALI20100129BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1861411860" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B08B   3/14        20130101 LI20170105BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1861413120" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B08B   3/08        20130101 FI20170105BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1861413410" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B01J  41/05        20170101 LI20170102BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370460" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">VERFAHREN UND MASCHINE ZUR SÄUREENTFERNUNG IN REINIGUNGSPROZESSEN</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370461" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">PROCESS AND MACHINE FOR ACID REMOVAL IN CLEANING PROCESSES</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370462" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">PROCÉDÉ ET MACHINE D'ÉLIMINATION D'ACIDE DANS DES PROCÉDÉS DE NETTOYAGE</invention-title><citations><patent-citations><patcit mxw-id="PCIT370901611" load-source="docdb" ucid="US-5500127-A"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>5500127</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>19960319</date></document-id><sources><source name="EXA" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT370899597" load-source="docdb" ucid="US-6217771-B1"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>6217771</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20010417</date></document-id><sources><source name="EXA" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit></patent-citations></citations></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919509559" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>DOW GLOBAL TECHNOLOGIES LLC</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919538879" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>DOW GLOBAL TECHNOLOGIES LLC</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919526605" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>GEISSLER KONRAD</last-name><address><country>CH</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919538629" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>GEISSLER, KONRAD</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919023900" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>GEISSLER, KONRAD</last-name><address><street>Viktoriastrasse 49</street><city>CH-8050 Zurich</city><country>CH</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919538322" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>KUEMIN MARIUS</last-name><address><country>CH</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919544604" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>KUEMIN, MARIUS</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919023901" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>KUEMIN, MARIUS</last-name><address><street>Sonnhaldenstrasse 23</street><city>CH-6331 Hunenberg</city><country>CH</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919023903" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Dow Global Technologies LLC</last-name><iid>101225780</iid><address><street>2040 Dow Center</street><city>Midland, MI 48674</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919023902" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Raynor, John</last-name><iid>101206848</iid><address><street>Beck Greener Fulwood House 12 Fulwood Place</street><city>London WC1V 6HR</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="US-2009003884-W"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2009003884</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20090630</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2010005518-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2010005518</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20100114</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549804285" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549924773" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549894724" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549877793" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549924774" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549804286" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549881943" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549924775" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549924776" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549871988" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549894729" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549877798" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549881944" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549924777" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549881945" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549804287" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549877799" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549924778" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549894730" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549924779" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549894731" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549787208" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549894732" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549894749" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549787213" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS549787214" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549787215" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549877800" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549787216" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549871989" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549788248" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549787221" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549881950" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549877801" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549924780" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63961029" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001"><u>Field of Disclosure</u></heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">Embodiments of the present disclosure include removal of acidic components in cleaning processes; more specifically, embodiments of the present disclosure include removal of acidic components from a cleaning composition for use in cleaning processes.</p><heading id="h0002"><u>Background</u></heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">Examples of cleaning and degreasing methods that have been applied to metals, ceramics, plastics, and other materials in the past can include alkali cleaning, cleaning with a surface active agent, cleaning with chloro-solvent, and/or cleaning with a fluoro-solvent. Alkali cleaning is cleaning achieved by dipping the material into a warm aqueous solution or alcohol solution of sodium hydroxide or other alkali agent, or by spraying such a solution. Cleaning with a surface active agent is achieved by dipping the material into a warm aqueous solution of a surface active agent, or by spraying such a solution. Cleaning with chloro-solvent involves dipping or vapor cleaning by using a chloro-solvent, such as, for example, 1,1,1-trichloroethane, trichloroethylene, and perchloroethylene. Finally, cleaning with a fluoro-solvent involves dipping or vapor cleaning, such as, for example, by using Freon 113.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">Currently, organic solvents used in cleaning processes for various materials include hydrocarbons, halogenated hydrocarbons, propylene and ethylene glycol ethers, esters, or mixtures thereof. These solvents are useful since they can be recycled within the process by distillation. However, during the cleaning process, since closed-loop cleaning machines internally recycle the organic solvents by distillation, volatile acids which are brought in and/or generated in the cleaning process are often not removed from the cleaning fluid and therefore can enrich over time. These acids can be harmful to the machine and/or the cleaned parts.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p><p id="p0004" num="0004"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US5782989A"><text>US 5,782,989 A</text></patcit> teaches polymer scale removal from vinyl polymerization reactors without the use of polar aprotic solvents or aromatic solvents, by adding to the reactor, a scale removal composition comprising acetone, a minor amount of a strong base, and a minor amount of a hydroxyl- or amino-functional polar organic solvent. The composition may contain surfactants, chelating or sequestering agents, detergent builders, and the like, and water in amounts of up to 3 weight percent. Scale removal is said to be efficient and rapid when the scale removing composition is agitated in the reactor at temperatures ranging from 50 °C to 120 °C.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005"><patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="DE19609119A1"><text>DE 196 09 119 A1</text></patcit> teaches a general-purpose cleaning process, in which a liquid is heated to produce steam and then brought into contact with the items to be cleaned. The liquid is a mixture of water, and a further component incorporating molecules with both hydrophilic and lipophilic groups of molecules. The further component and water form an azeotrope at the liquid/steam interface. The further component is Dipropylene-glycol-mono-propylether. The active cleaning fluid agent incorporates a non-evaporating cleaning amplifier. The cleaning agents and steam are maintained within a closed system preventing escape to the atmosphere.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006"><patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="US2003024883A1"><text>US 2003/024883 A1</text></patcit> discloses a chemical distribution system having improved organic solvent fluid purity and consistency. The system includes a vessel containing ion-exchange media positioned within a fluid flow pathway such that the organic solvent fluid passes through the ion-exchange media, thereby effecting removal of undesired impurities. Different embodiments of the system position the vessel at varying locations within the fluid flow pathway. The system also preferably includes a return chemical flow pathway that recirculatcs purified organic solvent fluid through the ion-exchange media-containing vessel and thereby enables the system operator to conduct incremental adjustment of the solvent purity until a desired overall purity is attained.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007"><patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="US6217771B1"><text>US 6,217,771 B1</text></patcit> teaches a method for removing corrosive contaminants from a polar extraction solvent comprising adding water to the solvent to provide a mixture. The mixture is then contacted with a basic ion exchanger resin to remove the corrosive contaminants. The solvent is recovered and may be reused.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008"><patcit id="pcit0005" dnum="US5500127A"><text>US 5,500,127 A</text></patcit> relates to a process for the purification of an organic solution containing an acid labile material, comprising contacting the organic solution with a combination of a cation exchange resin and an anion exchange resin. The cation exchange resin has weak acidic groups to reduce attack on the acid labile material within the organic solution. The anion exchange resin preferably has hydroxide exchange groups. The combination of exchange resins yields counterions that form water in the solution treated upon contact with the solution with the exchange resin mixture.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p><heading id="h0003"><u>Summary</u></heading><p id="p0009" num="0009">Embodiments of the present disclosure include cleaning processes, cleaning machines, and methods of preventing acidification of a cleaning composition in a cleaning process. As discussed herein, embodiments of the cleaning process include contacting an article having solids on its surface with a cleaning composition to remove contaminants from the article, where the cleaning composition comes to have acidic components as a result of contacting the article with the cleaning composition, and where at least 85 percent by weight, based on a total weight of cleaning composition, of the cleaning composition is an organic solvent. The cleaning process also includes collecting the cleaning composition with the contaminants and the acidic components. The process also includes separating the contaminants from the cleaning composition, and passing the cleaning composition with the acidic components over an ion exchange resin to remove the acidic components from the cleaning composition.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">In some embodiments, the ion exchange resin can be a strong anion exchange resin, for example, the ion exchange resin can be in OH<sup>-</sup> form, or can be a styrene-divinylbenzene (styrene-DVB) copolymer resin.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">In some embodiments, passing the cleaning composition with the acidic components over the ion exchange resin to remove the acidic components from the cleaning composition occurs continuously. As used herein, a "continuous" process step refers to a process where the ion exchange resin is positioned such that substantially all the cleaning composition that is separated from the contaminants continuously passes through the ion exchange resin.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">In some embodiments, passing the cleaning composition and acidic components over the ion exchange resin to remove the acidic components from the cleaning composition occurs semi-continuously. As used herein, a "semi-continuous" process refers to the cleaning process including process streams connected to a feed reservoir, which acts as a buffer for process streams that are produced continuously or batch-wise with a frequency different than the distillation process.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">As used herein, "a", "an", "the", "at least one", and "one or more" are used interchangeably. The terms "comprises" and variations thereof do not have a limiting meaning where these terms appear in the description and claims. Thus, for example, a cleaning process that comprises contacting "an" article with a cleaning<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> composition can be interpreted to mean that the cleaning process includes contacting "one or more" articles with the cleaning composition.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">The term "and/or" means one, more than one or all of the listed elements.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">Also herein, the recitations of numerical ranges by endpoints include all numbers subsumed within that range (e.g., 1 to 5 includes 1, 1.5, 2, 2.75, 3, 3.80, 4, 5, etc.).</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">The above summary of the present disclosure is not intended to describe each disclosed embodiment or every implementation of the present disclosure. The description that follows more particularly exemplifies illustrative embodiments. In several places throughout the application, guidance is provided through lists of examples, which can be used in various combinations. In each instance, the recited list serves only as a representative group and should not be interpreted as an exclusive list.</p><heading id="h0004"><u>Brief Description of the Drawings</u></heading><p id="p0017" num="0017"><ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> illustrates an embodiment of a cleaning machine to perform a cleaning process according to embodiments of the present disclosure.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref> illustrates an exchange capacity of an acid absorbing material of the present disclosure as a function of time.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0005"><u>Detailed Description</u></heading><p id="p0018" num="0018">Embodiments of the present disclosure include cleaning processes, cleaning machines, and methods of preventing acidification of a cleaning composition in a cleaning process. For the sake of convenience, the following description relates to the cleaning of an "article" although the process of the present disclosure is not limited to the cleaning of one article but is equally useful for cleaning several articles. In addition, the cleaning process steps, as described herein, can be performed in any order. Any such order given to the cleaning process steps are for description purposes only and are not intended to be limiting.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">The cleaning process includes contacting an article having solids on its surface with a cleaning composition to remove contaminants from the article, where the cleaning composition comes to have acidic components as a result of contacting the article with the cleaning composition, and where at least 85 percent by weight,<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> based on a total weight of the cleaning composition, of the cleaning composition is an organic solvent. The cleaning process also includes collecting the cleaning composition with the contaminants and acidic components, separating the contaminants from the cleaning composition, and passing the cleaning composition with the acidic components over an ion exchange resin to remove the acidic components from the cleaning composition.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">As used herein, "contaminants" in the cleaning composition result from soils on the surface of the article to be cleaned that are dissolved by the cleaning composition. When the article is cleaned in embodiments of the present disclosure, the soils on the surface of the article are removed by the cleaning composition. As a result, the cleaning composition includes the contaminants after contacting the surface of the article.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">In addition, the cleaning composition comes to have acidic components as a result of contacting the article with the cleaning composition. The acidic components can be produced during the cleaning process, for example, from side reactions between contaminants before contaminant removal. In some instances, the contaminants that are dissolved from the article surface can include acidic components as a result of contacting the article with the cleaning composition. In such embodiments, as discussed further herein, when the contaminants are separated from the cleaning composition, the use of the word "contaminants" refers to soils that are dissolved from the article surface that are not acidic, and the use of the term "acidic components" refers to components from the soils that are acidic as well as acidic components in the cleaning composition from other sources.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">In the Figure herein, as will be appreciated, elements shown in the embodiment herein can be added, exchanged, and/or eliminated so as to provide any number of additional embodiments of processes and/or systems. In addition, as will be appreciated the proportion and the relative scale of the elements provided in the figure is intended to illustrate the embodiments of the present invention, and should not be taken in a limiting sense. The drawing is a schematic illustration of an embodiment of the apparatus of the present disclosure.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023"><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> illustrates a cleaning machine 100 to perform a cleaning process, where an article can be cleaned according to embodiments of the present disclosure. As shown, an article to be cleaned can be loaded into the cleaning chamber 102. The article can be loaded in a known manner, for example, the article<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> can be placed into a container (e.g., a basket) if appropriate. Articles that can be provided to the cleaning chamber 102 include articles formed of metal, ceramic, glass, plastic, and/or other materials.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">The cleaning chamber 102 can be an open chamber or a closed chamber. In embodiments where the article to be cleaned includes volatile contaminants and/or soils on the article surface, and/or in embodiments where the cleaning composition used in the cleaning process includes hazardous substances, a closed cleaning chamber 102 can be used to reduce the likelihood of hazardous substances being released into the atmosphere.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">As will be appreciated by one skilled in the art, embodiments including a closed cleaning chamber 102 can employ the use of vacuum pumps for achieving a desired pressure reduction inside the closed cleaning chamber 102.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">Inside the cleaning chamber 102, a surface of the article having contaminants can be contacted with a cleaning composition to clean the surface of the article. There are several different methods in which the surface of the article can be contacted with the cleaning composition. For example, in some embodiments, the cleaning chamber 102 can be flooded with cleaning composition in order to immersion wash the surface of the article. In addition, embodiments of the present disclosure also include spraying the cleaning composition in a liquid phase onto the surface of the article in order to clean the surface of the article. Spraying subjects the surface of the article to a solvent-flushing action as it flows downward. The liquid drops can be collected, and the process can be continued until the article has a clean surface.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">Embodiments of the present disclosure also include vaporizing the cleaning composition and providing the cleaning composition vapor to the cleaning chamber 102. In such embodiments, the surface of the article can have a lower temperature than the vapor, allowing the vapor to condense on the article and subject its surface to a cleaning composition flushing action as it flows downward. The condensed cleaning composition can then be re-vaporized and provided back to the cleaning chamber. Thus, the surface of the article is continually rinsed with condensed vapor until the surface of the article has the same temperature of the vapor and condensation ceases. The continuous rinsing with the condensed vapor can also be stopped before the article has the same temperature of the vapor. Very effective cleaning of the surface of the article can be achieved.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p><p id="p0028" num="0028">In some embodiments, immersion washing, liquid spraying, and vapor degreasing can be performed sequentially on each article provided in the cleaning chamber 102. Embodiments also include performing one method of contacting the article with the cleaning composition, as well as different combinations of each method. For example, in some embodiments, the cleaning process can include spraying the article with the cleaning composition followed by a vapor degreasing step, as described herein. The vapor degreasing step can be a beneficial second step in the cleaning process since the vapors remain substantially free of the contaminants, or soils, after being revaporized. Also, the use of elevated temperatures in the vapor degreasing step can accelerate the rate of soil dissolution into the cleaning composition.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">In some embodiments, the method of contacting the article with the cleaning composition, and/or the order of the methods of contacting the article, can depend on the type of material forming the article and/or the type of soils on the surface of the article.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">As discussed herein, cleaning compositions used in cleaning processes of the present disclosure include organic solvents. The term "organic solvent," as used herein, encompasses undiluted organic compounds as well as mixtures of two or more organic compounds which are generally designated in the art as organic solvents, and also mixtures of one or more such organic compounds with water. The organic solvents in the cleaning composition can include hydrocarbons, halogenated hydrocarbons, alcohols, glycol ethers, esters, propylene glycol ethers, dipropylene glycol ethers, ethylene glycol ethers, ethylene glycol ether acetates, propylene glycol ether acetates, or mixtures thereof, among others.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">Also, if the cleaning composition contains water, it preferably contains less than 15 percent, more preferably less than 10 percent, and most preferably contains less than 5 percent water, based on the total weight of the cleaning composition.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">In some embodiments, the cleaning composition can also include additional elements, including, but not limited to, organic or inorganic acids, organic or inorganic bases (e.g., for pH control), antioxidants, corrosion inhibitors, metal passivators, and/or staining inhibitors, among others.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">In addition, the cleaning composition can have a boiling point in a range of about 40 degrees Celsius to about 240 degrees Celsius. Preferably, the<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> cleaning composition can have a boiling point in a range of about 90 degrees Celsius to about 200 degrees Celsius. By having a boiling point in such ranges, the cleaning composition can be separated from the contaminants in a distillation apparatus, as appreciated by one skilled in the art.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">Also, as discussed herein, the cleaning composition comes to have acidic components as a result of contacting the article with the cleaning composition. The acidic components in the cleaning composition can result from the cleaning process, for example, the contaminants on the article that are removed can include acidic components. In addition, the acidic components can result from side reactions occurring throughout the cleaning process. Other ways of forming acidic components are also possible.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">As discussed herein, the method of cleaning the article includes collecting the cleaning composition with the contaminants and the acidic components, and separating the contaminants from the cleaning composition. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>, the cleaning machine 100 includes a conduit system equipped with valves connecting the cleaning chamber 102 to other equipment in the cleaning machine 100. In addition, as shown, inlet air 123 can be fed into the cleaning chamber 102, while waste gas 121 can be removed from the cleaning machine 100 by means of a vacuum pump 124.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">The cleaning composition with the contaminants and acidic components can be collected by including a process stream 104 connected to the cleaning chamber 102. The cleaning composition with the contaminants and acidic components can be transferred through the process stream 104 to one or more storage tanks 106, 108. The storage tanks 106, 108 can be connected to the cleaning chamber 102 in a known way. The cleaning process shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> includes two storage tanks 106, 108, however, cleaning processes can include one storage tank, as well as more than two storage tanks.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">The cleaning composition with the contaminants and the acidic components can then be transferred from the storage tanks 106, 108 back to the cleaning chamber via process streams 110 and 112, or the cleaning composition with the contaminants and the acidic components can be transported to a distillation apparatus 114 via process stream 116. In some embodiments, the cleaning composition with the contaminants and the acidic components can be transported to the distillation apparatus 114 continuously. In other words, the process stream 116 is<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> constantly feeding the distillation apparatus 114 with cleaning composition from the storage tanks 106, 108.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">In addition, in various embodiments, the cleaning composition with the contaminants and the acidic components can be transported to the distillation apparatus semi-continuously. In such embodiments, process streams 110, 112 and also process stream 116 can be opened and closed periodically using valves to transfer the cleaning composition with the contaminants and the acidic components directly back to the cleaning chamber 102 and to the distillation apparatus 114 depending on which process streams are opened. In such embodiments, the periodicity of when the cleaning composition with the contaminants and the acidic components is transferred to the distillation apparatus 114 can be based on a number of different factors. For example, the periodicity can be based on the type and amount of soils on the surface of the article, the method of contacting the article with the cleaning composition (e.g., fluid spraying), the type of article, and/or the level of cleanliness required for the article, among others.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">As used herein, "distilling" refers to a process of separating compounds based on their differences in volatilities by vaporization and subsequent condensation, as for purification or concentration. In embodiments discussed herein, distillation can be performed on the cleaning composition to purify the cleaning composition. In addition, as used herein, a "distillation apparatus" refers to a device that carries out the distillation process.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">The distillation apparatus 114 of the present disclosure can include enough equilibrium stages to remove the contaminants from the cleaning composition. As used herein, an "equilibrium stage" can refer to a hypothetical zone or stage in which two phases, such as the liquid and vapor phases of a substance, establish equilibrium with each other. The equilibrium stage can also be referred to as a theoretical tray.</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">The distillation apparatus 114 of the present disclosure can have trays, dumped packing, or structured packing. In embodiments where the distillation apparatus 114 has trays, the trays can be physical devices which are used to provide contact between an upflowing vapor and a downflowing liquid inside the distillation apparatus 114.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">In some embodiments, the distillation apparatus 114 can use packing rather than trays. In some embodiments, packing can offer the advantage of a lower<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> pressure drop across the distillation apparatus 114 (when compared to trays). In embodiments using packing, the packing material can be random dumped packing such as, for example, Raschig rings, Pall rings, or Bialecki rings in metal or ceramic. The packing material can also be structured sheet-metal packing such as those known and commercially available for example under the designations Gempak ® (Glitsch, Inc. Dallas, Tex., U.S.A), Mellapak ® (Gebr. Sulzer, Winterthur, Switzerland), or Relapak®.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">In some embodiments the distillation apparatus 114 is operated under vacuum. As the boiling point of a solvent is lowered at lowered pressure, the temperature in the distillation bottom can be lowered under vacuum. This can be used to minimize the formation of unwanted products by thermal decomposition reactions. Furthermore, the cleaning composition content of the waste stream from the distillation bottom can be minimized which leads to lower cleaning composition consumption.</p><p id="p0044" num="0044">Distilling the cleaning composition with the contaminants and the acidic components in the distillation apparatus 114 can remove the contaminants from the cleaning composition. However, the separation process is unable to remove the acidic components from the cleaning composition. For example, in some embodiments, the cleaning composition includes volatile acidic components even after it exits the distillation apparatus 114. In addition, as appreciated by one skilled in the art, separating the cleaning composition from the contaminants can include further separation within the cleaning process. For example, the cleaning process can include passing the distillate (i.e., the cleaning composition) from the distillation apparatus 114 to a water decanter and/or a condenser.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045">In prior art processes, the cleaning composition with the acidic components exit the distillation apparatus 114 and are transported back to the cleaning chamber 102 for additional cleaning of the article, or to restart the cleaning process for a new article, using the continuous process as has been described thus far. However, in such processes, the acidic components in the cleaning composition can build to a level that can be harmful to the closed loop cleaning machine 100 and/or the article to be cleaned.</p><p id="p0046" num="0046">As such, a method of preventing the build up of acidic components in the cleaning composition has been sought. Such methods have included, for example, draining the cleaning composition with the acidic components from the cleaning<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> machine 100 and replacing with new cleaning composition when the acidic components in the cleaning composition reaches a certain level. As will be appreciated by one skilled in the art, this process is time consuming and costly both due to the loss in efficiency from shutting the cleaning machine 100 down but also due to the loss of organic solvents in the cleaning composition.</p><p id="p0047" num="0047">Another method of preventing the build up of acidic components in the cleaning composition includes adding additives to the cleaning composition in order to react with the acidic components, thereby neutralizing the acidic components. For example, in some embodiments amine-based additives have been added to the cleaning composition. However, although the amine-based additives can neutralize some of the acidic components, it has been found that not all of the acidic components are neutralized. In this case, although the amine-based additives can slow the buildup of acidic components in the cleaning composition, the build up continues until the cleaning composition with the acidic components is harmful, and thus, in need of replacement.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048">Since there exists the problem of acidic component build up in the cleaning composition, and the methods in the prior art are unsuccessful and/or too costly and inefficient to be satisfactory, a method of removing the acidic components from the cleaning composition in a cleaning machine 100 is sought.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">The inventors of the present disclosure considered the problem of acidic component build up in the cleaning composition and the methods in the prior art. To determine why the amine-based additives did not neutralize substantially all the acidic components in the cleaning composition, analysis of process streams by ion chromatography and distillation lab trials with amines and acids were performed. From the analysis, it was determined that amine salts of some acids are not stable under the conditions of the distillation unit, thus, the amine-based additive does not react with all the acidic components to form an amine salt that can then be separated from the cleaning composition in the distillation unit.</p><p id="p0050" num="0050">Once it was determined why the amine-based additive did not work to neutralize the acidic components in the cleaning composition, several other additives were experimented with to remove the acidic components. First, over-based calcium sulfonates were added to the cleaning composition. However, the over-based calcium sulfonates formed a thick, gel-like substance in the cleaning composition. Second, sodium carbonate was added to the cleaning composition. However, the sodium<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> carbonate does not react with the acidic components without the presence of water in the cleaning composition. Since the cleaning composition can be substantially water-free, the sodium carbonate would not work in all cleaning processes using the cleaning composition of the present disclosure. Last, sodium hydroxide was added to the cleaning composition. However, the sodium hydroxide, although it can react with substantially all the acidic components in the cleaning composition to neutralize the acidic components, it is a very strong base that can be harmful to the cleaning machine 100 and/or to the articles to be cleaned.</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">Since the addition of additives to the cleaning composition had problems associated with each, the inventors of the present disclosure looked to a method of removing the acidic components using spatial separation in the cleaning process. As such, embodiments of the present disclosure include passing the cleaning composition with the acidic components from the distillation apparatus 114 over an ion exchange resin 125 to remove the acidic components from the cleaning composition.</p><p id="p0052" num="0052">In some embodiments, the ion exchange resin 125 can be a strong anion exchange resin. I n various embodiments, the ion exchange resin can be in OH<sup>-</sup> form. Also, the ion exchange resin can be a styrene-divinylbenzene (styrene-DVB) copolymer resin.</p><p id="p0053" num="0053">In some embodiments, the ion exchange resin 125 can be positioned between the distillation apparatus 114 and the cleaning chamber 102. In various embodiments, the ion exchange resin 125 can be located in the distillate stream (e.g., process stream 122) down stream of the distillation apparatus 114. For example, the ion exchange resin 125 can be positioned between the distillation apparatus 114 and the cleaning chamber 102. In addition, as discussed herein, in some embodiments, the ion exchange resin 125 can be positioned after a water decanter, or a condenser. As such, the ion exchange resin 125 can be contained in a cartridge that is insertable into the cleaning machine 100 at the various possible positions. For example, process stream 122 can be set up so as to allow the ion exchange resin 125 to be inserted and/or exchanged. For example, valve 126 can be closed in order to replace the ion exchange resin 125 without disrupting the cleaning process. The cleaning composition can then pass over the ion exchange resin 125 to remove the acidic components from the cleaning composition before it is transferred back to the cleaning chamber 102 and/or the storage tanks 106, 108.<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --></p><p id="p0054" num="0054">As discussed herein, in some embodiments, the cleaning composition with the contaminants and the acidic components can bypass the distillation apparatus 114, or can be transferred to the distillation apparatus 114 semi-continuously. Similarly, in some embodiments, the distillate (i.e., cleaning composition and acidic components) can pass over the ion exchange resin 125 continuously. In other words, valve 126 can be closed, forcing all the cleaning composition with the acidic components to flow to the ion exchange resin 125.</p><p id="p0055" num="0055">In addition, in various embodiments, the cleaning composition with the acidic components can be passed over the ion exchange resin 125 semi-continuously. In such embodiments, valve 126 can be opened and closed periodically to transfer the cleaning composition with the acidic components directly back to the cleaning chamber 102 and to the ion exchange resin 125 depending on whether valve 126 is opened. In such embodiments, the periodicity of when the cleaning composition with the acidic components is transferred to the ion exchange resin 125 can be based on a number of different factors. For example, the periodicity can be based on the amount of acidic components in the cleaning composition, the type and amount of soils on the surface of the article, the method of contacting the article with the cleaning composition (e.g., fluid spraying), the type of article, and/or the level of cleanliness required for the article, among others.</p><p id="p0056" num="0056">The cleaning composition can be recycled back to the cleaning chamber 102 via process stream 122. In addition, in some embodiments, additional cleaning composition can be transferred to the closed chamber 102 from a storage tank 128 containing unused, unrecycled cleaning composition.</p><p id="p0057" num="0057">As appreciated by one skilled in the art, the cleaning composition with the contaminants and the acidic components can be passed over the ion exchange resin 125 to remove the acidic components to be used to clean the article inside the cleaning chamber 102 continuously while the article is being cleaned. Since the cleaning composition is being recovered and recycled throughout the cleaning machine 100, the cleaning machine operates in a closed loop. In other words, in some embodiments, the cleaning process can continue without the addition of new, unused cleaning composition.</p><p id="p0058" num="0058">As appreciated by one skilled in the art, once the article is cleaned, the cleaned articles can be dried, and the cleaning chamber 102 can be unloaded.<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></p><heading id="h0006">EXAMPLES</heading><p id="p0059" num="0059">The following examples are given to illustrate, but not limit, the scope of this disclosure. Unless otherwise indicated, all parts and percentages are by weight. Unless otherwise specified, all instruments and chemicals used are commercially available.</p><heading id="h0007"><u>Materials</u></heading><p id="p0060" num="0060">Sodium Hydroxide (NaOH): available from Sigma Aldrich, St. Louis, MO USA.</p><p id="p0061" num="0061">Charcoal NORIT® RO SX 1 available from Sigma Aldrich, St. Louis, MO USA.</p><p id="p0062" num="0062">Charcoal NORIT® RO 0.8 available from Sigma Aldrich, St. Louis, MO USA.</p><p id="p0063" num="0063">Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> spheres (Fluka 06400) available from Sigma Aldrich, St. Louis, MO USA.</p><p id="p0064" num="0064">Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> (basic) powder, (Fluka 17994) available from Sigma Aldrich, St. Louis, MO USA.</p><p id="p0065" num="0065">Calcinate™ OR overbased calcium sulfonates: available from Blaser Swisslube, Inc., Goshen, NY USA.</p><p id="p0066" num="0066">Acetic acid (99-100 percent): available from Merck &amp; Co., Whitehouse Station, NJ USA.</p><heading id="h0008">Ion Exchange Resins:</heading><p id="p0067" num="0067">DOWEX™ resins: available from The Dow Chemical Company, Midland, MI USA.</p><p id="p0068" num="0068">Lewatit® resins: available from LANXESS Deutschland GmbH, Leverkusen, Germany.</p><p id="p0069" num="0069">DOWCLENE™ 1601: available from The Dow Chemical Company, Midland, MI USA.</p><p id="p0070" num="0070">DOWCLENE™ 1611: available from The Dow Chemical Company, Midland, MI USA.</p><heading id="h0009">EXAMPLE 1</heading><p id="p0071" num="0071">In this example, the total exchange capacity of potential acid absorbing materials is determined. The absorber materials listed in Table 1 are flushed with DOWCLENE™ 1601 solvent to remove excess water prior to the experiment. Then,<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> 10 to 20 grams of absorber materials and 250 milliliters (ml) of DOWCLENE™ 1601 are spiked with a defined amount of acetic acid (e.g., about 2,000 parts per million-weight (ppm-wt.)) and agitated at room temperature. Solvent samples are taken until a stable acetate level (steady state) is measured by ion chromatography. From the mass balance of acetic acid in the solvent before and after the experiment, the capacity of the absorber materials can be calculated. Table 1 gives the capacities of various absorber materials.
<tables id="tabl0001" num="0001"><table frame="topbot"><title>Table 1</title><tgroup cols="2" colsep="0"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="55mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="28mm"/><thead><row><entry align="center" valign="top">Absorber Material</entry><entry align="center" valign="top">Capacity (mg/g)</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry align="center">Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> spheres (Fluka 06400)</entry><entry align="center">12</entry></row><row><entry align="center">Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> (basic) powder, (Fluka 17994)</entry><entry align="center">38</entry></row><row><entry align="center">Charcoal NORIT® RO SX 1</entry><entry align="center">5</entry></row><row><entry align="center">Charcoal NORIT® RO 0.8</entry><entry align="center">15</entry></row><row><entry align="center">Resin Lewatit® Monoplus MP800</entry><entry align="center">53</entry></row><row><entry align="center">Resin DOWEX™ MSA-1C(OH)</entry><entry align="center">85</entry></row><row><entry align="center">Resin DOWEX™ SBR(OH)</entry><entry align="center">103</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></tables></p><p id="p0072" num="0072">High capacities are found for a gel-type resin (DOWEX™ SBR) while the other ion exchange resins still have higher capacities than charcoal or aluminum oxide. Although basic aluminum oxide (Fluka 17994) has a total capacity clearly better than charcoal or the Al<sub>2</sub>O<sub>3</sub> sphere, it has very slow exchange kinetics, as only 50 percent of its capacity is reached after 24 hours, while the ion exchange resins reach steady state after 2 to 4 hours.</p><heading id="h0010">EXAMPLE 2</heading><p id="p0073" num="0073">In Example 2, a continuous set up is used. In order to remove excess water, 22.6 g DOWEX™ SBR (OH) is treated 3 times for 30 minutes (min) each with 250 ml DOWCLENE™ 1601. The resin is then packed into a fixed bed (e.g., glass column) and continuously flushed in a loop with acetic acid-spiked DOWCLENE™ 1601 using a peristaltic pump. Measurement of acetate in the solvent is done by ion chromatography. When a concentration of less than 1 ppm-wt is reached, additional acetic acid is added to the solvent until breakthrough of the acid is detected.</p><p id="p0074" num="0074">The results in Table 2 illustrate that complete removal (e.g., less than 1 ppm-wt) of acetic acid can be achieved in a continuous step until breakthrough capacity is reached. Also, as can be seen from the analysis of samples 3 and 4,<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> flushing the partially loaded bed with virtually acetate-free feed for more than 4 hours does not lead to desorption and breakthrough of acetate.
<tables id="tabl0002" num="0002"><table frame="topbot"><title>Table 2</title><tgroup cols="3" colsep="0"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="16mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="79mm"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="31mm"/><thead><row><entry align="center" valign="top">t (h:min)</entry><entry align="center" valign="top">Step</entry><entry align="center" valign="top">c acetate (ppm-wt)</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry align="center">0</entry><entry align="center">concentration measurement at start of trial</entry><entry align="center">736</entry></row><row><entry align="center">0:45</entry><entry align="center">Solvent sample 1</entry><entry align="center">20</entry></row><row><entry align="center">3:00</entry><entry align="center">Solvent sample 2</entry><entry align="center">&lt;1</entry></row><row><entry align="center">3:45</entry><entry align="center">spiked with 1124 ppm acetic acid</entry><entry align="center"/></row><row><entry align="center">5:15</entry><entry align="center">Solvent sample 3</entry><entry align="center">&lt;1</entry></row><row><entry align="center">9:30</entry><entry align="center">solvent sample 4 and addition of 2460 ppm acetic acid</entry><entry align="center">&lt;1</entry></row><row><entry align="center">12:45</entry><entry align="center">Solvent sample 5</entry><entry align="center">&lt;1</entry></row><row><entry align="center">15:00</entry><entry align="center">addition of 4128 ppm acetic acid</entry><entry align="center"/></row><row><entry align="center">15:45</entry><entry align="center">Solvent sample 6</entry><entry align="center">1601</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></tables></p><heading id="h0011">EXAMPLE 3</heading><p id="p0075" num="0075">In this example, the total exchange capacity of a potential acid absorbing material is determined, as is described in Example 1. However, in this example, the resin DOWEX™ MSA-1C(OH) is flushed before the experiment with a molecular sieve-dried DOWCLENE™ 1601 until the water content of the flushing liquid is only 0.07 percent water. Furthermore, the DOWCLENE™ 1601 solvent used as a carrier for the acetic acid is dried with a molecular sieve before the experiment. In this example, the acetic acid capacity of the DOWEX™ MSA-1C(OH) resin is 85 milligrams per gram (mg/g). This is the same value as is determined in Example 1 for this particular resin. As such, the results indicate that water is not a necessary component to carry out the reaction to remove acid from the stream passing through the resin.</p><heading id="h0012">EXAMPLE 4</heading><p id="p0076" num="0076">In this example, the total exchange capacity of an acid absorbing material is determined over a period of time. As in Example 1, the resin is flushed with DOWCLENET™ 1601 solvent to remove excess water prior to the experiment. However, in this example, 10 to 20 g of absorber materials and 250 ml DOWCLENE™ 1601 are spiked with 4,906 ppm-wt acetic acid and left standing at room temperature, as opposed to agitating the absorber material and the DOWCLENE™. The acetate level of the solvent is measured regularly by ion<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> chromatography. The graph, shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref>, shows the acetic acid concentration as a function of time.</p><p id="p0077" num="0077">As can be seen from <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref>, the reaction is almost in the steady state after 5 hours of reaction time, even without mixing the absorber material and the solvent. The acid levels in cleaning machines can change at a maximum of about 100 to about 500 ppm-wt within one week, therefore, from <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref>, the reaction of the absorber materials is fast enough to be commercially practical.</p><heading id="h0013">EXAMPLE 5</heading><p id="p0078" num="0078">In this Example, in order to determine the stability of the resin in the organic medium, 25 ml of resin is added to 25 ml of solvents and then kept for 48 hours at 80 degrees Celsius. After filtration, the solvent is evaporated over night at 80 degrees Celsius and the residue is weighed. Table 3 shows that only a very small amount of the resins is dissolved during the experiment.
<tables id="tabl0003" num="0003"><table frame="topbot"><title>Table 3</title><tgroup cols="6" colsep="0"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="12mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="31mm"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="31mm"/><colspec colnum="4" colname="col4" colwidth="32mm"/><colspec colnum="5" colname="col5" colwidth="32mm"/><colspec colnum="6" colname="col6" colwidth="31mm"/><thead><row><entry valign="top"/><entry namest="col2" nameend="col3" align="center" valign="top">Resin type</entry><entry namest="col4" nameend="col5" align="center" valign="top">Solvent Type</entry><entry valign="top">Solubility</entry></row><row><entry valign="top">No.</entry><entry valign="top">Lewatit® Monoplus MP800</entry><entry valign="top">DOWEX™ SBR(OH)</entry><entry valign="top">DOWCLENE ™ 1601</entry><entry valign="top">DOWCLENE ™ 1611</entry><entry valign="top">Dissolved Resin (wt. percent)</entry></row><row><entry valign="top"/><entry valign="top">m (g)</entry><entry valign="top">m(g)</entry><entry valign="top">m (g)</entry><entry valign="top">m (g)</entry><entry valign="top"/></row></thead><tbody><row><entry>1</entry><entry align="char" char=".">12.98</entry><entry align="char" char="."/><entry align="char" char=".">21.55</entry><entry align="char" char="."/><entry align="char" char=".">0.005</entry></row><row><entry>2</entry><entry align="char" char="."/><entry align="char" char=".">26.33</entry><entry align="char" char=".">22.19</entry><entry align="char" char="."/><entry align="char" char=".">0.003</entry></row><row><entry>3</entry><entry align="char" char=".">13.35</entry><entry align="char" char="."/><entry align="char" char="."/><entry align="char" char=".">23.52</entry><entry align="char" char=".">0.027</entry></row><row><entry>4</entry><entry align="char" char="."/><entry align="char" char=".">25.41</entry><entry align="char" char="."/><entry align="char" char=".">23.31</entry><entry align="char" char=".">0.023</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></tables></p><p id="p0079" num="0079">As can be seen from Table 3, very little resin dissolves in the solvent after 48 hours. As the resins are stable in the tested solvents, these resins can be used in cleaning machines where non-volatile residue content of the solvent is considered a critical quality factor.</p><heading id="h0014">EXAMPLE 6</heading><p id="p0080" num="0080">In this example, 150 ml (132 g) of DOWCLENE™ 1601, 4 ml (4.196 g) acetic acid, and 10.83 g Calcinate™ OR overbased calcium sulfonate are fractionally distilled at 100 millibar (mbar). Fractional distillation is the separation of a mixture into its component parts, or fractions, by heating them to a temperature at which several fractions of the compound will evaporate. The amount of overbased<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> calcium sulfonate is calculated to be 110 percent of the equimolar amount needed to neutralize the acetic acid. A sample of the initial mixture is tested to be alkaline using pH indicator paper. The results of the distillation are shown in Table 4.
<tables id="tabl0004" num="0004"><table frame="topbot"><title>Table 4</title><tgroup cols="6" colsep="0"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="29mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="39mm"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="18mm"/><colspec colnum="4" colname="col4" colwidth="23mm"/><colspec colnum="5" colname="col5" colwidth="14mm"/><colspec colnum="6" colname="col6" colwidth="24mm"/><thead><row><entry align="center" valign="top">Distillate fraction</entry><entry align="center" valign="top">bottom temperature (°C)</entry><entry align="center" valign="top">mass (g)</entry><entry align="center" valign="top">Volume (ml)</entry><entry align="center" valign="top">pH:</entry><entry align="center" valign="top">acetate (mg/l)</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry align="center">1</entry><entry align="center">102</entry><entry align="center">11.45</entry><entry align="center">13.01</entry><entry align="center">2.81</entry><entry align="center">12,287</entry></row><row><entry align="center">2</entry><entry align="center">103</entry><entry align="center">37.98</entry><entry align="center">43.16</entry><entry align="center">3.01</entry><entry align="center">4,353</entry></row><row><entry align="center">3</entry><entry align="center">109</entry><entry align="center">35.44</entry><entry align="center">40.27</entry><entry align="center">3.1</entry><entry align="center">2,095</entry></row><row><entry align="center">4</entry><entry align="center">135</entry><entry align="center">17.39</entry><entry align="center">19.76</entry><entry align="center">3.38</entry><entry align="center">853</entry></row><row><entry align="center">bottom</entry><entry align="center"/><entry align="center">37.4</entry><entry align="center">100</entry><entry align="center">n.d.</entry><entry align="center">36,227</entry></row></tbody></tgroup><tgroup cols="6" rowsep="0"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="29mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="39mm"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="18mm"/><colspec colnum="4" colname="col4" colwidth="23mm"/><colspec colnum="5" colname="col5" colwidth="14mm"/><colspec colnum="6" colname="col6" colwidth="24mm"/><tbody><row><entry namest="col1" nameend="col6" align="justify">*n.d. = not determined</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></tables></p><p id="p0081" num="0081">As shown in Table 4, acetic acid is found in all the distillate fractions. As such, the overbased calcium sulfonate is shown to not be able to bind with acetic cid under the conditions of the distillation, which closely resembles the operation of a solvent redistillation unit in a cleaning machine.</p><p id="p0082" num="0082">Similar trials using Na<sub>2</sub>CO<sub>3</sub> and triethanolamine in place of overbased calcium sulfonate are also shown to not be suited to capture acetic acid under the conditions of Example 6.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56985827" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Ein Reinigungsprozess, der Folgendes beinhaltet:
<claim-text>In-Kontakt-Bringen eines Gegenstands, der auf seiner Oberfläche Schmutz aufweist, mit einer Reinigungszusammensetzung, um Verschmutzungsstoffe von dem Gegenstand zu entfernen, wobei die Reinigungszusammensetzung als Ergebnis des In-Kontakt-Bringens des Gegenstands mit der Reinigungszusammensetzung dazu übergeht, saure Komponenten aufzuweisen, und wobei mindestens 85 Gewichtsprozent der Reinigungszusammensetzung, bezogen auf ein Gesamtgewicht der Reinigungszusammensetzung, ein organisches Lösungsmittel ist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Auffangen der Reinigungszusammensetzung mit den Verschmutzungsstoffen und den sauren Komponenten;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Trennen der Verschmutzungsstoffe von der Reinigungszusammensetzung; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Führen der Reinigungszusammensetzung mit den sauren Komponenten über ein Ionenaustauschharz, um die sauren Komponenten aus der Reinigungszusammensetzung zu entfernen.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Prozess gemäß Anspruch 1, wobei das Ionenaustauschharz ein starkes Anionenaustauschharz ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Prozess gemäß Anspruch 1, wobei das Ionenaustauschharz ein Styren-Divinylbenzen-Copolymerharz ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Prozess gemäß einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei das Führen der Reinigungszusammensetzung mit den sauren Komponenten über das Ionenaustauschharz, um die sauren Komponenten aus der Reinigungszusammensetzung zu entfernen, kontinuierlich stattfindet.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Prozess gemäß einem der Ansprüche 1-3, wobei das Führen der Reinigungszusammensetzung mit den sauren Komponenten über das Ionenaustauschharz, um die sauren Komponenten aus der Reinigungszusammensetzung zu entfernen, halbkontinuierlich stattfindet.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Prozess gemäß einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei die Reinigungszusammensetzung im Wesentlichen wasserfrei ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Prozess gemäß einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei die organischen Lösungsmittel in der Reinigungszusammensetzung aus Alkoholen,<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> Propylenglykolethern, Ethylenglykolethern, Ethylenglykoletheracetaten, Propylenglykoletheracetaten, Estern, Kohlenwasserstoffen, Halogenkohlenwasserstoffen oder Mischungen davon ausgewählt sind.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Prozess gemäß Anspruch 7, wobei die Reinigungszusammensetzung einen Siedepunkt in einem Bereich von 40 Grad Celsius bis 240 Grad Celsius aufweist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Prozess gemäß Anspruch 8, wobei die Reinigungszusammensetzung einen Siedepunkt in einem Bereich von 90 Grad Celsius bis 200 Grad Celsius aufweist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Eine Reinigungsmaschine (100) mit geschlossenem Kreislauf, um den Prozess, wie in Ansprüchen 1-9 beschrieben, durchzuführen, die Folgendes beinhaltet:
<claim-text>eine Reinigungskammer (102) zum In-Kontakt-Bringen einer Verschmutzungsstoffe aufweisenden Oberfläche des Gegenstands mit einer Reinigungszusammensetzung, um die Oberfläche des Gegenstands zu reinigen;</claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Mittel zum Auffangen der Reinigungszusammensetzung mit den Verschmutzungsstoffen und sauren Komponenten aus der Reinigungskammer (102); eine Destillationsvorrichtung (114) zum Trennen der Verschmutzungsstoffe von der Reinigungszusammensetzung mit den Verschmutzungsstoffen und den sauren Komponenten; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Ionenaustauschharz (125); und</claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Mittel zum Führen der Reinigungszusammensetzung mit den sauren Komponenten aus der Destillationsvorrichtung über das Ionenaustauschharz (125).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Reinigungsmaschine (100) mit geschlossenem Kreislauf gemäß Anspruch 10, wobei das Mittel zum Auffangen der Reinigungszusammensetzung mit den Verschmutzungsstoffen und den sauren Komponenten aus der Reinigungskammer (102) einen oder mehr Aufbewahrungsbehälter (106, 108) umfasst, die durch einen Prozessstrom (104) mit der Reinigungskammer (102) verbunden sind.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Ein Verfahren zum Verhindern der Versauerung einer Reinigungszusammensetzung in einem Reinigungsprozess, das Folgendes beinhaltet:
<claim-text>Bereitstellen eines Gegenstands, der auf einer Gegenstandsoberfläche Verschmutzungsstoffe aufweist, wobei die Verschmutzungsstoffe entfernt werden sollen;</claim-text>
<claim-text>In-Kontakt-Bringen der Gegenstandsoberfläche mit der Reinigungszusammensetzung, um die Verschmutzungsstoffe von der Gegenstandsoberfläche zu entfernen, wobei die Reinigungszusammensetzung als Ergebnis des In-Kontakt-Bringens des Gegenstands<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --> mit der Reinigungszusammensetzung dazu übergeht, saure Komponenten aufzuweisen, und wobei mehr als 85 Gewichtsprozent der Reinigungszusammensetzung, bezogen auf ein Gesamtgewicht der Reinigungszusammensetzung, ein organisches Lösungsmittel ist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Auffangen der Reinigungszusammensetzung mit den Verschmutzungsstoffen und den sauren Komponenten;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Trennen der Verschmutzungsstoffe von der Reinigungszusammensetzung; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Führen der Reinigungszusammensetzung mit den sauren Komponenten über ein Ionenaustauschharz, um die sauren Komponenten aus der Reinigungszusammensetzung zu entfernen.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Verfahren gemäß Anspruch 12, wobei das Ionenaustauschharz ein starkes Anionenaustauschharz ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Verfahren gemäß einem der Ansprüche 12-13, wobei das Ionenaustauschharz in OH<sup>-</sup>-Form vorliegt.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56985828" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A cleaning process, comprising:
<claim-text>contacting an article having soils on its surface with a cleaning composition to remove contaminants from the article, where the cleaning composition comes to have acidic components as a result of contacting the article with the cleaning composition, and where at least 85 percent by weight, based on a total weight of the cleaning composition, of the cleaning composition is an organic solvent;</claim-text>
<claim-text>collecting the cleaning composition with the contaminants and the acidic components;</claim-text>
<claim-text>separating the contaminants from the cleaning composition; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>passing the cleaning composition with the acidic components over an ion exchange resin to remove the acidic components from the cleaning composition.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The process of claim 1, where the ion exchange resin is a strong anion exchange resin.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The process of claim 1, where the ion exchange resin is a styrene-divinylbenzene copolymer resin.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The process as in any one of the preceding claims, where passing the cleaning composition with the acidic components over the ion exchange resin to remove the acidic components from the cleaning composition occurs continuously.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The process as in any one of claims 1-3, where passing the cleaning composition with the acidic components over the ion exchange resin to remove the acidic components from the cleaning composition occurs semi-continuously.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The process as in any one of the preceding claims, where the cleaning composition is substantially free of water.<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The process as in any one of the preceding claims, where the organic solvents in the cleaning composition are selected from alcohols, propylene glycol ethers, ethylene glycol ethers, ethylene glycol ether acetates, propylene glycol ether acetates, esters, hydrocarbons, halogenated hydrocarbons, or mixtures thereof.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The process of claim 7, where the cleaning composition has a boiling point in a range of 40 degrees Celsius to 240 degrees Celsius.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The process of claim 8, where the cleaning composition has a boiling point in a range of 90 degrees Celsius to 200 degrees Celsius.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>A closed-loop cleaning machine (100) to perform the process as described in claims 1 - 9, comprising:
<claim-text>a cleaning chamber (102) for contacting a surface of the article having contaminants with a cleaning composition to clean the surface of the article;</claim-text>
<claim-text>means for collecting the cleaning composition with the contaminants and acidic components from the cleaning chamber (102);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a distillation apparatus (114) for separating the contaminants from the cleaning composition with the contaminants and the acidic components; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an ion exchange resin (125); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>means for passing the cleaning composition with the acidic components from the distillation apparatus over the ion exchange resin (125).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>The closed-loop cleaning machine (100) of claim 10, where the means for collecting the cleaning composition with the contaminants and the acidic components from the cleaning chamber (102) include one or more storage tanks (106, 108) joined to the cleaning chamber (102) by a process stream (104).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>A method of preventing acidification of a cleaning composition in a cleaning process, comprising:<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> -->
<claim-text>providing an article having contaminants on an article surface, where the contaminants are to be removed;</claim-text>
<claim-text>contacting the article surface with the cleaning composition to remove the contaminants from the article surface, where the cleaning composition comes to have acidic components as a result of contacting the article with the cleaning composition, and where more than 85 percent by weight, based on a total weight of the cleaning composition, of the cleaning composition is an organic solvent;</claim-text>
<claim-text>collecting the cleaning composition with the contaminants and the acidic components;</claim-text>
<claim-text>separating the contaminants from the cleaning composition; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>passing the cleaning composition with the acidic components over an ion exchange resin to remove the acidic components from the cleaning composition.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>The method of claim 12, where the ion exchange resin is a strong anion exchange resin.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>The method as in any one of claims 12-13, where the ion exchange resin is in OH<sup>-</sup> form.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56985829" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Un procédé de nettoyage, comprenant :
<claim-text>mettre en contact un article ayant des salissures sur sa surface avec une composition de nettoyage pour enlever des contaminants de l'article, où la composition de nettoyage vient à avoir des composants acides en résultat de la mise en contact de l'article avec la composition de nettoyage, et où au moins 85 pour cent en poids, rapporté à un poids total de la composition de nettoyage, de la composition de nettoyage est un solvant organique ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>recueillir la composition de nettoyage avec les contaminants et les composants acides ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>séparer les contaminants de la composition de nettoyage ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>faire passer la composition de nettoyage avec les composants acides par-dessus une résine échangeuse d'ions pour enlever les composants acides de la composition de nettoyage.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Le procédé de la revendication 1, où la résine échangeuse d'ions est une résine échangeuse d'anions forte.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Le procédé de la revendication 1, où la résine échangeuse d'ions est une résine copolymère styrène-divinylbenzène.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Le procédé tel que dans n'importe laquelle des revendications précédentes, où faire passer la composition de nettoyage avec les composants acides par-dessus la résine échangeuse d'ions pour enlever les composants acides de la composition de nettoyage a lieu de façon continue.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Le procédé tel que dans n'importe laquelle des revendications 1 à 3, où faire passer la composition de nettoyage avec les composants acides par-dessus la résine échangeuse d'ions pour enlever les composants acides de la composition de nettoyage a lieu de façon semi-continue.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Le procédé tel que dans n'importe laquelle des revendications précédentes, où la composition de nettoyage est substantiellement dépourvue d'eau.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Le procédé tel que dans n'importe laquelle des revendications précédentes, où les solvants organiques dans la composition de nettoyage sont sélectionnés parmi les alcools, les éthers de propylène glycol, les éthers d'éthylène glycol, les acétates d'éther d'éthylène glycol, les acétates d'éther de propylène glycol, les esters, les hydrocarbures,<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> les hydrocarbures halogénés, ou des mélanges de ceux-ci.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Le procédé de la revendication 7, où la composition de nettoyage a un point d'ébullition compris dans une gamme allant de 40 degrés Celsius à 240 degrés Celsius.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Le procédé de la revendication 8, où la composition de nettoyage a un point d'ébullition compris dans une gamme allant de 90 degrés Celsius à 200 degrés Celsius.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Une machine de nettoyage en boucle fermée (100) pour réaliser le procédé tel que décrit dans les revendications 1 à 9, comprenant :
<claim-text>une chambre de nettoyage (102) pour mettre en contact une surface de l'article ayant des contaminants avec une composition de nettoyage pour nettoyer la surface de l'article ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un moyen destiné à recueillir la composition de nettoyage avec les contaminants et les composants acides de la chambre de nettoyage (102) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un appareil de distillation (114) destiné à séparer les contaminants de la composition de nettoyage avec les contaminants et les composants acides ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>une résine échangeuse d'ions (125) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un moyen destiné à faire passer la composition de nettoyage avec les composants acides de l'appareil de distillation par-dessus la résine échangeuse d'ions (125).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>La machine de nettoyage en boucle fermée (100) de la revendication 10, où le moyen destiné à recueillir la composition de nettoyage avec les contaminants et les composants acides de la chambre de nettoyage (102) inclut un ou plusieurs réservoirs de stockage (106, 108) joints à la chambre de nettoyage (102) par un flux à traiter (104).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Une méthode pour empêcher une acidification d'une composition de nettoyage dans un procédé de nettoyage, comprenant :
<claim-text>fournir un article ayant des contaminants sur une surface d'article, où les contaminants doivent être enlevés ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>mettre en contact la surface d'article avec la composition de nettoyage pour enlever les contaminants de la surface d'article, où la composition de nettoyage vient à avoir des composants acides en résultat de la mise en contact de l'article avec la composition de nettoyage, et où plus de 85 pour cent en poids, rapporté à un poids total de la composition de nettoyage, de la composition de nettoyage est un solvant organique ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>recueillir la composition de nettoyage avec les contaminants et les composants acides ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>séparer les contaminants de la composition de nettoyage ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>faire passer la composition de nettoyage avec les composants acides par-dessus une<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --> résine échangeuse d'ions pour enlever les composants acides de la composition de nettoyage.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>La méthode de la revendication 12, où la résine échangeuse d'ions est une résine échangeuse d'anions forte.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>La méthode telle que dans n'importe laquelle des revendications 12 à 13, où la résine échangeuse d'ions est sous une forme OH<sup>-</sup>.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16672274" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="161" he="216" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="152" he="95" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
