<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2959804-A1" country="EP" doc-number="2959804" kind="A1" date="20151230" family-id="52003709" file-reference-id="254717" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="160452297" ucid="EP-2959804-A1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2959804</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20151230</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-14461547-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP193867562" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>14461547</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20140627</date><lang>PL</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP193867563" load-source="patent-office" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>14461547.3</doc-number><date>20140627</date><lang>PL</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC162027517" ucid="EP-14461547-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>14461547</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20140627</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1988521816" load-source="docdb">F25D  25/02        20060101ALI20150216BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1988523565" load-source="docdb">A47F   3/04        20060101AFI20150216BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1987786029" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A47F   3/0491      20130101 FI20150205BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1987787247" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A47F   3/0439      20130101 LA20150205BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT165548357" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Kühlregal</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT165548358" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Refrigerated display stand</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT165548359" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Présentoir frigorifique</invention-title><citations><patent-citations><patcit mxw-id="PCIT335963490" load-source="docdb" ucid="DE-102008005736-A1"><document-id format="epo"><country>DE</country><doc-number>102008005736</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20090730</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="I" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT335963492" load-source="docdb" ucid="EP-2491828-A1"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>2491828</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20120829</date></document-id><sources><source name="APP" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT335963491" load-source="docdb" ucid="US-20100212343-A1"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>20100212343</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20100826</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="I" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT335963493" load-source="docdb" ucid="US-20140041407-A1"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>20140041407</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140213</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="X" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT335963489" load-source="docdb" ucid="US-2030780-A"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>2030780</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>19360211</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="I" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit></patent-citations></citations></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR1103315014" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>KOWALEWSKI SP Z O O</last-name><address><country>PL</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR1103344511" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>KOWALEWSKI SP. Z O. O.</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR1101650857" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Kowalewski Sp. z o. o.</last-name><iid>101463418</iid><address><street>Stawiszcze 1A</street><city>98-200 Sieradz</city><country>PL</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1103320101" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>KOWALEWSKA ALEKSANDRA</last-name><address><country>PL</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1103323680" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>Kowalewska, Aleksandra</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1101641731" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Kowalewska, Aleksandra</last-name><address><street>Stawiszcze 1A</street><city>98-200 Sieradz</city><country>PL</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR1101647189" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Rumpel, Alicja</last-name><iid>101058758</iid><address><street>Kancelaria Federowicz i Rumpel Al. Smiglego-Rydza 29/11</street><city>93-281 Lódz</city><country>PL</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS660619981" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS660622156" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS660619987" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS660705175" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS660699536" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS660621749" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS660621750" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS660787589" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS660619988" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS660619989" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS660716338" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS660705176" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS660705177" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS660787590" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS660619990" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS660787591" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS660621755" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS660699537" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS660619999" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS660705178" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS660620000" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS660787592" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS660622157" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS660787593" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS660787594" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS660622158" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS660622167" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS660716343" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS660700237" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS660716344" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS660705183" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS660716345" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS660705184" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS660716346" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS660699538" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS660700238" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS660700243" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS660622168" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states><ep-extended-states><ep-extended-state-data><country>BA</country></ep-extended-state-data><ep-extended-state-data><country>ME</country></ep-extended-state-data></ep-extended-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA166480667" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p id="pa01" num="0001">The refrigerated display stand according to the invention comprising a base (1) with enclosed one refrigerating unit (2) or more, with a refrigerating unit heat exchanger connected to it, as well as fittings (4) transporting the cooling medium, comprising at least one shelf (5) located above the unit (2) with a separated lowered temperature area, mounted to at least one support or wall and is placed above the unit so that at least 25% of its circumference is accessible, and that the lowered temperature area has the form of a heat exchanger (3) placed in the shelf structure.
<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="111" he="118" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA166760479" lang="EN" source="EPO" load-source="docdb"><p>The refrigerated display stand according to the invention comprising a base (1) with enclosed one refrigerating unit (2) or more, with a refrigerating unit heat exchanger connected to it, as well as fittings (4) transporting the cooling medium, comprising at least one shelf (5) located above the unit (2) with a separated lowered temperature area, mounted to at least one support or wall and is placed above the unit so that at least 25% of its circumference is accessible, and that the lowered temperature area has the form of a heat exchanger (3) placed in the shelf structure.</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES98405368" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><p id="p0001" num="0001">The subject of this invention is an advertising stand for displaying refrigerated merchandise, enabling contact refrigeration of displayed products.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002">Today, cooling devices, such as refrigerators or freezers are present in every household, as well as in a countless number of gastronomy or production units. Their principle of operation is always the same - to lower the temperature of the products placed inside in order to suspend the natural putrefaction or fermentation processes. Such devices include insulated housing with attached coil pipe and a heat exchanges with a compressor. Cooling down the medium transported in the coil pipes causes the reception of heat collected through the internal casing of the device and the lowering of temperature in its interior. Traditional refrigerators and freezers do not allow for presenting their contents for marketing purposes.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">Refrigerating devices for displaying food products are commonly known and used. Usually, they are equipped with counter cooling fittings, under the surface of which one or more compressors, a defrosting installation and a power supply installation are placed. Refrigerating counters ensure access for the personnel to the merchandise inside, for instance to cured meat or dairy products, restricting customer access with a glass cover facing the customer. The cover is usually equipped with doors limiting exchange of heat with the environment.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">In the case of certain food products, such as dairy articles packed in units, it is possible to allow customers to collect the merchandise straight from the shelf. In this case, it is necessary to maintain fixed temperature not exceeding a specified value (usually 7°C) on all display rack levels, which results in the most popular offer of refrigerating display racks, currently used in trade. An example of this rack is a solution according to patent claim number <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="EP2491828A"><text>EP 2491828</text></patcit>, in which the air cooled by the heat exchanger is directed via channels in the back wall in the upward direction, and then is distributed via nozzles in the form of ventilation directed towards the front onto the displayed merchandise. At the same time, as a result of contact with the channel, in which the air is transported in the upward direction in the rear wall of the rack, the rear<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> wall of the rack serves as a heat exchanger for the merchandise displayed on the shelves. This type of display rack requires the lateral surfaces to be enclosed in order to ensure the correct air circulation, as a result of which the displayed merchandise is not visible and its packaging does not evoke the desired marketing effect. Therefore, in order to ensure improved display of the merchandise, racks in the form of typical refrigerators with glazed doors and side walls are performed.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">Patent claim number <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="WO2009008849A"><text>2009008849</text></patcit> specifies a refrigerator with glazed lateral surfaces, applying traditional cooled air circulation. Bending the front surface of the refrigerator produces an uneven distribution of temperatures inside the refrigerator space, which prevents the use of racks of this type particularly for dairy products, for instance yoghurts, in which case such condition results in mold overgrowth.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">Other refrigerating devices, such as the one as per patent claim number wo2012152646 are characterized on that in order to eliminate heat loss, the transporting fittings, permanently attached to the internal walls of the refrigerator, are enclosed in a foam panel and additionally insulated with a vacuum sleeve.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">Familiar solutions focus multiple features, among which the basic one is to reach and maintain the preset temperature. Generally, however, meeting these conditions often affects the way, in which the merchandise is displayed from the marketing point of view. Therefore, the objective was to develop an advertising stand, which would allow for proper presentation of the merchandise and its simultaneous cooling. This possibility is provided by the advertising stand according to the invention.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">The advertising stand according to the invention contains a base with an enclosed refrigerating unit or more, with a refrigerating unit heat exchanger connected to it, as well as fittings transporting the cooling medium - in a beneficial embodiment of the invention, a mix of water and glycol or glycerin, in a beneficial embodiment of the invention, in a 50/50 ratio - as well as at least one shelf located above the unit, with a separated lowered temperature area. At least one shelf is mounted to at least one support or wall and is placed above the unit so that at least 25% of its circumference is accessible without the need to go round the walls or supports. The fittings transporting<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> the cooling medium link the refrigerating unit, the heat exchanger and the heat exchangers of the shelves 5.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">In a beneficial embodiment, the connecting fittings of the refrigerating unit and at least one shelf are located in ducts in at least one wall or support, and all fitting connections are performed as quick couplings.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">The lowered temperature area is performed as at least one heat exchanger shelf, preferably of the plate-type, located in the structure. In a beneficial embodiment, the entire shelf is a heat exchanger, preferably a plate-type. A plate heat exchanger is equipped with an upper plate, preferably made of aluminum, at least 3 mm thick, and a coil pipe made of aluminum or copper pipe, preferably 6 mm in diameter, which is located under the plate. The heat exchanger is separated from the styrofoam shelf, in whose structure it is located, using a tray, preferably made as a perforated shelf out of plastic. At least one shelf, in which the plate heat exchanger is located, is made of material with insulating properties, preferably out of styrofoam. Water condensed on the shelf surface is drained from the tray through at least one drain hole and a tube. In a beneficial embodiment of the invention, the tray and the plate are surface-finished in the form of sprayed-on silver or copper ions preventing the development of microorganisms.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">The tube draining water leads to the base of the advertising stand according to the invention, and its outlet is located in a partially open container, which also houses the refrigerating unit heat exchanger and preferably a heater for vaporizing the condensate.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">The refrigerating unit is controlled by a thermostat, which offers at least two modes of operation, that is cooling the plate exchanger to maintain fixed temperature, also in the case of below-zero temperatures, and temporary defrosting. The cooling glycol solution is cooled in a temperature exchanger within the scope from -7°C to -12°C.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">The advertising stand according to the invention guarantees perfect display of the merchandise in the form of cans or beverage bottles. Due to the contact cooling method, the solution is particularly suitable for cooling and displaying beverages in<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> aluminum cans. In the case of cooled products, apart from lowering their temperature, it was proven that strong cooling, below 0°C magnified the marketing effect of their packaging, since the resulting temperature difference between the upper and lower surface of the packaging leads to condensation on the external packaging surfaces. In the case of beverages, for instance beer or other sparkling beverages, this effect suggests that the beverage is at ideal drinking temperature.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">After collecting the product from the advertising stand according to the invention, the contents of the packaging is mixed and the temperature is homogenized, therefore, as confirmed by laboratory tests, while consuming, the temperature of the displayed product is not differentiated.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">The advertising stand according to the invention is presented in the figure, in which <figref idrefs="f0001">fig. 1</figref> presents the cross-section of the advertising stand according to the invention, and <figref idrefs="f0002">fig. 2</figref> presents the cross-section and the vertical section of the stand shelf according to the invention.</p><heading id="h0001">Example I</heading><p id="p0016" num="0016">The advertising stand according to the invention contains a base 1 with an enclosed refrigerating unit 2 or more, with a refrigerating unit heat exchanger 3 connected to it, as well as fittings 4 transporting the cooling medium, as well as at least one shelf 5 located above the unit 2, with a separated lowered temperature area. The shelves are mounted to a support and are placed above the unit so that 100% of its circumference is accessible without the need to go round the walls or supports. The fittings 4 transporting the cooling medium link the refrigerating unit, the heat exchanger 3 and the heat exchangers of shelves 5.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">The lowered temperature area is performed as at least one heat exchanger 7 shelf. The shelves 5, in which the plate heat exchanger 7 is located, are made of material with insulating properties, preferably out of styrofoam. The heat exchanger 7 is in the form of a coil pipe located under the aluminum plate, and a tray 6 equipped with drainage, located in between them and the styrofoam shelf 5. Water is drained through<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> a tube leading to the base 1, the outlet of which is located in a partially open container 8, which also houses the refrigerating unit 2 heat exchanger 3 and preferably a heater.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">The refrigerating unit 2 is controlled by a thermostat, which offers at least two modes of operation, that is cooling the plate exchanger to maintain fixed temperature, also in the case of below-zero temperatures, and temporary defrosting.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">The advertising stand according to the invention guarantees perfect display of the merchandise in the form of cans or beverage bottles. Due to the contact cooling method, the solution is particularly suitable for cooling and displaying beverages in aluminum cans. In the case of cooled products, apart from lowering their temperature, it was proven that strong cooling, below 0°C magnified the marketing effect of their packaging, since the resulting temperature difference between the upper and lower surface of the packaging leads to condensation on the external packaging surfaces. In the case of beverages, for instance beer or other sparkling beverages, this effect suggests that the beverage is at ideal drinking temperature.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">After collecting the product from the advertising stand according to the invention, the contents of the packaging is mixed and the temperature is homogenized, therefore, as confirmed by laboratory tests, while consuming, the temperature of the displayed product is not differentiated.</p><heading id="h0002">Example II</heading><p id="p0021" num="0021">The advertising stand according to the invention contains a base 1 with an enclosed refrigerating unit 2, a refrigerating unit heat exchanger 3, as well as fittings 4 transporting the cooling medium, as well as at least one shelf 5 located above the unit 2, with a separated lowered temperature area. The shelves are mounted to a support and are placed above the unit so that their surfaces are accessible without the need to go round the walls or supports. The fittings 4 transporting the cooling medium link the refrigerating unit, the heat exchanger 3 and the heat exchangers of shelves 5.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">The shelves 5 housing the heat exchanger 7 are made of material with insulating properties, preferably out of styrofoam. The heat exchanger 7 is in the form of a coil pipe 10 located under the aluminum plate 9, and a tray 6 equipped with drainage,<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> located in between them and the styrofoam shelf 5. Water is drained through a tube leading to the base 1, the outlet of which is located in a partially open container 8, which also houses the refrigerating unit 2 heat exchanger 3 and preferably a heater.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">The refrigerating unit 2 is controlled by a thermostat, which offers at least two modes of operation, that is cooling the plate exchanger to maintain fixed temperature, also in the case of below-zero temperatures, and temporary defrosting.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">The advertising stand according to the invention guarantees perfect display of the merchandise in the form of cans or beverage bottles. Due to the contact cooling method, the solution is particularly suitable for cooling and displaying beverages in aluminum cans. In the case of cooled products, apart from lowering their temperature, it was proven that strong cooling, below 0°C magnified the marketing effect of their packaging, since the resulting temperature difference between the upper and lower surface of the packaging leads to condensation on the external packaging surfaces. In the case of beverages, for instance beer or other sparkling beverages, this effect suggests that the beverage is at ideal drinking temperature.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">After collecting the product from the advertising stand according to the invention, the contents of the packaging is mixed and the temperature is homogenized, therefore, as confirmed by laboratory tests, while consuming, the temperature of the displayed product is not differentiated.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM90460329" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --><claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>The advertising stand according to the invention comprising a base with enclosed one refrigerating unit or more, with a refrigerating unit heat exchanger connected to it, as well as fittings transporting the cooling medium, <b>characterized in that</b> is comprises at least one shelf (5) located above the unit (2), with a separated lowered temperature area, mounted to at least one support or wall and is placed above the unit so that at least 25% of its circumference is accessible, and that the lowered temperature area has the form of a heat exchanger placed in the shelf structure.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The advertising stand as per claim 1 <b>characterized in that</b> the fittings (4) transporting the cooling medium link the refrigerating unit (2) with the heat exchanger (7) of the lowered temperature area, and that the cooling medium is a mixture of water and glycerin.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The advertising stand as per claim 2 <b>characterized in that</b> the fittings (4) transporting the cooling medium link the refrigerating unit (2) with the heat exchanger (7) of the lowered temperature area, and that the cooling medium is a mixture of water and glycerin in the 50/50 ratio.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The advertising stand as per claim 2 <b>characterized in that</b> at least one shelf (5) with a lowered temperature area is mounted to the wall or support so that they are connected with feather-rabbet elements, and that the transporting fittings (4) are additionally insulated.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The advertising stand as per claim 1, 2, 3 or 4 <b>characterized in that</b> the connecting fittings of the refrigerating unit (2) and at least one shelf (5) are located in ducts in at least one wall or support, and all fitting connections are performed as quick couplings</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The advertising stand as per claim 1, 2, 3, 4 or 5 <b>characterized in that</b> the lowered temperature area is performed as at least one heat exchanger (7) shelf (5), preferably of the plate-type, located in the structure, wherein the plate heat exchanger (7) is equipped with an upper plate (9), preferably made of aluminum, at least 3 mm thick, and a coil pipe (10) is located under the plate.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The advertising stand as per claim 6 <b>characterized in that</b> at least one shelf (5) has the form of a heat exchanger.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The advertising stand as per claim 6 or 7 <b>characterized in that</b> the coil pipe (10) of the heat exchanger (7) is made of aluminum or copper pipe, of at least 6 mm in diameter.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The advertising stand as per claim 6, 7 or 8 <b>characterized in that</b> the heat exchanger (7) is separated from the styrofoam shelf (5) with a tray.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The advertising stand as per claim 9 <b>characterized in that</b> the tray is performed as a pressed PET foil element, and that a tube leading from the tray is connected to a container housing the refrigerating unit (2) heat exchanger (3).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>he advertising stand as per claim 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8, 9 or 10 <b>characterized in that</b> the surface of the shelves (5) and the transport fittings (4) have a sprayed-on silver or copper ion layer.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW20422999" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="148" he="156" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="140" he="123" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="129" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --><figure id="f0004" num="4"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="156" he="167" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><search-report-data><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="162" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="162" he="233" type="tif"/></search-report-data><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
