<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-1727627-B1" country="EP" doc-number="1727627" kind="B1" date="20140101" family-id="35056759" file-reference-id="306737" date-produced="20180822" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146553793" ucid="EP-1727627-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>1727627</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-05726016-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154827716" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>05726016</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20050321</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP174943462" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>05726016.8</doc-number><date>20050321</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140449569" ucid="US-2005009437-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>2005009437</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20050321</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140446697" ucid="US-55457704-P" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>55457704</doc-number><kind>P</kind><date>20040319</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140446265" ucid="US-56530304-P" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>56530304</doc-number><kind>P</kind><date>20040426</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140452701" ucid="US-62037704-P" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>62037704</doc-number><kind>P</kind><date>20041020</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140450338" ucid="US-63376604-P" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>63376604</doc-number><kind>P</kind><date>20041207</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140451074" ucid="US-8385905-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>8385905</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20050318</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130711</date></intention-to-grant-date><search-report-dispatch-date><date>20110816</date></search-report-dispatch-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988096138" load-source="docdb">B08B   9/093       20060101AFI20130603BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988116798" load-source="docdb">E21B  27/00        20060101ALI20130603BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988118261" load-source="docdb">B01D  21/00        20060101ALI20130603BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988121461" load-source="docdb">B01D  21/24        20060101ALI20130603BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988125671" load-source="docdb">C02F   1/38        20060101ALI20130603BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988125678" load-source="docdb">B01D  21/02        20060101ALI20130603BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2034567330" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B01D  21/34        20130101 LI20150729BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2036734316" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B01D  21/2472      20130101 LI20150723BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2036734852" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B01D  21/2483      20130101 LI20150723BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2051767799" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">C02F   1/38        20130101 LA20150520BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2051774836" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B01D2221/04        20130101 LA20150518BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2051780085" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B01D  21/02        20130101 LI20150520BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2051780791" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B08B   9/0933      20130101 FI20150520BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2051783958" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B08B   9/093       20130101 LI20150520BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132193863" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">AUTOMATISCHES TANKREINIGUNGSSYSTEM</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132193864" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">AUTOMATIC TANK CLEANING SYSTEM</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132193865" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">SYSTEME AUTOMATIQUE DE NETTOYAGE DE BASSIN</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918168997" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>MI LLC</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918139638" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>M-I L.L.C.</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918147242" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>ERIKSEN FRANK</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918159946" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>ERIKSEN, FRANK</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918997913" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>ERIKSEN, FRANK</last-name><address><street>1300 Woodhollow Dr. Apt. 24101</street><city>Houston, TX 77056</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918997915" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>M-I L.L.C.</last-name><iid>100170269</iid><address><street>5950 North Course Drive</street><city>Houston, TX 77072</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918997914" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Gill, Stephen Charles</last-name><suffix>et al</suffix><iid>100058353</iid><address><street>Mewburn Ellis LLP 33 Gutter Lane</street><city>London EC2V 8AS</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="US-2005009437-W"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2005009437</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20050321</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2005092046-A2"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2005092046</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20051006</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548868034" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS548979736" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS548830135" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS548986765" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS548982641" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS548868035" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS548979737" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548982642" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS548982643" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS548990212" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS548830136" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS548986766" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548979738" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548982644" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS548868036" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS548990213" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS548982645" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS548830137" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS548982646" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS548830138" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS548980508" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS548830139" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS548990214" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS548990215" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS548830140" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS548868037" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS548990216" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS548986767" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS548885388" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS548980509" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63957418" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001"><b>BACKGROUND OF INVENTION</b></heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">Rotary drilling methods employing a drill bit and drill stems have long been used to drill wellbores in subterranean formations. Drilling fluids or muds are commonly circulated in the well during such drilling to cool and lubricate the drilling apparatus, lift cuttings out of the wellbore, and counterbalance the subterranean formation pressure encountered. Drilling fluids and muds often contain entrained solids which have been purposefully added, such as: weighting agents, such as barite, hematite, aluminite, and the like; viscosifying agents including sepolite clay, and other viscosifying clays; and fluid loose control agents, etc... as well as very fine solid particles generated by the drilling process. Unlike drill cuttings, these entrained solids are difficult to remove by screening. However, upon standing, the solids often settle out over long periods of time (i.e. hours to days). Thus when the used drilling fluids or muds are being stored in tanks awaiting transport for recycling, these entrained solids typically settle out into the bottom of the tank and form a dense layer of solids.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002">Removal of the settled entrained solids from the bottom of a tank has proven to be a difficult problem. The current state of the art is to have a crew of at least two men enter the drained tank and using high pressure washing equipment and vacuums, wash and remove via vacuum the dense layer of solids. Such operations are both time and labor intensive and involve placing people inside of large storage tanks which raises certain safety concerns. One alternative has been to use tanks with a steep conical sidewall shape which helps prevent the settling of the solids. However, such tanks are expensive and an inefficient use of space on an offshore drilling rig or drilling rig service boat.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US5908040A"><text>US5908040</text></patcit> discloses a method of cleaning boats that have been contaminated with oil and gas well drilling fluids and hazardous waste. <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="GB2228751A"><text>GB 2228751 A</text></patcit> discloses a grease trap having a removable bucket.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">Thus there exists an ongoing need for improvements in the apparatus and methods used to clean tanks of sediments and solids deposited in them.</p><heading id="h0002"><b>SUMMARY</b></heading><p id="p0005" num="0005">A first aspect of the present invention provides an apparatus according to claim 1. A second aspect of the present invention provides a method according to claim 13.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">The present disclosure is generally directed to an apparatus and method for washing / cleaning the inside of a tank in which fluid having entrained solids have been stored. One illustrative embodiment of the present invention is a portable or permanently installed tank washing system which recovers water from slop (dirty cleaning water) by separating water, oil, and solids. The slop is directed to a water recycling unit. The solids collected in the water recycling unit are sent to a cuttings box that is temporarily modified to serve as a weir tank. In the cuttings box weir tank, water is recovered and pumped back to the water recycling unit. An overflow line from the water recycling unit is also connected to the same cutting box to prevent overfilling the tank. The same overflow line sends separated oil to the cuttings box. Water that passes under the weir in the water recycling unit is directed to one or more hydrocyclones. The purge flow from the hydrocyclone is sent to the cuttings box weir tank. The overflow from the hydrocyclone is sent to the clean water compartment of the water recycling unit. Water recovered by the water recycling unit is pumped to the tank cleaning machines via<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> a chemical inductor where cleaning chemicals may be added. Tank cleaning machines are rotary jet heads that clean the internal surfaces of the tank.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">One of skill in the art will notice that the illustrated system can be portable; it recycles the water by separating solids (barite) using hydrocyclones in line with a weir tank that also serves as a buffer tank. It uses a hydraulic portable submersible pump and a any kind of cuttings box serving as a temporary weir tank to bring back the water to the process.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">Other aspects and advantages of the claimed subject matter will be apparent from the following description and the appended claims.</p><heading id="h0003"><b>DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</b></heading><p id="p0009" num="0009"><ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> is a schematic view of the automatic tank cleaning system.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref> is a cutaway perspective view of the water recycling unit tank.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3</figref> is a schematic view of the skidded components of the automatic tank cleaning system.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 4</figref> is a schematic view of one embodiment of a washer nozzle head placement.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005">Figure 5</figref> is a schematic view of one embodiment of a washer nozzle head placement.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0004"><b>DETAILED DESCRIPTION</b></heading><p id="p0010" num="0010">The above illustrative embodiment will be better understood with reference to <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> in which the tank cleaning system 10 is schematically shown. One of skill in the art should appreciate that the schematic utilizes generally accepted representations of pumps, etc., which should be well known.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">Turning now to <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>, the tank cleaning system 10 includes a water recycling unit 19 and one or more rotary jet head washers 60. Discussion of the components of this closed system will begin with the rotary jet head washers 60.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3</figref>, one or more of the rotary jet head washers 60 are positioned within the mud tank 18. Although shown as being fixed in position, these multi -headed or single-headed nozzle rotary jet heads 60 may be lowered into the tank 18 or otherwise suspended and positioned temporarily or permanently within the tank 18 using brackets 83, stands, penetration through the deck/side of the tank or the like. The rotary jet heads 60 are supplied with pressurized wash fluid by way of the wash fluid lines 84. The rotation of the nozzles might be provided by a pneumatic motor or by a turbine in the cleaning fluid flow. As the wash fluid exits the rotary jet heads 60, the tank 18 is washed with pressurized wash fluid which dislodges any solids or sediments present in the tank 18, thus generating tank slop 85 which is a combination of solids and wash fluid. A hydraulic pump 62 connected to a hydraulic power unit 88 is used to take up the tank slop 85 and pump the combination of solids and wash fluid up the tank slop line 90. As shown, the hydraulic pump 62 is lowered into the tank 18 for use in the washing operation, but alternatively the pump 62 may be mounted either temporarily on brackets or permanently mounted in the tank 18. The tank slop line 90 carries the tank slop 85 directly to the water recycling unit 19 or through a modular fluid distribution manifold 92 which is designed with control valves (not shown) and hose connections 94, or preferably quick connect hose lines. The tank slop 85 is then pumped by way of the external slop line 96 to the water recycling unit 19.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, the water recycling unit 19 includes a water recycling tank 20, a cuttings box 16, and a hydrocyclone 80. The water recycling tank 20 is a type of weir tank having a weir 22 extending from a top cover (shown but not numbered) into the water recycling unit to separate a dirty water compartment 33 from a clean water compartment 30. The tank slop 85 is pumped into the top portion of the water recycling tank 20 at<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> an inlet 24 located near the top edge distal the weir 22. A turbulence preventer 31 preferably is included near all water and slop inlets and outlets to prevent turbulence in the water recycling unit 19. Such a turbulence preventer 31 may be of any structure sufficient to dissipate the force associated with a well-defined fluid streams, including a shield, a forked nozzle to disperse the stream into multiple streams, or other type of diffuser. The water recycling tank 20 has a sloped bottom 25, which might be round, squared or rectangular. The solids 26 from the tank slop 85 fall to the bottom of the water recycling tank 20 and are gathered in the sloped bottom 25. The solids that collect at the sloped bottom 25 of the water recycling tank 20 are pumped by an auger fed progressive cavity pump 28 to the cutting box 16 through a line 27 at a volumetric flow rate Q6. Alternatively, the solids may be released from the water recycling tank 20 by a valve and pumped to the cuttings box 16.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">The liquid in the water recycling tank 20 that is just about to enter the clean water compartment 30 from the dirty water compartment 33 may be pumped to one or more hydrocyclones 80. Small solids that did not settle out of the fluid when introduced in the water recycling tank 20 are removed by the centrifugal force created within the hydrocyclone 80. Solids are directed by purge flow line 66 from the hydrocyclone 80 to the cuttings box 16 with a volumetric flow rate Q5. The solids may be gravity fed or pumped from the hydrocyclone 80. The overflow from the hydrocyclone 80 is directed through line 64 to the clean water compartment 30 with a volumetric flow rate Q4. A turbulence preventer 31, located at the inlet of the clean water compartment 30 prevents turbulence and may be a shield, a forked nozzle to disperse the stream into multiple streams, or other type of diffuser. As will be shown, the substantially solids-lean wash fluid generated by the separation units is recycled to serve as the wash fluid.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">An overflow line 21 from the water recycling unit 20 directs fluid from the top portion of the water recycling tank 20 to the cuttings box 16 with a volumetric flow rate Q7. The fluid through overflow line 21 may be pumped or gravity fed to the cuttings box 16. The overflow line 21 prevents spills caused by overfilling the water recycling tank 20 and directs separated oil to the cuttings box 16.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">The cutting box 16 used to promote the settling of the solids 42 from the solid slurry may be any cutting box normally found onboard drilling rigs. To promote such settling of solids, a temporary and portable weir bucket 15 may be utilized. The weir bucket 15 is suspended within the cuttings box 16 above the cuttings box floor 14. As the level of solids 42 in the cuttings box 16 rises, the weir bucket 15 may be raised so that solids do not drop over the weir bucket wall 17 into the weir bucket 15. The substantially solids-lean fluid 44 in the cuttings box 16 is allowed to overflow into the weir bucket 15. An oil trap 45 surrounds an upper portion of the weir bucket 15. The oil trap 45 is spaced apart from the weir bucket 15 and preferably is substantially parallel with the weir bucket wall 17. The oil trap 45 has a top edge 46 located above the top edge 13 of the weir bucket 15, and a bottom edge 47 located below the top edge 13 of the weir bucket 15. Once the level of fluid 44 within the cuttings box 16 rises to the level of the bottom edge 47 of the oil trap 45, any oil floating atop the fluid 44 is prevented from flowing into the weir bucket 15 by the oil trap 45. Water will pass under the oil trap 45, and to the space between the oil trap 45 and the weir bucket 15 before overflowing into the weir bucket 15. From within the weir bucket 15, the substantially solids-lean fluid is pumped through fluid line 48 to the clean water compartment 30 of the water recycling tank 20 with a volumetric flow rate Q8.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">As previously discussed, the cuttings box 16 may be any cuttings box as used onboard a rig and as typically used to transport drill cuttings. Once a first cuttings box 16 is nearly full with solids 42, the weir<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> bucket 15 is removed and positioned within a second, empty cuttings box 16. The second cuttings box 16 then replaces the first cuttings box 16. Valves may be used to temporarily stop or divert the flow to the first cuttings box 16 while it is replaced with the second cuttings box 16.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">The flow from each flow line 21, 27, 66, may be commingled in a hopper and directed into the cuttings box 16 in a controlled stream. A turbulence preventer 31 may be included to minimize agitation to the solids 42 collected in the cuttings box 16 and prevent remixing of the solids 42 and the fluid 44. The turbulence preventer 31 may include diffusing nozzles or forked flow directors at each outlet to reduce the force associated with any one flow while maintaining the overall flow rate into the cuttings box 16.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">The flow of fluid into the clean water compartment 30 comes from the weir bucket 15 at a flow rate Q8 and from the hydrocyclone overflow line 64 at a flow rate Q4. The total volumetric flow rate into the clean water compartment 30 is thus Q8 + Q4. The flow rate of the fluid out of the clean water compartment 30 to the mud tank 18 is Q1. In the water recycling tank 20, the total flow rate into the clean water compartment, Q8 + Q4 typically will be greater than the flow rate Q1 to the mud tank 18 resulting in positive pressure inside the clean water compartment 30. That is, the pressure inside the clean water compartment 30 will be greater than the pressure within the remainder of the water recycling tank 20. Thus, the water within the clean water compartment 30 is not contaminated with dirty fluid from within the dirty water compartment 33 of the water recycling tank 20 as long as the hydrocyclone 80 is in use.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">The use of hydrocyclones 80 to remove fine solids from the water is not necessary for the operation of the automatic tank cleaning system 10, however efficiency of the system 10 is reduced when no further separation operations are included.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0001">Figs. 1</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0002">2</figref>, the water recycling tank 20 includes turbulence preventers 31 at the inlet to the clean water compartment 30 from flow lines 48, 64 where the combined volumetric flow rate is Q4+Q8, the outlet to the flow line to the hydrocyclone 80 where the volumetric flow rate is Q3, the outlet to flow line 84 to the mud tank nozzles 60 where the flow rate is Q1, and the inlet to the water recycling tank 20 from the mud tank 18 where the flow rate is Q2. In addition, turbulence preventers are included where the hydrocyclone over flow line 64, the overflow line 21 from the water recycling tank 20, and the solids discharge line 27 enter the cuttings box 16 with flow rates of Q5, Q7, and Q6, respectively. Turbulence inside the water recycling tank 20 and the cuttings box 16, or forces that cause the water to spin inside the tank or cuttings box, reduces the efficiency of the automatic cleaning system 10. Therefore, it is important to prevent such turbulence. The turbulence preventer 31 breaks the stream from the individual flow lines.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">The clean water from the clean water compartment 30 is pumped through flow line 84 with a volumetric flow rate of Q1, to one or more rotary jet heads 60 that clean the tank 18. Upon consideration of the above illustrative apparatus, one of skill in the art should understand and comprehend the method by which a tank can be quickly and easily cleaned of sediment or other solids that may be present. It also should be appreciated that a wide variety of wash fluids will be able to used with the present illustrated embodiment. Such fluids may include detergents, surfactants, antifoaming agents, suspending agents, lubricating agents (to reduce the wear caused by the flowing solids), and the like to assist in the quick and efficient cleaning of the tank. A chemical inductor 50 may be used to add such cleaning chemicals 51 to the wash water.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">The water recycling tank 20 also acts as a buffer tank. The transfer of clean water from the clean water compartment 30 to the mud tank 18 and the return of slop, or dirty water, from the mud tank 18 to the water<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> recycling tank 20 is not instantaneous. In addition to the time required for the fluid to cycle from the mud tank 18 to the water recycling tank 20, solids in the mud tank 18 can trap water and further delay the return of slop to the water recycling unit tank 20. The buffer capacity compensates for this delay of return.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">The water recycling tank 20 has a minimum operational level 23a and a maximum operational level 23b. The minimum operational level 23a is located slightly above the outlet to flow line 84 to the mud tank 18. When the fluid level within the water recycling tank 20 drops below the minimum operational level 23a, the flow through flow line 84 will stop. When the fluid level within the water recycling tank 20 raises above the maximum operational level 23b, the fluid will flow into overflow line 21 to the cuttings box 16. The overflow line 21 will direct oil that has separated from the water in the dirty water compartment to the cuttings box 16.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">Upon reflection, one of skill in the art will appreciate that with a system as described herein, a wide variety of tanks, specifically mud tanks can be cleaned automatically, faster, safer and with less people than using manual labor. Further it will be appreciated that the disclosed system will reduce or eliminate confined space entry, which is required under the current state of the art practices. In addition it will be appreciated by such a skilled artisan that the disclosed systems and methods will reduce the quantity of waste generated in the cleaning process as compared to other state of the art apparatus and methods.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">With reference to <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 5</figref> the strategic positioning of the washers within the tank can be an important to maximize the cleaning action of the rotary jet heads. The list of factors taken into account in the placement of the rotary jet heads include: the design and nature of the effective cleaning area and pattern of the rotary jet heads; the position of the rotary jet head relative to the tank's surfaces to be cleaned; the presence or absence of bulkheads or other supporting structures; the presence of any "shadow" areas within the tank that may prove difficult to clean; the extent of wash overlap (i.e. areas of the tank that are washed by more than one of the rotary jet heads) desired; the areas of the tank where maximum cleaning is desired; the desirable pattern of washing towards the pump and other factors which will be apparent to one of skill in the art. It should be appreciated that each tank will have an optimum location pattern for the washer nozzles. This optimum pattern may be determined by taking into account the above noted factors, or alternatively by simple trial and error methods of temporarily locating the washers and running tests to optimize the washing effect.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">With reference to <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 5</figref> it should be noted that in some instances the rotary jet heads will be mounted on brackets and extension pipes above the surface of the tank to achieve the optimized washing effect. The use of tubing and brackets of various angles will necessarily depend upon the tank configuration as will be appreciated by one of skill in the art. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 5</figref>. a change in the types of nozzles used (i.e. the nozzles spray pattern in one figure are "programmable" and in the second they are fixed) causes a change in the configuration of and placement of the nozzles. With the benefit of the present disclosure, one of skill in the art should be able to maximize the washing efficiency of the nozzles within a specific tank without undue experimentation.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">While the claimed subject matter has been described with respect to a limited number of embodiments, those skilled in the art, having benefit of this disclosure, will appreciate that other embodiments can be devised which do not depart from the scope of the claimed subject-matter.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56979743" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Reinigen eines Behälters (18) mit einer Innenfläche und einer Bodenfläche, wobei die Vorrichtung Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>einen Wasserwiederaufbereitungsbehälter (20), der einen Einlass (24) und einen konisch geformten Boden (25) mit einem Auslass umfasst, worin eine Reinwasserkammer (30) und eine Schmutzwasserkammer (33) durch ein Wehr (22) voneinander getrennt sind;</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Schneidkasten (16), der in Fluidverbindung mit dem Auslass am Boden des Wasserwiederaufbereitungsbehälters (20) steht:
<claim-text>eine Vielzahl von Düsen (60), die innerhalb des Behälters (18) angeordnet sind, worin jede Düse in Fluidverbindung mit der Reinwasserkammer (30) steht und betätigbar ist, ein Reinfluid in den Behälter abzugeben, um Feststoffe, die auf den Innen- und Bodenflächen anhaften, zu verlagern; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Pumpe (62), die betätigbar ist, um Fluid und verlagerte Feststoffe von der Bodenfläche des Behälters (18) zum Einlass (24) der Wasserwiederaufbereitungseinheit (19) zu pumpen;</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text><b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die Vorrichtung ferner Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>eine transportable Wehrwanne (15), die innerhalb des Schneidkastens (16) wahlweise hängend angeordnet ist und eine obere Kante (13) aufweist, über die im Wesentlichen Feststoff-freies Fluid in die Wehrwanne strömen kann, so dass die Wehrwanne (15) einen Fluidsammelbereich für das im Wesentlichen Feststoff-freie Fluid definiert; und eine Fluidleitung (48), durch die das im Wesentlichen Feststoff-freie Fluid im Fluidsammelbereich zur Reinwasserkammer (30) gepumpt wird.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Vorrichtung nach Anspruch 1, ferner umfassend:
<claim-text>ein Trenneinheit mit einem Einlass, der in Fluidverbindung mit dem Hauptbehälter der Wasserwiederaufbereitungseinheit steht und im Wesentlichen der Reinwasserkammer Feststoff-freies Abwasser bereitstellt und Feststoffe in den Schneidkasten abgibt.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Vorrichtung nach Anspruch 2, worin die Trenneinheit (80) eine Hydrozyklon-Trenneinheit ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Vorrichtung nach Anspruch 2, ferner umfassend:
<claim-text>eine modulare Fluidverteilungseinheit, die Steuerventile umfasst, die betätigbar sind, um die Strömung des Fluids und der verlagerten Feststoffe vom Behälter zum Einlass der Wasserwiederaufbereitungseinheit zu steuern.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Vorrichtung nach Anspruch 4, worin die Strömung des Fluids und der verlagerten Feststoffe in den Einlass (24) des Wasserwiederaufbereitungsbehälters (20) dissipiert wird, um Turbulenzen in der Schmutzwasserkammer zu vermeiden.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Vorrichtung nach Anspruch 2, ferner umfassend:
<claim-text>eine Überlaufleitung (21), die Reinigungsfluid und getrenntes Öl oberhalb eines Maximalbetriebsniveaus (23b) der Schmutzwasserkammer des Wasserwiederaufbereitungsbehälters (20) zum Schneidkasten (16) leitet.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Vorrichtung nach Anspruch 6, worin die Wasserwiederaufbereitungseinheit (19) ein Minimalbetriebsniveau (23a) aufweist, unter dem das Fluid aufhört, zwischen der Reinwasserkammer (30) und den Düsen (60) kommuniziert zu werden.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Vorrichtung nach Anspruch 1, worin die Wasserwiederaufbereitungseinheit (19) ferner Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>eine schneckenversorgte Pumpe (28), um die Fluidverbindung von Feststoffen vom Auslass der Schmutzwasserkammer (33) zum Schneidkasten (16) wahlweise bereitzustellen oder zu stoppen.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Vorrichtung nach Anspruch 1, worin die tragbare Wehrwanne (15) im Schneidkasten (16) einen Wehrboden und eine Wehrwand mit einer Oberkante (13) umfasst, die darin eine Buchse definiert.<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Vorrichtung nach Anspruch 9, worin die transportable Wehrwanne (15) wahlweise innerhalb des Schneidkastens (16) angehoben und gesenkt werden kann.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Vorrichtung nach Anspruch 9, ferner umfassend:
<claim-text>einen Ölfang (45), der beabstandet von und parallel zur Seite der temporären Wehrwanne (15) angeordnet ist und oberhalb der Bodenfläche des Schneidkastens (16) zurückgehalten ist, worin der Ölfang (45) eine Oberkante, die oberhalb der Oberkante der Wehrwand angeordnet ist, und eine Bodenkante, die unterhalb der Oberkante der Wehrwand angeordnet ist, umfasst.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Vorrichtung nach Anspruch 1, ferner umfassend:
<claim-text>einen chemischen Induktor (50) zwischen der Reinwasserkammer (30) und den Düsen (60), worin der chemische Induktor (50) dem in Richtung der Düsen (60) verlaufenden Fluid Reinigungsverbindungen bereitstellt.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Verfahren zur Wiederaufbereitung von Wasser in einem Behälterreinigungssystem, umfassend:
<claim-text>Sammeln der Behälterschlempe (85) vom Schmutzwassertank (18);</claim-text>
<claim-text>Pumpen der Behälterschlempe (85) zu einer Schmutzwasserkammer (33) eines Wasserwiederaufbereitungsbehälters (20);</claim-text>
<claim-text>Sammeln von Feststoffen (26) von der Behälterschlempe auf einem geneigten Boden (25) des Wasserwiederaufbereitungstanks (20);</claim-text>
<claim-text>Übertragen der Feststoffe (26) vom Boden des Wasserwiederaufbereitungsbehälters (20) an einen Schneidkasten (16);</claim-text>
<claim-text>Pumpen von Fluid von der Schmutzwasserkammer (33) des Wasserwiederaufbereitungsbehälters (20) zu einer Hydrozyklon-Trenneinheit (80);</claim-text>
<claim-text>Trennen kleinerer Feststoffe von dem Fluid in der Hydrozyklon-Trenneinheit (80);</claim-text>
<claim-text>Abgeben der Feststoffe von der Hydrozyklon-Trenneinheit (80) zum Schneidkasten (16);</claim-text>
<claim-text>Übertragen von Abwasser von der Hydrozyklon-Trenneinheit (80) zu einer Reinwasserkammer (30) im Wasserwiederaufbereitungsbehälter (20); und<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>Pumpen des Fluids von der Reinwasserkammer (30) zu zumindest einem Drehstrahlkopf (60) innerhalb des schmutzigen Behälters (18);</claim-text>
wobei das Verfahren ferner Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>Sammeln von Fluid in einer transportablen Wehrwanne (15), die in dem Schneidkasten (16) hängend angeordnet ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Pumpen des Fluids von innerhalb der transportablen Wehrwanne (15) zur Reinwasserkammer (30) der Wasserwiederaufbereitungseinheit (19).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 13, ferner umfassend:
<claim-text>Leiten von Fluid oberhalb eines Maximalbetriebsniveaus (23b) im Hauptbehälter (20) der Wasserwiederaufbereitungseinheit (19) zum Schneidkasten (16);</claim-text>
<claim-text>Entfernen der transportablen Wehrwanne (15) im Schneidkasten (16), wenn der Schneidkasten voll ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Austauschen der transportablen Wehrwanne (15) in einem anderen Schneidkasten (16), der anstelle des vollen Schneidkastens (16) zu verwenden ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56979744" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>An apparatus for cleaning a tank (18) having an inner surface and a bottom surface, the apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a water recycling tank (20) including an inlet (24) and a conically-shaped bottom (25) having an outlet, wherein a weir (22) separates a clean water compartment (30) and a dirty water compartment (33);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a cutting box (16) in fluid communication with the outlet in the bottom of the water recycling tank (20):
<claim-text>a plurality of nozzles (60) located within the tank (18), wherein each nozzle is in fluid communication with the clean water compartment (30) and is operable to discharge clean fluid into the tank to dislodge solids affixed to the inner and bottom surfaces; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pump (62) operable to pump fluid and dislodged solids from the bottom surface of the tank (18) to the inlet (24) of the water recycling unit (19);</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text><b>characterised in that</b> the apparatus further comprises:
<claim-text>a portable weir bucket (15) selectively suspended within the cutting box (16) and having a top edge (13) over which substantially solids-free fluid may flow into the weir bucket, such that the weir bucket (15) defines a fluid collection area for the substantially solids-free fluid; and a fluid line (48) through which the substantially solids-free fluid in the fluid collection area is pumped to the clean water compartment (30).</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The apparatus of claim 1, further comprising:
<claim-text>a separator having an inlet in fluid communication with the main tank of the water recycling unit and providing substantially solids-free effluent to the clean water compartment and discharging solids to the cutting box.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The apparatus of claim 2, wherein the separator (80) is a hydrocylone separator.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The apparatus of claim 2, further comprising:
<claim-text>a modular fluid distribution manifold including control valves operable to control flow of fluid and dislodged solids from the tank to the inlet of the water recycling unit.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The apparatus of claim 4 wherein the flow of fluid and dislodged solids into the inlet (24) of the water recycling tank (20) is dissipated to prevent turbulence in the dirty water compartment.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The apparatus of claim 2, further comprising:
<claim-text>an overflow line (21) directing cleaning fluid and separated oil above a maximum operational level (23b) of the dirty water compartment of the water recycling tank (20) to the cutting box (16).</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The apparatus of claim 6 wherein the water recycling unit (19) has a minimum operational level (23a) below which fluid ceases to be communicated between the clean water compartment (30) and the nozzles (60).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The apparatus of claim 1 wherein the water recycling unit (19) further comprises:
<claim-text>an auger fed pump (28) to selectively provide or stop fluid communication of solids from the outlet of the dirty water compartment (33) to the cutting box (16).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The apparatus of claim 1 wherein the portable weir bucket (15) in the cutting box (16) has a weir bottom and a weir wall having a top edge 13 defining a receptacle therein.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The apparatus of claim 9 wherein the portable weir bucket (15) may be selectively raised and lowered within the cuttings box (16).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>The apparatus of claim 9 further comprising:
<claim-text>an oil trap (45) spaced apart from and parallel to the side of the temporary weir bucket (15) and retained above the bottom surface of the cutting box (16), wherein the oil trap (45) includes a top edge located above the top edge of the weir wall and a bottom edge located below the top edge of the weir wall.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>The apparatus of claim 1 further comprising:
<claim-text>a chemical inductor (50) between the clean water compartment (30) and the nozzles (60), wherein the chemical inductor (50) provides cleaning compounds to the fluid directed to the nozzles (60).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>A method of recycling water in a tank cleaning system comprising:
<claim-text>collecting tank slop (85) from the dirty tank (18);</claim-text>
<claim-text>pumping the tank slop (85) to a dirty water compartment (33) of a water recycling tank (20);</claim-text>
<claim-text>collecting solids (26) from the tank slop in a sloped bottom (25) of the water recycling tank (20);</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting the solids (26) from the bottom of the water recycling tank (20) to a cuttings box (16);</claim-text>
<claim-text>pumping fluid from the dirty water compartment (33) of the water recycling tank (20) to a hydrocyclonic separator (80);</claim-text>
<claim-text>separating finer solids from the fluid in the hydrocyclonic separator (80);</claim-text>
<claim-text>discharging the solids from the hydrocyclonic separator (80) to the cuttings box (16);</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmitting effluent from the hydrocyclonic separator (80) to a clean water compartment (30) in the water recycling tank (20); and<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>pumping the fluid from the clean water compartment (30) to at least one rotary jet head (60) within the dirty tank (18);</claim-text>
the method further comprising:
<claim-text>collecting fluid in a portable weir bucket (15) suspended in the cuttings box (16); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>pumping the fluid from inside the portable weir bucket (15) to the clean water compartment (30) of the water recycling unit (19).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>The method of claim 13, further comprising:
<claim-text>directing fluid above a maximum operational level (23b) in the main tank (20) of the water recycling unit (19) to the cuttings box (16);</claim-text>
<claim-text>removing the portable weir bucket (15) in the cuttings box (16) when the cuttings box is full; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>replacing the portable weir bucket (15) in another cuttings box (16) to be used in place of the full cuttings box (16).</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56979745" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Appareil pour nettoyer un bassin (18) ayant une surface interne et une surface inférieure, l'appareil comprenant:
<claim-text>un bassin de recyclage d'eau (20) comprenant une entrée (24) et un fond de forme conique (25) ayant une sortie, dans lequel un déversoir (22) sépare un compartiment d'eau propre (30) et un compartiment d'eau sale (33);</claim-text>
<claim-text>un bac de déblais de forage (16) en communication de fluide avec la sortie dans le fond du bassin de recyclage d'eau (20):
<claim-text>une pluralité de buses (60) positionnées à l'intérieur du bassin (18), dans lequel chaque buse est en communication de fluide avec le compartiment d'eau propre (30) et peut être actionnée pour décharger le fluide propre dans le bassin afin de déloger des solides fixés sur les surfaces interne et inférieure; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>une pompe (62) pouvant fonctionner pour pomper du fluide et des solides délogés de la surface inférieure du bassin (18) vers l'entrée (24) de l'unité de recyclage d'eau (19);</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text><b>caractérisé en ce que</b> l'appareil comprend en outre:
<claim-text>un auget de déversoir portable (15) sélectivement suspendu à l'intérieur du bac de déblais de forage (16) et ayant un bord supérieur (13) sur lequel le fluide sensiblement dépourvu de solides peut s'écouler dans l'auget de déversoir, de sorte que l'auget de déversoir (15) définit une zone de collecte de fluide pour le fluide sensiblement dépourvu de solides; et une conduite de fluide (48) à travers laquelle le fluide sensiblement dépourvu de solides dans la zone de collecte de fluide est pompé vers le compartiment d'eau propre (30).</claim-text></claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Appareil selon la revendication 1, comprenant en outre:
<claim-text>un séparateur ayant une entrée en communication de fluide avec le bassin principal de l'unité de recyclage d'eau et amenant un effluent sensiblement dépourvu de solides au compartiment d'eau propre et déchargeant les solides dans le bac de déblais de forage.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Appareil selon la revendication 2, dans lequel le séparateur (80) est un hydrocyclone.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Appareil selon la revendication 2, comprenant en outre:
<claim-text>un collecteur de distribution de fluide modulaire comprenant des valves de régulation pouvant fonctionner pour réguler l'écoulement de fluide et des solides délogés du bassin à l'entrée de l'unité de recyclage d'eau.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Appareil selon la revendication 4, dans lequel l'écoulement de fluide et de solides délogés dans l'entrée (24) du bassin de recyclage d'eau (20) est dissipé pour empêcher la turbulence dans le compartiment d'eau sale.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Appareil selon la revendication 2, comprenant en outre:
<claim-text>une conduite de trop-plein (21) dirigeant le fluide de nettoyage et le pétrole séparé, au-dessus d'un niveau opérationnel maximum (23b) du compartiment d'eau sale du bassin de recyclage d'eau (20) vers le bac de déblais de forage (16).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Appareil selon la revendication 6, dans lequel l'unité de recyclage d'eau (19) a un niveau opérationnel minimum (23a) au-dessous duquel le fluide cesse d'être en communication entre le compartiment d'eau propre (30) et les buses (60).<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Appareil selon la revendication 1, dans lequel l'unité de recyclage d'eau (19) comprend en outre:
<claim-text>une pompe d'alimentation à vis sans fin (28) pour fournir ou arrêter sélectivement la communication de fluide des solides, de la sortie du compartiment d'eau sale (33) au bac de déblais de forage (16).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Appareil selon la revendication 1, dans lequel l'auget de déversoir portable (15) dans le bac de déblais de forage (16) a un fond de déversoir et une paroi de déversoir ayant un bord supérieur (13) définissant un réceptacle à l'intérieur de ce dernier.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Appareil selon la revendication 9, dans lequel l'auget de déversoir portable (15) peut être sélectivement levé ou abaissé à l'intérieur du bac de déblais de forage (16).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Appareil selon la revendication 9, comprenant en outre:
<claim-text>un séparateur de pétrole (45) espacé de et parallèle au côté de l'auget de déversoir temporaire (15) et retenu au-dessus de la surface inférieure du bac de déblais de forage (16), dans lequel le séparateur de pétrole (45) comprend un bord supérieur positionné au-dessus du bord supérieur de la paroi de déversoir et un bord inférieur positionné au-dessous du bord supérieur de la paroi de déversoir.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Appareil selon la revendication 1, comprenant en outre:
<claim-text>un inducteur chimique (50) entre le compartiment d'eau propre (30) et les buses (60), dans lequel l'inducteur chimique (50) fournit des composés de nettoyage au fluide dirigés vers les buses (60).</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Procédé pour recycler de l'eau dans un système de nettoyage de bassin comprenant les étapes consistant à :
<claim-text>collecter les résidus de bassin (85) du bassin sale (18);</claim-text>
<claim-text>pomper les résidus de bassin (85) vers un compartiment d'eau sale (33) d'un bassin de recyclage d'eau (20);</claim-text>
<claim-text>collecter des solides (26) des résidus de bassin dans un fond incliné (25) du bassin de recyclage d'eau (20);</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmettre les solides (26) du fond du bassin de recyclage d'eau (20) à un bac de déblais de forage (16);</claim-text>
<claim-text>pomper le fluide du compartiment d'eau sale (33) du bassin de recyclage d'eau (20) vers un hydrocyclone (80);</claim-text>
<claim-text>séparer les solides plus fins du fluide dans l'hydrocyclone (80);</claim-text>
<claim-text>décharger les solides de l'hydrocyclone (80) vers le bac de déblais de forage (16);</claim-text>
<claim-text>transmettre l'effluent de l'hydrocyclone (80) à un compartiment d'eau propre (30) dans le bassin de recyclage d'eau (20); et</claim-text>
<claim-text>pomper le fluide du réservoir d'eau propre (30) vers au moins une tête à jet rotatif (60) à l'intérieur du bassin sale (18);</claim-text>
<claim-text>le procédé comprenant en outre les étapes consistant à:
<claim-text>collecter du fluide dans un auget de déversoir portable (15) suspendu dans le bac de déblais de forage (16); et</claim-text>
<claim-text>pomper le fluide de l'intérieur de l'auget de déversoir portable (15) vers le compartiment d'eau propre (30) de l'unité de recyclage d'eau (19).</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 13, comprenant en outre les étapes consistant à:
<claim-text>diriger le fluide au-dessus d'un niveau opérationnel maximum (23b) dans le bassin principal (20) de l'unité de recyclage d'eau (19) vers le bac de déblais de forage (16);<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>retirer l'auget de déversoir portable (15) dans le bac de déblais de forage (16) lorsque le bac de déblais de forage est plein; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>replacer l'auget de déversoir portable (15) dans un autre bac de déblais de forage (16) destiné à être utilisé à la place du bac de déblais de forage (16) plein.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16668952" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="146" he="196" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="133" he="152" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="138" he="185" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --><figure id="f0004" num="4"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="134" he="211" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --><figure id="f0005" num="5"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="133" he="207" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
