<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-1367250-B1" country="EP" doc-number="1367250" kind="B1" date="20140101" family-id="29249156" file-reference-id="257001" date-produced="20180822" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146554324" ucid="EP-1367250-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>1367250</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-03251104-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154828247" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>03251104</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20030225</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140449441" ucid="US-13417202-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>13417202</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20020429</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130801</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988096814" load-source="ipcr">F01D   5/03        20060101A I20051008RMEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988099250" load-source="ipcr">F01D   5/02        20060101ALI20030605BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988099857" load-source="ipcr">F02C   3/067       20060101A I20051008RMEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988116941" load-source="ipcr">F02K   3/06        20060101ALI20060310RMJP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988121530" load-source="ipcr">F02K   3/072       20060101AFI20030605BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988129366" load-source="ipcr">F04D  29/38        20060101ALI20060310RMJP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988104031" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F01D   5/022       20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988108759" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F02K   3/072       20130101 FI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988113341" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F01D   5/03        20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988125787" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F02C   3/067       20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132195456" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Gegenläufige Niederdruckverdichteranlage für eine Gasturbine</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132195457" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Counter-rotatable booster compressor assembly for a gas turbine engine</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132195458" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Ensemble de compresseur booster contrarotatif pour une turbine à gaz</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918145657" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>GEN ELECTRIC</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918155678" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>GENERAL ELECTRIC COMPANY</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918132389" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>MONIZ THOMAS ORY</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918142348" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>MONIZ, THOMAS ORY</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918999427" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>MONIZ, THOMAS ORY</last-name><address><street>3050 Columbia Trail</street><city>Loveland, Ohio 45140</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918136460" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>ORLANDO ROBERT JOSEPH</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918171479" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>ORLANDO, ROBERT JOSEPH</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918999426" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>ORLANDO, ROBERT JOSEPH</last-name><address><street>7249 Brushwood Drive</street><city>West Chester, Ohio 45069</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918999428" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>GENERAL ELECTRIC COMPANY</last-name><iid>100129092</iid><address><street>1 River Road</street><city>Schenectady, NY 12345</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918999429" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Szary, Anne Catherine</last-name><iid>101292928</iid><address><street>GPO Europe GE International Inc. The Ark 201 Talgarth Road Hammersmith</street><city>London W6 8BJ</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548993168" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548986492" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548993169" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548986493" load-source="docdb">IT</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63957731" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates generally to a counter-rotatable fan section and counter-rotatable booster compressor for a gas turbine engine and, in particular, to a fan blade assembly of a counter-rotatable fan section which also functions as a compressor blade in the booster compressor.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002">Gas turbine engines are continuously being improved so as to achieve greater thrust with lower noise and greater operating efficiency. One approach has become known as the bypass turbofan engine, where the airflow is divided into two separate and concentric flow streams. An outer flow stream is compressed only by a fan section of the engine and is utilized to provide most of the overall thrust, while an inner flow stream passes through the fan, core engine, and turbine to provide power in which to drive the fan. In order to achieve an increase in fan pressure ratio and maintain fan efficiency with lower relative noise, the fan section includes two stages or rows of fan blades which rotate in opposite direction so as to be a counter-rotatable fan. For lower noise and greater efficiency, it has become desirable to separate the two rows of fan blades axially to allow attenuation of the wake between them.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">To reduce the extra length necessitated by the spacing of the fan blade rows, the inner and outer flow streams are separated at a location axially between such fan stages and the booster compressor positioned within the inner diameter of the second fan stage. Initial configurations of the booster compressor utilized in bypass turbofan engines included various stages of rotor blades which rotated in accordance with the first fan stage, as well as a stator vane stage positioned between each pair of rotor blades (see <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US6220012B"><text>U.S. Patent 6,220012 to Hauser et al.</text></patcit>, for example). Thereafter, as seen in <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="US4860537A"><text>U.S. Patent 4,860,537 to Taylor</text></patcit>, <patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="US5307622A"><text>U.S. Patent 5,307,622 to Ciokajlo et al.</text></patcit>, and <patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="US4790133A"><text>U.S. Patent 4,790,133 to Stuart</text></patcit>, the booster compressor was designed so as to<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> have counter-rotatable blade rows or sections therein which rotate in accordance with corresponding stages of the counter-rotatable fan.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">It has been found that driving the separate blade rows of the booster compressor introduces certain mechanical complexities. In addition, support for the second fan stage is required which does not unduly disrupt sealing of the outer and inner flow streams, particularly since the inner flow stream through the booster compressor must pass through the second fan stage. Thus, in light of the foregoing, it would be desirable for a counter-rotatable fan section and counter-rotatable booster compressor be developed which simplifies rotation of the second fan stage and the corresponding row of booster compressor blades. It would also be desirable for the disk retaining the second fan stage blades to be located closer to a central axis of the engine to better maintain tip clearances. <patcit id="pcit0005" dnum="US5388964A"><text>US 5 388 964</text></patcit> discloses a counter rotatable booster compressor assembly according to the preamble of claim 1.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">In a first exemplary embodiment of the invention, a fan blade assembly for a gas turbine engine having a counter-rotatable fan section and a counter-rotatable booster compressor is disclosed as including a disk connected to a drive shaft, a fan blade row retained within the disk, a first platform member integral with each fan blade at a first location so as to form an inner flowpath for the counter-rotatable booster compressor, and a second platform member integral with each fan blade at a second location so as to form an outer flowpath for the counter-rotatable booster compressor, wherein a portion of each fan blade extending between the first and second platform members functions as a compressor blade in a compressor blade row of the counter-rotatable booster compressor.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">In a second exemplary embodiment of the invention, a counter-rotatable booster compressor assembly for a gas turbine engine having a counter-rotatable fan section with a first fan blade row connected to a first drive shaft and a second fan blade row axially spaced from the first fan blade row and connected to a second drive shaft is disclosed. The counter-rotatable booster compressor assembly includes a first compressor blade row connected to the<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> first drive shaft and a second compressor blade row interdigitated with the first compressor blade row and connected to the second drive shaft, wherein a portion of each fan blade of the second fan blade row extends through a flowpath of the counter-rotatable booster compressor so as to function as a compressor blade in the second compressor blade row.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">In a third exemplary embodiment of the invention, a gas turbine engine is disclosed as including a high pressure rotor including a high pressure turbine, a low pressure turbine located aft of the high pressure rotor having counterrotating low pressure inner and outer rotors effective for rotating first and second drive shafts, a counter-rotatable fan section completely forward of the high pressure rotor including a first fan blade row connected to the first drive shaft and a second fan blade row axially spaced from the first fan blade row and connected to the second drive shaft, and a counter-rotatable booster compressor including a first compressor blade row connected to the first drive shaft and a second compressor blade row interdigitated with the first compressor blade row and connected to the second drive shaft, whereby each low pressure turbine rotor respectively drives both a fan blade row and a compressor blade row, wherein a portion of each fan blade of the second fan blade row extends through a flowpath of the counter-rotatable booster so as to function as a compressor blade in the second compressor blade row of the counter-rotatable booster compressor.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">The invention will now be described in greater detail, by way of example, with reference to the drawings, in which:-
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is a sectional view of a gas turbine engine including a counter-rotatable fan section and counter-rotatable booster compressor in accordance with the present invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> is an enlarged, partial sectional view of the gas turbine engine depicted in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>;<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> is a partial perspective view of the second fan stage of the gas turbine engine depicted in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figs. 1</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0002">2</figref>;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4</figref> is a forward looking aft perspective view of a fan blade assembly depicted in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5</figref> is an aft looking forward perspective view of the fan blade assembly depicted in <figref idrefs="f0003">Figs. 3</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0004">4</figref>; and,</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 6</figref> is a partial sectional view of the second fan stage of the gas turbine engine having an alternative configuration in accordance with the invention.</li></ul></p><p id="p0009" num="0009">Referring now to the drawings in detail, wherein identical numerals indicate the same elements throughout the figures, <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> depicts an exemplary turbofan gas turbine engine 10 having a fan section 12 which receives an inlet flow of ambient air represented by arrow 14. Fan section 12 preferably includes a first stage 16 having a first row of fan blades 18 and a second stage 20 having a second row of fan blades 22. In the typical bypass turbofan arrangement, first row fan blades 18 will rotate in an opposite direction from, or counter to, the rotation of second row fan blades 22. It will be appreciated that first fan stage 16 and second fan stage 20 preferably are spaced a desired axial distance with respect to a centerline axis 24 extending through gas turbine engine 10 so as to minimize any wake in the air flow therebetween.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">A high pressure rotor 26, also known herein as a middle core engine, is positioned downstream of fan section 12, where it will be understood from <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> that the left side thereof is representative of an upstream side or direction and the right side thereof is representative of a downstream side or direction given the flow of air through gas turbine engine 10. It will be understood that high pressure rotor 26 includes a high pressure compressor 28 which is rotatably driven to compress air entering high pressure rotor 26 to a relatively high pressure, a combustor 30 which mixes fuel with air 14 pressurized by high pressure compressor 28 and ignited to generate<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> combustion gases which flow downstream, and a high pressure turbine 32 which receives the combustion gases and is rotatably driven thereby. High pressure turbine 32, in turn, rotatably drives high pressure compressor 28 via a high pressure drive shaft 34 which interconnects high pressure turbine 32 and high pressure compressor 28. Preferably, high pressure rotor 26 is modular so that as a single unit it can be independently replaced with respect to other parts of gas turbine engine 10.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">It will be seen that a booster compressor 36, which is preferably located upstream of high pressure rotor 26, includes a first row of booster compressor blades 38 and a second row of booster compressor blades 40 interdigitated with first booster compressor blade row 38. Booster compressor 36 is counter-rotatable, meaning that first booster compressor blade row 38 rotates in a direction opposite that of second booster compressor blade row 40. Gas turbine engine 10 is preferably designed such that booster compressor blades 40 and fan blades 22 of second fan stage 20 rotate in a direction opposite that of high pressure compressor 28 so as to reduce the sensitivity of gas turbine engine 10 to airflow inlet distortion of fan section 12, as well as reduce mutual sensitivity to rotating stall cells in the other rotors. An outlet guide van 42 may be provided between second fan stage 20 and high pressure compressor 28 to assist in deswirling the air flow to high pressure compressor 28.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">A counter-rotatable low pressure turbine 44 positioned downstream of high pressure turbine 32 expands the combustion gases flowing through high pressure turbine 32 and functions to rotatably drive first fan stage 16 and first booster compressor blade row 38 by means of a first or inner low pressure drive shaft 46 and rotatably drive second fan stage 20 and second booster compressor blade row 40 by means of a second or outer low pressure drive shaft 48.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">More specifically, low pressure turbine 44 includes an annular outer drum rotor 50 rotatably mounted to first inner low pressure drive shaft 46 by an aft<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> low pressure inner conical extension 52. Outer drum rotor 50 further includes a plurality of first low pressure turbine blade rows 54 extending radially inwardly therefrom and axially spaced from each other. It will be seen that outer drum rotor 50 is cantilevered off of a final stage 56 of low pressure turbine blade rows 54 and is bolted to aft low pressure inner conical shaft extension 52. Low pressure inner drive shaft 46 is then seen to drivingly connect outer drum rotor 50 to first fan stage 16 and first fan blade row 18 by means of a forward conical inner shaft extension 58. First booster compressor blade row 38 is then indirectly driven by low pressure inner drive shaft 46 due to a shaft 60 connecting first fan stage 16 thereto, causing first stage fan blade row 18 and first booster compressor blade row 38 to rotate in the same direction.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">Low pressure turbine 44 also includes an annular inner drum rotor 62 which is rotatably mounted to second outer low pressure drive shaft 48 by an aft low pressure outer conical shaft extension 64. Inner drum rotor 62 further includes a plurality of second low pressure turbine blade rows 66 extending radially outwardly therefrom and axially spaced from each other. It will be appreciated that first low pressure turbine blade rows 54 are preferably interdigitated with respect to second low pressure turbine blade rows 66. It will be seen that inner drum rotor 62 is conventionally attached through a final stage 68 of low pressure turbine blade rows 66 and is bolted to aft low pressure outer conical shaft extension 64. Low pressure outer drive shaft 48 is then seen to drivingly connect inner drum rotor 62 to second fan stage 18 and second fan blade row 20 by means of a forward conical outer shaft extension 70. As will be discussed in greater detail herein, second booster compressor blade row 40 is also driven by low pressure outer drive shaft 48, causing second stage fan blade row 20 and second booster compressor blade row 40 to rotate in the same direction, which is counter to the direction of rotation by first fan stage 16 and first booster compressor blade row 38.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">A flow path represented by an arrow 72 for fan 12 is defined by a fan casing 74 and a hub 76 for first fan stage 16 (see <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>). It will be seen that flow<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> path 72 is then preferably divided upstream of second fan stage 20, where an outer portion represented by an arrow 78 bypasses the rest of engine 10 (except for passing through second fan stage 20) and an inner portion represented by arrow 80 is directed into booster compressor 36 and an inlet duct 82 to high pressure compressor 28. It will be appreciated that a splitter nose 84 is provided in order to divide flow path 72, which will be discussed in greater detail herein. In association with splitter nose 84, an inner bypass platform member 86 and a wall 88 positioned downstream thereof are provided so as to maintain a bypass duct 90 with fan casing 74 through which outer flow path portion 78 flows. Similarly, a wall 92 is connected to hub 76, and in conjunction with splitter nose 84, a booster inner platform member 94, and a booster outer platform member 96, form inner flow path portion 80 (otherwise known herein as the booster flow path).</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">As best seen in <figref idrefs="f0002">Figs. 2</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0003">3</figref>, second fan stage 18 preferably includes a conventional disk 98 having dovetails therein to retain fan blades 22. Disk 98 is connected to a shaft extension 100, which is in turn connected to forward conical outer shaft extension 70. In this way, disk 98 and fan blades 22 are then driven by low pressure outer drive shaft 48.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">In accordance with the present invention, it will be seen that each fan blade 22 preferably includes booster inner platform member 94 integral therewith so as to maintain an inner boundary for booster flow path 80. Booster outer platform member 96 is also preferably integral with each fan blade 22 in order to form an outer boundary of booster flow path 80. In this way, an inner portion 102 of each fan blade 22 which extends between inner and outer booster platform members 94 and 96, respectively, functions as a compressor blade 104 in second booster compressor blade row 40 of booster compressor 36.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">It is further seen that each fan blade 22 preferably includes inner bypass platform member 86 integral therewith at a location radially outside of outer booster platform member 96. In order to facilitate connection of splitter nose<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> 84 with outer booster platform member 96 and inner bypass platform member 86, a flange 106 is provided which joins platform members 86 and 96 at an upstream end. Flange 106 is then preferably connected to splitter nose 84 by means of a bolt 108 and swage nut 110. In this way, at least one additional spool or stage for booster compressor 36 may be provided, whereby one or more rows of compressor blades 112 may extend radially inward from splitter nose 84 and rotate in accordance with fan blades 22. Of course, compressor blades 112 are designed so as to interface with wall 92. It will also be understood that such row of compressor blades 112 will be located upstream of first row booster compressor blades 38 so that rotates counter to first stage fan blades 18 and booster compressor blades 38.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">As seen in <figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 6</figref>, it is also contemplated that an additional compressor blade 114 be positioned between inner booster platform member 94 and outer booster platform member 96 adjacent inner fan blade portion 102 of at least certain desired fan blades 22. It will be noted that such compressor blades 114 preferably have a width less than inner fan blade portion 102. Accordingly, when leading edge 116 of compressor blade 114 is positioned substantially in line with a leading edge 118 of inner fan blade portion 102, a trailing edge 120 of compressor blade 114 extends only partially toward trailing edge 122 of inner fan blade portion 102.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980682" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Gegenläufig drehbare Boosterkompressoreinheit (36) für einen Gasturbinenmotor (10), der einen gegenläufig drehbaren Lüfterabschnitt (12) mit einer ersten Lüfterflügelreihe (18) hat, welche mit einer ersten Antriebswelle (46) verbunden ist, und der eine zweite Lüfterflügelreihe (22) hat, die einen axialen Abstand von der ersten Lüfterflügelreihe (18) hat und mit einer zweiten Antriebswelle (48) verbunden ist, wobei die gegenläufig drehbare Boosterkompressoreinheit (36) Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>(a) eine erste Kompressorflügelreihe (38), die mit der ersten Antriebswelle (46) verbunden ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) eine zweite Kompressorflügelreihe (40), die mit der ersten Kompressorflügelreihe (38) verschränkt und mit der zweiten Antriebswelle (48) verbunden ist; wobei ein Teil (102) jedes Lüfterflügels (22) der zweiten Lüfterflügelreihe (22) sich durch einen Strömungsweg (80) des gegenläufig drehbaren Boosterkompressors (36) erstreckt, um so als Kompressorflügel (104) in der zweiten Kompressorflügelreihe (40) zu fungieren, wobei jeder Lüfterflügel der zweiten Lüfterflügelreihe ferner <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet ist, dass</b> er Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>(a) ein erstes Plattformelement, integriert in jeden Lüfterflügel der zweiten Lüfterflügelreihe an einer ersten Stelle, um so einen inneren Strömungsweg für den gegenläufig drehbaren Boosterkompressor zu bilden; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) ein zweites Plattformelement, integriert in<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> jeden Lüfterflügel der zweiten Lüfterflügelreihe an einer zweiten Stelle, um so einen äußeren Strömungsweg für den gegenläufig drehbaren Boosterkompressor zu bilden.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Gegenläufig drehbare Boosterkompressoreinheit (36) nach Anspruch 1, die ferner ein drittes Plattformelement (86) integriert in jeden Lüfterflügel (22) der zweiten Lüfterflügelreihe (22) an einer dritten Stelle umfasst, um so einen inneren Strömungsweg für den gegenläufig drehbaren Lüfterabschnitt (12) zu bilden.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Gegenläufig drehbare Boosterkompressoreinheit (36) nach Anspruch 2, wobei das zweite und dritte Plattformelement (96, 86) an einem stromaufwärtigen Ende miteinander verbunden sind, um einen stromaufwärtigen Flansch (106) zu bilden.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Gegenläufig drehbare Boosterkompressoreinheit (36) nach Anspruch 3, die ferner einen Boostersteuerschieber stromaufwärts von der zweiten Lüfterflügelreihe (22) umfasst, der mit dem stromaufwärtigen Flansch (106) verbunden ist, wobei der Boostersteuerschieber mindestens einen Kompressorflügel (112) umfasst, der sich von dort aus erstreckt, welcher in Übereinstimmung mit der zweiten Lüfterflügelreihe (22) rotiert.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Gegenläufig drehbare Boosterkompressoreinheit (36) nach Anspruch 1, die ferner eine Auslassführungsfahne (42) umfasst, welche im Boosterströmungsweg (80) stromabwärts von der zweiten Lüfterflügelreihe (22) angeordnet ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Gegenläufig drehbare Boosterkompressoreinheit (36)<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> nach Anspruch 1, wobei der Boosterkompressor (36) sich zwischen der ersten und zweiten Lüfterflügelreihe (18, 22) befindet.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Gegenläufig drehbare Boosterkompressoreinheit (36) nach Anspruch 1, die ferner eine Scheibe (98) zum Halten der zweiten Lüfterflügelreihe (22) umfasst, wobei die Scheibe (98) mit der zweiten Antriebswelle (48) verbunden ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Gegenläufig drehbare Boosterkompressoreinheit (36) nach Anspruch 1, die ferner einen zusätzlichen Boosterkompressorflügel (114) umfasst, der sich angrenzend an zumindest einige der Lüfterflügel (22) in der zweiten Lüfterflügelreihe (22) befindet, wobei die zusätzlichen Boosterkompressorflügel (114) sich zwischen dem ersten und zweiten Plattformelement (94, 96) erstrecken und mit denselben verbunden sind.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Lüfterflügeleinheit nach Anspruch 8, wobei die zusätzlichen Boosterkompressorflügel (114) eine Breite haben, die kleiner als eine Breite der Lüfterflügelproportionen (102) sind, welche als Kompressorflügel (104) fungieren.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Lüfterflügeleinheit nach Anspruch 9, wobei eine Vorderkante (116) der zusätzlichen Boosterkompressorflügel (114) im Wesentlichen in einer Linie mit der Vorderkante (118) für die Lüfterflügelabschnitte (102) positioniert ist, die als Kompressorflügel (104) fungieren.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980683" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A counter-rotatable booster compressor assembly (36) for a gas turbine engine (10) having a counter-rotatable fan section (12) with a first fan blade row (18) connected to a first drive shaft (46) and a second fan blade row (22) axially spaced from said first fan blade row (18) and connected to a second drive shaft (48), said counter-rotatable booster compressor assembly (36) comprising:
<claim-text>(a) a first compressor blade row (38) connected to said first drive shaft (46); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) a second compressor blade row (40) interdigitated with said first compressor blade row (38) and connected to said second drive shaft (48); wherein a portion (102) of each fan blade (22) of said second fan blade row (22) extends through a flowpath (80) of said counter-rotatable booster compressor (36) so as to function as a compressor blade (104) in said second compressor blade row (40), each said fan blade of said second fan blade row further <b>characterised in</b> comprising:
<claim-text>(a) a first platform member integral with each said fan blade of said second fan blade row at a first location so as to form an inner flowpath for said counterrotatable booster compressor; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) a second platform member integral with each said fan blade of said second fan blade row at a second location so as to form an outer flowpath for said counterrotatable booster compressor.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The counter-rotatable booster compressor assembly (36) of claim 1, further comprising a third platform member (86) integral with each said fan blade (22) of said second fan blade row (22) at a third location so as to form an inner flowpath for said counter-rotatable fan section (12).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The counter-rotatable booster compressor assembly (36) of claim 2, said second and third platform members (96,86) being joined together at an upstream end to form an upstream flange (106).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The counter-rotatable booster compressor assembly (36) of claim 3, further comprising a booster spool upstream of said second fan blade row<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> (22) connected to said upstream flange (106), said booster spool including at least one compressor blade (112) extending therefrom which rotates in accordance with said second fan blade row (22).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The counter-rotatable booster compressor assembly (36) of claim 1, further comprising an outlet guide vane (42) positioned in said booster flowpath (80) downstream of said second fan blade row (22).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The counter-rotatable booster compressor assembly (36) of claim 1, wherein said booster compressor (36) is located between said first and second fan blade rows (18,22).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The counter-rotatable booster compressor assembly (36) of claim 1, further comprising a disk (98) for retaining said second fan blade row (22), wherein said disk (98) is connected to said second drive shaft (48).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The counter-rotatable booster compressor assembly (36) of claim 1, further comprising an additional booster compressor blade (114) located adjacent to at least some of said fan blades (22) in said second fan blade row (22), said additional booster compressor blades (114) extending between and connected to said first and second platform members (94,96).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The fan blade assembly of claim 8, wherein said additional booster compressor blades (114) have a width which is less than a width of said fan blade portions (102) functioning as a compressor blade (104).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The fan blade assembly of claim 9, wherein a leading edge (116) of said additional booster compressor blades (114) is positioned substantially in line with a leading edge (118) for said fan blade portions (102) functioning as a compressor blade (104).</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980684" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Ensemble de compresseur accélérateur contrarotatif (36) pour une turbine à gaz (10) ayant une section de soufflante contrarotative (12) avec une première rangée de pales de soufflante (18) raccordée à un premier arbre d'entraînement (46) et une seconde rangée de pales de soufflante (22) axialement espacée de ladite première rangée de pales de soufflante (18) et raccordée à un second arbre d'entraînement (48), ledit ensemble de compresseur accélérateur contrarotatif (36) comprenant :
<claim-text>(a) une première rangée de pales de compresseur (38) raccordée audit premier arbre d'entraînement (46) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) une seconde rangée de pales de compresseur (40) imbriquée dans ladite première rangée de pales de compresseur (38) et raccordée audit second arbre d'entraînement (48) ; dans lequel une partie (102) de chaque pale de soufflante (22) de ladite seconde rangée de pales de soufflante (22) s'étend à travers un trajet d'écoulement (80) dudit compresseur accélérateur contrarotatif (36) de manière à fonctionner comme pale de compresseur (104) dans ladite seconde rangée de pales de compresseur (40), chaque dite pale de soufflante de ladite seconde rangée de pales de soufflante étant en outre <b>caractérisée en ce qu'</b>elle comprend :
<claim-text>(a) un premier élément de plate-forme formé d'une seule pièce avec chaque dite pale de soufflante de ladite seconde rangée de pales de soufflante à un<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> premier emplacement de manière à former un trajet d'écoulement interne pour ledit compresseur accélérateur contrarotatif ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>(b) un deuxième élément de plate-forme formé d'une seule pièce avec chaque dite pale de soufflante de ladite seconde rangée de pales de soufflante à un deuxième emplacement de manière à former un trajet d'écoulement interne pour ledit compresseur accélérateur contrarotatif.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Ensemble de compresseur accélérateur contrarotatif (36) selon la revendication 1, comprenant en outre un troisième élément de plate-forme (86) formé d'une seule pièce avec chaque dite pale de soufflante (22) de ladite seconde rangée de pales de soufflante (22) à un troisième emplacement de manière à former un trajet d'écoulement interne pour ladite section de soufflante contrarotative (12).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Ensemble de compresseur accélérateur contrarotatif (36) selon la revendication 2, lesdits deuxième et troisième éléments de plate-forme (96, 86) étant joints l'un à l'autre à une extrémité amont pour former une bride amont (106).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Ensemble de compresseur accélérateur contrarotatif (36) selon la revendication 3, comprenant en outre une bobine accélératrice en amont de ladite seconde rangée de pales de soufflante (22) raccordée à ladite bride amont (106), ladite bobine accélératrice comprenant au moins une pale de compresseur (112) qui s'étend à partir de celle-ci et qui tourne en conformité avec ladite seconde rangée de pales de soufflante (22).<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Ensemble de compresseur accélérateur contrarotatif (36) selon la revendication 1, comprenant en outre une aube de guidage de sortie (42) positionnée dans ledit trajet d'écoulement (80) de l'accélérateur en aval de ladite seconde rangée de pales de soufflante (22).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Ensemble de compresseur accélérateur contrarotatif (36) selon la revendication 1, dans lequel ledit compresseur accélérateur (36) est situé entre lesdites première et seconde rangées de pales de soufflante (18, 22).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Ensemble de compresseur accélérateur contrarotatif (36) selon la revendication 1, comprenant en outre un disque (98) pour retenir ladite seconde rangée de pales de soufflante (22), dans lequel ledit disque (98) est raccordé audit second arbre d'entraînement (48).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Ensemble de compresseur accélérateur contrarotatif (36) selon la revendication 1, comprenant en outre une pale de compresseur accélérateur supplémentaire (114) située adjacente à au moins certaines desdites pales de soufflante (22) de ladite seconde rangée de pales de soufflante (22), lesdites pales de compresseur accélérateur supplémentaires (114) s'étendant entre lesdits premier et deuxième éléments de plate-forme (94, 96) et étant raccordées à ceux-ci.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Ensemble de pales de soufflante selon la revendication 8, dans lequel lesdites pales de compresseur accélérateur supplémentaires (114) ont une largeur qui est inférieure à la largeur<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> desdites parties de pales de soufflante (102) fonctionnant comme pale de compresseur (104).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Ensemble de pales de soufflante selon la revendication 9, dans lequel un bord d'attaque (116) desdites pales de compresseur accélérateur supplémentaires (114) est positionné sensiblement en alignement avec un bord d'attaque (118) pour lesdites parties de pales de soufflante (102) fonctionnant comme pale de compresseur (104).</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16669233" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="117" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="165" he="214" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="165" he="216" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --><figure id="f0004" num="4,5"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="164" he="214" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --><figure id="f0005" num="6"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="110" he="227" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
