<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2683078-A2" country="EP" doc-number="2683078" kind="A2" date="20140108" family-id="48793854" file-reference-id="308367" date-produced="20180822" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146585171" ucid="EP-2683078-A2"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2683078</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-13003262-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154847363" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>13003262</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20130626</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP168045707" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>13003262.6</doc-number><date>20130626</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140551263" ucid="US-201213540133-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>201213540133</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120702</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989322439" load-source="docdb">H02P   9/02        20060101AFI20131113BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1646577709" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H02J   3/46        20130101 LI20180427BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1646577710" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H02J   3/381       20130101 LI20180427BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1873986390" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H02P   9/02        20130101 LI20161126BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1873986391" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H02J   3/38        20130101 FI20161124BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1900017235" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 307/696       20150401 LA20160831BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132360146" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Generatorverwaltungssystem, das Generatoren basierend auf einem Betriebsparameter selektiv aktiviert</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132360147" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Generator management system that selectively activates generators based on an operating parameter</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132360148" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Système de gestion de générateur qui active de manière sélective les générateurs sur la base d'un paramètre de fonctionnement</invention-title><citations><non-patent-citations><nplcit><text>None</text><sources><source mxw-id="PNPL45210956" load-source="docdb" name="APP"/></sources></nplcit></non-patent-citations></citations></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919542131" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>KOHLER CO</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919543895" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>KOHLER CO.</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919013608" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>KOHLER CO.</last-name><iid>100159348</iid><address><street>444 Highland Drive</street><city>Kohler, WI 53044</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919533211" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>FRAMPTON ISAAC S</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919534312" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>FRAMPTON, ISAAC S.</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919006861" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>FRAMPTON, ISAAC S.</last-name><address><street>4639 Fisher Rd.</street><city>Strattanville, PA 16258</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919510084" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>MAUK RICHARD A</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919534450" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>MAUK, RICHARD A.</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919014512" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>MAUK, RICHARD A.</last-name><address><street>W1997 Fairfield Lane</street><city>Sheboygan, WI 53083</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919540461" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>DORN DOUGLAS W</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919511769" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>DORN, DOUGLAS W.</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919009628" load-source="patent-office" sequence="3" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>DORN, DOUGLAS W.</last-name><address><street>W2549 County Road O</street><city>Sheboygan Falls, WI 53085</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919016525" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Hoefer &amp; Partner</last-name><iid>101307873</iid><address><street>Pilgersheimer Straße 20</street><city>81543 München</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549819445" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS549816843" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549819451" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549745527" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549908814" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549817316" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549816844" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549819452" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549817317" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549817322" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549745583" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549745528" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549908815" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549819453" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549817323" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549819486" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549816845" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549743355" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549817324" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549908816" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549817325" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549745557" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549815522" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549745558" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549745559" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549815523" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS549815524" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549743356" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549745584" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549743361" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549745560" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549816850" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549745601" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS549743362" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549908817" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549745589" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549743363" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS549815525" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states><ep-extended-states><ep-extended-state-data><country>BA</country></ep-extended-state-data><ep-extended-state-data><country>ME</country></ep-extended-state-data></ep-extended-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA128673343" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p id="pa01" num="0001">Some embodiments relate to an example generator management system. The generator management system includes a first generator that is adapted to supply power to a load and a first generator controller that operates the first generator. The generator management system further includes a second generator that is adapted to supply power to the load and a second generator controller that operates the second generator. The generator management system further includes a communication bus that connects the first generator controller and the second generator controller such that the first generator controller and the second generator controller exchange data. At least one of the first generator controller and the second generator controller selectively activates the first generator and the second generator in an order that depends on an operating parameter of the first generator and the second generator (as opposed to a fixed sequence which is done in existing systems).
<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="89" he="93" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA128737494" lang="EN" source="EPO" load-source="docdb"><p>Some embodiments relate to an example generator management system. The generator management system includes a first generator that is adapted to supply power to a load and a first generator controller that operates the first generator. The generator management system further includes a second generator that is adapted to supply power to the load and a second generator controller that operates the second generator. The generator management system further includes a communication bus that connects the first generator controller and the second generator controller such that the first generator controller and the second generator controller exchange data. At least one of the first generator controller and the second generator controller selectively activates the first generator and the second generator in an order that depends on an operating parameter of the first generator and the second generator (as opposed to a fixed sequence which is done in existing systems).</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES63959331" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">Embodiments pertain to a generator management system, and more particularly to a generator management system that selectively activates generators based on an operating parameter.</p><heading id="h0002">BACKGROUND</heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">Electric generators are typically used to provide electrical power. One common use of electric generators is as a standby power source. Another common use of electric generators is to provide power at a remote location where utility company power is not available.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">One common type of electric generator includes an internal combustion engine. The internal combustion engine drives an electrical alternator that produces alternating electricity.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">Many existing system often include multiple electric generators, especially in situations where there is a potential high demand for power. There can be advantages to employing multiple small generators rather than a single large generator.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">One of the advantages is that if one generator fails, or requires maintenance, a multi-generator system can still supply some power while a single generator system would otherwise not be able to meet demand. Another advantage is that load growth may be addressed by adding another generator rather than replacing an existing generator with a larger (and more expensive) generator.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">Another advantage of using multiple generators is that it is possible to stop generators that are not needed to provide power at a particular point in time. Stopping generators (i) saves wear and tear on the generators; (ii) decreases sound emissions at a location; (iii) decreases fuel consumption (and corresponding harmful environmental emissions).<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p><p id="p0007" num="0007">Stopped generators can also be restarted as demand increases. This starting and stopping of certain generators within a plurality of generators is referred to as generator management.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">Some of the drawbacks with existing generator management systems may include (i) the need for expensive external controls in order to adequately start and stop particular generators; or (ii) unequal wear of the generators resulting from the inability to dynamically change the order in which each of the plurality of generators are started and stopped in response to changes in demand.</p><heading id="h0003">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading><p id="p0009" num="0009"><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic plan view of an example generator management system.</p><heading id="h0004">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading><p id="p0010" num="0010">The following description and the drawings sufficiently illustrate specific embodiments to enable those skilled in the art to practice them. Other embodiments may incorporate structural, logical, electrical, process, and other changes. Portions and features of some embodiments may be included in, or substituted for, those of other embodiments. Embodiments set forth in the claims encompass all available equivalents of those claims.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011"><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a schematic plan view of an example generator management system 10. The generator management system 10 includes a first generator 11 that is adapted to supply power to a load L and a first generator controller 12 that operates the first generator 11. The generator management system 10 further includes a second generator 13 that is adapted to supply power to the load L and a second generator controller 14 that operates the second generator 13.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">The generator management system 10 further includes a communication bus 15 that connects the first generator controller 12 and the second generator controller 14 such that the first generator controller 12 and the second generator controller 14 exchange data. At least one of the first generator controller 12 and the second generator controller 14 selectively activates the first generator 11<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> and the second generator 13 in an order that depends on an operating parameter of the first generator 11 and the second generator 13 (as opposed to a fixed sequence or order which is done in existing systems). Therefore, the generator management system 10 is able to dynamically change the order in which each of the first and second generators 11, 13 are started and stopped in order to meet a changing demand for power at the load L.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">In the example embodiment illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, the generator management system 10 further includes a server 16 that is connected to the first and second generator controllers 12, 14 via a network (e.g. the Internet I). It should be noted that in embodiments that include server 16, at least one of the first generator controller 12, the second generator controller 14 and the server 16 may selectively activate the first generator 11 and the second generator 13 in an order that depends on an operating parameter of the first generator 11 and the second generator 13.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">In some embodiments, the order in which the first generator 11 and the second generator 13 are selectively activated depends on a total number of run hours that is associated with each of the first and second generators 11, 13. As an example, the order may be established such that the one of the first generator and the second generator 11, 13 with the lower number of total run hours is selected to activate first.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">Embodiments are also contemplated where the order depends on a total amount of emissions that are generated by each of the first and second generators 11, 13. As an example, the order is established such that the one of the first generator 11 and the second generator 13 which generates fewer emissions is selected to activate first.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">It should be noted that various different types of emissions may be used to establish the order for selectively activating the first generator 11 and the second generator 13. Example emissions include hydrocarbon emissions and sound emissions (among others).</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">In some embodiments, the order in which the first generator 11 and the second generator 13 are selectively activated depends on a cost that is associated with operating each of the first and second generators 11, 13. As an example, the<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> cost may be determined by a rate of fuel consumption of each of the first and second generators 11, 13. As another example, the cost may be determined by maintenance costs that are associated with operating each of the first and second generators 11, 13.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">Embodiments are also contemplated where the order depends on a pre-fault condition that exists for each of the first and second generators 11, 13. One example pre-fault condition may be low fuel level. As an example, when one of the first and second generators 11, 13 has a low fuel level, the other of the first and second generators 11, 13 may be selectively activated first.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">In embodiments where the first and second generators 11, 13 each supply the load through circuit breakers, an example pre-fault condition may be that one of the circuit breakers is unable to open. In this example, the generator that is connected to the load through the circuit breaker that is unable to open is selectively activated first.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">In embodiments where the first and second generators 11, 13 each include an engine, the pre-fault condition may relate to an operating parameter of the respective engine. Some examples of pre-fault condition that relates to engines include; high coolant temperature warning, low oil pressure warning, sensor malfunction and low battery voltage warning.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">Embodiments are also contemplated where the order depends on the age of the fuel with each respective engine. As an example, when one of the first and second generators 11, 13 has an older fuel supply, that generator 11, 13 that includes the older fuel supply may be selectively activated first to consume the older fuel.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">In some embodiments, the order in which the first generator 11 and the second generator 13 are selectively activated depends on a minimum load requirement for each of the first and second generators 11, 13. As an example, the minimum load requirement may be set by local emissions standards.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">Embodiments are contemplated where a secondary operating parameter is designated for selectively activating one of the first and second generators when the primary operating parameter is effectively equal.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></p><p id="p0024" num="0024">As an example, during operation of the generator management system 10, the first and second generators 11, 13 will tend to equalize their primary operating parameter (e.g., fuel levels within the first and second generators 11, 13 will tend to equalize when the fuel level is the primary operating parameter). In addition, external activity may tend to equalize the primary operating parameter (e.g., when a fuel equalizing tube is placed between the first and second generators 11, 13).</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">It should be noted although only first and second generators 11, 13 are described herein, the generator management system 10 may include any additional number of generators. The generator management system 10 would be able to selectively activate some (or all) of the additional generators in an order that depends on an operating parameter of the generators.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">The generator management systems 10 described herein may serve to equalize some primary (and possibly secondary) operating parameter of the generators that are part of the generator management system 10. In addition, the generator management systems 10 described may be able to dynamically change the order in which each of the generators within the generator management systems 10 are started and stopped to meet changing load demands (without the need for expensive external controls).</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">The Abstract is provided to comply with 37 C.F.R. Section 1.72(b) requiring an abstract that will allow the reader to ascertain the nature and gist of the technical disclosure. It is submitted with the understanding that it will not be used to limit or interpret the scope or meaning of the claims. The following claims are hereby incorporated into the detailed description, with each claim standing on its own as a separate embodiment.<br/>
The present invention can also be described by the following clauses:
<ol><li>1. A generator management system comprising:
<ul><li>a first generator that is adapted to supply power to a load;</li><li>a first generator controller that operates the first generator;<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></li><li>a second generator that is adapted to supply power to the load;</li><li>a second generator controller that operates the second generator;</li><li>a communication bus connecting the first generator controller and the second generator controller such that the first generator controller and the second generator controller exchange data; and</li><li>wherein at least one of the first generator controller and the second generator controller selectively activates the first generator and the second generator in an order that depends on an operating parameter of the first generator and the second generator.</li></ul></li><li>2. The generator management system of clause 1, further comprising a server that is connected to the communication buss via a network, wherein at least one of the first generator controller, the second generator controller and the server selectively activates the first generator and the second generator in an order that depends on an operating parameter of the first generator and the second generator.</li><li>3. The generator management system of clause 1, wherein the order depends on a total number of run hours that is associated with each of the first and second generators.</li><li>4. The generator management system of clause 3, wherein the order is established such that the one of the first generator and the second generator with the lower number of total run hours is selected first.</li><li>5. The generator management system of clause 1, wherein the order depends on a total amount of emissions that are generated by each of the first and second generators.</li><li>6. The generator management system of clause 5, wherein the order is established such that the one of the first generator and the second generator which generates fewer emissions is selected first.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></li><li>7. The generator management system of clause 5, wherein the emissions that establish the order are hydrocarbon emissions.</li><li>8. The generator management system of clause 5, wherein the emissions that establish the order are sound emissions.</li><li>9. The generator management system of clause 1, wherein the order depends on a cost that is associated with operating each of the first and second generators.</li><li>10. The generator management system of clause 9, wherein the cost is determined by a rate of fuel consumption of each of the first and second generators.</li><li>11. The generator management system of clause 9, wherein the cost is determined by maintenance costs that are associated with operating each of the first and second generators.</li><li>12. The generator management system of clause 1, wherein the order depends on whether a pre-fault condition exists for each of the first and second generators.</li><li>13. The generator management system of clause 12, wherein the pre-fault condition is low fuel level.</li><li>14. The generator management system of clause 12, wherein the first and second generators each include an engine, and wherein the pre-fault condition relates to an operating parameter of the respective engine.</li><li>15. The generator management system of clause 1, wherein the order depends on a minimum load requirement for each of the first and second generators.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></li><li>16. The generator management system of clause 15, wherein at least one of the first and second generators includes a diesel engine that has a particulate filter, and wherein the minimum load requirement is due to the particulate filter regeneration cycle.</li><li>17. The generator management system of clause 15, wherein the minimum load requirement is set by local emissions standards.</li><li>18. The generator management system of clause 1, wherein a user selects the particular operating parameter of the first generator and the second generator that the controller utilizes to selectively activate the first generator and the second generator based on the operating parameter.</li><li>19. The generator management system of clause 1, wherein the order depends on an age of fuel that is used to run each of the first and second generators.</li><li>20. The generator management system of clause 1, wherein the order depends on a secondary operating parameter that the controller utilizes to selectively activate the first and second generator when the first operating parameter of the first and second generators is effectively equal.</li></ol></p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56982365" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --><claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A generator management system comprising:
<claim-text>a first generator that is adapted to supply power to a load;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first generator controller that operates the first generator;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second generator that is adapted to supply power to the load;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second generator controller that operates the second generator;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a communication bus connecting the first generator controller and the second generator controller such that the first generator controller and the second generator controller exchange data; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein at least one of the first generator controller and the second generator controller selectively activates the first generator and the second generator in an order that depends on an operating parameter of the first generator and the second generator.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The generator management system of claim 1, further comprising a server that is connected to the communication buss via a network, wherein at least one of the first generator controller, the second generator controller and the server selectively activates the first generator and the second generator in an order that depends on an operating parameter of the first generator and the second generator.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The generator management system of claim 1 or 2, wherein the order depends on a total number of run hours that is associated with each of the first and second generators.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The generator management system of claim 3, wherein the order is established such that the one of the first generator and the second generator with the lower number of total run hours is selected first.<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The generator management system of claim 1 or 2, wherein the order depends on a total amount of emissions that are generated by each of the first and second generators.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The generator management system of claim 5, wherein the order is established such that the one of the first generator and the second generator which generates fewer emissions is selected first.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The generator management system of claim 5 or 6, wherein the emissions that establish the order are hydrocarbon emissions or sound emissions.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The generator management system of claim 1 or 2, wherein the order depends on a cost that is associated with operating each of the first and second generators.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The generator management system of claim 8, wherein the cost is determined by a rate of fuel consumption of each of the first and second generators or maintenance costs that are associated with operating each of the first and second generators.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The generator management system of claim 1 or 2, wherein the order depends on whether a pre-fault condition exists for each of the first and second generators.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>The generator management system of claim 10, wherein the pre-fault condition is low fuel level.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>The generator management system of claim 10, wherein the first and second generators each include an engine, and wherein the pre-fault condition relates to an operating parameter of the respective engine.<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>The generator management system of claim 1 or 2, wherein the order depends on a minimum load requirement for each of the first and second generators.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>The generator management system of claim 13, wherein at least one of the first and second generators includes a diesel engine that has a particulate filter, and wherein the minimum load requirement is due to the particulate filter regeneration cycle.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>The generator management system of claim 1, wherein a user selects the particular operating parameter of the first generator and the second generator that the controller utilizes to selectively activate the first generator and the second generator based on the operating parameter.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16670745" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="158" he="166" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
