<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2473208-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2473208" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="42830112" file-reference-id="315055" date-produced="20180825" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146587907" ucid="EP-2473208-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2473208</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-10749559-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154850099" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>10749559</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20100824</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140551840" ucid="US-2010046478-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>2010046478</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20100824</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140554515" ucid="US-23923709-P" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>23923709</doc-number><kind>P</kind><date>20090902</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130802</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989324221" load-source="docdb">A61L  31/16        20060101ALI20120220BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989324222" load-source="docdb">A61L  27/50        20060101ALI20120220BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989324223" load-source="docdb">A61L  27/36        20060101AFI20120220BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989324224" load-source="docdb">A61L  31/00        20060101ALI20120220BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2102545201" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">Y10T 156/1002      20130101 LA20150123BCEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2102547796" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61L2430/36        20130101 LA20150124BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2102552209" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61L  27/3604      20130101 FI20150124BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2102552876" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61L  27/507       20130101 LI20150124BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132368354" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">GEFÄSSERSATZ AUS ZELLENLOSER GEWEBEMATRIX</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132368355" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">VASCULAR GRAFTS DERIVED FROM ACELLULAR TISSUE MATRICES</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132368356" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">GREFFES VASCULAIRES ISSUES DE MATRICES DE TISSUS ACELLULAIRES</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919541002" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>LIFECELL CORP</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919545348" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>LIFECELL CORPORATION</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919506172" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>XU HUI</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919534719" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>XU, HUI</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919020597" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>XU, HUI</last-name><address><street>10 Daisy Court</street><city>Plainsboro, NJ 08536</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919520234" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>CUI CUNQUI</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919511374" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>CUI, CUNQUI</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919020598" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>CUI, CUNQUI</last-name><address><street>4 Mozart Court</street><city>East Windsor, NJ 08536</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919523203" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>CZECZUGA JOSHUA</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919520466" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>CZECZUGA, JOSHUA</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919020599" load-source="patent-office" sequence="3" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>CZECZUGA, JOSHUA</last-name><address><street>2003 Jamestown Common</street><city>Hillsborough, NJ 08844</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919526388" load-source="docdb" sequence="4" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>LOMBARDI JARED</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919541520" load-source="docdb" sequence="4" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>LOMBARDI, JARED</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919020600" load-source="patent-office" sequence="4" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>LOMBARDI, JARED</last-name><address><street>10 Matthew Court</street><city>Lebanon, NJ 08833</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919020602" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Lifecell Corporation</last-name><iid>101235774</iid><address><street>One Millennium Way</street><city>Branchburg, NJ 08876</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919020601" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Ashton, Timothy</last-name><suffix>et al</suffix><iid>101298667</iid><address><street>Forresters Skygarden Erika-Mann-Strasse 11</street><city>80636 München</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="US-2010046478-W"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2010046478</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20100824</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2011028521-A2"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2011028521</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20110310</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549863441" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS549867523" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549865113" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549886589" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549795272" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549865118" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549867524" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549863446" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549865119" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549865120" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549921811" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549886594" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549795281" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549863447" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549865121" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549863448" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549867525" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549795282" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549865126" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549886595" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549865127" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549886596" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549779898" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549886597" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549886602" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549779899" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS549779900" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549779913" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549795283" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549779914" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549921812" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549779312" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549779915" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549863449" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549795284" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549795289" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS549865128" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63960340" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present disclosure relates to vascular grafts, and more specifically, to vascular grafts derived from acellular tissue matrices.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002">Recent advancements in the field of bioengineering and cardiovascular research have lead to the development of new techniques and materials for constructing vascular conduits for bypass surgery, repair of damaged or diseased blood vessels, and other vascular procedures. Vascular grafts include a wide variety of synthetic and biological constructs.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">Despite developments in graft technology, the repair or replacement of vascular structures continues to remain challenging, particularly due to the complications resulting from synthetic graft use, such as enteric fistulae formation, distal embolization, graft infection and occlusion, limited durability, and lack of compliance of the graft around the anastomosis, thus necessitating further intervention. The application of autografts for vascular replacement is hindered by the dimensional limitation of the harvested grafts, donor site morbidity and surgical costs associated with the harvest of autologous vessels. Additionally, a significant number of patients do not have veins suitable for grafting due to preexisting vascular disease, vein stripping or prior vascular procedures.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US6918396B"><text>US6918396</text></patcit> discloses a tissue graft from either a submucosa or a basement membrane.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005"><patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="WO2005023321A"><text>WO2005/023321</text></patcit> and <patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="US2007004961A"><text>US2007/004961</text></patcit> separately discloses a basement membrane only used as a vascular graft.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006"><patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="US6416995B"><text>US6416995</text></patcit> discloses an acellular tissue graft from which the basement membrane is completely or partially removed.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">The present disclosure provides improved methods and materials for construction of vascular grafts.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">In one aspect of the present disclosure, a vascular graft for treatment of a diseased or damaged blood vessel is provided. The vascular graft comprises a tubular conduit comprising a tubular wall that is impervious to blood and defining a lumen for the passage of blood there through. The tubular wall comprises a sheet of acellular tissue matrix having a basement membrane. The basement membrane forms a luminal surface of the tubular conduit.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --><!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p><p id="p0009" num="0009">In another aspect of the present disclosure, a method of forming a vascular graft is provided. The method comprises the steps of providing a sheet of acellular tissue matrix having a basement membrane, and forming the sheet into a tubular conduit. The basement membrane forms an inner luminal surface of the tubular conduit.</p><heading id="h0001">Brief Description of Drawings</heading><p id="p0010" num="0010"><ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1A</figref> shows an exemplary embodiment of a vascular graft for treatment of a diseased or damaged blood vessel;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1B</figref> shows an alternate configuration of the vascular graft depicted in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2A</figref> shows another exemplary embodiment of a vascular graft for treatment of a diseased or damaged blood vessel;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2B</figref> shows yet another exemplary embodiment of a vascular graft for treatment of a diseased or damaged blood vessel;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> illustrates a method of forming a vascular graft according to certain embodiments;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">FIGS. 4A-4H</figref> are images of histological sections of explanted vascular grafts stained with hemotoxylin and eosin, as described in Example 1;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005">FIGS. 5A-5F</figref> are images of histological sections of explanted vascular grafts stained with Verhoeff Van Geison stain, as described in Example 1;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0006">FIGS. 6A-6F</figref> are scanning electron micrographs of explanted vascular grafts, as described in Example 1;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0007">FIGS. 7A and 7B</figref> are transmission electron micrographs of an explanted vascular graft and a rat aorta, as described in Example 1;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0008">FIGS. 8A-8D</figref> are images of histological sections of explanted vascular grafts stained with antibodies against endothelial cells, as described in Example 1;<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></li><li><figref idrefs="f0008">FIGS. 8E-8H</figref> are images of histological sections of explanted vascular grafts stained with antibodies against von Willebrand Factor, as described in Example 1;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0009">FIGS. 9A-9E</figref> are images of histological sections of explanted vascular grafts stained with antibodies against smooth muscle cells, as described in Example 1;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0009">FIGS. 9F-9J</figref> are images of histological sections of explanted vascular grafts stained with antibodies against fibroblast cells, as described in Example 1;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0010">FIGS. 10A-10L</figref> are images of histological sections of explanted vascular grafts stained with antibodies against rat T-cell, B cell and macrophage, as described in Example 1;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0011">FIGS. 11A-11 E</figref> are images of histological sections of explanted vascular grafts stained with antibodies against rat IgG, as described in Example 1;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0011">FIGS. 11F-11G</figref> are images of histological sections of explanted vascular grafts stained with antibodies against rat IgM, as described in Example 1;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0012">FIG. 12</figref> shows the thermostability results of glued acellular dermal matrices, as described in Example 2; and</li><li><figref idrefs="f0013">FIG. 13</figref> illustrates the effect of bioglues on the antithrombotic property of heparin coated on acellular dermal matrices, as described in Example 2.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0002"><b>Description of Exemplary Embodiments</b></heading><p id="p0011" num="0011">Reference will now be made in detail to certain embodiments consistent with the present disclosure, examples of which are illustrated in the accompanying drawings. Wherever possible, the same reference numbers will be used throughout the drawings to refer to the same or like parts.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">In this application, the use of the singular includes the plural unless specifically stated otherwise. In this application, the use of "or" means "and/or" unless stated otherwise. Furthermore, the use of the term "including", as well as other forms, such as "includes" and "included", is not limiting. Also, terms such as "element" or "component" encompass both elements and components comprising one unit and elements and components that comprise more than one subunit, unless specifically stated otherwise. Also the use of the term "portion" may include part of a moiety or the entire moiety.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></p><p id="p0013" num="0013">The term "acellular tissue matrix," as used herein, refers generally to any tissue matrix that is substantially free of cells and other antigenic material. In various embodiments, acellular tissue matrices derived from human or xenogenic sources may be used to produce the scaffolds. Skin, parts of skin (e.g., dermis), and other tissues such as blood vessels, heart valves, fascia and nerve connective tissue may be used to create acellular matrices to produce tissues scaffolds within the scope of the present disclosure.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">The section headings used herein are for organizational purposes only and are not to be construed as limiting the subject matter described. All documents, or portions of documents, cited in this application, including but not limited to patents, patent applications, articles, books, and treatises, are hereby expressly incorporated by reference in their entirety for any purpose.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">In various embodiments, materials and methods for construction of arterial or venous grafts for treatment of blood vessel defects are provided. In various embodiments, the vascular grafts are used for replacement of a portion of a diseased or damaged blood vessel, for example, replacement of a weakened portioned of the aorta, treatment of damaged vessels due to trauma, treatment of vascular diseases caused by medical conditions (e.g. diabetes, autoimmune disease, etc.). In some embodiments, the vascular grafts are used for bypassing and/or replacing stenotic or partially occluded segments of a blood vessel, for example, coronary and peripheral artery bypass grafting.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">In some embodiments, a vascular graft comprises a sheet of material formed into a tubular conduit. The tubular wall of the graft is impermeable to blood under hemodynamic pressures experienced by native blood vessels. In various embodiments, the material sheet forming the tubular graft has sufficient strength and durability for use in vascular applications, and the mechanical properties (e.g., elasticity) are similar to those of the adjacent host vessel. In certain embodiments, the luminal lining of the graft is antithrombotic. In some embodiments, the material sheet forming the graft supports tissue remodeling and repopulation of the graft with the host cells. In certain embodiments, the material forming the graft supports endothelial cell deposition on the luminal surface and smooth muscle cell integration into the tubular wall of the graft.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">A basement membrane is a thin sheet of extracellular material contiguous with the basilar aspect of epithelial cells. Sheets of aggregated<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> epithelial cells form an epithelium. Thus, for example, the epithelium of skin is called the epidermis, and the skin basement membrane lies between the epidermis and the dermis. The basement membrane is a specialized extracellular matrix that provides a barrier function and an attachment surface for epithelial-like cells; however, it does not contribute any significant structural or biomechanical role to the underlying tissue (e.g., dermis). Components of basement membranes include, for example, laminin, collagen type VII, and nidogen. The temporal and spatial organizations of the epithelial basement membrane distinguish it from, e.g., the dermal extracellular matrix.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">The sheet of material includes an acellular tissue matrix. In various embodiments, the acellular tissue matrix comprises an intact basement membrane. The basement membrane forms the luminal surface of the vascular conduit. The basement membrane provides a continuous, non-porous luminal surface to the graft, and thereby, prevents leakage of blood from the lumen of the graft. In addition, the basement membrane may support growth of endothelial cells and prevent thrombosis. The basement membrane may, therefore, allow formation of an endothelial lining that prevents leakage and/or thrombosis, but does not require seeding or culture with exogenous cells.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">The acellular tissue matrix can be formed from a number of different tissues that include a basement membrane. For example, the acellular tissue matrix can be formed from skin, urinary bladder, intestine, pericardial tissue, peritoneum or combinations of tissues. One biomaterial suitable for forming the acellular matrix is derived from human skin, such as ALLODERM<sup>®</sup>, which is available from (LifeCell Corp, Branchburg, NJ). ALLODERM<sup>®</sup> is a human acellular dermal matrix that has been processed to remove both the epidermis and the cells that can lead to tissue rejection and graft failure, without damaging the dermal proteins and the basement membrane. In another exemplary embodiment, the acellular tissue matrix comprises a pericardial matrix generated by processing pericardial tissue while maintaining the integrity of the basement membrane. In yet another embodiment, the acellular tissue matrix is derived from peritoneal membrane, which is processed to remove the cells while keeping the basement membrane intact. Production of suitable acellular tissue matrices is described in more detail below.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p><p id="p0020" num="0020">In various embodiments, the luminal surface of the graft is modified using anti-thrombotic and/or anti-calcification agents to inhibit graft occlusion after surgery. In other embodiments, the luminal surface of the vascular graft is treated with growth factors that enhance proliferation of endothelial cells along the luminal surface.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">To form a sheet of acellular tissue matrix into a tube, opposing edges of the sheet may be attached to one another. In various embodiments, the edges are attached to one another using sutures, a biologically compatible adhesive, or a combination of both, to form a fluid-tight seam extending longitudinally along the length of the graft. In some embodiments, the edges of the rolled sheet are secured using heat and pressure treatment. Suitable sutures include, for example, polypropylene sutures (PROLENE<sup>®</sup>), and can be continuous or interrupted. Suitable adhesives include, for example, fibrin glue, cyanoacrylate-based tissue adhesives (e.g., DERMABOND<sup>®</sup>), and chitosan tissue adhesives. In some embodiments, the edges of the sheet are crosslinked (e.g., using chemical or radiation induced cross-linking) to each other or to an underlying layer of material to ensure that the edges do not come loose after the sheet is rolled in a tubular construct.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022"><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1A</figref> shows an exemplary embodiment of a vascular graft 10 in accordance with the present disclosure. Graft 10 comprises a sheet of material 12 that is rolled into a tubular construct defining a lumen 13 and a tubular wall 15 having a luminal surface 17 and abluminal surface 19. Longitudinal edges 14, 16 of the sheet are brought into contact with each other on the abluminal side of the tubular construct, and are attached using surgical sutures and/or bioadhesives along the length of the graft. The attachment of the longitudinal edges 14, 16 creates a longitudinal ridge 18 that protrudes above abluminal surface 19 and extends along the length of the tubular graft. In one embodiment, longitudinal ridge 18 is folded and attached to the abluminal surface 19 of graft 10, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG.1 B</figref>. Longitudinal ridge 18 is secured to tubular wall 15 along the length of the graft using sutures, adhesives, or a combination of both.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023"><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2A</figref> shows an exemplary embodiment of a vascular graft 20 in accordance with the present disclosure. Graft 20 comprises a sheet of material 22 that is rolled into a tubular structure defining a lumen 23. The sheet of material 22 forms a tubular wall 21 having a luminal surface 27 and an abluminal surface 29.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> The sheet 22 comprises a first longitudinal edge 24 and a second longitudinal edge 26 at opposite ends of the sheet 22. When the sheet 22 is rolled into a tube, second longitudinal edge 26 extends over first edge 24 to define a multi-layered overlapped region 25 extending between first edge 24 and second edge 26. The overlapped region 25 is sealed along the length of the graft using sutures and/or adhesives. In certain embodiments, the range of overlap is at least 10% of the width of an individual sheet of material.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">Suitable vascular grafts can be formed using a number of techniques. Generally, grafts will be produced based on a desired size, length, and biomechanical requirements needed for a selected implant location. For example, a graft intended for use as an aortic vascular graft will generally have a size and biomechanical properties (e.g., burst strength) that are higher than those for other location, which may experience lower pressures and carry less blood flow.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">In various embodiments, the thickness of the sheet of material is consistent with the wall thickness of a blood vessel to be replaced by the vascular graft. In certain embodiments, the sheet of material is sized to correspond to the wall thickness of a native blood vessel.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">In some embodiments, grafts can be formed by rolling a sheet of material to a predetermined size (i.e. luminal diameter). In some embodiments, as illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>, a vascular graft can be formed by wrapping a sheet of biomaterial 32 around the exterior surface of a cylindrical rod or tube 30. A longitudinal section 34 of the sheet is folded around a cylindrical rod 30. In one embodiment, a locking rod 35 is positioned parallel to the cylindrical rod 30, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3</figref>, to lock section 34 against the cylindrical rod. A suture held taut between two holders can also be used to lock section 34 against the cylindrical rod. The rod is then rolled at least 360° about a longitudinal axis 31 of the rod to wrap the sheet of material around the exterior surface of the rod. In one embodiment, sheet 32 is wrapped around the rod multiple times to form a multi-layered graft. After the sheet is wound around the cylindrical rod, the outer edge 36 of the sheet is secured to an underlying layer of sheet, as illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">In one embodiment, adhesive strips 38 are attached to sheet 32 on multiple locations across the width of the sheet, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3</figref>. In such an embodiment, adhesive strips 38 bind the sheet 32 to an underlying layer of material as the sheet is wrapped around the cylindrical rod 30.<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --></p><p id="p0028" num="0028">The inner diameter of the tubular graft is substantially equal to the outer diameter of cylindrical rod or tubing 30. Therefore, the diameter of the rod or tube is selected to match the luminal diameter of the native blood vessel to be replaced by the graft construct. In one embodiment, the diameter of the rod is approximately between 4-5 mm, which is used for constructing small-diameter (&lt; 6 mm) vascular grafts. In another embodiment, the wall thickness of the tube is 1 mm. After the sheet is wrapped around the rod and the longitudinal edge(s) of the sheet are secured, the rod is withdrawn from within the rolled sheet. In another embodiment, the tubing is stretch longitudinally to slide the sheet off of the tubing. The material of the cylindrical rod is selected to inhibit attachment of the sheet to the exterior surface of the rod. In one exemplary embodiment, the cylindrical rod used is a glass rod. In another embodiment, the cylindrical tube used is a rubber tube. In yet another embodiment, the tube used is a silicone tube.</p><heading id="h0003"><u>Suitable Acellular Tissue Matrices</u></heading><p id="p0029" num="0029">In some embodiments, suitable acellular tissue matrices may, for example, retain certain biological functions, such as cell recognition, cell binding, the ability to support cell spreading, cell proliferation, cellular in-growth and cell differentiation. Such functions may be provided, for example, by undenatured collagenous proteins (e.g., type I collagen) and a variety of non-collagenous molecules (e.g., proteins that serve as ligands for either molecules such as integrin receptors, molecules with high charge density such as glycosaminoglycans (e.g., hyaluronan) or proteoglycans, or other adhesins). In some embodiments, the acellular tissue matrices may retain certain structural functions, including maintenance of histological architecture and maintenance of the three-dimensional array of the tissue's components. The acellular tissue matrices described herein may also, for example, exhibit desirable physical characteristics such as strength, elasticity, and durability, defined porosity, and retention of macromolecules. Suitable acellular tissue matrices may be crosslinked or uncrosslinked.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">In some embodiments, the graft material is amenable to being remodeled by infiltrating cells, such as differentiated cells of the relevant host tissue, stem cells such as mesenchymal stem cells, or progenitor cells. This may be accomplished, for example, by forming the grafted matrix material from tissue that is identical to the surrounding host tissue, but such identity is not necessary.<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></p><p id="p0031" num="0031">Remodeling may be directed by the above-described acellular tissue matrix components and signals from the surrounding host tissue (such as cytokines, extracellular matrix components, biomechanical stimuli, and bioelectrical stimuli). For example, the presence of mesenchymal stem cells in the bone marrow and the peripheral circulation has been documented in the literature and shown to regenerate a variety of musculoskeletal tissues [<nplcit id="ncit0001" npl-type="s"><text>Caplan (1991) J. Orthop. Res. 9:641-650</text></nplcit>;<nplcit id="ncit0002" npl-type="s"><text> Caplan (1994) Clin. Plast. Surg. 21:429-435</text></nplcit>; and <nplcit id="ncit0003" npl-type="s"><text>Caplan et al. (1997) Clin Orthop. 342:254-269</text></nplcit>]. Additionally, the graft should provide some degree (greater than threshold) of tensile and biomechanical strength during the remodeling process.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">Acellular tissue matrices may be manufactured from a variety of source tissues. For example, acellular tissue matrix may be produced from any collagen-containing soft tissue and muscular skeleton (e.g., dermis, fascia, pericardium, dura, umbilical cords, placentae, cardiac valves, ligaments, tendons, vascular tissue (arteries and veins such as saphenous veins), neural connective tissue, urinary bladder tissue, ureter tissue, or intestinal tissue), as long as the above-described properties are retained by the matrix.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">While an acellular tissue matrix may be made from one or more individuals of the same species as the recipient of the acellular tissue matrix graft, this is not necessarily the case. Thus, for example, an acellular tissue matrix may be made from porcine tissue and implanted in a human patient. Species that can serve as recipients of acellular tissue matrix and donors of tissues or organs for the production of the acellular tissue matrix include, without limitation, humans, nonhuman primates (e.g., monkeys, baboons, or chimpanzees), pigs, cows, horses, goats, sheep, dogs, cats, rabbits, guinea pigs, gerbils, hamsters, rats, or mice. Of particular interest as donors are animals (e.g., pigs) that have been genetically engineered to lack the terminal α-galactose moiety. For descriptions of appropriate animals see co-pending <patcit id="pcit0005" dnum="US896594A"><text>U.S. Application Serial No. 10/896,594</text></patcit> and <patcit id="pcit0006" dnum="US6166288A"><text>U.S. Patent No. 6,166,288</text></patcit>.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">In some embodiments, a freeze dried acellular tissue matrix is produced from human dermis by the LifeCell Corporation (Branchburg, NJ) and marketed in the form of small sheets as ALLODERM®. The cryoprotectant used for freezing and drying ALLODERM® is a solution of 35% maltodextrin and 10mM<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> ethylenediaminetetraacetate (EDTA). Thus, the final dried product contains about 60% by weight acellular tissue matrix and about 40% by weight maltodextrin. The LifeCell Corporation also makes an analogous product made from porcine dermis (designated XENODERM) having the same proportions of acellular tissue matrix and maltodextrin as ALLODERM®.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">As an alternative to using such genetically engineered animals as donors, appropriate tissues and organs can be treated, before or after decellularization, with the enzyme α-galactosidase, which removes terminal α-galactose (α-gal) moieties from saccharide chains on, for example, glycoproteins. Methods of treating tissue with α-galactosidase to remove these moieties are described in, for example, <patcit id="pcit0007" dnum="US6331319B"><text>U.S. Patent No. 6,331,319</text></patcit>.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">In an implementation, either before or after the cells are killed in the acellular tissue matrix, the collagen-containing material is subjected to <i>in vitro</i> digestion of the collagen-containing material with one or more glycosidases, and particularly galactosidases, such as α-galactosidase. In particular, α-gal epitopes are eliminated by enzymatic treatment with α-galactosidases.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">The N-acetylactosamine residues are epitopes that are normally expressed on human and mammalian cells and thus are not immunogenic. The <i>in vitro</i> digestion of the collagen-containing material with glycosidases may be accomplished by various methods. For example, the collagen-containing material can be soaked or incubated in a buffer solution containing glycosidase. Alternatively, a buffer solution containing the glycosidase can be forced under pressure into the collagen-containing material via a pulsatile lavage process.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">Elimination of the α-gal epitopes from the collagen-containing material may diminish the immune response against the collagen-containing material. The α-gal epitope is expressed in non-primate mammals and in New World monkeys (monkeys of South America) as well as on macromolecules such as proteoglycans of the extracellular components. <nplcit id="ncit0004" npl-type="s"><text>U. Galili et al., J. Biol. Chem. 263: 17755 (1988</text></nplcit>). This epitope is absent in Old World primates (monkeys of Asia and Africa and apes) and humans, however. <i>Id.</i> Anti-gal antibodies are produced in humans and primates as a result of an immune response to α-gal epitope carbohydrate structures on gastrointestinal bacteria. <nplcit id="ncit0005" npl-type="s"><text>U. Galili et al., Infect. Immun. 56: 1730 (1988</text></nplcit>); <nplcit id="ncit0006" npl-type="s"><text>R. M. Hamadeh et al., J. Clin. Invest. 89: 1223 (1992</text></nplcit>).<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></p><p id="p0039" num="0039">Since non-primate mammals (e.g., pigs) produce α-gal epitopes, xenotransplantation by injection of collagen-containing material from these mammals into primates often results in rejection because of primate anti-Gal binding to these epitopes on the collagen-containing material. The binding results in the destruction of the collagen-containing material by complement fixation and by antibody dependent cell cytotoxicity. <nplcit id="ncit0007" npl-type="s"><text>U. Galili et al., Immunology Today 14: 480 (1993</text></nplcit>); <nplcit id="ncit0008" npl-type="s"><text>M. Sandrin et al., Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 90: 11391 (1993</text></nplcit>); <nplcit id="ncit0009" npl-type="s"><text>H. Good et al., Transplant. Proc. 24: 559 (1992</text></nplcit>); <nplcit id="ncit0010" npl-type="s"><text>B. H. Collins et al., J. Immunol. 154: 5500 (1995</text></nplcit>). Furthermore, xenotransplantation results in major activation of the immune system to produce increased amounts of high affinity anti-gal antibodies. Accordingly, the substantial elimination of α-gal epitopes from cells and from extracellular components of the collagen-containing material, and the prevention of re-expression of cellular α-gal epitopes can diminish the immune response against the collagen-containing material associated with anti-gal antibody binding to α-gal epitopes.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">Acellular tissue matrix's suitable for use in the present disclosure can be produced by a variety of methods, so long as their production results in matrices with the above-described biological and structural properties. In general, the steps involved in the production of an acellular tissue matrix include harvesting the tissue from a donor e.g., a human cadaver or any of the above-listed mammals), chemical treatment so as to stabilize the tissue and avoid biochemical and structural degradation together with, or followed by, cell removal under conditions that similarly preserve biological and structural function. The initial stabilizing solution arrests and prevents osmotic, hypoxic, autolytic, and proteolytic degradation, protects against microbial contamination, and reduces mechanical damage that can occur with tissues that contain, for example, smooth muscle components (e.g., blood vessels). The stabilizing solution may contain an appropriate buffer, one or more antioxidants, one or more oncotic agents, one or more antibiotics, one or more protease inhibitors, and in some cases, a smooth muscle relaxant. In some exemplary embodiments, the harvested tissue (e.g. dermal tissue) is treated with a chemical de-epithelialization solution to remove the epithelium from the tissue sample. For instance, in some embodiments, a sample comprising human or porcine dermal tissue is soaked overnight in 1 M NaCl solution at room temperature to remove the epithelial layer. In certain embodiments, the concentration of the<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> NaCl solution is increased to 1.5 M to ensure complete removal of the epithelial layer.</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">The tissue is then placed in a decellularization solution to remove viable cells (e.g., epithelial cells, endothelial cells, smooth muscle cells, and fibroblasts) from the structural matrix without damaging the basement membrane complex or the biological and structural integrity of the collagen matrix. The decellularization solution may contain an appropriate buffer, salt, an antibiotic, one or more detergents (e.g., TRITON X-100™, sodium deoxycholate, polyoxyethylene (20) sorbitan mono-oleate), one or more agents to prevent cross-linking, one or more protease inhibitors, and/or one or more enzymes. In some embodiments, the decellularization solution comprises 1% TRITON X-100™ in RPMI media with Gentamicin and 25 mM EDTA (ethylenediaminetetraacetic acid). In some embodiments, the tissue is incubated in the decellularization solution overnight at 37 °C with gentle shaking at 90 rpm. In certain embodiments, additional detergents may be used to remove fat from the tissue sample. For example, in some embodiments, 2% sodium deoxycholate is added to the decellularization solution for the treatment of peritoneal membranes.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">After the decellularization process, the tissue sample is washed thoroughly with saline. In some exemplary embodiments, e.g., when xenogenic material is used, the decellularized tissue is then treated overnight at room temperature with a deoxyribonuclease (DNase) solution. In some embodiments, the tissue sample (e.g. peritoneum and pericardial tissue) is treated with a DNase solution prepared in DNase buffer (20 mM HEPES (4-(2-hydroxyethyl)-1-piperazineethanesulfonic acid), 20 mM CaCl<sub>2</sub> and 20 mM MgCl<sub>2</sub>). Optionally, an antibiotic solution (e.g., Gentamicin) may be added to the DNase solution.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">After washing the tissue thoroughly with saline to remove the DNase solution, the tissue sample may be subjected to one or more enzymatic treatments to remove any immunogenic antigens if present in the sample. As noted earlier, the tissue sample may be treated with an α-galactosidase enzyme to eliminate α-gal epitopes if present in the tissue. In some embodiments, the tissue sample is treated with α-galactosidase at a concentration of 300 U/L prepared in 100 mM phosphate buffer at pH 6.0 In other embodiments, the concentration of α-galactosidase is increased to 400 U/L for adequate removal of the α-gal epitopes<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> from the harvested tissue (for example, in the treatment of porcine-derived dermal tissues).</p><p id="p0044" num="0044">After thorough removal of dead and/or lysed cell components, and antigens that may cause inflammation as well as any bioincompatible cell-removal agents, the matrix can be treated with a cryopreservation agent and cryopreserved and, optionally, freeze dried, again under conditions necessary to maintain the described biological and structural properties of the matrix. After cryopreservation or freeze-drying, the acellular tissue matrix can be thawed or rehydrated, respectively. All steps are generally carried out under aseptic, preferably sterile, conditions.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045">After the acellular tissue matrix is formed, histocompatible, viable cells may optionally be seeded to the acellular tissue matrix to produce a graft that may be further remodeled by the host. In one embodiment, histocompatible viable cells may be added to the matrices by standard <i>in vitro</i> cell co-culturing techniques prior to transplantation, or by <i>in vivo</i> repopulation following transplantation. <i>In vivo</i> repopulation can be by the recipient's own cells migrating into the acellular tissue matrix or by infusing or injecting cells obtained from the recipient or histocompatible cells from another donor into the acellular tissue matrix <i>in situ.</i></p><p id="p0046" num="0046">The cell types chosen for reconstitution may depend on the nature of the tissue or organ to which the acellular tissue matrix is being remodeled. For example, endothelial cell is important for the reconstitution of vascular conduits. Such cells line the inner surface of the tissue, and may be expanded in culture. The endothelial cells may be derived directly from the intended recipient patient or from umbilical arteries or veins, and can be used to reconstitute an acellular tissue matrix and the resulting composition grafted to the recipient. Alternatively, cultured (autologous or allogeneic) cells can be added to the acellular tissue matrix. Such cells can be, for example, grown under standard tissue culture conditions and then added to the acellular tissue matrix. In another embodiment, the cells can be grown in and/or on an acellular tissue matrix in tissue culture. Cells grown in and/or on an acellular tissue matrix in tissue culture can be obtained directly from an appropriate donor (e.g., the intended recipient or an allogeneic donor) or they can be first grown in tissue culture in the absence of the acellular tissue matrix.<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --></p><p id="p0047" num="0047">The following examples are provided to better explain the various embodiments and should not be interpreted in any way to limit the scope of the present disclosure.</p><heading id="h0004"><u>Example 1. Functional Study of Vascular Grafts Derived from Dermal Matrices</u></heading><p id="p0048" num="0048">Vascular grafts were formed using ALLODERM<sup>®</sup>, which is a human acellular dermal matrix (HADM) available from LifeCell Corporation (Branchburg, NJ). The HADM was provided in sheets having a thickness between 0.3-0.5 mm. The HADM was soaked in saline solution for 30 min and then cut into 0.5 x 1.5 cm section. ALLODERM<sup>®</sup> HADM includes an intact basement membrane, and the HADM sections were rolled into tubes with the basement membrane along the luminal surface of the tube. The tubes were sutured along the joining edge so as to create a single layer tube construct.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">The vascular grafts were then tested in a rat abdominal aorta replacement model. Twenty adult (9-11 weeks old) male Lewis rats were anesthetized with intraperitoneal pentobarbital 40 mg/kg, and a midline abdominal incision was formed in each rat. A 1-cm segment of the abdominal aorta, from below the renal arteries to just above the aortic bifurcation, was excised through the midline incision. The excised arterial segment was replaced with a HADM-derived vascular graft. The grafts were implanted in the orthotopic position with end-to-end anastomoses using 9-0 nylon interrupted sutures. The quality of the graft and the extent of healing of the implantation site was recorded at four study end-points (1, 3, 6 and 12 months). Five animals were sacrificed at each endpoint. 1-cm of the vascular graft and 0.5 cm of host tissue material beyond the anastomoses (total explant length of 2-cm) were excised from each sacrificed animal, along with a sample of the spleen and lymph node. The explanted sections were used for histology, immunohostichemistry, SEM (Scanning Electron Microscopy) and TEM (Transmission Electron Microscopy) analyses. The excised samples, representing the graft mid-portion and graft-host tissue interface, were placed in 10% formalin or 8% Glutaraldehyde (for SEM &amp; TEM analysis) for fixation and subsequent analysis.</p><heading id="h0005"><u>Clinical Observation</u></heading><p id="p0050" num="0050">All animals that received the vascular graft had normal post-surgical recovery and either maintained or gained weight during the study period, similar to non-operated animals. Fourteen animals survived to their predetermined sacrifice<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> date with no clinical indication of implant failure as evidenced by limitation of leg movement and pathological changes in the legs. One animal died at four days post-implantation due to internal bleeding. There was no evidence of infection at the surgical site in any animal during the study. Gross observation of the explanted vascular grafts showed no evidence of stenosis, aneurysm, hyperplasia, suture dehiscence or thrombus formation. Additionally, most of the explanted grafts had smooth luminal surfaces and no evidence of calcification was observed. Two of the grafts (explanted at 6 and 12 months) showed areas more rigid than normal vascular structure, suggesting vascular calcification. All of the grafts were well integrated with the native rat aorta at the site of anastomoses.</p><heading id="h0006"><u>Histology</u></heading><p id="p0051" num="0051">The explanted graft sections were processed with H&amp;E (Hematoxylin and Eosin) and Verhoeff Van Geison staining. H&amp;E staining of a representative graft cross-section at 3-months (<figref idrefs="f0004">FIGS. 4A and 4B</figref>) and 12-months (<figref idrefs="f0004">FIGS. 4C-4G</figref>) demonstrated fibroblast cells populating the grafts and a few endothelial cells lining the luminal surface of the grafts. <figref idrefs="f0004">FIGS. 4A-4E</figref> are H&amp;E stained cross-sections taken at the mid-portion of the grafts, <figref idrefs="f0004">FIGS. 4F and 4G</figref> are H&amp;E stained of cross-sections taken at the site of anastomoses, and <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 4H</figref> is an H&amp;E stained of a graft that was never implanted and was used as a control in the study.</p><p id="p0052" num="0052">Histology of the explanted anastomosis site showed complete tissue integration and smooth transition of the graft to host blood vessel. A mild inflammatory cell infiltration was observed at 1-month, but the level diminished over time, and no inflammatory cells were observed at 3-months, indicating that no chronic inflammation was induced by the implanted grafts.</p><p id="p0053" num="0053"><figref idrefs="f0005">FIGS. 5A and 5B</figref> show Verhoff's staining of cross-sections taken at the mid-portion of the grafts, <figref idrefs="f0005">FIGS. 5C and 5D</figref> show Verhoff's staining of cross-sections taken at the site of anastomosis, <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 5E</figref> shows Verhoff's staining of a normal rat aorta and <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 5F</figref> shows a pre-implant vascular graft used as a control. Verhoff's staining of the graft cross-sections indicated that the neomedia was rich in collagen, and cells appeared to have extensive elastin deposition.</p><heading id="h0007"><u>SEM and TEM Analyses</u></heading><p id="p0054" num="0054"><figref idrefs="f0006">FIGS. 6A-6F</figref> are SEM micrographs of vascular grafts produced as described above. SEM of pre-implant grafts showed no cell structures on the<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> surface of the basement membrane, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 6A</figref>. Vascular grafts explanted at 1-month had endothelial cells on their luminal surfaces (<figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 6B</figref>), and at 3-month endothelial-type cells completely covered the luminal surface (<figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 6C</figref>). The interface of the graft and the rat aorta showed intact anastomosis, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 6D</figref>. The surface of the graft at 3-months (<figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 6E</figref>) was completely covered with cells and was indistinguishable from the surface of the rat aorta (<figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 6F</figref>).</p><p id="p0055" num="0055">Similarly, TEM micrographs of representative vascular grafts taken at 1-month (<figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 7A</figref>) showed flat endothelial cells with accompanying basement membrane (BM) lining the lumen of the graft. Smooth muscle cells (SMC) with microfilaments and dense bodies were also clearly seen on the TEM images. The dark staining material along the surface of the smooth muscle cells, which is representative of elastic fiber formation, was observed on the TEM micrographs, although the elastic fibers formed were immature compared to the internal elastic lamina (IEL) observed in the TEM image of normal rat aorta (<figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 7B</figref>).</p><heading id="h0008"><u>Immunostaining</u></heading><p id="p0056" num="0056">Endothelial cell development on the luminal surface of the grafts was confirmed using endothelial cell staining and vWF (von Willebrand Factor) staining. Specific antibodies against rat endothelial cells and vWF were used to identify endothelial cell deposition on the surface of the lumen. Endothelial cells were observed at 1-month, but did not fully cover the lumen, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 8A</figref>. Significant deposition of endothelial cells was observed at 3-months, 6-months and 12-months, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0008">FIGS. 8B, 8C and 8D</figref>, respectively. Immunohistological staining by vWF showed that the entire surface of the graft was lined with endothelium, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0008">FIGS. 8E-8H</figref>.</p><p id="p0057" num="0057">Repopulation of the vascular graft with smooth muscle cells and fibroblast cells was verified by staining with specific antibodies against α-smooth muscle actin and vimetin, respectively. Cross-sections of rat abdominal aorta were also stained with antibodies against α-smooth muscle actin and fibroblast cells for use as control (<figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 9A and 9F</figref>, respectively). The grafts at 1-month (<figref idrefs="f0009">FIGS. 9B and 9G</figref>), 3-months (<figref idrefs="f0009">FIGS. 9C and 9H</figref>), 6-months (<figref idrefs="f0009">FIGS. 9D and 9I</figref>) and 12-months (<figref idrefs="f0009">FIGS. 9E and 9J</figref>) showed repopulation of the graft with smooth muscle cells and fibroblast cells starting at 1 month post-implantation.</p><heading id="h0009"><u>Inflammatory and Immune Response</u></heading><!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --><p id="p0058" num="0058">The explanted sections were stained with anti-rat T cell, B cell and macrophage antibodies to identify the inflammatory response of the host against the implanted graft. <figref idrefs="f0010">FIGS. 10A-10D</figref> represent grafts stained with anti-rat T cell antibodies at 1-month, 3-months, 6-months and 12-months, respectively. Similarly, <figref idrefs="f0010">FIGS. 10E-10H</figref> represent grafts stained with B cell antibodies, and <figref idrefs="f0010">FIGS. 101-10L</figref> represent grafts stained with antibodies against macrophages. All three types of inflammatory cells were found to infiltrate the implanted grafts moderately at 1-month, but no inflammatory cell infiltration was detected in the neomedia. Inflammatory cells diminished significantly at 3-months, and those that were observed were primarily near the periphery of the graft. No inflammatory cells were observed after 6 months.</p><p id="p0059" num="0059">Similarly, a moderate level of IgG antibody was seen on the grafts during the first 3 months, but not in the neomedia. Rat IgG (<figref idrefs="f0011">FIGS. 11A-11E</figref>) and IgM (<figref idrefs="f0011">FIGS. 11F-11J</figref>) bound to the vascular grafts were examined at 1-month <figref idrefs="f0011">(FIGS. 11A and 11 F</figref>), 3-months (<figref idrefs="f0011">FIGS. 11 B and 11 G</figref>), 6-months (<figref idrefs="f0011">FIGS. 11C and11 H</figref>) and 12-months (<figref idrefs="f0011">FIGS. 11D and 11I</figref>). Normal rat abdominal aorta (<figref idrefs="f0011">FIGS. 11E and 11J</figref>) was used as a control. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0011">FIGS. 11A-11D</figref>, moderate level of antibody IgG was discovered on the graft during the first 3 months. After 3-months, the IgG level diminished significantly. IgM deposition was not found in any graft during the study.</p><heading id="h0010"><u>Example 2. Assessment of Mechanical Strength, Thermostability and Thrombotic Effect of Vascular Grafts Formed Using Bioadhesives.</u></heading><p id="p0060" num="0060">Vascular grafts derived from human acellular dermal matrix (HADM) were used for this study. Sheets of HADM were rolled into tubular constructs, and the edges of the sheet were attached using fibrin glue. The burst strength of the grafts was evaluated using burst test (American National Institute of Standards (ANSI) code: ANSI/AAMI/ISO 7198:1998/2001/®2004). The maximum burst strength was calculated to be 1639 ± 432 mmHg (n=2), which indicated that the vascular grafts formed using bioadhesives were strong enough to sustain physiological blood pressures.</p><p id="p0061" num="0061">The denaturation onset temperatures of collagen in the dermal matrices was determined by Differential Scanning Calorimetry (DSC). As shown in the graph in <figref idrefs="f0012">FIG. 12</figref>, the collagen denaturation temperature of the glued vascular grafts compared favorably with that of human acellular dermal matrices. The graph<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> includes data that corresponds to denaturation onset temperature of untreated HADM, and vascular grafts formed by gluing HADM with DERMABOND<sup>®</sup>, fibrinogen and chitosan-based adhesives. Data from this experiment indicates that the bioadhesives did not alter the biochemical properties of the matrix.</p><p id="p0062" num="0062">The efficacy of antithrombotic agents (e.g. heparin) on glued vascular grafts was assessed using a clot forming method. Heparin coating was performed by suspending the vascular grafts in a 0.4% heparin sodium salt solution for 24 hours at room temperature. 200 µl of blood and 12.5 µl of 100 mM CaCl<sub>2</sub> were added to the luminal surface of 1 cm<sup>2</sup> sections of the vascular grafts, and the graft sections were then placed in an incubator for 1 hour at 37 °C with 5% CO<sub>2</sub>. Any visible clot was removed from the surface with forceps, placed in a tube, lyophilized, and weighed. As shown in the graph in <figref idrefs="f0013">FIG. 13</figref>, the antithrombotic property of heparin is not affected when heparin came in contact with a bioadhesive. The graph includes data that corresponds to weight of blood clots formed on untreated HADM, heparin treated HADM (HADM + Hep), fibronogen glue (FG) and HADM treated with both heparin and fibrinogen glue (HADM + FG + Hep). As shown in the graph, the amount of blood clot formed on HADM treated with both heparin and fibrinogen glue compared favorably with the blood clot data from the heparin treated HADM, indicating that the fibrinogen glue did not interfere with the antithrombotic function of the heparin coating on dermal matrices.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56983757" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Gefäßtransplantat, umfassend:
<claim-text>eine schlauchförmige Leitung, die eine Schlauchwand umfasst, wobei die Schlauchwand ein Lumen für den Durchfluss von Blut durch diese begrenzt; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei die Schlauchwand eine zellenlose Gewebematrix umfasst, die aus einem Gewebe gebildet ist, welches eine fundamentale Membran beinhaltet, wobei die zellenlose Matrix die fundamentale Membran umfasst und die fundamentale Membran eine luminale Oberfläche der Schlauchwand bildet.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Gefäßtransplantat nach Anspruch 1, wobei eine erste Längskante der zellenlosen Gewebematrix an einer zweiten Längskante der zellenlosen Gewebematrix angebracht ist, um eine fluiddichte Naht zu bilden, die sich längs des Transplantats erstreckt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Gefäßtransplantat nach Anspruch 2, wobei die Anbringung der ersten und zweiten Längskante einen länglichen Kamm erzeugt, der von einer abluminalen Oberfläche der Schlauchwand vorsteht.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Gefäßtransplantat nach Anspruch 2, wobei die erste und die zweite Längskante unter Verwendung von zumindest einer Naht und zumindest einem Klebemittel angebracht sind.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Gefäßtransplantat nach Anspruch 2, wobei sich die erste Längskante über die zweite Längskante erstreckt, um eine mehrschichtige überlappte Region zu bilden.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Gefäßtransplantat nach Anspruch 7, wobei die Schichten in der überlappten Region aneinander angebracht sind.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Gefäßtransplantat nach Anspruch 1, wobei die zellenlose Gewebematrix eine Hautmatrix und/oder eine Perikardgewebematrix und/oder eine peritoneale Membran umfasst.<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Gefäßtransplantat nach Anspruch 7, wobei die Hautmatrix von menschlicher Haut stammt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Gefäßtransplantat nach Anspruch 1, wobei die zellenlose Gewebematrix von Gewebe stammt, das für einen menschlichen Empfänger xenogen ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Gefäßtransplantat nach Anspruch 9, wobei das Gewebe von einem Schwein mit einem α1,3-Galactosyltransferase (α1,3GT)-Mangel stammt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Gefäßtransplantat nach Anspruch 1, wobei die zellenlose Gewebematrix von Gewebe stammt, das für einen menschlichen Empfänger allogen ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Gefäßtransplantat nach Anspruch 1, wobei die zellenlose Gewebematrix mehrere übereinander gelagerte Bahnen umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Gefäßtransplantat nach Anspruch 1, wobei die zellenlose Gewebematrix mit Wachstumsfaktoren behandelt wird, die eine Gewebeneuformung fördern.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Gefäßtransplantat nach Anspruch 1, wobei die fundamentale Membran mit Antithrombosemitteln behandelt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Gefäßtransplantat nach Anspruch 1, wobei die fundamentale Membran mit Antiverkaltungsmitteln behandelt wird.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56983758" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A vascular graft, comprising:
<claim-text>a tubular conduit comprising a tubular wall, the tubular wall defining a lumen for the passage of blood therethrough; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the tubular wall comprises an acellular tissue matrix, <u>formed from a tissue that includes a basement membrane, wherein the acellular matrix comprises said basement membrane,</u> the basement membrane forming a luminal surface of the tubular wall.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The vascular graft of claim 1, wherein a first longitudinal edge of the acellular tissue matrix is attached to a second longitudinal edge of the acellular tissue matrix to form a fluid-tight seam extending along the length of the graft.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The vascular graft of claim 2, wherein the attachment of the first and the second longitudinal edges creates a longitudinal ridge protruding from an abluminal surface of the tubular wall.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The vascular graft of claim 2, wherein the first and the second longitudinal edges are attached using at least one of sutures and at least one adhesive.<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The vascular graft of claim 2, wherein the first longitudinal edge extends over the second longitudinal edge to form a multi-layered overlapped region.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The vascular graft of claim 7, wherein the layers in the overlapped region are attached to one another.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The vascular graft of claim 1, wherein the acellular tissue matrix comprises at least one of a dermal matrix, a pericardial tissue matrix, and a peritoneal membrane.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The vascular graft of claim 7, wherein the dermal matrix is derived from human skin.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The vascular graft of claim 1, wherein the acellular tissue matrix is derived from tissue that is xenogeneic to a human recipient.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The vascular graft of claim 9, wherein the tissue is from an α1,3-galactosyltransferase (α1,3GT) deficient pig.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>The vascular graft of claim 1, wherein the acellular tissue matrix is derived from tissue that is allogeneic to a human recipient.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>The vascular graft of claim 1, wherein the acellular tissue matrix comprises multiple superimposed sheets.<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>The vascular graft of claim 1, wherein the acellular tissue matrix is treated with growth factors that promote tissue remodeling.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>The vascular graft of claim 1, wherein the basement membrane is treated with anti-thrombotic agents.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>The vascular graft of claim 1, wherein the basement membrane is treated with anti-calcification agents.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56983759" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Greffe vasculaire, comprenant :
<claim-text>un conduit tubulaire comprenant une paroi tubulaire, la paroi tubulaire définissant une lumière pour que le sang puisse y passer ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>ladite paroi tubulaire comprenant une matrice de tissu acellulaire, formée à partir d'un tissu qui comporte une membrane basale, la matrice acellulaire comprenant ladite membrane basale, la membrane basale formant une surface luminale de la paroi tubulaire.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Greffe vasculaire selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle un premier bord longitudinal de la matrice de tissu acellulaire est lié à un deuxième bord longitudinal de la matrice de tissu acellulaire pour former une jonction étanche aux fluides dans le sens de la longueur de la greffe.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Greffe vasculaire selon la revendication 2, dans laquelle la liaison des premier et deuxième bords longitudinaux crée un pli longitudinal protubérant par rapport à une surface abluminale de la paroi tubulaire.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Greffe vasculaire selon la revendication 2, dans laquelle les premier et deuxième bords longitudinaux sont liés au moyen d'au moins une suture et au moins un adhésif.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Greffe vasculaire selon la revendication 2, dans laquelle le premier bord longitudinal s'étend sur le deuxième bord longitudinal pour former une région superposée de plusieurs couches.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Greffe vasculaire selon la revendication 7, dans laquelle les couches de la région superposée sont liées ensemble.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Greffe vasculaire selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle la matrice de tissu acellulaire comprend au moins une matrice choisie parmi une matrice dermique, une matrice de tissu péricardique et une membrane péritonéale.<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Greffe vasculaire selon la revendication 7, dans laquelle la matrice dermique est dérivée de peau humaine.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Greffe vasculaire selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle la matrice de tissu acellulaire est dérivée d'un tissu xénogénique chez un receveur humain.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Greffe vasculaire selon la revendication 9, dans laquelle le tissu provient d'un porc déficient en α1,3-galactosyltransférase (α1,3GT).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Greffe vasculaire selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle la matrice de tissu acellulaire est dérivée d'un tissu allogénique chez un receveur humain.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Greffe vasculaire selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle la matrice de tissu acellulaire comprend plusieurs feuilles superposées.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Greffe vasculaire selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle la matrice de tissu acellulaire est traitée avec des facteurs de croissance qui favorisent le remodelage du tissu.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Greffe vasculaire selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle la membrane basale est traitée avec des agents antithrombotiques.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Greffe vasculaire selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle la membrane basale est traitée avec des agents anti-calcification.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16671645" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1A,1B"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="154" he="187" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2A,2B"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="160" he="178" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="150" he="167" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --><figure id="f0004" num="4A,4B,4C,4D,4E,4F,4G,4H"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="165" he="186" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --><figure id="f0005" num="5A,5B,5C,5D,5E,5F"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="150" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --><figure id="f0006" num="6A,6B,6C,6D,6E,6F"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="156" he="226" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --><figure id="f0007" num="7A,7B"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="145" he="219" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --><figure id="f0008" num="8A,8B,8C,8D,8E,8F,8G,8H"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="141" he="231" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --><figure id="f0009" num="9A,9B,9C,9D,9E,9F,9G,9H,9I,9J"><img id="if0009" file="imgf0009.tif" wi="112" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="36"> --><figure id="f0010" num="10A,10B,10C,10D,10E,10F,10G,10H,10I,10J,10K,10L"><img id="if0010" file="imgf0010.tif" wi="165" he="218" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="37"> --><figure id="f0011" num="11A,11B,11C,11D,11E,11F,11G,11H,11I,11J"><img id="if0011" file="imgf0011.tif" wi="114" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="38"> --><figure id="f0012" num="12"><img id="if0012" file="imgf0012.tif" wi="141" he="228" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="39"> --><figure id="f0013" num="13"><img id="if0013" file="imgf0013.tif" wi="154" he="223" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
