<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2678059-A1" country="EP" doc-number="2678059" kind="A1" date="20140101" family-id="45774284" file-reference-id="296411" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146551412" ucid="EP-2678059-A1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2678059</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-12706698-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154825335" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12706698</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120215</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP220438396" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12706698.3</doc-number><date>20120215</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140446387" ucid="EP-11156036-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>11156036</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20110225</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140449069" ucid="EP-12706698-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12706698</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120215</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140450610" ucid="IB-2012050691-W" linkage-type="W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>IB</country><doc-number>2012050691</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20120215</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988108430" load-source="docdb">B05B  17/06        20060101ALI20120911BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988119546" load-source="docdb">A61M  15/00        20060101ALI20120911BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988124809" load-source="docdb">A61M  11/00        20060101AFI20120911BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1702765123" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B05B  15/58        20180201 LI20180202BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988096235" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61M2205/3606      20130101 LA20131214BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988104865" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B05B  12/10        20130101 LI20131214BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988107977" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61M  11/005       20130101 FI20131214BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988125102" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61M2205/3368      20130101 LA20131214BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988126030" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61M  15/0085      20130101 LI20131214BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988127246" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B05B  17/0676      20130101 LI20131214BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988127399" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61M2205/3382      20130101 LA20131214BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988138785" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B05B  17/0646      20130101 LI20131214BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132186720" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">AEROSOLERZEUGENDE VORRICHTUNG ZUM ZERSTÄUBEN VON FLÜSSIGKEITEN UND VERFAHREN ZUR TEMPERATURKONTROLLE EINER ZU ZERSTÄUBENDEN FLÜSSIGKEIT</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132186721" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">AN AEROSOL GENERATING DEVICE FOR NEBULIZING A LIQUID AND A METHOD OF TEMPERATURE CONTROL OF A LIQUID TO BE NEBULIZED</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132186722" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">DISPOSITIF DE GÉNÉRATION D'AÉROSOL POUR NÉBULISER UN LIQUIDE ET PROCÉDÉ DE RÉGULATION DE TEMPÉRATURE D'UN LIQUIDE À NÉBULISER</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918155746" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>KONINKL PHILIPS NV</last-name><address><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918133225" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>KONINKLIJKE PHILIPS N.V.</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918979334" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Koninklijke Philips N.V.</last-name><iid>101391185</iid><address><street>High Tech Campus 5</street><city>5656 AE Eindhoven</city><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918153213" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>BENTVELSEN PETRUS HENRICUS CORNELIUS</last-name><address><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918159131" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>BENTVELSEN, PETRUS HENRICUS CORNELIUS</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918992460" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>BENTVELSEN, PETRUS HENRICUS CORNELIUS</last-name><address><street>c/o High Tech Campus Building 44</street><city>NL-5656 AE Eindhoven</city><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918151700" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>HUIJGEN HENDRIK</last-name><address><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918170316" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>HUIJGEN, HENDRIK</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918991829" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>HUIJGEN, HENDRIK</last-name><address><street>c/o High Tech Campus Building 44</street><city>NL-5656 AE Eindhoven</city><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918981178" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Steffen, Thomas</last-name><iid>100958149</iid><address><street>Philips Intellectual Property &amp; Standards P.O. Box 220</street><city>5600 AE Eindhoven</city><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="IB-2012050691-W"><document-id><country>IB</country><doc-number>2012050691</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20120215</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2012114230-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2012114230</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20120830</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548866683" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS548917745" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS548866684" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS548931319" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS548933484" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS548816748" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS548917750" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS548866685" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548816749" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS548816750" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS548935834" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS548931320" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS548838146" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548866686" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548816751" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS548866687" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS548917751" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS548933485" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS548816752" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS548838147" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS548816753" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS548931321" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS548928764" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS548931326" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS548931327" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS548928765" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS548928834" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS548838148" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS548935835" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS548933486" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS548928835" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS548838149" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS548928836" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS548933487" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS548917752" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS548935836" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS548933488" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS548931328" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA99623608" ref-ucid="WO-2012114230-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p num="0000">An aerosol generating device (20) comprises a reservoir(1) for containing a liquid to be atomized and a nebulization chamber (3) for nebulizing a portion of the liquid received from the reservoir. The aerosol device further comprises liquid exchange means (7,8) for exchanging in use a further portion of the liquid received in the nebulization chamber with liquid from the reservoir to reduce a temperature increase of liquid in the nebulization chamber caused by heat produced by the piezo (4).</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA99822427" ref-ucid="WO-2012114230-A1" lang="EN" source="national office" load-source="docdb"><p>An aerosol generating device (20) comprises a reservoir(1) for containing a liquid to be atomized and a nebulization chamber (3) for nebulizing a portion of the liquid received from the reservoir. The aerosol device further comprises liquid exchange means (7,8) for exchanging in use a further portion of the liquid received in the nebulization chamber with liquid from the reservoir to reduce a temperature increase of liquid in the nebulization chamber caused by heat produced by the piezo (4).</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA99623609" ref-ucid="WO-2012114230-A1" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><p num="0000">L'invention concerne un dispositif de génération d'aérosol (20) comprenant un réservoir(1) destiné à contenir un liquide à atomiser, et une chambre de nébulisation (3) destinée à nébuliser une partie du liquide provenant du réservoir. Le dispositif aérosol comprend également des moyens d'échange de liquide (7, 8) pour échanger, lorsqu'on l'utilise, une autre partie du liquide provenant de la chambre de nébulisation par un liquide provenant du réservoir afin de réduire l'augmentation de température du liquide dans la chambre de nébulisation provoquée par la chaleur produire par le piezo (4).</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA99822428" ref-ucid="WO-2012114230-A1" lang="FR" source="national office" load-source="docdb"><p>L'invention concerne un dispositif de génération d'aérosol (20) comprenant un réservoir(1) destiné à contenir un liquide à atomiser, et une chambre de nébulisation (3) destinée à nébuliser une partie du liquide provenant du réservoir. Le dispositif aérosol comprend également des moyens d'échange de liquide (7, 8) pour échanger, lorsqu'on l'utilise, une autre partie du liquide provenant de la chambre de nébulisation par un liquide provenant du réservoir afin de réduire l'augmentation de température du liquide dans la chambre de nébulisation provoquée par la chaleur produire par le piezo (4).</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES50930906" ref-ucid="WO-2012114230-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="2"/>--><p id="p0001" num="0001"> An aerosol generating device for nebulizing a liquid and a method of temperature control of a liquid to be nebulized </p><p id="p0002" num="0002">TECHNICAL FIELD OF THE INVENTION </p><p id="p0003" num="0003"> The invention relates to an aerosol generating device for nebulizing a liquid. Such an aerosol device may for example be used for nebulizing a drug for inhalation by a patient whereby the nebulized drug is administered to the patient through deposition in his lungs. The invention further relates to a method of temperature control of a liquid to be nebulized. The liquid may for example be a drug. </p><p id="p0004" num="0004">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION </p><p id="p0005" num="0005"> Several different types of nebulizers are known such as for example ultrasonic type nebulizers which use a piezo electric crystal to atomize the liquid received in a nebulization chamber using a mesh. The piezo electric crystal may for example be used to vibrate the mesh causing the liquid to be dispersed through the mesh to form a spray of small droplets. In another example the piezo electric crystal is used to vibrate the liquid in the nebulization chamber causing it to be nebulized through the mesh. The temperature of some liquids, such as for example drugs, must be kept within specified limits. Due to efficiency limitations the piezo electric crystal will transform part of the electrical energy offered at its terminals to mechanical movement and another part to heat. As the piezo electric crystal is in direct or indirect contact with the liquid that is received in the nebulization chamber the heat produced by the piezo electric crystal may cause a temperature rise of the liquid. It is an object of the invention to reduce a temperature rise of the liquid in the nebulization chamber. </p><p id="p0006" num="0006">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </p><p id="p0007" num="0007"> The object is achieved with the aerosol generating device for nebulizing a liquid according to claim 1.The liquid in the nebulizing chamber is received from the reservoir and brought into vibration by the vibration means. Due to limitations in the efficiency the vibration means will produce heat causing the temperature of the nebulization chamber and the liquid contained therein to increase. To limit this temperature increase a further portion of the liquid received in the nebulization chamber is exchanged with liquid from the reservoir. The liquid in the reservoir is not affected by the heat generated by the 
<!-- EPO <DP n="3"/>-->
 vibration source and has therefore a lower temperature than the portion of the liquid that is contained in the nebulization chamber. By exchanging the further portion of the liquid with the liquid contained in the reservoir the temperature rise of the portion of the liquid contained in the nebulization chamber is limited and the temperature of the liquid contained in the nebulization chamber is reduced. </p><p id="p0008" num="0008"> In an embodiment the volume of the nebulization chamber is in the range of 0.1ml to 0.2ml and the sum of the volumes of the nebulization chamber and the reservoir is in the range of 0.25ml to 1.75ml. In another embodiment the volume of the reservoir is at least 5 times larger than the volume of the nebulization chamber. </p><p id="p0009" num="0009"> In an embodiment the aerosol generating device is arranged for filling the reservoir from an external source such as a vial. In a further embodiment the aerosol generating device comprises a further reservoir for metering the liquid received from an external source, the reservoir being arranged to receive a metered liquid dose from the further reservoir. </p><p id="p0010" num="0010"> In a further embodiment the mesh is mounted across an aperture in the nebulization chamber, the vibration source being arranged to vibrate the mesh. The vibrations of the mesh causes the liquid contained in the nebulization chamber to pass through the holes in the mesh forming droplets which are released from the front surface of the mesh. </p><p id="p0011" num="0011"> In a further embodiment the nebulization chamber is constructed to form a gap between the mesh and the vibration source. The portion of the liquid that is received in the nebulization chamber is fed into the space between the mesh and the vibration source. The vibration source causes pressure waves in the liquid contained in the space causing the liquid to pass through the holes in the mesh thereby forming a spray of droplets. </p><p id="p0012" num="0012"> The exchange means for exchanging liquid between the reservoir and the nebulization chamber may comprise for example a channel, or a pump, or both. The liquid exchange may for example result from capillary or gravity force. In a further embodiment the reservoir and the nebulization chamber are positioned relative to each other to allow in use the nebulization chamber to be filled as a result of the gravity force. The reservoir may be interfacing with the nebulization chamber and may have an aperture in the wall where the reservoir and nebulization chamber interface to allow the nebulization chamber to be filled with the portion of the liquid from the reservoir through said aperture. To support the exchanging the exchange means may further comprise a return channel for feeding the further portion from the nebulization chamber to the reservoir. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="4"/>-->
 In a further embodiment the exchange means include an active component such as for example a pump wherein the pump is controlled in dependence of a measured temperature of the liquid in the nebulization chamber. When the measured temperature is above a predetermined threshold the pump is activated to flush the liquid contained in the nebulization chamber. In a further embodiment the aerosol generating device may further comprise temperature sensing means to measure a temperature of the liquid contained in the reservoir or nebulization chamber. Due to the nebulizing of the liquid contained in the nebulization chamber the total volume of liquid in the nebulization chamber and the reservoir decreases. This will cause a temperature rise of the liquid contained in the reservoir and nebulization chamber. If the temperature of the liquid contained in the reservoir or nebulization chamber is above a predetermined threshold the nebulizing may be stopped, paused or continued at a reduced power level such that the heat produced by the nebulizing means is reduced. In a further embodiment the liquid exchange means may further comprise cooling means. These cooling means may for example be passive such as a heat sink coupled to a return channel. The cooling means may also be active such a Peltier element which for example may be operated in dependence of a measured liquid temperature in the nebulization chamber and/or reservoir. </p><p id="p0013" num="0013"> The object is further achieved with a method of temperature control of a liquid to be nebulized in an aerosol generating device according to claim 12. </p><p id="p0014" num="0014">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </p><p id="p0015" num="0015"> Specific embodiments of the invention will now be described, by way of example only, with reference to the following drawings, in which: </p><p id="p0016" num="0016"> Fig. 1 shows an embodiment of an aerosol generating device; </p><p id="p0017" num="0017"> Fig. 2a shows a further embodiment of an aerosol generating device; </p><p id="p0018" num="0018"> Fig. 2b shows an embodiment of a vibration means coupled to a mesh; </p><p id="p0019" num="0019"> Fig. 3 shows a further embodiment of an aerosol generating device comprising one return channel and pumping means; </p><p id="p0020" num="0020"> Fig. 4 shows a further embodiment of an aerosol generating device comprising pumping means in the supply channel; </p><p id="p0021" num="0021"> Fig. 5 shows an embodiment of an aerosol generating device comprising cooling means; </p><p id="p0022" num="0022"> Fig. 6 shows an embodiment of an aerosol generating device with a metering chamber; 
<!-- EPO <DP n="5"/>-->
 Fig. 7 shows an embodiment of pumping means; </p><p id="p0023" num="0023"> Fig. 8 shows an embodiment of a method of temperature control of a liquid to be nebulized in an aerosol generating device. </p><p id="p0024" num="0024">DETAILLED DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENTS </p><p id="p0025" num="0025"> Figs. 1 - 6 show embodiments of an aerosol generating device comprising a reservoir 1, a nebulization chamber 3 and liquid exchanging means 2, 7, 8 coupled between the nebulization chamber and the reservoir. The liquid exchange means supplies in use a portion of a liquid from the reservoir to the nebulization chamber and exchanges a further portion of the liquid received in the nebulization chamber with liquid from the reservoir. Fig. 1 shows an aerosol generating device 20 or nebulizer having a mesh 5 mounted across an aperture in the nebulization chamber 3. The mesh is realized by for example thin metal plate with small holes. A vibration means 4 such as a piezo electric element is coupled to the nebulization chamber such that in operation its produced heat and vibrations are transferred to the liquid contained in the nebulization chamber. Figs. 2a shows a further embodiment of a nebulizer 20 in which the vibration means 4 is coupled to the nebulization chamber 3. In this embodiment the vibration means is for example an O-ring shaped piezo electric element. The piezo is connected to the mesh 5 see Fig. 2b showing a front side view, wherein the mesh may have a concave shape. During a vibrational motion of the piezo pressure is built up in the vicinity of the mesh causing an ejection of the fluid through the holes as droplets and creating an aerosol. In both shown embodiments of Figs. 1 and 2 the liquid to be atomized into an aerosol 6 is driven through the holes of the mesh 5 by the vibration of the piezo 4. The heat produced in the piezo will cause a temperature rise of the liquid contained in the nebulization chamber 3. In an embodiment the volume of the nebulization chamber 3 is in the range of 0.1ml to 0.2ml and the sum of the volumes of the reservoir 1 and the nebulization chamber is in the rage of 0.25ml to 0.75ml. The nebulization output rate resulting in spray 6 may for example be in the range of 0.25 ml/minute to 1.5ml/minute. With an output rate of 0.25ml/minute and a sum of the volumes of reservoir and the nebulization chamber of 0.75ml the nebulizing of the fluid takes about 3 minutes. During these 3 minutes the dissipation of the piezo will cause a temperature rise of the liquid, and thus also of the spray 6. This temperature rise may for some liquids such as drugs be undesirable. The produced heat can be decreased by operating the vibration means 4 at a lower power level at the cost of a reduced output flow of the spray 6. The power level at which the piezo is operating is controlled by a controller 13 which may determine a frequency, a duty cycle and voltage 
<!-- EPO <DP n="6"/>-->
 level at which the piezo is driven. The nebulizer 20 further comprises a reservoir 1 that is coupled via a supply channel 2 to the nebulization chamber. The reservoir may for example be filled by the user with a medicine from a drug vial 12. In another embodiment the volume of the drug to be delivered to the patient's lungs is equal to the sum of the volumes of the reservoir and the nebulization chamber. As the volume in the vial may be larger than the volume of the reservoir 1 an overflow chamber 10 may be added such as shown in the embodiment of Fig. 6 in which the reservoir has the function of a metering chamber 11 with a volume corresponding to a treatment. In a further embodiment, not shown, the nebulizer may have a metering chamber and overflow chamber for metering the volume of the drug and a reservoir arranged for receiving the metered volume from the metering chamber. It is preferred that the volume of the reservoir is larger than the volume of the nebulization chamber. In operation of the nebulizer the nebulization chamber 3 is filled with a portion of the liquid contained in the volume of the reservoir 1. The supply channel 2 coupling the reservoir 1 to the chamber 3 may be dimensioned to provide a capillary filling of the nebulization chamber. Fig. 1 shows the aerosol device 20 being constructed to obtain that in use the reservoir 1 is positioned above the nebulization chamber 3 such that the gravity force causes a liquid flow from the reservoir 1 to the chamber 3. Fig. 3 shows an embodiment of an aerosol device 20 in which the reservoir 1 and nebulization chamber 3 are coupled without a supply channel. In use the heat produced by the vibration source 4 is transferred to the liquid contained in the chamber 3 causing a temperature rise. To obtain a reduction of the temperature of the liquid in the nebulization chamber 3 a liquid exchange between the nebulization chamber and the reservoir 1 is realized. The liquid exchange may for example be realized by pumping a further portion of the liquid contained in the nebulization chamber 3 back to the reservoir 1 and refill the nebulization chamber with liquid from the reservoir such that the average temperature of the liquid contained in the nebulization chamber is reduced. In Fig. 3 the liquid exchange means comprise a return channel 7 with a pump 8. The operation of the pump may for example be dependent on the controller 13 such as shown in Fig. 3. When the controller 13 drives the piezo 4 above a predetermined power level the pump 8 is activated, and the pump may remain being activated a predetermined time after the piezo has stopped being driven (and the nebulizing has been halted or paused) to allow a flushing of the liquid contained in the nebulization chamber 3. The nebulizer 20 may further comprise temperature sensing means 14, see Fig. 3, wherein the operation of the pump 8 by the controller 13 is further in dependence of the temperature of the liquid in the nebulization chamber 3 and/or reservoir 1. Also the power level at which the vibration means 4 is operated 
<!-- EPO <DP n="7"/>-->
 may be adjusted by the controller 13 in response to the measured temperature. Continuing with the embodiment shown in Fig. 4, the pumping means 8 may also be provided in the supply channel 2. This embodiment has the advantage of providing more freedom in the positioning of the reservoir 1 relative to the nebulization chamber 3 as the filling of the chamber can be made independent of gravity. In case the temperature decrease by the liquid exchange between the nebulization chamber and the reservoir is insufficient cooling means 9 may be included in the nebulizer 20. Fig. 5 shows an embodiment in which cooling means 9 have been added to the return channel 7. Cooling means may be active such as with a Peltier element or use a cool fluid, or be passive such as with a heat sink. In an embodiment the surface area of the return channel 7 is enlarged with a heat sink to allow an improved heat exchange with the surrounding material or air. In a further embodiment, not shown in a Figure, the shape and inner surface area of the walls of the reservoir are adapted to maximize its contact area with the fluid contained in the reservoir to optimize a heat exchange between the fluid and the material of the reservoir. The reservoir comprises preferably made a material with a low specific heat such as for example copper. The reservoir may further be coupled to a heat conductor adapted to transport the heat to an area where it can easily exchange the transported heat with the ambient air surrounding the nebulizer. In a further embodiment, not shown in a Figure, a fluid sensor is located between the reservoir and the nebulization chamber such that, once the liquid to be atomized has almost all been aerosolized, this is detected by the controller and the pumping means and vibration means are switched off. Fig. 7 shows an example of a pumping means 8 which comprises of a plurality of moving elements 32 such as shown in the left figure of Fig. 7. The plurality of moving elements 32, see right figure of Fig. 7, press successively on a flexible tube or channel 30 which is clamped between the plurality of moving elements and a resilient member 31 to create a peristaltic like movement resulting in a fluid flow 33. The fluid is not in direct contact with the pump 8 which has the advantage that the pump does not need to be cleaned regularly. For hygiene the flexible tube 30 may be cleaned or replaced after use of the nebulizer. </p><p id="p0026" num="0026"> Fig. 8 shows an embodiment of a method of temperature control of a liquid to be nebulized in an aerosol generating device 20. The method comprises the step of filling 40 the reservoir 1 with a drug. This may be a metered volume corresponding to a treatment. After or during the filling of the reservoir 1 in a next step 41 a portion of the liquid is received in the nebulization chamber 3 which is arranged to nebulize the liquid received therein. Subsequently in step 42 after activation of the nebulizer 20 by the patient the 
<!-- EPO <DP n="8"/>-->
 controller 13 activates the vibration means 4 causing the generation of a spray 6 of small droplets. Part of the energy supplied to the vibration means 4 is dissipated as heat. During the nebulizing in a next step 43 of the method the temperature of the liquid in the nebulization chamber 3 is measured with a sensor 14. The controller 13 compares the measured temperature with a predetermined threshold in step 44. In case the temperature is higher than said threshold the controller 13 activates in a subsequent step 45 a pumping means 8 to exchange liquid between the nebulization chamber and reservoir until the temperature of the liquid in the nebulization chamber 3 has dropped below the predetermined threshold. In a further embodiment of the method the controller 13 reduces the power level with which the vibration means 4 is driven if the measured liquid temperature has increased above a further predetermined threshold as illustrated by the dashed line in Fig. 8. In another embodiment there is no step of measuring liquid temperature and is the exchange of the liquid between the nebulization chamber and the reservoir started when the patient activates the nebulizer. </p><p id="p0027" num="0027"> Summarizing in the invention an aerosol generating device 20 comprises a reservoir 1 for containing a liquid to be atomized and a nebulization chamber 3 for nebulizing a portion of the liquid received from the reservoir. The aerosol device further comprises liquid exchange means 7,8 for exchanging in use a further portion of the liquid received in the nebulization chamber with liquid from the reservoir to reduce a temperature increase of liquid in the nebulization chamber caused by heat produced by the vibration source 4. </p><p id="p0028" num="0028"> While the invention has been illustrated and described in detail in the drawings and foregoing description, such illustration and description are to be considered illustrative or exemplary and not restrictive; the invention is not limited to the disclosed embodiments. Variations to the disclosed embodiments can be understood and effected by those skilled in the art in practicing the claimed invention, from a study of the drawings, the disclosure, and the appended claims. For example in the embodiments described above the vibration means causes a pressure wave in the liquid causing the liquid to pass through the mesh to form a spray of small droplets. The invention also applies to nebulizers with other arrangements in which a vibration means is used to cause directly or indirectly a vibration of a mesh or nozzle plate and in which the heat produced by the vibration means causes a temperature increase of the spray of nebulized droplets. </p><p id="p0029" num="0029"> In the claims, the word "comprising" does not exclude other elements or steps, and the indefinite article "a" or "an" does not exclude a plurality. The mere fact that certain measures are recited in mutually different dependent claims does not indicate that a 
<!-- EPO <DP n="9"/>-->
 combination of these measured cannot be used to advantage. Any reference signs in the claims should not be construed as limiting the scope. 
</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM44726852" ref-ucid="WO-2012114230-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><claim-statement><!-- EPO <DP n="10"/>-->CLAIMS: </claim-statement><claim id="clm-0001" num="1"><claim-text>1. An aerosol generating device (20) for nebulizing a liquid, the device comprising a reservoir (1) and a nebulization chamber (3) being arranged for receiving in use a portion of a liquid from the reservoir; the device further comprising a vibration means (4) coupled to the nebulization chamber and arranged for bringing the portion of the liquid in vibration, the device further comprising liquid exchange means (2,7,8) for exchanging in use a further portion of the liquid received in the nebulization chamber with liquid from the reservoir. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0002" num="2"><claim-text>2. An aerosol generating device according to claim 1 wherein the liquid exchange means comprise at least one channel (2,7) coupled between the reservoir and the nebulization chamber. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0003" num="3"><claim-text>3. An aerosol generating device (2) according to claim 1 wherein the liquid exchange means comprise a supply channel (2) for feeding in use the portion of liquid from the reservoir to the nebulization chamber and a return channel (7) for feeding the further portion of the liquid from the nebulization chamber to the reservoir. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0004" num="4"><claim-text>4. An aerosol generating device according to any one of claims 1, 2 and 3 wherein the liquid exchange means comprise pumping means (8). </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0005" num="5"><claim-text>5. An aerosol generating device (20) according to claim 4 wherein the pumping means (8) are arranged to operate in dependence of a controlling (13) of the vibration means (4)· </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0006" num="6"><claim-text>6. An aerosol generating device according to any one of claims 1-5 further comprising cooling means (9) for reducing the temperature of the liquid contained in the reservoir. <!-- EPO <DP n="11"/>--> </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0007" num="7"><claim-text>7. An aerosol generating device (20) according to any one of claims 1-5 wherein the liquid exchange means further comprise cooling means (9) for reducing the temperature of the further portion of the liquid. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0008" num="8"><claim-text>8. An aerosol generating device (20) according to claim 6 or 7 further comprising temperature sensing means (14) arranged for measuring a temperature of the portion of the liquid contained in the nebulization chamber, the cooling means (9) and/or the pumping means (8) being arranged to operate in dependence of the measured temperature. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0009" num="9"><claim-text>9. An aerosol generating device (20) according to any one of claims 1-8 wherein the nebulization chamber is arranged such that the liquid is received in a space between the vibration source (4) and a mesh (5), wherein the vibration means (4) is arranged to bring the liquid comprised in said space in vibration, the mesh having a plurality of orifices for dispersing another portion of the liquid received in the nebulization chamber as a spray (6) of small droplets as a result of the vibration. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0010" num="10"><claim-text>10. An aerosol generating device (2) according to any one of claims 1-9 wherein in use a height difference in the relative positioning of the reservoir (1) and the nebulization chamber (3) causes a liquid flow from the reservoir to the nebulization chamber as a result of gravity. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0011" num="11"><claim-text>11. An aerosol generating device (20) according to any one of claims 1 - 10 wherein the reservoir (1) comprises a metering chamber (11) and an overflow chamber (10), the metering chamber defining the volume of the liquid to be nebulized, the metering chamber being arranged such that the liquid is poured into the metering chamber from outside the nebulizer and any liquid in excess of the volume being retained in the overflow chamber, the nebulization chamber being arranged for receiving the portion of the liquid from the metering chamber, the aerosol generating device being arranged for exchanging the further portion of the liquid between the metering chamber (11) and the nebulization chamber (3). </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0012" num="12"><claim-text>12. A method of temperature control of a liquid to be nebulized in an aerosol generating device (20), the aerosol generating device comprising a nebulization chamber (3) for nebulizing a portion of the liquid received from a reservoir (1), the method comprising the <!-- EPO <DP n="12"/>--> steps of filling the reservoir with the liquid; receiving the portion of the liquid in the nebulization chamber; controlling a vibration means (4) to control the nebulizing of the portion of the liquid; exchanging a further portion of the liquid received in the nebulization chamber between the reservoir and the nebulization chamber. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0013" num="13"><claim-text>13. A method according to claim 12 wherein the step of exchanging the further portion is independence of a temperature of the liquid contained in the nebulization chamber and/or of a controlling of the vibration means (4). </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0014" num="14"><claim-text>14. A method according to claim 12 or 13 wherein the step of exchanging includes generating a liquid flow from the nebulization chamber (3) via a return channel (7) to the reservoir (1). </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0015" num="15"><claim-text>15. A method according to claim 14 wherein the step of controlling the vibration means (4) is in dependence of a temperature of the liquid contained in the reservoir (1). </claim-text></claim></claims><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
