<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2153444-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2153444" kind="B1" date="20140101" family-id="39581847" file-reference-id="270075" date-produced="20180822" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146554024" ucid="EP-2153444-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2153444</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-08742935-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154827947" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>08742935</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20080416</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140454099" ucid="US-2008004884-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>2008004884</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20080416</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140452579" ucid="US-79965807-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>79965807</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20070502</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130726</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988104354" load-source="ipcr">G11C  11/56        20060101ALI20081126BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988113389" load-source="ipcr">G11C  16/34        20060101AFI20081126BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988098561" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G11C  16/349       20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988101715" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G11C  11/5628      20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988105777" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G11C  11/5642      20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988109362" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G11C2211/5634      20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988116539" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G11C  16/0483      20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988132893" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G11C  16/3418      20130101 FI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132194556" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">NICHTFLÜCHTIGE MEHRNIVEAU-SPEICHERZELLEN MIT VON REFERENZZELLEN GELESENEN DATEN</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132194557" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">NON-VOLATILE MULTILEVEL MEMORY CELLS WITH DATA READ OF REFERENCE CELLS</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132194558" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">CELLULES DE MÉMOIRE NON-VOLATILES MULTI-NIVEAU AVEC LECTURE DE DONNÉES DE CELLULES DE RÉFÉRENCE</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918162221" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>MICRON TECHNOLOGY INC</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918152006" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>MICRON TECHNOLOGY, INC.</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918134424" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>SARIN VISHAL</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918153852" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>SARIN, VISHAL</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918998670" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>SARIN, VISHAL</last-name><address><street>20266 Vista Court</street><city>Cupertino, CA 95014</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918164290" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>HOEI JUNG SHENG</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918155657" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>HOEI, JUNG, SHENG</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918998671" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>HOEI, JUNG, SHENG</last-name><address><street>39878 Potrero Drive</street><city>Newark, CA 94560</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918140898" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>ROOHPARVAR FRANKIE F</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918148072" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>ROOHPARVAR, FRANKIE, F.</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918998669" load-source="patent-office" sequence="3" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>ROOHPARVAR, FRANKIE, F.</last-name><address><street>16255 Ridgecrest Avenue</street><city>Monte Sereno, CA 95030</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918998673" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Micron Technology, Inc.</last-name><iid>100178172</iid><address><street>8000 S. Federal Way</street><city>Boise, ID 83716-9632</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918998672" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Beresford, Keith Denis Lewis</last-name><iid>100012917</iid><address><street>BERESFORD &amp; Co. 16 High Holborn</street><city>London WC1V 6BX</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="US-2008004884-W"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2008004884</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20080416</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2008136907-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2008136907</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20081113</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548831292" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS548992037" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS548982630" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS548983619" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS548886600" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS548831293" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS548992038" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548886601" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS548886602" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS548986147" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS548982631" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS548982632" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548992039" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548886603" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS548992040" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS548831294" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS548983620" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS548886604" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS548982633" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS548886605" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS548872503" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS548831295" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS548872504" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS548872505" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS548989992" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS548992041" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS548982634" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS548872506" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS548983621" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS548992042" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS548872507" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS548983734" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS548982635" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS548886606" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63957573" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present disclosure relates to memory devices having non-volatile memory cells.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002">Memory devices are typically provided as internal, semiconductor, integrated circuits in computers or other electronic devices. There are many different types of memory including random-access memory (RAM), read only memory (ROM), dynamic random access memory (DRAM), synchronous dynamic random access memory (SDRAM), and flash memory, among others.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">Flash memory devices are utilized as non-volatile memory for a wide range of electronic applications. Flash memory devices typically use a one-transistor memory cell that allows for high memory densities, high reliability, and low power consumption.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">Uses for flash memory include memory for personal computers, personal digital assistants (PDAs), digital cameras, and cellular telephones. Program code and system data, such as a basic input/output system (BIOS), are typically stored in flash memory devices. This information can be used in personal computer systems, among others.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">Two common types of flash memory array architectures are the "NAND" and "NOR" architectures, so called for the logical form in which the basic memory cell configuration of each is arranged</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">A NAND array architecture arranges its array of floating gate memory cells in a matrix such that the gates of each floating gate memory cell of the array are coupled by rows to word select lines. However each memory cell is not directly coupled to a column bit line by its drain. Instead, the memory cells of the array are coupled together in series, source to drain, between a source line and a column bit line.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">Memory cells in a NAND array architecture can be configured, e.g., programmed, to a desired state. That is, electric charge can be placed on, or removed from, the floating gate of a memory cell to put the cell into a number of<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> stored states. For example, a single level cell (SLC) can represent two binary states, e.g., 1 or 0. Flash memory cells can also store more than two binary states, e.g., 1111, 0111, 0011, 1011, 1001, 0001, 0101, 1101, 1100, 0100, 0000, 1000, 1010, 0010, 0110, and 1110. Such cells may be referred to as multi state memory cells, multibit cells, or multilevel cells (MLCs). MLCs can allow the manufacture of higher density memories without increasing the number of memory cells since each cell can represent more than one bit. MLCs can have more than one programmed state, e.g., a cell capable of representing four bits can have fifteen programmed states and an erased state.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">MLC memory stores multiple bits on each cell by using different threshold voltage (Vt) levels for each state that is stored. The difference between adjacent Vt distributions may be very small for a MLC memory device as compared to a SLC memory device. The reduced margins between adjacent Vt distributions, e.g., program states, can increase the difficulty associated with distinguishing between adjacent program states, which can lead to problems such as reduced data retrieval reliability.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">For example, various data degradation mechanisms exist which can cause the Vt level of a cell to shift such that the Vt level no longer corresponds to a desired Vt distribution, e.g., program state, for the cell. Data degradation mechanisms can affect the Vt levels of cells at various times such as during programming and/or reading of the data stored by a memory cell. Data degradation mechanisms can include program disturb mechanisms, program verify and/or read disturb mechanisms, and charge loss mechanisms, to name a few.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">Some such data degradation mechanisms can have systematic effects on cells of a given row, e.g., word line, of a memory array. The systematic effects can occur on a group basis, e.g., on groups of cells such as pages and/or sectors of cells on a word line that can be programmed and/or read together. That is, some degradation mechanisms can cause a Vt shift of groups of cells on a word line in a systematic manner. For instance, some program and/or read disturb mechanisms can cause the Vt levels of a group of cells on a particular word line to shift by particular voltage amounts, e.g., 20mV, 50mV, 100mV, or 200mV, on a relatively consistent basis. In some cases, a systematic Vt level shift associated with the group of cells may depend on the desired<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> program state, e.g., the Vt level shift may be different for program states corresponding to higher target Vt levels than for program states corresponding to lower target Vt levels.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">Memory cells affected by data degradation mechanisms can become unreliable, e.g., the logical value read from the cells may not necessarily be the logical value written to the cells.<br/>
In United States Patent Application <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US20040255090A"><text>US 2004/0255090 (Guterman et al.</text></patcit>), "tracking cells" are read, then a rotation scheme is computed and an associated quality gauge is determined. Then it is determined whether the data (associated with the tracking cells) is high or low quality. Thereafter, user data is read using the computed rotation scheme. I.e. this reference employs tracking cell processing to determine a new set of compare points, and these determined compare points then are used to re-read the tracking cells and data cells. Thus, according to this reference, one first performs a read on tracking cells, then performs a read on data cells, then adjusts read voltage level compare points, then reads the data cells again using the adjusted compare points to determine the logic state represented by particular data cells.</p><heading id="h0001"><u>Summary of the Invention</u></heading><p id="p0012" num="0012">The present invention provides a method for operating an array of non-volatile multilevel memory cells comprising: programming a number of groups of data cells coupled to a selected word line, each group having an associated number of batches of reference cells interleaved therewith that are programmed and read at the same time as the respective group of data cells, wherein the data cells and reference cells have the same target threshold voltage "Vt" levels; performing a read operation on a particular group of data cells and on its associated batches of reference cells, each of the associated batches having been programmed to a different particular target state; determining, based on the read operation, whether the batches of reference cells represent a logic state other than the particular target state to which the batches were programmed; and if it is<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> determined that the batches of reference cells represent the logic state other than the particular target state which the batches were programmed, changing logic states represented by those data cells in the particular group that were programmed to one of the different particular target states corresponding to a batch of reference cells determined to represent the logic state other than the particular target state to the particular target state by using a data correction circuit coupled to the array.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">The method disclosed herein is, in accordance with the present invention, characterised in that the changing of logic states is performed without changing read reference voltages used to perform the read operation.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">The present invention also provides a non-volatile memory system comprising: an array of non-volatile multilevel memory cells arranged in rows coupled by word lines and columns coupled by bit lines, the rows including a number of data cells having an associated number of target threshold voltage "Vt" levels which correspond to a number of target states; a number of batches of reference cells interleaved with the data cells, the reference cells having the same target Vt levels and target states as the data cells; and control circuitry coupled to the array of memory cells and configured to execute the method just defined.</p><heading id="h0002"><u>Brief Description of the Drawings</u></heading><p id="p0015" num="0015"><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> is a block diagram of an electronic system having a memory device in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016"><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref> is a schematic of a portion of a non-volatile memory array that can be used with embodiments of the present disclosure.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017"><figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3</figref> is a schematic of a portion of an array of non- volatile memory cells having reference cells interleaved with data cells in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018"><figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 4</figref> illustrates a diagram of target Vt distributions in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></p><p id="p0019" num="0019"><figref idrefs="f0005">Figure 5</figref> illustrates an embodiment of a method for non-volatile multilevel memory cells with data read of reference cells.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020"><figref idrefs="f0006">Figure 6</figref> is a functional block diagram of an electronic memory system having at least one memory device in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021"><figref idrefs="f0006">Figure 7</figref> is a functional block diagram of a memory module having at least one memory device in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure.<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></p><heading id="h0003">Detailed Description</heading><p id="p0022" num="0022">Embodiments of the present disclosure provide methods, devices, modules, and systems for improving non-volatile multilevel memory cell data retrieval with data read of reference cells. Embodiments use reference cells interleaved with data cells to compensate for various systematic and/or transient data degradation mechanisms. One method embodiment includes programming at least one data cell of a number of data cells coupled to a selected word line to a target data threshold voltage (Vt) level corresponding to a target state; programming at least one reference cell of a number of reference cells coupled to the selected word line to a target reference Vt level, the number of reference cells interleaved with the number of data cells; determining a reference state based on a data read of the at least one reference cell; and changing a state read from the at least one data cell based on a change of the at least one reference cell. In various embodiments, the method includes changing the state read from the at least one data cell to an appropriate state based on a difference between the determined reference state and a target reference state corresponding to the target reference Vt level.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">In various embodiments, the target data Vt level and the target reference Vt level are the same. Changing the state read from the at least one data cell can include changing the state of the at least one data cell to the target state if it is determined that the reference state is a state other than the target state. In various embodiments, determining the reference state based on the data read of the reference cells includes determining a Vt shift amount, away from the target Vt level, associated with the reference cells and determining whether the Vt shift amount is more than an acceptable margin from the target Vt level such that the shifted Vt level corresponds to a state other than the target state. In some embodiments, the Vt shift amount is an average Vt shift amount associated with a statistically significant number of a group of reference cells each programmed to the same target Vt level. In some embodiments, determining the Vt shift amount includes using a statistical method to determine an overall shift of the interleaved reference cells.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">In various embodiments, the data cells and the interleaved reference cells are programmed simultaneously. The target Vt levels and<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> associated target states of the data cells can be the same target Vt levels and target states of the interleaved reference cells.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">In various embodiments, a read of a group of data cells on a selected word line is performed at the same time as corresponding reference cells on the selected word line are read. The read conditions for reading the data cells and the reference cells can be the same in various embodiments. For instance, in some embodiments, the read reference voltages used to perform the data read of the reference cells can be the same as read reference voltages used to read the data cells.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">In the following detailed description of the present disclosure, reference is made to the accompanying drawings that form a part hereof, and in which is shown by way of illustration how various embodiments of the disclosure may be practiced. These embodiments are described in sufficient detail to enable those of ordinary skill in the art to practice the embodiments of this disclosure, and it is to be understood that other embodiments may be utilized and that process, electrical, or mechanical changes may be made without departing from the scope of the present disclosure.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027"><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> is a block diagram of an electronic system 100 having a memory device 104 in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure. In the system 100, the memory device 104, e.g., a NAND flash memory device 104, is coupled to a controller 166 via interface 122. The controller 166 can provide access to the memory device 104 from an external host (not shown), e.g., a personal computer, cellular telephone, digital camera, personal digital assistant, or other external host device, via an interface 106. In various embodiments, the controller 166 can be coupled to more than one memory device, e.g., 104.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">In the embodiment illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>, the controller 166 includes a control state machine 110, e.g., an embedded processor 110, which can direct internal operation of the memory device 104. For instance, the control state machine 110 can perform functions including managing one or more memory arrays 108, directing data accesses, updating internal control registers and tables (not shown), and/or directing operation of other possible hardware components (not shown) of the memory device 104 and/or controller 166, among various other functions. As one of ordinary skill in the art will<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> appreciate, the controller 166 can also include associated buffer memory (not shown), e.g., RAM and/or ROM, which can store data being written to and/or read from the memory array 108.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">As illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>, in various embodiments, the controller 166 includes a data correction and retrieval component 118. The data correction and retrieval component 118 can be circuitry that is integrated with and/or controlled by control state machine 110. As described in further detail below, the data correction and retrieval component 118 can be used to improve non-volatile multilevel memory cell data retrieval reliability by using reference cells interleaved with data cells to compensate for various systematic and/or transient data degradation mechanisms associated with memory device 104 and/or interface 122.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">In the embodiment illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>, the controller 166 is external to the memory device 104. However, in various embodiments, the controller 166 can be an internal controller of the memory device 104. In such embodiments, the system 100 can be referred to as a memory subsystem 100. In such embodiments, the memory subsystem 100 can be a flash memory card, as one example.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">The memory array 108 contains floating gate memory cells arranged in a sequence of memory blocks 116-0 (BLOCK 0), 116-1 (BLOCK 1). As an example, the number of memory blocks in array 108 may be 128 blocks, 512 blocks, or 1,024 blocks, but embodiments are not limited to a particular number of memory blocks in an array 108. In various embodiments, the blocks 116-0 and 116-1 can be referred to as erase blocks. In such embodiments, the memory cells in each block are erased at the same time. Each memory block, e.g., 116-0 and 116-1, contains a number of physical rows 120 of memory cells.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">In various embodiments, and as described further in connection with <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3</figref>, each physical row 120 of memory cells includes reference memory cells interleaved with the data memory cells. The reference cells are physically the same as the data cells, e.g., they both are floating gate memory cells. In various embodiment, the target Vt levels to which the memory cells are programmed are the same for both the data cells and interleaved reference cells. Also, in various embodiments, the same read conditions can be used to read the states of the data cells and the reference cells. For example, in some<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> embodiments, the read reference voltages used to read the states of the memory cells are the same for both the data cells and the reference cells.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">In various embodiments, the reference cells coupled to each physical row 120 can be organized as a number of reference cell batches. The number of batches of reference cells can be the same as the number of program states associated with the data cells. For example, the number of batches can be sixteen for a four-bit data cell, e.g., a cell having sixteen target states. In this example, each of the sixteen batches of the reference cells can be associated with a different target Vt level, e.g., target state.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">The reference cells can be erased and programmed at the same time as the data cells in a particular row such that the reference cells are exposed to the same or similar erase/program cycling and the same program disturb conditions as the data cells. The batches of reference cells can also be read at the same time as an associated group, e.g., a logical sector or a page, of data cells.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">In various embodiments, the controller 166, e.g., control state machine 110 and/or data correction and retrieval component 118, can perform an averaging of a read batch of reference cells programmed to a particular target Vt level in order to determine an average Vt level associated with the read batch of reference cells, e.g., an average Vt shift away from the particular target Vt level. If it is determined that the average Vt level of the read batch of reference cells corresponds to a program state other than the target state to which the batch was programmed, then the data correction and retrieval component 118 can change the logic state of read data cells that were also programmed to the particular target Vt level/target state. That is, data stored in data cells read to store data corresponding to the program state determined based on the averaging performed on the batch of reference cells can be changed back to the target state via the data correction component 118.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">For example, assume that a number of data cells in a group, e.g., logical sector 121, and an associated batch of reference cells interleaved with the group are programmed to a particular target Vt level corresponding to a particular target state, e.g., '"01," "00," or "10" for a two-bit cell. For this example, assume various data cells in the group and the associated batch of<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> reference cells are programmed to a target Vt level corresponding to the "01" target state. A read operation can then be performed to determine the present Vt levels/states for the cells, which may have changed since the cells were programmed to the particular target state, e.g., due to various data degradation mechanisms such as program disturb, read disturb, charge loss disturb, and/or other systematic and/or transient data degradation mechanisms.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">In various embodiments, the data correction and retrieval component 118 8 can perform an averaging on the batch of read reference cells and can adjust the logic states of the data cells based on the averaging performed on the read batch of reference cells. For instance, the averaging performed on the batch of read reference cells can result in a determination that the batch of reference cells represents the "00" state instead of the "01" target state. In various embodiments, the data correction and retrieval component 118 8 can correct the data stored in the read data cells that were programmed to the "01" target state, but may now store "00" due to a Vt level shift. That is, the data stored in data cells read as storing "00", e.g., the state of the read batch of reference cells based on the averaging operation, can be changed/corrected to "01", e.g., the target state.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">In this manner, data retrieval errors and unreliability caused by various systematic data degradation mechanisms discussed herein can be reduced or prevented For instance, the data read from the data cells that were programmed to ``01'' target state in this example would be corrected from "00" to "01" based on the average read state of the batch of reference cells such that the incorrect state, e.g., "00" in this example, is not erroneously reported to an external host that requested the data stored by the group of data cells. Embodiments are not limited to the above example.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">The number of cells per physical row 120 corresponds to the number of columns, e.g., bit lines, and can be 4,256, 8,512, or 16,384, among various other numbers of cells, which may depend on factors such as the amount of overhead data associated with the user data. In some embodiments, the cells in each row 120 are associated with an even or an odd bit line. In some embodiments, the number of rows 120 in each memory block can be 32, but embodiments are not limited to a particular number of rows 120 per block.<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --></p><p id="p0040" num="0040">In various embodiments, the rows 120 contain one or more logical sectors 121. Each logical sector 121 can store a number of bytes of data, e.g., 256 bytes, 512 bytes, or 1,024 bytes, but embodiments are not limited to a particular number of bytes of data stored in a logical sector 121. In operation, the memory cells in each logical sector 121 can be selected to be simultaneously written to and/or read from as a group. As one of ordinary skill in the art will appreciate, the memory cells in each logical sector 121 can have a number of associated logical pages. The logical pages can correspond to the number of binary bits stored in each cell and can be separately addressed, which can allow for the logical pages of the cells to be programmed and/or read at different times. As an example, in an array of two-bit cells, e.g., cells storing one of four binary states, the cells in each logical sector 121 may have two logical pages, e.g., an upper page and a lower page, while an array of four-bit cells may have four logical pages, e.g., an upper page and three lower pages, associated with each logical sector 121. In multilevel cells, each of the bits stored in a single memory cell can be from a different logical page.</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">It is noted that other formats and/or configurations for the blocks 116-0, 116-1, rows 120, sectors 121, and pages are possible. For example, the rows 120 of the memory blocks 116-0, 116-1 can include a single sector 121 which can include more or less than 512 bytes of data.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042"><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref> is a schematic of a portion of a non-volatile memory array 200 that can be used with embodiments of the present disclosure. The embodiment of <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref> illustrates a NAND architecture non-volatile memory. However, embodiments described herein are not limited to this example. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref>, the memory array 200 includes word lines 205-1, ..., 205-N and intersecting bit lines 207-1, ..., 207-M. For ease of addressing in the digital environment, the number of word lines 205-1, ..., 205-N and the number of bit lines 207-1, ..., 207-M are each some power of two, e.g., 256 word lines by 4,096 bit lines, etc.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">Memory array 200 includes NAND strings 209-1, .... 209-M. Each NAND string includes non-volatile memory cells 211-1, ..., 211-N, each located at an intersection of a word line 205-1, ..., 205-N and a local bit line 207-1, ..., 207-M. The non-volatile memory cells 211-1, ..., 211-N of each NAND string 209-1, ..., 209-M are connected in series source to drain between<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> a source select gate (SGS), e.g., a field-effect transistor (FET) 213, and a drain select gate (SGD), e.g., FET 219. Source select gate 213 is located at the intersection of a local bit line 207-1 and a source select line 217 while drain select gate 219 is located at the intersection of a local bit line 207-1 and a drain select line 215.</p><p id="p0044" num="0044">As shown in the embodiment illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref>, a source of source select gate 213 is connected to a common source line 223. The drain of source select gate 213 is connected to the source of the memory cell 211-1 of the corresponding NAND string 209-1. The drain of drain select gate 219 is connected to the local bit line 207-1 for the corresponding NAND string 209-1 at drain contact 221-1. The source of drain select gate 219 is connected to the drain of the last memory cell 211-N, e.g., floating-gate transistor, of the corresponding NAND string 209-1.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045">In various embodiments, construction of non-volatile memory cells, 211-1, ..., 211-N, includes a source, a drain, a floating gate or charge storage layer, and a control gate. Non-volatile memory cells, 211-1, ..., 211-N, have their control gates coupled to a word line, 205-1, ..., 205-N respectively. A column of the non-volatile memory cells, 211-1, ..., 211-N, make up the NAND strings, e.g., 209-1, ..., 209-M, coupled to a given local bit line, e.g., 207-1, ..., 207-M respectively. A row of the non-volatile memory cells are commonly coupled to a given word line, e.g., 20S-1, ..., 205-N. An AND array architecture would be similarly laid out except that the string of memory cells would be coupled in parallel between the select gates.</p><p id="p0046" num="0046">In various embodiments, and as described further in connection with <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3</figref>, each row 205-1 to 205-N of non-volatile memory cells includes a number of reference cells interleaved with the data cells of a given row 205-1 to 205-N. The reference cells can be interleaved with the data cells of a given row 205-1 to 205-N in a variety of ways.</p><p id="p0047" num="0047">As previously mentioned, in various embodiments, the reference cells have the same target Vt levels corresponding to program states as the data cells, e.g., the target Vt level for a particular program state, e.g., "1101," is the same for a data cell and a reference cell. Similarly, the read reference voltages used to read data stored by a data cell are the same read reference voltages used to read data stored by a reference cell. For instance, if a data cell and reference<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> cell are both programmed to a particular target state, e.g., "1101," and a read reference voltage associated with the "1101" state is 1.6V, then a read reference voltage of 1.6V is used to read both the data cell and the reference cell that was programmed to the "1101" target state. Simultaneously programming both data cells and interleaved reference cells to the same target Vt levels and performing read operations using the same reference read voltages for both data cells and interleaved reference cells can allow the read state of the reference cells to be used to correct for systematic errors for respective data cells caused by various systematic data degradation mechanisms.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048"><figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3</figref> is a schematic of a portion of an array, e.g., memory array 108 shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> or array 200 shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure2</figref>, of non-volatile multilevel memory cells having reference cells interleaved with data cells in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure. In the embodiment illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3</figref>, the array includes a number of rows of memory cells, e.g., ROW-0, ROW-1, ... , ROW-N. The index "N" is used to indicate that the array can include a number of rows, e.g., 16, 32, 64, etc. The cells on each row are coupled to a word line, e.g., word lines 205-1 to 205-N shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref>. ROW-0 to ROW-N can correspond to the rows in a block of the array, e.g., block 116-0 and 116-1 shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>. Each of the memory cells is coupled to a bit line, e.g., bit lines 207-1 to 207-M shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref>, which may be either an even or odd bit line in some embodiments.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">In some embodiments in which even and odd bit lines are used, all the memory cells of a row that are coupled to an even bit line can be written to and/or read from at the same time while all the memory cells of the row coupled to an odd bit line can be written to and/or read from at the same time. In such embodiments, the cells of each row form at least two logical pages, e.g., an even page and an odd page.</p><p id="p0050" num="0050">As shown in the embodiment illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3</figref>, each row of memory cells includes both data cells, e.g., 312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D and 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D, and reference cells, e.g., 322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R and 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R, interleaved therewith. The reference cells can be interleaved with the data cells in a variety of manners.</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">In the embodiment illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3</figref>, the data cells 312-1 to 312-D represent a first group of data cells having an associated number of<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> reference cells 322-1 to 322-R interleaved therewith. The data cells 314-1 to 314-D represent a second group of data cells having an associated number of reference cells 324-1 to 324-R interleaved therewith. Although the embodiment illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3</figref> includes two groups of data cells 312-1 to 312-D and 314-1 to 314-D and two groups of reference cells 322-1 to 322-R and 324-1 to 324-R, embodiments are not limited to a particular number of groups of data cells and/or reference cells. In some embodiments, the first group of data cells 312-1 to 312-D and associated reference cells 322-1 to 322-R can be associated with an even bit line while the second group of data cells 314-1 to 314-D and associated reference cells 324-1 to 324-R can be associated with an odd bit line. However, embodiments are not limited to this example.</p><p id="p0052" num="0052">In various embodiments, the first group of data cells 312-1 to 312-D can represent a first logical sector, e.g., sector 121 shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>, and the second group of data cells 314-1 to 314-D can represent a second logical sector. In such embodiments and as mentioned above, the memory cells in each logical sector can be simultaneously written to and/or read from as a group. Also, the memory cells in each logical sector can have a number of associated logical pages that can be separately addressed, e.g., each of the multiple bits stored in a multilevel cell can be from a different logical page. As such, the individual bits stored in a memory cell can be programmed and/or read at different times.</p><p id="p0053" num="0053">The indices "D" and "R" are used to indicate that the groups of data cells can include a number of data cells and reference cells, respectively. The number of reference cells in each group, e.g., 322-1 to 322-R and 324-1 to 324-R, can depend of a variety of factors such as the type of multilevel cells, e.g., 2-bit or 4-bit MLCs, the number of data cells per group, e.g., 312-1 to 312-D and 314-1 to 314-N, and/or the number of data cells per row, e.g., ROW-0 to ROW-N. As an example, for 4-bit MLCs, e.g., the data cells and reference cells store four data bits, each row can include about 8,000 to 16,000 data cells and about 128 to 1,024 interleaved reference cells.</p><p id="p0054" num="0054">In various embodiments, the reference cells associated with a group of data cells are interleaved with the respective data cells. For example, the reference cells 322-1 to 322-R can be physically located among, e.g., between, a number of the associated data cells 312-1 to 312-D rather than<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> physically located apart from the associated data cells 312-1 to 312-D as shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3</figref>. Physically localizing the reference cells, e.g., 322-1 to 322-R, with an associated group of data cells, e.g., 312-1 to 312-D, can provide benefits such as an increased likelihood that both the data cells and the associated reference cells will observe the same or similar data degradation mechanisms including Vt disturbs due to word line and/or bit line transients and temperature effects, to name a few.</p><p id="p0055" num="0055">In various embodiments, each group of reference cells, e.g., 322-1 to 322-R, associated with a group of data cells, e.g., 312-1 to 312-D, can include a number of batches of reference cells. In such embodiments, the number of batches can correspond with the number of program Vt levels/states associated with the cells. That is, the number of batches can be four, e.g., for two-bit multilevel cells, can be eight, e.g., for three-bit multilevel cells, and can be sixteen, e.g., for four-bit multilevel cells. In such embodiments, each batch of reference cells can be programmed to a different particular target level/state among the number of program states, e.g., 4, 8, 16, etc. Also, each batch of reference cells can be programmed to its particular target level/state while the data cells, e.g., 312-1 to 312-D, in the associated group of data cells are being programmed to that particular target level/state such that the data cells and associated batch of reference cells being programmed to that particular target level/state experience the same or similar program disturb conditions or other data degradation mechanisms.</p><p id="p0056" num="0056">As an example, assume a number of data cells in the first group of data cells 312-1 to 312-D are to be programmed to a number of different data states, e.g., "1101" is to be written to some of the data cells 312-1 to 312-D, "0101" is to be written to some other of the data cells 312-1 to 312-D, etc. For four-bit MLCs, it is possible that each of the sixteen data states will be written to at least some of the data cells 312-1 to 312-D in the group. In this example, the reference cells 322-1 to 322-R of the associated batch of reference cells corresponding to the "1101" logic state are written/programmed while the data cells 312-1 to 312-D that are to have data "1101" written thereto are written/programmed.</p><p id="p0057" num="0057">As previously mentioned, each of the four bits in four-bit MLCs can correspond to different logical pages, e.g., an upper page and three lower<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> pages, which can each be programmed at different times. As one example, the first lower page of cells on a particular row, e.g., ROW-0, may be programmed, followed by the first lower page of cells on a different row, e.g., ROW-1-Subsequently to the programming of the first lower page cells on ROW-1, one or more of the second and third lower page and the upper page of cells on ROW-0 may be programmed. One of ordinary skill in the art will appreciate that a number of different page programming algorithms exist. Embodiments of the present disclosure are not limited to a particular programming algorithm. In embodiments in which the data bits stored on the memory cells are from different logical pages, which are programmed at different times, the pages of the interleaved reference cells, e.g., 322-1 to 322-R, associated with a group of data cells, e.g., 312-1 to 312-D, are programmed at the same time that the pages of the data cells in the group of data cells are programmed.</p><p id="p0058" num="0058">Each batch of reference cells can include a number of reference cells, e.g., 4 reference cells, 8 reference cells, or 20 reference cells, among various other numbers of reference cells. In various embodiments of the present disclosure, an averaging can be performed on the reference cells in each batch for purposes of data correction and/or data retrieval reliability as described herein. As such, the number of reference cells in each batch can depend on the particular averaging algorithm executed by the data correction and retrieval component, e.g., component 118 of controller 166 shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>.</p><p id="p0059" num="0059">For example, as mentioned above and described further below in connection with <figref idrefs="f0005 f0006">Figures 5-7</figref>, a read of the reference cells in each batch, e.g., each of the reference cells being programmed to a different particular Vt level/state, can be performed and a reference state can be determined based thereon, In some embodiments, the reference state can be based on an average Vt level shift amount, away from the particular target Vt level, for the cells in the batch.</p><p id="p0060" num="0060">In various embodiments, the Vt level shift amount is caused by a systematic data degradation mechanism that can cause the Vt levels of some or all of the cells, e.g., data cells as well as interleaved reference cells, on a row/word line to shift in a similar manner. In various embodiments, the determined average Vt shift amount and/or the determined reference state associated with the batch can be used to adjust the logic states of<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> data cells in the group of cells 312-1 to 312-D or in the entire row, e.g., ROW-0, which were programmed to the particular Vt level/state associated with the batch.</p><p id="p0061" num="0061">As an example, if the particular Vt state associated with the batch is "1101", e.g., the reference cells of the batch were programmed to the "1101" target state, and the averaging algorithm performed on the read reference cells determines that the Vt level shift amount is such that the reference state of the batch is "1100", e.g., a state other than the "1101" target state, then the logic states of data cells in the associated group of data cells 312-1 to 312-D or in ROW-0 that were programmed to the "1101" target state also experience a Vt level shift amount sufficient such that the data cells will be read as having "1100", e.g., an incorrect data state, stored thereon. As such, embodiments of the present disclosure correct the read state of the data cells 312-1 to 312-D, e.g., change the read state from "1100" to the correct "1101" target state in this example, based on the averaging of the batch of reference cells, e.g., a batch from reference cells 322-1 to 322-R, and determined reference state associated therewith.</p><p id="p0062" num="0062"><figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 4</figref> illustrates a diagram of target threshold voltage (Vt) distributions in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure. Although <figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 4</figref> illustrates four target Vt distributions 430, 432, 434, 436 for a four-state, e.g., two-bit, array of multilevel memory cells (MLCs), embodiments are not limited to two-bit MLCs or to a particular type of Flash architecture, e.g., NAND.</p><p id="p0063" num="0063">As shown in the diagram illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 4</figref>, each of the target Vt distributions 430, 432, 434, and 436 has a corresponding target Vt level 439-0, 439-1, 439-2, and 439-3. As the reader will appreciate, the target Vt distributions 430, 432, 434, and 436 are a result of the inability of program algorithms to achieve the exact target Vt levels 439-0, 439-1, 439-2, and 439-3. In the diagram of <figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 4</figref>, the four target Vt distributions 430, 432, 434, and 436 represent logic data states "11", "01", "00", and "10", respectively.</p><p id="p0064" num="0064">In an example programming algorithm, verify voltage levels, e.g., VR01, VR00, and VR10 as shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 4</figref>, can be used to determine when to cease applying programming voltage pulses to particular memory cells. In this example, cells are to be programmed from the erase state, e.g., "11", to some<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> other state, e.g., one of the program states "01", "00," and "10". For those cells to be programmed into state "01" out of erase state "11", the pulsing is terminated when their Vt level becomes equal to or greater than the program verify level VR01, corresponding to distribution 432. The states of the cells can be verified in between the programming pulses. Similarly, pulsing is terminated for those cells to be programmed into the "00" state when their Vt level becomes equal to or greater than the program verify level VR00, corresponding to distribution 434. Finally, for those cells being programmed into the "10" state, the program pulses are terminated when their Vt level reaches the program verify level VR10, corresponding to distribution 436. At that point, the parallel programming of the group of the memory cells has been completed.</p><p id="p0065" num="0065">The diagram illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 4</figref> represents an example of the target Vt distributions 430, 432, 434, and 436, target Vt levels 439-0, 439-1, 439-2, and 439-3, and verify voltage levels VR01, VR00, and VR10 for data cells, e.g., 312-1 to 312-D shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3</figref>, and for interleaved reference cells, e.g., 322-1 to 322-R shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3</figref>. That is, as noted above, target Vt levels, e.g., 439-0, 439-1, 439-2, and 439-3, and verify levels, e.g., VR01, VR00, and VR10, are the same for the data cells and reference cells. For instance, if the target Vt level 439-1 is 0.7V and the corresponding verify level VR01 is 0.5V for data cells, then those same values are used to program the reference cells.</p><p id="p0066" num="0066"><figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 4</figref> also illustrates the read reference voltages used to determine into which of the four target states the memory cells, e.g., data cells and reference cells have been programmed. The read reference voltage levels RD01, RD00, and RD 10 are reference voltages used to read the "01 ", "00" and "10" storage states, respectively. The read reference voltages are the voltages with which the Vt of each memory cell being read is compared. In various embodiments, the read reference voltages can be positioned roughly halfway between adjacent ones of the voltage distributions 430, 432, 434 and 436. As an example, RD01 may be about 0.1V, RD00 may be about 1.0V, and RD10 may be about 1.9V.</p><p id="p0067" num="0067">The difference between a program verify level and a corresponding read reference level can be referred to herein as a read margin. The distribution illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 4</figref> includes read margins 431,433-1, 433-2, 435-1, and 435-2. A memory cell intended to be programmed into the "00" state<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> may transition, e.g., shift due to disturb mechanisms, to an erroneous data state if the Vt level moves below the reference read level RD00 such that the Vt level is not within read margin 433-2. In this example, the memory cell would be read as being in an incorrect state, e.g., the "01 state. Similarly, the "00" cell would be read as having an incorrect data state, e.g., the "10" state, if the threshold level were to transition, e.g., shift, above the reference read level RD10.</p><p id="p0068" num="0068">As the reader will appreciate, narrower read margins can increase the likelihood of erroneous bits as relatively small Vt level shifts can cause the Vt level to shift across a reference read level from a correct to an incorrect state. Such Vt level shifts can result from various data degradation mechanisms. Some such data degradation mechanisms can be systematic, e.g., they can affect the Vt levels of programmed cells on a consistent basis and/or in a consistent manner.</p><p id="p0069" num="0069">As described herein, various embodiments of the present disclosure can provide for an increase in data retrieval reliability by including reference cells interleaved with data cells for each row in an array of non-volatile multilevel memory cells. In some embodiments, a number of data cells, e.g., 312-1 to 312-D shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3</figref>, and interleaved reference cells, e.g., 322-1 to 322-R shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3</figref>, coupled to a selected word line, e.g., row, are simultaneously programmed to the same target Vt level corresponding to a particular target state. In such embodiments, a reference state can be determined based on a data read of the reference cells, e.g., 322-1 to 322-R. In various embodiments the reference state is based on an averaging algorithm executed by a data correction component, e.g., correction component 118 of controller 166 shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>. In such embodiments, the data read operation performed on the programmed data cells, e.g., 312-1 to 312-D, can be simultaneously performed on the programmed reference cells, e.g., 322-1 to 322-R, and the data correction component can change the state read from the data cells to the correct state, e.g., the target state to which the data cells and reference cells were programmed, if it is determined that the reference state is a state other than the target state.<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --></p><p id="p0070" num="0070"><figref idrefs="f0005">Figure 5</figref> illustrates an embodiment of a method 700 for non-volatile multilevel memory cell data retrieval reliability by using reference cells interleaved with data cells to compensate for various systematic and/or transient data degradation mechanisms. At block 710, method 700 includes programming at least one data cell of a number of data cells coupled to a selected word line to a target data threshold voltage (Vt) level corresponding to a target state. At block 720, method 700 includes programming at least one reference cell of a number of reference cells coupled to the selected word line to a target reference Vt level. In various embodiments, the number of reference cells are interleaved with the number of data cells. In various embodiments, the data cells and the interleaved reference cells of a given row/word line are programmed simultaneously.</p><p id="p0071" num="0071">In various embodiments, the data cells and interleaved reference cells can be programmed to the same target Vt level, e.g., the target data Vt level can be the same as the target reference Vt level. However, embodiments are not<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> so limited. For instance, in some embodiments, the target data Vt level can be different than the target reference Vt level. In such embodiments, a state read from the data cells can be changed to an appropriate state based on a difference between a determined reference state and a target reference state corresponding to the target reference Vt level.</p><p id="p0072" num="0072">In various embodiments, the interleaved reference cells can include a number of batches and each batch can be associated with a different particular target Vt level/target state. In certain embodiments, for example, each batch of reference cells associated with a target state includes at least four reference cells. In such embodiments, including at least four reference cells in each batch of reference cells can provide a suitable accuracy associated with a determined average Vt shift amount of the batch. In various embodiments, the read conditions for reading the data cells are the same for a group of data cells and for a corresponding batch of interleaved reference cells. In some embodiments, the read reference voltages corresponding to the target states are the same for the data cells and interleaved reference cells.</p><p id="p0073" num="0073">At block 730, method 700 includes determining a reference state based on a data read of the at least one reference cell. In various embodiments, determining the reference state based on the data read of the reference cells includes determining a Vt shift amount, away from the target Vt level, associated with the reference cells and determining whether the Vt shift amount is sufficient such that the shifted Vt level corresponds to a state other than the target state. In some embodiments, the Vt shift amount is an average Vt shift amount of a group, e.g., batch, of reference cells each programmed to the same target Vt level. The Vt shift amount can occur subsequent to the data cells and reference cells being programmed and can be caused by one or more data degradation mechanisms such as program disturbs, read disturbs, charge loss, etc. In various embodiments, the averaging may be performed on only a fraction, e.g., a statistically significant number, of the number of reference cells in a batch. For instance, reference cells of a batch determined to have an associated Vt shift different from the other reference cells of the batch by more than a threshold amount, e.g., 25mV or 50mV, may not be considered in determining an average Vt shift amount for the batch. In some embodiments, determining the Vt shift<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> amount includes using a statistical method to determine an overall shift of the interleaved reference cells.</p><p id="p0074" num="0074">In various embodiments, a read of a group of data cells on a selected word line is performed at the same time as corresponding interleaved reference cells on the selected word line are read. The read reference voltages used to perform the data read of the reference cells can be the same as read reference voltages used to read the data cells. However, embodiments are not so limited. That is, in some embodiments, the data cell and associated reference cell may be read at different times and/or different read reference voltages may be used to read the data cells.</p><p id="p0075" num="0075">At block 730, method 700 includes changing a state read from the at least one data cell based on a change of the at least one reference cell. In various embodiments, changing the state read from the at least one data cell includes changing the state read from the data cells to the target state if it is determined that the reference state is a state other than the target state. As described herein above, due to systematic disturb conditions, if the determined reference state, e.g., based on an averaging performed on a batch of read data cells, is a state other than the target state, e.g., an incorrect state, then a read performed on data cells programmed to that target state will likely also yield an incorrect state. In various embodiments of the present disclosure, a data correction and retrieval component, e.g., component 118 shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>, can perform averaging on the reference cells and can change the read data states of the data cells based thereon. That is, the data cells programmed to the target state and read to store incorrect data can be corrected based on averaging performed on the associated reference cells.</p><p id="p0076" num="0076"><figref idrefs="f0006">Figure 6</figref> is a functional block diagram of an electronic memory system 800 having at least one memory device 820 in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure. Memory system 800 includes a processor 810 coupled to a non-volatile memory device 820 that includes a memory array 830 of non-volatile multilevel data cells and interleaved non-volatile multilevel reference cells as described herein above. The memory system 800 can include separate integrated circuits or both the processor 810 and the memory device 820 can be on the same integrated circuit. The processor 810 can be a microprocessor or some other type of controlling circuitry such as an<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> application-specific integrated circuit (ASIC). The processor 810 can be a processor of an external host device, e.g., a digital camera, digital recording and playback device, PDA, personal computer, memory card reader, interface hub, etc.</p><p id="p0077" num="0077">For clarity, the electronic memory system 800 has been simplified to focus on features with particular relevance to the present disclosure. The memory device 820 includes an array of non-volatile multilevel memory cells 830, which can be floating gate flash memory cells with a NAND architecture. The control gates of each row of memory cells are coupled with a word line, while the drain regions of the memory cells are coupled to bit lines. The source regions of the memory cells are coupled to source lines, as the same has been illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref>. As will be appreciated by those of ordinary skill in the art, the manner of connection of the memory cells to the bit lines and source lines depends on whether the array is a NAND architecture, a NOR architecture, and AND architecture, or some other memory array architecture.</p><p id="p0078" num="0078">The embodiment of <figref idrefs="f0006">Figure 6</figref> includes address circuitry 840 to latch address signals provided over I/O connections 862 through I/O circuitry 860. Address signals are received and decoded by a row decoder 844 and a column decoder 846 to access the memory array 830. In light of the present disclosure, it will be appreciated by those skilled in the art that the number of address input connections depends on the density and architecture of the memory array 830 and that the number of addresses increases with both increased numbers of memory cells and increased numbers of memory blocks and arrays.</p><p id="p0079" num="0079">The memory array 830 of non-volatile cells can include non-volatile multilevel memory cells programmed and read in various manners known to those of ordinary skill in the art. For example, the memory device 820 can read data in the memory array 830 by sensing voltage and/or current changes in the memory array columns using sense/buffer circuitry that, in this embodiment, can be read/latch circuitry 850. The read/latch circuitry 850 can be coupled to read and latch a row or sector of data from the memory array 830. I/O circuitry 860 is included for bi-directional data communication over the I/O connections 862 with the processor 810. Write circuitry 855 is included to write data to the memory array 830.<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --></p><p id="p0080" num="0080">Control circuitry 870 decodes signals provided by control connections 872 from the processor 810. These signals can include chip signals, write enable signals, and address latch signals that are used to control the operations on the memory array 830, including data read, data write, and data erase operations. In various embodiments, the control circuitry 870 is responsible for executing instructions from the processor 810 to perform the operating embodiments of the present disclosure. The control circuitry 870 can be a state machine, a sequencer, or some other type of controller.</p><p id="p0081" num="0081">The control circuitry 870 can include data correction and retrieval circuitry, e.g., data correction circuitry 118 of <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>, that can execute instructions to perform various data retrieval and correction methods to correct read data cells based on an averaging performed on reference cells interleaved therewith. It will be appreciated by those skilled in the art that additional circuitry and control signals can be provided, and that the memory device detail of <figref idrefs="f0006">Figure 6</figref> has been reduced to facilitate ease of illustration.</p><p id="p0082" num="0082"><figref idrefs="f0006">Figure 7</figref> is a functional block diagram of a memory module having at least one memory device in accordance with an embodiment of the present disclosure. Memory module 900 is illustrated as a memory card, although the concepts discussed with reference to memory module 900 are applicable to other types of removable or portable memory (e.g., USB flash drives) and are intended to be within the scope of "memory module" as used herein. In addition, although one example form factor is depicted in <figref idrefs="f0006">Figure 7</figref>, these concepts are applicable to other form factors as well.</p><p id="p0083" num="0083">In some embodiments, memory module 900 will include a housing 905 (as depicted) to enclose one or more memory devices 910, though such a housing is not essential to all devices or device applications. At least one memory device 910 includes an array of non-volatile multilevel memory cells programmed according to embodiments described herein. Where present, the housing 905 includes one or more contacts 915 for communication with a host device. Examples of host devices include digital cameras, digital recording and playback devices, PDAs, personal computers, memory card readers, interface hubs and the like. For some embodiments, the contacts 915 are in the form of a standardized interface. For example, with a USB flash drive, the contacts 915 might be in the form of a USB Type-A male connector. For some embodiments,<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --> the contacts 915 are in the form of a semi-proprietary interface, such as might be found on CompactFlash<sup>™</sup> memory cards licensed by SanDisk Corporation, Memory Stick<sup>™</sup> memory cards licensed by Sony Corporation, SD Secure Digital<sup>™</sup> memory cards licensed by Toshiba Corporation and the like. In general, however, contacts 915 provide an interface for passing control, address and/or data signals between the memory module 900 and a host having compatible receptors for the contacts 915.</p><p id="p0084" num="0084">The memory module 900 may optionally include additional circuitry 920, which may be one or more integrated circuits and/or discrete components. For some embodiments, the additional circuitry 920 may include a memory controller for controlling access across multiple memory devices 910 and/or for providing a translation layer between an external host and a memory device 910. For example, there may not be a one-to-one correspondence between the number of contacts 915 and a number of 910 connections to the one or more memory devices 910. Thus, a memory controller could selectively couple an I/O connection (not shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">Figure 7</figref>) of a memory device 910 to receive the appropriate signal at the appropriate I/O connection at the appropriate time or to provide the appropriate signal at the appropriate contact 915 at the appropriate time. Similarly, the communication protocol between a host and the memory module 900 may be different than what is required for access of a memory device 910. A memory controller could then translate the command sequences received from a host into the appropriate command sequences to achieve the desired access to the memory device 910. Such translation may further include changes in signal voltage levels in addition to command sequences.</p><p id="p0085" num="0085">The additional circuitry 920 may further include functionality unrelated to control of a memory device 910 such as logic functions as might be performed by an ASIC. Also, the additional circuitry 920 may include circuitry to restrict read or write access to the memory module 900, such as password protection, biometrics or the like. The additional circuitry 920 may include circuitry to indicate a status of the memory module 900. For example, the additional circuitry 920 may include functionality to determine whether power is being supplied to the memory module 900 and whether the memory module 900 is currently being accessed, and to display an indication of its status, such as a<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> solid light while powered and a flashing light while being accessed. The additional circuitry 920 may further include passive devices, such as decoupling capacitors to help regulate power requirements within the memory module 900.</p><heading id="h0004"><u>Conclusion</u></heading><p id="p0086" num="0086">Methods, devices, modules, and systems for non-volatile multilevel memory cell data retrieval with data read of reference cells. Embodiments use reference cells interleaved with data cells to compensate for various systematic and/or transient data degradation mechanisms have been described. One method embodiment includes programming at least one data cell of a number of data cells coupled to a selected word line to a target data threshold voltage (Vt) level corresponding to a target state; programming at least one reference cell of a number of reference cells coupled to the selected word line to a target reference Vt level, the number of reference cells interleaved with the number of data cells; determining a reference state based on a data read of the at least one reference cell; and changing a state read from the at least one data cell based on a change of the at least one reference cell.</p><p id="p0087" num="0087">Although specific embodiments have been illustrated and described herein, those of ordinary skill in the art will appreciate that an arrangement calculated to achieve the same results can be substituted for the specific embodiments shown. This disclosure is intended to cover adaptations or variations of various embodiments of the present disclosure. It is to be understood that the above description has been made in an illustrative fashion, and not a restrictive one. Combination of the above embodiments, and other embodiments not specifically described herein will be apparent to those of skill it in the art upon reviewing the above description. The scope of the various embodiments of the present disclosure includes other applications in which the above structures and methods are used. Therefore, the scope of various embodiments of the present disclosure should be determined with reference to the appended claims.</p><p id="p0088" num="0088">In the foregoing Detailed Description, various features are grouped together in a single embodiment for the purpose of streamlining the disclosure. This method of disclosure is not to be interpreted as reflecting an<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --> intention that the disclosed embodiments of the present disclosure have to use more features than are expressly recited in each claim. Rather, as the following claims reflect, inventive subject matter lies in less than all features of a single disclosed embodiment. Thus, the following claims are hereby incorporated into the Detailed Description, with each claim standing on its own as a separate embodiment.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980208" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Verfahren zum Betreiben eines Arrays (108; 200; 830) nichtflüchtiger Mehrniveau-Speicherzellen (211-1, ..., 211-N), in dem:
<claim-text>eine Anzahl von Gruppen von Datenzellen (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D), die mit einer ausgewählten Wortleitung (205-1, ..., 205-N) gekoppelt sind, programmiert wird, wobei jede Gruppe eine damit verschachtelte verknüpfte Anzahl von Stapeln von Referenzzellen (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) aufweist, die zur gleichen Zeit wie die jeweilige Gruppe von Datenzellen (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) programmiert und gelesen wird, wobei die Datenzellen und die Referenzzellen die gleichen Soll-Schwellenwertspannungs-(Vt)-Niveaus (439-0, 439-1, 439-2, 439-3; 639-0 bis 639-7) aufweisen, die den gleichen Soll-Logikzuständen (430, 432, 434, 436) entsprechen;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Leseoperation auf einer bestimmten Gruppe von Datenzellen (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) und auf deren verknüpften Stapeln von Referenzzellen (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) durchgeführt wird, wobei jeder der verknüpften Stapel auf einen verschiedenen bestimmten Soll-Logikzustand (430, 432, 434, 436) programmiert worden ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>anhand der Leseoperation festgestellt wird, ob die Stapel von Referenzzellen (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) einen anderen Logikzustand als den bestimmten Soll-Logikzustand (430, 432, 434, 436), auf den die Stapel programmiert wurden, darstellen;</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b>:
<claim-text>falls festgestellt wird, dass der Stapel von Referenzzellen einen anderen Logikzustand als den ursprünglichen Soll-Logikzustand, auf den der Stapel ursprünglich programmiert worden ist, darstellt,</claim-text><claim-text>eine mit dem Array (108; 200; 830) gekoppelte Datenkorrekturschaltung (118) verwendet wird, um den durch diese gelesenen<!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --> Datenzellen (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) dargestellten Logikzustand in einer bestimmten Gruppe, die auf den gleichen ursprünglichen Soll-Logikzustand (430, 432, 434, 436) wie der entsprechende Stapel von Referenzzellen (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) programmiert worden ist, auf den bestimmten Soll-Logikzustand zu ändern.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, wobei beim Feststellen, ob die Stapel von Referenzzellen (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) einen anderen Logikzustand (525-2) als den bestimmten Sollzustand darstellen, der durch die gelesenen Referenzzellen (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) in jedem Stapel dargestellte häufigste Logikzustand (430, 432, 434, 436; 525-1) festgelegt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 1, wobei beim Feststellen, ob die Stapel von Referenzzellen (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) einen anderen Logikzustand als den bestimmten Sollzustand darstellen, durch Verwenden einer mit dem Array (108; 200; 830) gekoppelten Datenkorrekturschaltung (118; 618) ein mit den gelesenen Referenzzellen (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) in jedem Stapel verknüpftes mittleres Vt-Niveau festgestellt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 3, wobei jeder Stapel von Referenzzellen (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) mindestens vier Referenzzellen enthält.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 3, in dem die Leseoperation auf der bestimmten Gruppe von Datenzellen (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) und auf deren verknüpften Stapeln von Referenzzellen (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) unter Verwendung desselben Referenzleseniveaus durchgeführt wird.<!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 3, wobei beim Feststellen anhand der Leseoperation der Stapel von Referenzzellen (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R), die einen anderen Logikzustand (525-2) als den bestimmten Sollzustand (430, 432, 434, 436; 525-1), auf den der Stapel programmiert wurde, darstellen, eine von einem Soll-Vt-Niveau (439-0, 439-1, 439-2, 439-3; 639-0 bis 639-7) entfernte Vt-Verstellmenge (655-2) festgelegt wird, die mit den jeweiligen Stapeln von Referenzzellen (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) verknüpft ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 6, in dem Logikzustände gewechselt werden (665), die durch solche Datenzellen (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) in der bestimmten Gruppe dargestellt werden, die auf einen der bestimmten Sollzustände (430, 432, 434, 436; 525-1) programmiert wurden und die einem Stapel von Referenzzellen (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) entsprechen, bei denen anhand der festgestellten Vt-Verstellmenge festgestellt wird, dass sie einen anderen Logikzustand (525-2) als den bestimmten Sollzustand (430, 432, 434, 436) darstellen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 6, wobei beim Feststellen der Vt-Verstellmenge (655-2) eine mittlere Vt-Verstellung festgelegt wird, die mit einer bestimmten Anzahl von Referenzzellen eines bestimmten jeweiligen Stapels von Referenzzellen (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) verknüpft ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 3, in dem die Leseoperation auf der bestimmten Gruppe von Datenzellen (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) und auf deren verknüpften Stapeln von Referenzzellen (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) zur gleichen Zeit durchgeführt wird.<!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 9, in dem die Leseoperation auf der bestimmten Gruppe von Datenzellen (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) und auf deren verknüpften Stapeln von Referenzzellen (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) unter Verwendung der gleichen Lesezustände für sowohl die Datenzellen (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) und die Referenzzellen (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) durchgeführt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 3, in dem die Leseoperation auf der bestimmten Gruppe von Datenzellen (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) und auf deren verknüpften Stapeln von Referenzzellen (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) zu verschiedenen Zeitpunkten durchgeführt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 3, wobei jede Datenzelle (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) und jede Referenzzelle (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) eine Vier-Bit-Zelle-Mehrniveau-Speicherzelle (211-1, ..., 211-N) ist, die sechzehn verschiedene Logikzustände (430, 432, 434, 436) darstellen kann.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 3, wobei die bestimmte Gruppe von Datenzellen (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) einer ersten Seite von Daten entspricht und wobei die ausgewählte Wortleitung (205-1, ..., 205-N) eine zweite Gruppe von Datenzellen (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) enthält, die einer zweiten Seite von Daten entspricht.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Nichtflüchtiges Speichersystem (100), umfassend:
<claim-text>ein Array (108) nichtflüchtiger Mehrniveau-Speicherzellen (312-324), die in durch Wortleitungen gekoppelte Zeilen (120) und durch Bitleitungen gekoppelte Spalten angeordnet sind, wobei die Zeilen (120) eine Anzahl von Datenzellen (312, 314) enthalten, die eine verknüpfte Anzahl von Soll-Schwellwert-Spannungs-"Vt"-Niveaus<!-- EPO <DP n="36"> --> aufweisen, die einer Anzahl von Sollzuständen entsprechen;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Anzahl von Stapeln (116) von Referenzzellen (322, 324), die mit den Datenzellen verschachtelt sind, wobei die Referenzzellen (322, 324) dieselben Soll-Vt-Niveaus und Sollzustände wie die Datenzellen (312, 314) aufweisen; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Steuerschaltkreis (166; 110, 118), die mit dem Array (108) der Speicherzellen (312-324) gekoppelt ist und dazu ausgelegt ist, ein Verfahren nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche auszuführen.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980209" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A method for operating an array (108; 200; 830) of non-volatile multilevel memory cells (211-1, .., 211-N), comprising:
<claim-text>programming a number of groups of data cells (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) coupled to a selected word line (205-1, ..., 205-N), each group having an associated number of batches of reference cells (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) interleaved therewith that are programmed and read at the same time as the respective group of data cells (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D), wherein the data cells and reference cells have the same target threshold voltage (Vt) levels (439-0, 439-1, 439-2, 439-3; 639-0 to 639-7) that correspond to the same target logic states (430, 432, 434, 436);</claim-text>
<claim-text>performing a read operation on a particular group of data cells (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) and on its associated batches of reference cells (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R), each of the associated batches having been programmed to a different particular target logic state (430, 432, 434, 436); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>determining, based on the read operation, whether the batches of reference cells (322-1, 322-2... 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) represent a logic state other than the particular target logic state (430, 432, 434, 436) to which the batches were programmed;<br/>
<b>characterised by</b>: if it is determined that the batch of reference cells represent a logic state other than the original target logic state to which the batch had been programmed.</claim-text>
<claim-text>using a data correction circuit (118), coupled to the array (108; 200; 830), to change the logic state represented by those read data cells (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) in a particular group that has been programmed to the same original target logic state (430, 432, 434, 436) as the corresponding batch of reference cells (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R), to the particular target logic state.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The method of claim 1, wherein determining whether the batches of reference cells (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) represent a logic state (525-2) other than the particular target state includes determining a most common logic state (430, 432, 434, 436; 525-1) represented by the read reference cells (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) in each batch.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The method of claim 1, wherein determining whether the batches of reference cells (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) represent a logic state other than the particular target state includes determining, by using a data correction circuit (118; 618) coupled to the array (108; 200; 830), an average Vt level associated with the read reference cells (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) in each batch.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The method of any one of claims 1-3, wherein each batch of reference cells (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) includes at least four reference cells.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The method of any one of claims 1-3, including performing the read operation on the particular group of data cells (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) and on its associated batches of reference cells (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) using the same reference read levels.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The method of any one of claims 1-3, wherein determining, based on the read operation, those batches of reference cells (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) that represent a logic state (525-2) other than the particular target state (430, 432, 434, 436; 525-1) to which the batch was programmed includes determining a Vt shift amount (655-2), away from a target Vt level (439-0, 439-1, 439-2, 439-3; 639-0 to 639-7), associated with the respective batches of reference cells (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R).<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The method of claim 6, including changing (665) logic states represented by those data cells (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) in the particular group that were programmed to one of the different particular target states (430, 432, 434, 436; 525-1) corresponding to a batch of reference cells (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) determined to represent the logic state (525-2) other than the particular target state (430, 432, 434, 436) based on the determined Vt shift amount.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The method of claim 6, wherein determining the Vt shift amount (655-2) includes determining an average Vt shift associated with a particular number of reference cells of a particular respective batch of reference cells (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The method of any one of claims 1-3, including performing the read operation on the particular group of data cells (312-1, 312-2,.., 312-D; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) and on its associated batches of reference cells (322-1, 322-2,.., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2,.., 324-R) at the same time.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The method of claim 9, including performing the read operation on the particular group of data cells (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D; 314-1, 314-2,.., 314-D) and on its associated batches of the reference cells (322-1, 322-2,.., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2,.., 324-R) using the same read conditions for both the data cells (312-1, 312-2,.., 312-D; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) and the reference cells (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2,.., 324-R).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>The method of any one of claims 1-3, including performing the read operation on the particular group of data cells (312-1, 312-2,.., 312-D; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) and on its associated batches of reference cells (322-1, 322-2,.., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2,.., 324-R) at different times.<!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>The method of any one of claims 1-3, wherein each data cell (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) and each reference cell (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) is a four-bit cell multilevel memory cell (211-1,..., 211-N) capable of representing sixteen different logic states (430, 432, 434, 436).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>The method of any one of claims 1-3, wherein the particular group of data cells (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) corresponds to a first page of data and wherein the selected word line (205-1, ..., 205-N) includes a second group of data cells (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) corresponding to a second page of data.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>A non-volatile memory system (100) comprising:
<claim-text>an array (108) of non-volatile multilevel memory cells (312-324) arranged in rows (120) coupled by word lines and columns coupled by bit lines, the rows (120) including a number of data cells (312, 314) having an associated number of target threshold voltage "Vt" levels which correspond to a number of target states;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a number of batches (116) of reference cells (322, 324) interleaved with the data cells, the reference cells (322, 324) having the same target Vt levels and target states as the data cells (312, 314); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>control circuitry (166: 110, 118) coupled to the array (108) of memory cells (312-324) and configured to execute a method in accordance with the method of any preceding claim.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980210" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="37"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Procédé permettant de faire fonctionner un réseau (108 ; 200 ; 830) de cellules de mémoire non volatile multi-niveaux (211-1, ..., 211-N), comprenant le fait :
<claim-text>de programmer un nombre de groupes de cellules de données (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D ; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) couplées à une ligne de mots sélectionnée (205-1, ..., 205-N), chaque groupe ayant un nombre associé de lots de cellules de référence (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R ; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) intercalées avec celles-ci qui sont programmées et lues en même temps que le groupe respectif de cellules de données (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D ; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D), où les cellules de données et les cellules de référence ont les mêmes niveaux de tension de seuil (Vt) cibles (439-0, 439-1, 439-2, 439-3 ; 639-0 à 639-7) qui correspondent aux mêmes états logiques cibles (430, 432, 434, 436) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>d'effectuer une opération de lecture sur un groupe particulier de cellules de données (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D ; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) et sur ses lots associés de cellules de référence (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R ; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R), chacun des lots associés ayant été programmé à un état logique cible particulier différent (430, 432, 434, 436) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>de déterminer, sur la base de l'opération de lecture, si les lots de cellules de référence (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R ; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) représentent un état logique autre que l'état logique cible particulier (430, 432, 434, 436) auquel les lots ont été programmés ;</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>caractérisé par</b> le fait suivant :
<claim-text>s'il est déterminé que le lot de cellules de référence représente un état logique autre que l'état logique cible d'origine auquel le lot a été programmé, utiliser un circuit de correction de données (118), couplé au réseau (108 ; 200 ; 830), afin de changer l'état logique représenté par ces cellules de données lues (312-1, 312-2,<!-- EPO <DP n="38"> --> ..., 312-D ; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) dans un groupe particulier qui a été programmé au même état logique cible d'origine (430, 432, 434, 436) que le lot correspondant de cellules de référence (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R ; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R), en l'état logique cible particulier.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Procédé de la revendication 1, dans lequel le fait de déterminer si les lots de cellules de référence (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R ; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) représentent un état logique (525-2) autre que l'état cible particulier inclut la détermination de l'état logique le plus courant (430, 432, 434, 436 ; 525-1) représenté par les cellules de référence lues (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R ; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) dans chaque lot.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Procédé de la revendication 1, dans lequel le fait de déterminer si les lots de cellules de référence (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R ; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) représentent un état logique autre que l'état cible particulier inclut la détermination, en utilisant un circuit de correction de données (118 ; 618) couplé au réseau (108 ; 200 ; 830), d'un niveau Vt moyen associé aux cellules de référence lues (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R ; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) dans chaque lot.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Procédé de l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 3, dans lequel chaque lot de cellules de référence (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R ; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) comporte au moins quatre cellules de référence.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Procédé de l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 3, comportant le fait d'effectuer l'opération de lecture sur le groupe particulier de cellules de données (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D ; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) et sur ses lots associés de cellules de référence (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R ; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) en utilisant les mêmes niveaux de lecture de référence.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Procédé de l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 3, dans lequel le fait de déterminer, sur la base de l'opération de lecture, ces lots de cellules de référence<!-- EPO <DP n="39"> --> (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R ; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) qui représentent un état logique (525-2) autre que l'état cible particulier (430, 432, 434, 436 ; 525-1) auquel le lot a été programmé, inclut la détermination d'une valeur de décalage de Vt (655-2), éloignée d'un niveau Vt cible (439-0, 439-1, 439-2, 439-3 ; 639-0 à 639-7), associée aux lots respectifs de cellules de référence (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R ; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Procédé de la revendication 6, comportant le fait de changer (665) des états logiques représentés par ces cellules de données (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D ; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) dans le groupe particulier qui ont été programmées en l'un des états cibles particuliers différents (430, 432, 434, 436 ; 525-1) correspondant à un lot de cellules de référence (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R ; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) déterminées pour représenter l'état logique (525-2) autre que l'état cible particulier (430, 432, 434, 436) sur la base de la valeur de décalage de Vt déterminée.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Procédé de la revendication 6, dans lequel le fait de déterminer la valeur de décalage de Vt (655-2) inclut la détermination d'un décalage de Vt moyen associé à un nombre particulier de cellules de référence d'un lot respectif particulier de cellules de référence (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R ; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Procédé de l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 3, comportant le fait d'effectuer l'opération de lecture sur le groupe particulier de cellules de données (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D ; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) et sur ses lots associés de cellules de référence (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R ; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) en même temps.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Procédé de la revendication 9, comportant le fait d'effectuer l'opération de lecture sur le groupe particulier de cellules de données (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D ; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) et sur ses lots associés des cellules de référence (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R ; 324-1, 324-2,<!-- EPO <DP n="40"> --> ..., 324-R) en utilisant les mêmes conditions de lecture à la fois pour les cellules de données (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D ; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) et pour les cellules de référence (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R ; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Procédé de l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 3, comportant le fait d'effectuer l'opération de lecture sur le groupe particulier de cellules de données (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D ; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) et sur ses lots associés de cellules de référence (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R ; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) à des moments différents.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Procédé de l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 3, dans lequel chaque cellule de données (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D ; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) et chaque cellule de référence (322-1, 322-2, ..., 322-R ; 324-1, 324-2, ..., 324-R) est une cellule de mémoire multi-niveaux du type cellule à quatre bits (211-1, ..., 211-N) capable de représenter seize états logiques différents (430, 432, 434, 436).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Procédé de l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 3, dans lequel le groupe particulier de cellules de données (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D ; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) correspond à une première page de données et dans lequel la ligne de mots sélectionnée (205-1, ..., 205-N) comporte un deuxième groupe de cellules de données (312-1, 312-2, ..., 312-D ; 314-1, 314-2, ..., 314-D) correspondant à une deuxième page de données.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Système de mémoire non volatile (100) comprenant :
<claim-text>un réseau (108) de cellules de mémoire non volatile multi-niveaux (312-324) agencées en rangées (120) couplées par des lignes de mots et en colonnes couplées par des lignes de bits, les rangées (120) comportant un nombre de cellules de données (312, 314) ayant un nombre associé de niveaux de tension de seuil « Vt » cibles qui correspondent à un nombre d'états cibles ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un nombre de lots (116) de cellules de référence (322, 324) intercalées avec les cellules de données, les cellules<!-- EPO <DP n="41"> --> de référence (322, 324) ayant les mêmes niveaux Vt cibles et les mêmes états cibles que les cellules de données (312, 314) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>des circuits de commande (166 : 110, 118) couplés au réseau (108) de cellules de mémoire (312-324) et configurés pour exécuter un procédé conformément au procédé de l'une des revendications précédentes.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16669090" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="42"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="165" he="172" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="43"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="165" he="223" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="44"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="141" he="106" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="45"> --><figure id="f0004" num="4"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="139" he="61" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="46"> --><figure id="f0005" num="5"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="128" he="110" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="47"> --><figure id="f0006" num="6,7"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="155" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
