<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2681969-A1" country="EP" doc-number="2681969" kind="A1" date="20140108" family-id="46047159" file-reference-id="313847" date-produced="20180822" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146585638" ucid="EP-2681969-A1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2681969</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-11794283-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154847830" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>11794283</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20111116</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP173923807" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>11794283.9</doc-number><date>20111116</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140556366" ucid="US-2011061033-W" linkage-type="W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>2011061033</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20111116</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140548119" ucid="US-201113298002-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>201113298002</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20111116</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140547942" ucid="US-41429110-P" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>41429110</doc-number><kind>P</kind><date>20101116</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989316547" load-source="docdb">H05B  39/04        20060101ALI20121010BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989317067" load-source="docdb">H05B  33/08        20060101AFI20121010BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989321726" load-source="docdb">H05B  39/08        20060101ALI20121010BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2056022017" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H05B  33/0851      20130101 LI20150514BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2056025445" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H05B  33/0815      20130101 LI20150514BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2056029851" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H05B  39/048       20130101 LI20150514BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989628912" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H05B  37/02        20130101 FI20131219BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132361547" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">AUSTRITTSKANTENDIMMERKOMPATIBILITÄT MIT HOHER DIMMERWIDERSTANDSPROGNOSE</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132361548" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">TRAILING EDGE DIMMER COMPATIBILITY WITH DIMMER HIGH RESISTANCE PREDICTION</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132361549" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">COMPATIBILITÉ D'UN GRADATEUR DE FLANC ARRIÈRE AVEC UNE PRÉDICTION DE HAUTE RÉSISTANCE DE GRADATEUR</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919528748" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>CIRRUS LOGIC INC</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919524120" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>CIRRUS LOGIC, INC.</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919014202" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Cirrus Logic, Inc.</last-name><iid>101380314</iid><address><street>800 West 6th Street</street><city>Austin, TX 78701</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919535527" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>MELANSON JOHN L</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919545801" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>MELANSON, JOHN, L.</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919007646" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>MELANSON, JOHN, L.</last-name><address><street>901 West 9th Street 201</street><city>Austin, TX 78703</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919505949" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>KING ERIC J</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919505379" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>KING, ERIC, J.</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919007880" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>KING, ERIC, J.</last-name><address><street>1050 Trail Head Circle</street><city>Dripping Springs, TX 78620</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919008713" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Freeman, Jacqueline Carol</last-name><iid>100033954</iid><address><street>WP Thompson 55 Drury Lane</street><city>London WC2B 5SQ</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="US-2011061033-W"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2011061033</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20111116</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2012128794-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2012128794</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20120927</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549822520" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS549754226" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549750165" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549827611" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549831264" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549750166" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549751408" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549822521" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549750167" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549750168" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549828005" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549827612" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549827613" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549822550" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549750177" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549822551" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549751417" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549831265" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549750178" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549827618" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549750179" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549827619" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549754227" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549827620" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549827621" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549754228" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS549754241" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549828018" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549911075" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549828019" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549754242" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549831270" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549754243" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS549828020" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549751418" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549911076" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549911077" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS549827626" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA100472124" ref-ucid="WO-2012128794-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p num="0000">Electronic system (100) including a controller (402), which provides compatibility between an electronic light source (410) and a trailing edge dimmer (404). The controller is capable of predicting an estimated occurrence &lt; a trailing edge of a phase cut AC voltage and accelerating a transition of the phase cut voltage from the trailing edge to a predetermined voltage treshold. The controller predicts an estimated occurrence of the trailing edge of the phase cut AC voltage on the basis of actual observations from one or more previous cycles of the phase cut AC voltage.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA100678716" ref-ucid="WO-2012128794-A1" lang="EN" source="national office" load-source="docdb"><p>Electronic system (100) including a controller (402), which provides compatibility between an electronic light source (410) and a trailing edge dimmer (404). The controller is capable of predicting an estimated occurrence &lt; a trailing edge of a phase cut AC voltage and accelerating a transition of the phase cut voltage from the trailing edge to a predetermined voltage treshold. The controller predicts an estimated occurrence of the trailing edge of the phase cut AC voltage on the basis of actual observations from one or more previous cycles of the phase cut AC voltage.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA100472125" ref-ucid="WO-2012128794-A1" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><p num="0000">L'invention concerne un système électronique (100) comprenant un contrôleur (402) lequel assure une compatibilité entre une source de lumière électronique (410) et un gradateur (404) de flanc arrière. Le contrôleur est capable de prédire une occurrence estimée de flanc arrière d'une tension CA de coupure de phase et d'accélérer une transition de la tension de coupure de phase du flanc arrière à un seuil de tension prédéterminé. Le contrôleur prédit une occurrence estimée du flanc arrière de la tension CA de coupure de phase sur la base des observations effectives provenant d'un ou de plusieurs cycles de la tension CA de coupure de phase.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA100678717" ref-ucid="WO-2012128794-A1" lang="FR" source="national office" load-source="docdb"><p>L'invention concerne un système électronique (100) comprenant un contrôleur (402) lequel assure une compatibilité entre une source de lumière électronique (410) et un gradateur (404) de flanc arrière. Le contrôleur est capable de prédire une occurrence estimée de flanc arrière d'une tension CA de coupure de phase et d'accélérer une transition de la tension de coupure de phase du flanc arrière à un seuil de tension prédéterminé. Le contrôleur prédit une occurrence estimée du flanc arrière de la tension CA de coupure de phase sur la base des observations effectives provenant d'un ou de plusieurs cycles de la tension CA de coupure de phase.</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES51558993" ref-ucid="WO-2012128794-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="2"/>--><p id="p0001" num="0001"> TRAILING EDGE DIMMER COMPATIBILITY WITH DIMMER HIGH </p><p id="p0002" num="0002"> RESISTANCE PREDICTION </p><p id="p0003" num="0003">CROSS-REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATION </p><p id="p0004" num="0004">[001] This application claims the benefit under 35 U.S.C. § 119(e) and 37 C.F.R. § 1.78 of U.S. Provisional Application No. 61/414,291, filed on Nov. 16, 2010, which is incorporated by reference in its entirety. This application also claims the benefit under 35 U.S.C. § 120 and 37 C.F.R. § 1.78 of U.S. of U.S. Patent Application No. 13/298,002, filed November 16, 2011, which is incorporated by reference in its entirety. </p><p id="p0005" num="0005">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION Field of the Invention </p><p id="p0006" num="0006">[002] The present invention relates in general to the field of electronics, and more specifically to a method and system for trailing edge dimmer compatibility with dimmer high resistance prediction. </p><p id="p0007" num="0007">DESCRIPTION OF THE RELATED ART </p><p id="p0008" num="0008">[003] The development and use of energy efficient technologies continues to be a high priority for many entities including many companies and countries. One area of interest is the replacement of incandescent lamps with more energy efficient lamps such as lamps based on electronic light sources. For this description, electronic light sources are light emitting diodes (LEDs) and compact fluorescent lamps (CFLs). The development of electronic light source based lamps and are not without many challenges. One of the challenges is developing electronic light source based lamps that are compatible with existing infrastructure. The following discussion focuses on LED-based lighting systems but is also applicable to CFL-based lighting systems and combination LED and CFL based lighting systems. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="3"/>-->
 [004] Many electronic systems include circuits, such as switching power converters that interface with a dimmer. The interfacing circuits deliver power to a load in accordance with the dimming level set by the dimmer. For example, in a lighting system, dimmers provide an input signal to a lighting system. The input signal represents a dimming level that causes the lighting system to adjust power delivered to a lamp, and, thus, depending on the dimming level, increase or decrease the brightness of the lamp. Many different types of dimmers exist. In general, dimmers generate a digital or analog coded dimming signal that indicates a desired dimming level. A trailing edge dimmer phase cuts a trailing edge of an alternating current ("AC") supply voltage. </p><p id="p0009" num="0009">[005] Figure 1 depicts a lighting system 100 that includes a trailing edge, phase-cut dimmer 102. Figure 2 depicts an exemplary, trailing edge phase cut voltage graph 200 and a dimmer control signal 201 associated with the lighting system 100. Referring to Figures 1 and 2, the lighting system 100 receives an AC supply voltage Vi<sub>N</sub> from voltage supply 104. The supply voltage VI , indicated by voltage waveform 202, is, for example, a nominally 60 Hz/110 V line voltage in the United States of America or a nominally 50 Hz/220 V line voltage in Europe. The trailing edge dimmer 102 phase cuts trailing edges, such as trailing edges 202 and 204, of each half cycle of supply voltage VI - Since each half cycle of supply voltage VIN is 180 degrees of the supply voltage VIN, the trailing edge dimmer 102 phase cuts the supply voltage VIN at an angle greater than 0 degrees and less than 180 degrees. The phase cut, input voltage Vq&gt;_iN to the lighting system 100 represents a dimming level that causes the lighting system 100 to adjust power delivered to a lamp 106, and, thus, depending on the dimming level, increase or decrease the brightness of the lamp 106. The lamp 106 is an incandescent lamp and can generally be modeled as a resistor 108. </p><p id="p0010" num="0010">[006] The dimmer 102 includes a timer controller 110 that generates dimmer control signal DCS to control a duty cycle of switch 112. The duty cycle of switch 112 is a pulse width, e.g. times ti-to, divided by a period of the dimmer control signal, e.g. times t<sub>3</sub>-t<sub>0</sub>, for each cycle of the dimmer control signal DCS. The timer controller 110 converts a desired dimming level into the duty cycle for switch 112. The duty cycle of the dimmer control signal DCS is decreased for lower dimming levels, i.e. higher brightness for lamp 106, and increased for higher dimming levels. During a pulse, e.g. pulse 206 and pulse 208, of the dimmer control signal DCS, the 
<!-- EPO <DP n="4"/>-->
 switch 1 12 conducts, i.e. is ON, and the dimmer 102 enters a low resistance state. In the low resistance state of the dimmer 102, the resistance of the switch 1 12 is, for example, less than or equal to 10 ohms. During the low resistance state of switch 1 12, the phase cut, input voltage o I tracks the input supply voltage VI and the dimmer 102 transfers a dimmer current i<sub>DIM</sub> to the lamp 106. </p><p id="p0011" num="0011">[007] When the timer controller 1 10 causes the pulse of the dimmer control signal 206 to end, the dimmer control signal 206 turns the switch 1 12 OFF, which causes the dimmer 102 to enter a high resistance state, i.e. turns OFF. In the high resistance state of the dimmer 102, the resistance of the switch 1 12 is, for example, greater than 1 kohm. The dimmer 102 includes a capacitor 1 14, which charges to the supply voltage VI during each pulse of the timer control signal DCS. In both the high and low resistance states of the dimmer 102, the capacitor 1 14 remains connected across the switch 1 12. When the switch 1 12 is OFF and the dimmer 102 enters the high resistance state, the voltage Vc across capacitor 1 14 decays, e.g. between times ti and t<sub>2</sub> and between times and t<sub>5</sub>. The rate of decay is a function of the amount of capacitance C of capacitor 1 14 and the dimmer current IDIM that is transferred through the resistance R of lamp 108. Equation [1 ] represents the relationship between the capacitance C of capacitor 1 14, the dimmer current IDIM, and the rate of decay dV&lt;j&gt;<sub>j</sub>&gt;i/dt of the phase cut, input voltage Vo IN: </p><p id="p0012" num="0012">IDIM = C · dV&lt;t&gt; <sub>JN</sub>/dt [1 ] </p><p id="p0013" num="0013">[008] The resistance value R of lamp 106 is relatively low and permits a high enough value of the dimmer current i<sub>D</sub>M to allow the phase cut, input voltage V&lt;p IN to decay to a zero crossing, e.g. at times t<sub>2</sub> and t<sub>5</sub>, before the next pulse of the dimmer control signal DCS. </p><p id="p0014" num="0014">[009] Trailing edge dimmers, such as trailing edge dimmer 102, have some favorable characteristics. For example, trailing edge dimmer 102 does not have an abrupt voltage increase when the dimmer 102 begins to conduct, e.g. at times to and t<sub>3</sub>, and has a decaying decrease when the dimmer 102 enters the high resistance state. Thus, harmonic frequencies are lower, and the dimmer 102 generates less electromagnetic interference. </p><p id="p0015" num="0015">[0010] As previously discussed, electronic light sources have a higher energy efficiency than incandescent lamps of comparable light out. Thus, electronic light sources are being retrofitted into existing infrastructure that includes trailing edge dimmers, such as trailing edge dimmer 
<!-- EPO <DP n="5"/>-->
 102. An electronic light source has lower power requirements and, thus, less dimmer current IDIM is transferred to the electronic light sources. Thus, in accordance with Equation [1] for a smaller dimmer current IDIM, the decay rate dVo ικ/dt is less. If the decay rate dVo _m/dt is too low, the phase cut, input voltage Vo IN does not reach a zero crossing prior to a beginning of a next cycle of the supply voltage VIN. Failure to reach a zero-crossing can cause some trailing edge dimmers to malfunction. </p><p id="p0016" num="0016">[0011] Figure 3 depicts a lighting system 300 that includes the trailing edge dimmer 102 and LED(s) 302. The dimmer 102 functions as previously described and provides a phase cut, input voltage Vo IN and a dimmer current to a full bridge diode rectifier 304. The rectifier 304 provides the phase cut, rectified voltage VCD_R to a power converter 306. The power converter 306 respectively converts the phase cut, rectified voltage Vo R and the rectified input current i<sub>R</sub> into an approximately constant output voltage VOUT and an output current ίουτ· The output current ίουτ adjusts with the dimming level indicated by the phase angle of the phase cut, input voltage Vo IN and is approximately constant for any given dimming level. </p><p id="p0017" num="0017">[0012] The controller 308 includes a current controller 310 to control the transfer of current IR to the power converter 306 and regulate the power delivered to the LED(s) 302. The LED(s) require substantially less power to provide the equivalent light output of an incandescent bulb. For example, the LED(s) 302 use 4W of power to provide the equivalent light output of a 60W incandescent bulb. The output voltage VOUT is generally boosted by the power converter 306 to, for example, 400V. Since the power P provided to the LED(s) 302 is approximately </p><p id="p0018" num="0018">P = VOUT - ϊουτ, a maximum current i<sub>R</sub> transferred to the power converter 306 is typically only 50 mA, which is less than the approximately 545 mA maximum current drawn by a 60W bulb from a 110 V supply input voltage Vi<sub>N</sub>. Thus, the decay time dVo <sub>jN</sub>/dt for the lighting system 300 increases in accordance with Equation [1]. The controller 308 includes a comparator 312 to detect trailing edges, such as trailing edges 314 and 316, of the phase cut, rectified voltage Vo R. </p><p id="p0019" num="0019">[0013] Detection of the trailing edge of the phase cut, rectified voltage Vo R is not a simple task. The trailing edges of rectified input voltage VOR IN at times ti and t<sub>4</sub> are generally noisy and may contain other distortions. To detect the trailing edges, the controller 308 utilizes a comparator 312 to detect the trailing edge at a more stable portion of the phase cut, rectified voltage Vo R. The comparator 312 receives the phase cut, rectified voltage Vo R or a scaled version of the 
<!-- EPO <DP n="6"/>-->
 phase cut, rectified voltage V&lt;P_R at an inverting input of the comparator 312. The comparator 312 compares the phase cut, rectified voltage V&lt;t&gt;_R with a fixed, trailing edge detection voltage threshold, such as +20V, and generates a trailing edge detection signal TE_DETECT. The trailing edge detection signal TE DETECT signal is a logical 0 prior to detection of a trailing edge of phase cut, rectified voltage V&lt;p R and transitions to a logical 1 upon detection of the trailing edge. Once the trailing edge detection signal TE DETECT indicates detection of the trailing edge, the current controller 310 increases a transfer of current IDIM through the dimmer 102 to increase the rate of decay dVo <sub>j</sub>x/dt and, thus, increase the rate of decay of the phase cut, rectified voltage VCD at, for example times t<sub>2</sub> and t<sub>4</sub>. Increasing the rate of decay at times t<sub>2</sub> and t<sub>5</sub> helps ensure that the phase cut, rectified voltage Vo R reaches a zero crossing prior to a beginning of a next cycle of the phase cut, rectified voltage Vo R. The trailing edge detection threshold value is set low enough to avoid prematurely detecting a trailing edge. However, because the rate of decay dVcp<sub>jN</sub>/dt is greater for electronic light sources, the low value of the trailing edge detection threshold also means that the trailing edge might not be detected before a zero crossing of the phase cut, rectified voltage Vq&gt;_R for large phase angles. Increasing the value of the trailing edge detection threshold can result in transferring an unnecessary amount of current from the voltage supply 104. </p><p id="p0020" num="0020">[0014] It is desirable to improve compatibility with trailing edge dimmers. SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION </p><p id="p0021" num="0021">[0015] In one embodiment of the present invention, an apparatus includes a controller to provide compatibility between a lamp and a trailing edge dimmer. The controller is capable to predict an estimated occurrence of a high resistance state of the trailing edge dimmer. The high resistance state occurs when the trailing edge dimmer begins phase cutting an alternating current (AC) voltage signal. The controller is further capable to operate in a high current mode based on the estimated predicted occurrence of the high resistance state of the trailing edge dimmer. The controller is also capable to operate in a low impedance mode after the AC voltage signal reaches a low voltage threshold. </p><p id="p0022" num="0022">[0016] In a further embodiment of the present invention, a method to provide compatibility between a lamp and a trailing edge dimmer includes predicting an estimated occurrence of a high 
<!-- EPO <DP n="7"/>-->
 resistance state of the trailing edge dimmer. The high resistance state occurs when the trailing edge dimmer begins phase cutting an alternating current (AC) voltage signal. The method further includes operating a controller of at least a power converter in a high current mode based on the estimated predicted occurrence of the high resistance state of the trailing edge dimmer. The method also includes operating the controller in a low impedance mode after the AC voltage signal reaches a low voltage threshold. </p><p id="p0023" num="0023">[0017] In another embodiment of the present invention, an apparatus includes a controller that is a capable to predict an estimated occurrence of a high resistance state of a trailing edge dimmer. The high resistance state occurs when the trailing edge dimmer begins phase cutting an alternating current (AC) voltage signal of a phase cut AC voltage. The controller is further capable to accelerate a transition of the AC voltage from the trailing edge to a predetermined voltage threshold. </p><p id="p0024" num="0024">[0018] In a further embodiment of the present invention, a method includes predicting an estimated occurrence of a high resistance state of a trailing edge dimmer. The high resistance state occurs when the trailing edge dimmer begins phase cutting an alternating current (AC) voltage signal of a phase cut AC voltage. The method further includes accelerating a transition of the AC voltage from the trailing edge to a predetermined voltage threshold. </p><p id="p0025" num="0025">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </p><p id="p0026" num="0026">[0019] The present invention may be better understood, and its numerous objects, features and advantages made apparent to those skilled in the art by referencing the accompanying drawings. The use of the same reference number throughout the several figures designates a like or similar element. </p><p id="p0027" num="0027">[0020] Figure 1 (labeled prior art) depicts a lighting system that includes a trailing edge dimmer. </p><p id="p0028" num="0028">[0021] Figure 2 (labeled prior art) depicts a dimmer control signal and voltage waveform associated with the trailing edge dimmer of Figure 1. </p><p id="p0029" num="0029">[0022] Figure 3 (labeled prior art) depicts a lighting system that includes a trailing edge dimmer 102 and LED(s). 
<!-- EPO <DP n="8"/>-->
 [0023] Figure 4 depicts a lighting system that includes a controller that provides compatibility between the trailing edge dimmer and an electronic light source. </p><p id="p0030" num="0030">[0024] Figure 5 depicts exemplary voltage and current waveforms during operation of the lighting system of Figure 4. </p><p id="p0031" num="0031">[0025] Figure 6 depicts an exemplary trailing edge compatibility operational flow chart that represents one embodiment of providing compatibility between the trailing edge dimmer and electronic the light source of Figure 4. </p><p id="p0032" num="0032">[0026] Figure 7 depicts a lighting system that represents one embodiment of the lighting system of Figure 4. </p><p id="p0033" num="0033">[0027] Figure 8 depicts a zero crossing and active period detector. [0028] Figure 9 depicts a current control module. </p><p id="p0034" num="0034">DETAILED DESCRIPTION </p><p id="p0035" num="0035">[0029] In at least one embodiment, an electronic system includes a controller, and the controller provides compatibility between an electronic light source and a trailing edge dimmer. In at least one embodiment, the controller is capable of predicting an estimated occurrence of a trailing edge of a phase cut AC voltage and accelerating a transition of the phase cut AC voltage from the trailing edge to a predetermined voltage threshold. The terms "predict" and derivatives thereof, such as "predicting" and "prediction" mean to declare or indicate in advance. Thus, in at least one embodiment, predicting an estimated occurrence of a trailing edge of a phase cut AC voltage declares or indicates in advance the estimated occurrence of the trailing edge of the phase cut AC voltage. In at least one embodiment, the controller predicts an estimated occurrence of the trailing edge of the phase cut AC voltage on the basis of actual observations from one or more previous cycles of the phase cut AC voltage. </p><p id="p0036" num="0036">[0030] In at least one embodiment, to provide compatibility between a trailing edge dimmer and an electronic light source, the controller predicts an estimated occurrence of a high resistance state of the trailing edge dimmer. The trailing edge of a phase cut AC voltage begins when a trailing edge dimmer enters a high resistance state. Thus, the high resistance state occurs when the trailing edge dimmer begins phase cutting an alternating current (AC) voltage signal. Based 
<!-- EPO <DP n="9"/>-->
 on the prediction of the estimated occurrence of the high resistance state of the trailing edge dimmer, the controller is capable of and configured to further operate in a high current mode to increase a transfer of current from the trailing edge dimmer. Operating in the high current mode increases a decay rate of the phase cut AC voltage and, in at least one embodiment, ensures that the phase cut AC voltage reaches a low voltage threshold prior to beginning another cycle. Once the phase cut AC voltage reaches the low voltage threshold, the controller is capable of and configured to operate in a low impedance mode to hold the phase cut AC voltage at or below the low voltage threshold. </p><p id="p0037" num="0037">[0031 ] Figure 4 depicts a lighting system 400 that includes a controller 402 that provides compatibility between the trailing edge dimmer 404 and the light source 410. The trailing edge dimmer 404 can be any trailing edge dimmer, such as trailing edge dimmer 102, that phase cuts a trailing edge of the input supply voltage VIN from voltage supply 104. The full-bridge diode rectifier 408 rectifies the phase cut, input voltage Vq&gt;j to generate the phase cut, rectified voltage Vo R. The power converter 406 receives the phase cut, rectified voltage Vo R and the rectified current i<sub>R</sub> generates an output voltage VOUT and an output current ϊ<sub>0</sub>υτ· The output voltage VOUT and the output current ίουτ provide power for the light source 410. In at least one embodiment, the light source 410 is an electronic light source that includes one or more LEDs, one or more CFLs, or a combination of one or more LEDs and one or more CFLs. The power converter 406 can be any type of power converter and can include, for example, a boost converter, a buck converter, a boost-buck converter, or a Cuk converter. </p><p id="p0038" num="0038">[0032] Figure 5 depicts exemplary voltage and current waveforms 500 during operation of the lighting system 400. Figure 6 depicts an exemplary trailing edge compatibility operational flow chart 600 that represents one embodiment of providing compatibility between the trailing edge dimmer 404 and the light source 410. Referring to Figures 4, 5, and 6, the phase cut, rectified voltage Vo R has an active period from a first zero crossing to the second zero crossing of each cycle. The waveforms 500 depict a series of active periods ΤΑ(Π) - ΤΑ(Π-Λ of the phase cut, rectified voltage Vo R, where n is an integer index and jVis an integer greater than or equal to one. The "active time period TA(II-X)" refers to the portion of the phase cut AC voltage that is not equal to approximately zero for "X" ranging from 0 to N. In at least one embodiment, the controller 402 predicts an estimated active time period ΤΑ(η)<sub>Ε</sub>§τ of the η<sup>ώ</sup> cycle of the phase cut, 
<!-- EPO <DP n="10"/>-->
 rectified voltage Vq&gt;_R that spans from a first approximate zero crossing at time tzc(n)i until the next approximate zero crossing t<sub>Z</sub>c(n)<sub>2</sub> of the active time period T<sub>A</sub>(n). TA(II)EST represents the predicted estimate of the active time period ΤΑ(Π) for the present η<sup>Λ</sup> cycle </p><p id="p0039" num="0039">[0033] In at least one embodiment, controller 402 includes a trailing edge dimmer high resistance state predictor 412 to predict the estimated active time period TA(II)EST of the <sup>ηΛ</sup> cycle using the actual measured active time periods T<sub>A</sub>(n-l) through T<sub>A</sub>(n-N) of N previous cycle(s) of the phase cut, rectified voltage Vqj_R, where N is an integer greater than or equal to 1. The trailing edge high resistance state predictor 412 senses the phase cut, rectified voltage Υ _κ at node 414. Each active time period TA(H-X) equals the time between a first zero crossing tzc(n- X)] and the second zero crossing t<sub>zc</sub>(n-X)<sub>2</sub> of the (<sup>η</sup>-Χ)<sup>Ώ</sup> cycle of the rectified input voltage VOR IN. Thus, in at least one embodiment, in operation 602, the trailing edge high resistance state predictor 412 detects the time between approximate zero crossings tzc(n-X)i and tzc(n-X)<sub>2</sub> of each cycle of the phase cut, rectified voltage Vo R to determine the active periods T<sub>A</sub>(n-X) of the phase cut, rectified voltage Vcp_R for X ranging from 1 to N. </p><p id="p0040" num="0040">[0034] In operation 603, the trailing edge high resistance state predictor 412 predicts an estimated active period TA(II)EST of nth cycle of the phase cut, rectified voltage Vtt&gt;_R. The particular algorithm for predicting the estimated active period TA(II)EST is a matter of design choice. In at least one embodiment, the trailing edge high resistance state predictor 412 assumes that the estimated active period T<sub>A</sub>(n)<sub>EST</sub> is equal to the previous actual measured active period ΤΑ(Π- 1). In at least one embodiment, the trailing edge high resistance state predictor 412 utilizes an algorithm that reflects a trend of the durations of the active periods ΤΑ(Π-Χ) for the previous N cycles of the phase cut, rectified voltage V O_R. For example, in at least one embodiment, N equals 2, and the trailing edge high resistance state predictor 412 determines a trend in the durations of the active periods using Equation [2] to predict the estimated η<sup>ώ</sup> active period TA(II)EST: </p><p id="p0041" num="0041">T<sub>A</sub>(n)<sub>E</sub>ST = T<sub>A</sub>(n-l) + T<sub>A</sub>(n-l)-T<sub>A</sub>(n-2) = 2·Τ<sub>Α</sub>(<sup>η</sup>- 1) - T<sub>A</sub>(n-2) [2] . </p><p id="p0042" num="0042">In Equation [2], TAMEST represents the predicted active time period for the <sup>ηώ</sup> cycle, T<sub>A</sub>(n-l) represents an approximate actual time period for the previous (n-1) cycle, and T<sub>A</sub>(n-2) represents an approximate actual measured time period for the previous (n-2) cycle. As discussed in more detail in conjunction with Figure 8, the trailing edge high resistance state predictor 412 detects 
<!-- EPO <DP n="11"/>-->
 approximate actual zero crossings of each active cycle of the phase cut, rectified voltage Vo R. From the detection of the actual zero crossings, in at least one embodiment, the trailing edge high resistance state predictor 412 determines an approximate actual active time period ΤΑ(Π). The determined, approximate actual time period TA I) becomes the approximate actual time period ΤΑ(Π-1) used in Equation [2] when estimating the active time period for the next cycle of phase cut, rectified voltage Vo R and becomes the approximate actual time period ΤΑ(Π-2) used in Equation [2] when estimating the active time period for the cycle of phase cut, rectified voltage Vo R after the next cycle. </p><p id="p0043" num="0043">[0035] In at least one embodiment, the trailing edge high resistance state predictor 412 segregates the odd and even cycles of the phase cut, rectified voltage VO_R because the odd and even cycles correlate better with each other. When segregating the odd and even cycles, the trailing edge high resistance state predictor 412 determines the trend in the durations of the even active periods using Equation [3] to predict the estimated η<sup>ώ</sup> active period TA(II)EST: </p><p id="p0044" num="0044">T<sub>A</sub>(n)<sub>ES</sub>T = T<sub>A</sub>(n-2) + T<sub>A</sub>(n-2)-T<sub>A</sub>(n-4) = 2-T<sub>A</sub>(n-2) - T<sub>A</sub>(n-4) [3], </p><p id="p0045" num="0045">When segregating the odd and even cycles, the trailing edge high resistance state predictor 412 determines the trend in the durations of the odd active periods using Equation [4] to predict the estimated n+1 active period T<sub>A</sub>(n)<sub>EST</sub>: </p><p id="p0046" num="0046">T<sub>A</sub>(n+l)<sub>ES</sub>T = T<sub>A</sub>(n-l) + T<sub>A</sub>(n-l)-T<sub>A</sub>(n-3) = 2·Τ<sub>Α</sub>(<sup>η</sup>-1) - T<sub>A</sub>(n-3) [4]. </p><p id="p0047" num="0047"> [0036] In operation 604, the trailing edge high resistance state predictor 412 detects the first, approximate zero crossing tzc(n)i of the present η<sup>Λ</sup> cycle of the phase cut, rectified voltage Vo R. From a known first zero crossing time tzc(n)i of the η<sup>ώ</sup> cycle and the predicted, estimated zero crossing time period T<sub>A</sub>(n)<sub>E</sub>sT, the trailing edge high resistance state predictor 412 predicts when the second zero crossing time t<sub>Z</sub>c(n)<sub>2</sub> will occur. </p><p id="p0048" num="0048">[0037] In operation 606, the trailing edge high resistance state predictor 412 predicts an estimated occurrence of a high resistance state of the trailing edge dimmer 404 based on the duration of n prior cycles of the phase cut, rectified voltage V&lt;D R and detection of first, approximate zero crossing tzc(n)i of the present η<sup>Λ</sup> cycle. In at least one embodiment, the trailing edge high resistance state predictor 412 determines a predicted, estimated occurrence of the high resistance state of the trailing edge dimmer 404 for the η<sup>Λ</sup> cycle by assuming that the 
<!-- EPO <DP n="12"/>-->
 occurrence of the high resistance state of the trailing edge dimmer 404 equals the predicted second zero crossing tzc(n)<sub>2</sub> of the η<sup>Λ</sup> cycle less an estimated decay time T<sub>D</sub>c(n) of the trailing edge 502 of the phase cut, rectified voltage Vo R for the η<sup>ώ</sup> cycle. </p><p id="p0049" num="0049">[0038] The method of obtaining the estimated decay time T<sub>D</sub>c(n) is a matter of design choice. In at least one embodiment, the trailing edge high resistance state predictor 412 utilizes a pre-stored estimated decay time Toc(n), such as 180 μββϋ, based on a worst case value of a capacitor, such as capacitor 114 (Figure 1), of the trailing edge dimmer 404 and an amount of current IDIM controlled by the current control module 416. In other embodiments, the trailing edge high resistance state predictor 412 utilizes any of a number of algorithms to determine the estimated decay time TDC(II) of the phase cut, rectified voltage Vo R. For example, in at least one embodiment, estimated decay times are stored in a look-up table (not shown) for various capacitance values of the trailing edge dimmer 404 and the phase cut angles of phase cut, rectified voltage Vo R and accessed by the trailing edge high resistance state predictor 412. In at least one embodiment, a value of the capacitance of the trailing edge dimmer 404 is stored in an optional memory 417 of the trailing edge high resistance state predictor 412. In at least one embodiment, the trailing edge high resistance state predictor 412 measures or determines the decay time T<sub>D</sub>c(n-l) for the previous (η-1)<sup>Λ</sup> cycle of the phase cut, rectified voltage Vo R and utilizes the decay time T<sub>D</sub>c(n-l) from the previous (η-1)<sup>ώ</sup> cycle as the decay time T<sub>D</sub>c(n) for the present η<sup>Λ</sup> cycle of the phase cut, rectified voltage Vo R. In at least one embodiment, the decay times for the light source 410 at particular phase cut angles are empirically determined in a laboratory setting using actual dimmers and actual light sources, such as LEDs and/or CFLs. The decay times of the phase cut, rectified voltage Vo R are then stored in an optional nonvolatile memory 417 via a terminal 419 of the controller 402 and utilized by the trailing edge high resistance state predictor 412 to predict the estimated occurrence of a high resistance state of the trailing edge dimmer 404. </p><p id="p0050" num="0050">[0039] In at least one embodiment, the operation 606 takes into consideration that the phase angle of the phase cut, rectified voltage VO R can decrease from cycle-to-cycle as a dimming level is decreased. To compensate for a potential decrease in the phase angle, the trailing edge high resistance state predictor 412 subtracts a dynamic dimming level compensation time TDDLC from the second zero crossing time tzc(n)2 to obtain a predicted occurrence of the high resistance 
<!-- EPO <DP n="13"/>-->
 state of the dimmer at time t<sub>H</sub>R(n). The value of the dynamic dimming level compensation time tDDLC is a matter of design choice, and, in at least one embodiment, represents the largest possible change between the predicted estimates of the active periods TA(A)EST <sup>an</sup>d tA(n-l) EST- In at least one embodiment, the dynamic dimming level compensation time tDDLC is 1 0 μβεα Thus, in at least one embodiment, the predicted occurrence of the high resistance state of the dimmer t<sub>H</sub>R(n) equals t c(n)2 - (TDC - TDDLC)- In at least one embodiment, the dynamic dimming level compensation time tDDLC is a percentage, such as 50-75%, of the decay time T<sub>D</sub>c(n). The trailing edge high resistance state predictor 412 provides the HRSTATE PREDICTION signal to the current control module 416 to indicate the predicted occurrence of the high resistance state of the dimmer t<sub>H</sub>R(n). </p><p id="p0051" num="0051">[0040] In operation 608, at the predicted occurrence of the dimmer high resistance state t<sub>H</sub>R(n), the trailing edge high resistance state predictor 412 increases an amount of dimmer current IDIM transferred to the power converter 406 through the trailing edge dimmer 404. The increase in the dimmer current IDIM decreases the decay time TDC and, thus, accelerates transition of the trailing edge of the η<sup>Λ</sup> cycle of the phase cut, rectified voltage Vo R to a predetermined threshold voltage value. In at least one embodiment, the predetermined voltage threshold is in the range between 0 and 65V. In the exemplary depiction of the current IR, which is a rectified version of the dimmer current I<sub>D</sub>IM, the current i<sub>R</sub> tracks the phase cut, rectified voltage Y&lt;p R until the predicted occurrence of the dimmer high resistance state t<sub>H</sub>R(n). At the predicted occurrence of the dimmer high resistance state ΐΗ¾(η), the current control module 416 increases the current IR transferred through the trailing edge dimmer 404 to the power converter 406 to a trailing accelerator current value IR ACCEL than normal operation. </p><p id="p0052" num="0052">[0041] The particular value of the trailing accelerator current value IR ACCEL is a matter of design choice. Increasing the trailing accelerator current value IR ACCEL decreases the decay time T<sub>DC</sub> and increases the dimming range of the lighting system 400. Decreasing the trailing accelerator current value IR ACCEL increases the decay time T<sub>D</sub>c and decreases the dimming range of the lighting system 400. The dimming range of the lighting system 400 is increased because the range of phase cut angles, which correlate to dimming levels, is increased while still assuring that the phase cut, rectified voltage V&lt;p R reaches a zero crossing prior to the next zero crossing. However, increasing the value of the trailing accelerator current value IR ACCEL also potentially 
<!-- EPO <DP n="14"/>-->
 increases the amount of power to be dissipated by the power converter 406. Furthermore, increasing the value of the trailing accelerator current value IR ACCEL can result in the power converter 406 having higher current rated and, thus, more expensive components. </p><p id="p0053" num="0053">[0042] In at least one embodiment, the current control module 416 dynamically adjusts the value of the trailing accelerator current value 1 ACCEL to ensure operation in discontinuous current mode (DCM) while minimizing power dissipation. In at least one embodiment, the controller 402 can switch between operation in DCM, continuous conduction mode (CCM), and/or critical conduction mode (CRM) to allow the current control module 416 flexibility in selecting the value of the trailing accelerator current value 1R ACCEL- DCM is when the phase cut, rectified voltage V&lt;D_R reaches a second zero crossing t<sub>Z</sub>c(n-X)2 prior to the first zero crossing t<sub>Z</sub>c(n-X+l)i of the next cycle of the phase cut, rectified voltage Vcp_R. CCM is when the phase cut, rectified voltage V&lt;j&gt;_R does not reach a second zero crossing tzc(n-X)<sub>2</sub> prior to the first zero crossing tzc(n-X+l)i of the next cycle of the phase cut, rectified voltage Vo R. CRM is when the second zero crossing t<sub>Z</sub>c(n-X)<sub>2</sub> is the same as the first zero crossing ta^n-X+l^ of the next cycle of the phase cut, rectified voltage R. </p><p id="p0054" num="0054">[0043] In at least one embodiment, the trailing accelerator current value 1R ACCEL is 100-500% higher than the peak normal operational value of the current i<sub>R</sub>. In at least one embodiment, the normal operational current peaks at approximately 100 mA, and the trailing edge accelerator current value 1R ACCEL is approximately 500 mA. In at least one embodiment, the power converter 406 includes one or more optional power dissipation circuits 418 to transfer the additional current i<sub>R</sub> and dissipate power associated with the additional current i<sub>R</sub>. Exemplary power dissipation circuits are described in (i) U.S. Patent Application No. 13/289,845, filed November 4, 201 1 , entitled "Controlled Power Dissipation in a Switch Path in a Lighting System", and inventors John L. Melanson and Eric J. King, (ii) U.S. Patent Application No. 13/289,931 , filed November 4, 201 1 , entitled "Controlled Power Dissipation in a Lighting System", and inventors John L. Melanson and Eric J. King, and (iii) 13/289,967 filed November 4, 2011, entitled "Controlled Power Dissipation in a Link Path in a Lighting System", and inventors John L. Melanson and Eric J. King. </p><p id="p0055" num="0055">[0044] In at least one embodiment, because the voltage supply 104 is able to provide an amount of current that greatly exceeds the trailing accelerator current value 1 ACCEL, if the dimming level 
<!-- EPO <DP n="15"/>-->
 and, thus, the phase angle of the phase cut, rectified voltage V&lt;P_R increases rather than decreases, the trailing accelerator current value IR ACCEL will not distort the phase cut, rectified voltage Ύ κ waveform. </p><p id="p0056" num="0056">[0045] In at least one embodiment, at each second zero crossing tzc(n-X)2, the current control module 416 transfers current I through the dimmer 404 so that the power converter 406 enters a low impedance state. In at least one embodiment, the current in the low impedance state is referred to as a glue current and is, for example, generally described in U.S. Patent Application. No. 12/858,164, filed August 17, 2010, entitled: "Dimmer Output Emulation", and inventor: John L. Melanson (referred to herein as "Melanson I") and U.S. Patent Application No. </p><p id="p0057" num="0057">13/217,174, filed August 24, 2011, entitled: "Multi-Mode Dimmer Interfacing Including Attach State Control", and inventors: Eric J. King and John L. Melanson, which are both incorporated by reference in their entireties. </p><p id="p0058" num="0058">[0046] The particular implementation of the trailing edge high resistance state predictor 412 is a matter of design choice. The trailing edge high resistance state predictor 412 can be </p><p id="p0059" num="0059">implemented using analog, digital, or analog and digital circuits and can be implemented using discrete components. In at least one embodiment, the controller 402 is an integrated circuit, and the trailing edge high resistance state predictor 412 and current control module 416 are implemented as part of the integrated circuit. In at least one embodiment, the controller 402 includes a processor (not shown) and a memory (not shown) to store and execute code that implements one or more embodiments of the exemplary trailing edge compatibility operational flow chart 600. </p><p id="p0060" num="0060">[0047] Figure 7 depicts a lighting system 700, which is one embodiment of the lighting system 400. The lighting system 700 includes controller 702, which includes the trailing edge dimmer high resistance state predictor 412. The trailing edge dimmer high resistance state predictor 412 generates the HRSTATE PREDICTION signal and provides the HRSTATE PREDICTION signal to the current control module 704 to indicate the predicted occurrence of the high resistance state of the dimmer t<sub>H</sub>R(n) as previously described with reference to lighting system 400. The current control module 704 controls the boost-type switching power converter 706 using the same current and voltage profiles as discussed with reference to lighting system 400 and as depicted in the exemplary voltage and current waveforms 500 (Figure 5). The switching 
<!-- EPO <DP n="16"/>-->
 power converter 706 includes a boost switch 707, and the current control module 704 controls power factor correction and regulates the link voltage VLINK across link capacitor 708 as, for example, described in U.S. Patent Application No. 11/967,269, entitled "Power Control System Using a Nonlinear Delta-Sigma Modulator With Nonlinear Power Conversion Process </p><p id="p0061" num="0061">Modeling", filed on December 31, 2007, inventor John L. Melanson (referred to herein as "Melanson I"), U.S. Patent Application No. 11/967,275, entitled "Programmable Power Control System", filed on December 31, 2007, and inventor John L. Melanson (referred to herein as "Melanson Π"), U.S. Patent Application No. 12/495,457, entitled "Cascode Configured </p><p id="p0062" num="0062">Switching Using at Least One Low Breakdown Voltage Internal, Integrated Circuit Switch to Control At Least One High Breakdown Voltage External Switch", filed on June 30, 2009 ("referred to herein as "Melanson III"), and inventor John L. Melanson, and U.S. Patent Application No. 12/174,404, entitled "Constant Current Controller With Selectable Gain", filing date June 30, 2011, and inventors John L. Melanson, Rahul Singh, and Siddharth Maru, which are all incorporated by reference in their entireties. </p><p id="p0063" num="0063">[0048] The switching power converter includes capacitor 710, which filters high frequency components from rectified voltage VcpR _<sub>w</sub>. Gate bias voltage VG biases the gate of switch 707. The particular value of the gate bias voltage VQ is a matter of design choice and, for example, depends on the operational parameters of the switch 707. In at least one embodiment, the gate bias voltage VQ is +12V. To control the operation of switching power converter 108, controller 110 generates a control signal CSi to control conductivity of field effect transistor (FET) switch 707. The control signal CSi is a pulse width modulated signal. Each pulse of control signal CSi turns switch 707 ON (i.e. conducts), and the inductor current IR increases to charge inductor 712. Diode 714 prevents current flow from link capacitor 708 into switch 707. When the pulse ends, the inductor 712 reverses voltage polarity (commonly referred to as "flyback"), and the inductor current i<sub>R</sub> decreases during the flyback phase. The inductor current i<sub>R</sub> boosts the link voltage across the link capacitor 708 through diode 714. The switching power converter 706 is a boost- type converter, and, thus, the link voltage VLINK is greater than the phase cut, rectified voltage Vo R. The load with electronic light source 716 includes, for example, a transformer-based interface circuit to provide power to the electronic light sources. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="17"/>-->
 [0049] Figure 8 depicts one embodiment of a zero crossing and active time detector 800, which is used in one embodiment of the trailing edge high resistance state predictor 412 (Figure 4) to detect the approximate values of zero crossings tzc(n)i and tzc(n)<sub>2</sub> of the phase cut, rectified voltage V&lt;D_R. The zero crossing detector 800 includes a comparator 802 to compare the phase cut, rectified voltage Vq&gt;_R and a phase cut, rectified voltage Vq&gt;_R threshold value. The phase cut, rectified voltage V&lt;J&gt;_R threshold value is, for example, in the range of 0- 15V. When the comparator 802 detects that the phase cut, rectified voltage VO R has transitioned to become greater than the phase cut, rectified voltage Vcp R threshold, the ZC DETECT output signal of the comparator 802 indicates the transition by changing from a logical 1 to a logical 0. The transition indicates detection of the first zero crossing tzc(n)i. Then, the timer 804 begins counting at a frequency much greater than the frequency of phase cut, rectified voltage V&lt;J&gt;_R. For example, in at least one embodiment, the timer 804 counts at a frequency of 10 kHz or greater. When the comparator 802 detects that the phase cut, rectified voltage V&lt;P_R is less than the phase cut, rectified voltage Y$ <sub>R</sub> threshold, the ZC DETECT output signal of the comparator 802 indicates the detection by changing from a logical 0 to a logical 1. The transition from logical 0 to logical 1 of the ZC DETECT output signal indicates detection of the second zero crossing tzc(n)<sub>2</sub>. The timer 804 then indicates the time between the detection of the two zero crossings, which is the approximate actual active time ΤΑ(Π). </p><p id="p0064" num="0064">[0050] Figure 9 depicts a current control module 900, which represents one embodiment of a current control module 704. The current control module 900 includes a controllable current source 902. The current source 902 includes FETs 904 and 906, which are configured as a current mirror. Referring to Figures 7 and 9, in at least one embodiment, the controller 908 modulates the control signal CSi to control current through switch 707 to control power factor correction and regulate the link voltage VLINK of the switching power converter 706, generate the trailing accelerator current value IR ACCEL, generate the low impedance state of the switching power converter 706, and dissipate excess power, as previously described. </p><p id="p0065" num="0065">[0051 ] Current source 902 supplies a reference current IREF, which flows through FET 906. In at least one embodiment, control signal CSi turns boost switch 707 ON. The size of FET 904 is scaled to the size of FET 906 by a scaling factor of Z. The value of the scaling factor Z is a positive number and a matter of design choice. The value of the scaling factor Z times the value 
<!-- EPO <DP n="18"/>-->
 of the reference current i<sub>REF</sub> sets the trailing accelerator current value IR ACCEL- Thus, when the trailing edge high resistance state predictor 412 predicts the occurrence of the high resistance state of the dimmer tnR(n), the controller 908 causes the controllable current source 902 to transfer the trailing accelerator current value IR ACCEL to the switching power converter 706. </p><p id="p0066" num="0066">[0052] Thus, an electronic system includes a controller, and the controller provides compatibility between an electronic light source and a trailing edge dimmer. In at least one embodiment, the controller is capable of predicting an estimated occurrence of a trailing edge of a phase cut AC voltage and accelerating a transition of the phase cut AC voltage from the trailing edge to a predetermined voltage threshold. </p><p id="p0067" num="0067">[0053] Although embodiments have been described in detail, it should be understood that various changes, substitutions, and alterations can be made hereto without departing from the spirit and scope of the invention as defined by the appended claims. 
</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM45193524" ref-ucid="WO-2012128794-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><claim id="clm-0001" num="1"><!-- EPO <DP n="19"/>--><claim-text/><claim-text>WHAT IS CLAIMED IS: 1. An apparatus comprising: a controller to provide compatibility between a lamp and a trailing edge dimmer, wherein the controller is capable to: predict an estimated occurrence of a high resistance state of the trailing edge dimmer, wherein the high resistance state occurs when the trailing edge dimmer begins phase cutting an alternating current (AC) voltage signal; operate in a high current mode based on the estimated predicted occurrence of the high resistance state of the trailing edge dimmer; and operate in a low impedance mode after the AC voltage signal reaches a low </claim-text><claim-text> voltage threshold. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0002" num="2"><claim-text>2. The apparatus of claim 1 wherein the controller is further capable to operate in the low impedance mode until a next approximate zero crossing of the AC voltage signal following the phase cutting of the AC voltage signal. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0003" num="3"><claim-text>3. The apparatus of claim 1 wherein the controller is capable to operate in the high current mode prior to when the trailing edge dimmer begins phase cutting an alternating current (AC) voltage signal. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0004" num="4"><claim-text>4. The apparatus of claim 3 wherein the controller is capable to operate in the high current mode within 0.1 milliseconds prior to when the trailing edge dimmer begins phase cutting an alternating current (AC) voltage signal. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0005" num="5"><claim-text>5. The apparatus of claim 1 wherein the controller is capable to operate in the high current mode prior to the estimated predicted occurrence of the high resistance state of the trailing edge dimmer. <!-- EPO <DP n="20"/>--> </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0006" num="6"><claim-text>6. The apparatus of claim 1 wherein the controller is capable to predict the estimated occurrence of a high resistance state of the trailing edge dimmer in a present cycle of the AC voltage signal based on a trend of actual occurrences of the high resistance state in N </claim-text><claim-text>immediately prior cycles of the AC voltage signal, wherein N is an integer greater than or equal to 2. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0007" num="7"><claim-text>7. The apparatus of claim 1 wherein the controller is further capable to predict the estimated occurrence of a high resistance state of the trailing edge dimmer based on a profile of the voltage signal for N prior cycles of the voltage signal that occurred prior to a present cycle, wherein N is an integer greater than or equal to 1. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0008" num="8"><claim-text>8. The apparatus of claim 7 wherein the profile is a profile of current drawn by the lamp. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0009" num="9"><claim-text>9. The apparatus of claim 7 wherein the profile is a voltage profile of the lamp. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0010" num="10"><claim-text>10. The apparatus of claim 9 wherein the voltage profile is determined based on a change of the voltage over time of the AC voltage signal. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0011" num="11"><claim-text>11. The apparatus of claim 1 wherein the AC voltage signal is rectified AC voltage derived from a phase cut AC input supply voltage. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0012" num="12"><claim-text>12. The apparatus of claim 1 wherein the controller is capable to control the power converter, wherein the power converter is coupled between the trailing edge dimmer and one or more electronic light sources included in the lamp. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0013" num="13"><claim-text>13. The apparatus of claim 1 wherein the lamp comprises a member of a group consisting of: one or more light emitting diodes, one or more compact fluorescent bulbs, and one or more light emitting diodes and one or more compact fluorescent bulbs. <!-- EPO <DP n="21"/>--> </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0014" num="14"><claim-text>14. A method to provide compatibility between a lamp and a trailing edge dimmer, the method comprising: predicting an estimated occurrence of a high resistance state of the trailing edge dimmer, wherein the high resistance state occurs when the trailing edge dimmer begins phase cutting an alternating current (AC) voltage signal; operating a controller of at least a power converter in a high current mode based on the estimated predicted occurrence of the high resistance state of the trailing edge dimmer; and operating the controller in a low impedance mode after the AC voltage signal reaches a low voltage threshold. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0015" num="15"><claim-text>15. The method of claim 14 further comprising: operating the controller in the low impedance mode until a next approximate zero </claim-text><claim-text> crossing of the AC voltage signal following the phase cutting of the AC voltage signal. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0016" num="16"><claim-text>16. The method of claim 14 further comprising: operating the controller in the high current mode prior to when the trailing edge dimmer begins phase cutting an alternating current (AC) voltage signal. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0017" num="17"><claim-text>17. The method of claim 16 further comprising: operating the controller in the high current mode within 0.1 milliseconds prior to when the trailing edge dimmer begins phase cutting an alternating current (AC) voltage signal. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0018" num="18"><claim-text>18. The method of claim 14 further comprising: operating the controller in the high current mode prior to the estimated predicted </claim-text><claim-text> occurrence of the high resistance state of the trailing edge dimmer. <!-- EPO <DP n="22"/>--> </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0019" num="19"><claim-text>19. The method of claim 14 further comprising: predicting the estimated occurrence of a high resistance state of the trailing edge dimmer in a present cycle of the AC voltage signal based on a trend of actual occurrences of the high resistance state in N immediately prior cycles of the AC voltage signal, wherein N is an integer greater than or equal to 2. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0020" num="20"><claim-text>20. The method of claim 14 further comprising: predicting the occurrence of the phase-cut, trailing edge of the alternating current (AC) voltage signal based on a profile of the voltage signal for N prior cycles of the voltage signal that occurred prior to a present cycle, wherein N is an integer greater than or equal to 1. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0021" num="21"><claim-text>21. The method of claim 20 wherein the profile is a profile of current drawn by the lamp. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0022" num="22"><claim-text>22. The method of claim 20 wherein the profile is a voltage profile of the lamp. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0023" num="23"><claim-text>23. The method of claim 22 further comprising: determining the voltage profile based on a change of the voltage over time of the AC voltage signal. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0024" num="24"><claim-text>24. The method of claim 14 wherein the AC voltage signal is rectified AC voltage derived from a phase cut AC input supply voltage. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0025" num="25"><claim-text>25. The method of claim 14 further comprising: controlling the power converter, wherein the power converter is coupled between the trailing edge dimmer and one or more electronic light sources included in the lamp. <!-- EPO <DP n="23"/>--> </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0026" num="26"><claim-text>26. The method of claim 14 wherein the lamp comprises a member of a group consisting of: one or more light emitting diodes, one or more compact fluorescent bulbs, and one or more light emitting diodes and one or more compact fluorescent bulbs. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0027" num="27"><claim-text>27. An apparatus comprising: a controller capable to: predict an estimated occurrence of a high resistance state of a trailing edge </claim-text><claim-text> dimmer, wherein the high resistance state occurs when the trailing edge dimmer begins phase cutting an alternating current (AC) voltage signal of a phase cut AC voltage; and accelerate a transition of the AC voltage from the trailing edge to a predetermined voltage threshold. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0028" num="28"><claim-text>28. The apparatus of claim 27 wherein the controller is further capable to: operate in a high current mode based on the estimated predicted occurrence of the high resistance state of the trailing edge dimmer to accelerate the transition of the AC voltage from the trailing edge to the predetermined voltage threshold; and operate in a low impedance mode after the AC voltage signal reaches a low voltage threshold. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0029" num="29"><claim-text>29. The apparatus of claim 27 wherein the controller is capable to predict the estimated occurrence of a high resistance state of the trailing edge dimmer in a present cycle of the AC voltage signal based on a trend of actual occurrences of the high resistance state in N immediately prior cycles of the AC voltage signal, wherein N is an integer greater than or equal to 2. <!-- EPO <DP n="24"/>--> </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0030" num="30"><claim-text>30. The apparatus of claim 27 wherein the controller is further capable to predict the estimated occurrence of a high resistance state of the trailing edge dimmer based on active voltage periods of the voltage signal for N prior cycles of the voltage signal that occurred prior to a present cycle, wherein Nis an integer greater than or equal to 1. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0031" num="31"><claim-text>31. The apparatus of claim 27 wherein the AC voltage signal is rectified AC voltage derived from a phase cut AC input supply voltage. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0032" num="32"><claim-text>32. The apparatus of claim 27 wherein the controller is capable to control a power converter, wherein the power converter is coupled between the trailing edge dimmer and one or more electronic light sources included in the lamp. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0033" num="33"><claim-text>33. The apparatus of claim 27 wherein the lamp comprises a member of a group consisting of: one or more light emitting diodes, one or more compact fluorescent bulbs, and one or more light emitting diodes and one or more compact fluorescent bulbs. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0034" num="34"><claim-text>34. A method comprising: predicting an estimated occurrence of a high resistance state of a trailing edge dimmer, wherein the high resistance state occurs when the trailing edge dimmer begins phase cutting an alternating current (AC) voltage signal of a phase cut AC voltage; and accelerating a transition of the AC voltage from the trailing edge to a predetermined voltage threshold. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0035" num="35"><claim-text>35. The method of claim 34 further comprising: operating a controller of at least a power converter in a high current mode based on the estimated predicted occurrence of the high resistance state of the trailing edge dimmer to accelerate the transition of the AC voltage from the trailing edge to the predetermined voltage threshold; and <!-- EPO <DP n="25"/>--> operating the controller in a low impedance mode after the AC voltage signal reaches a low voltage threshold. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0036" num="36"><claim-text>36. The method of claim 34 further comprising: predicting the estimated occurrence of a high resistance state of the trailing edge dimmer in a present cycle of the AC voltage signal based on a trend of actual occurrences of the high resistance state in N immediately prior cycles of the AC voltage signal, wherein N is an integer greater than or equal to 2. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0037" num="37"><claim-text>37. The method of claim 34 further comprising: predicting the estimated occurrence of a high resistance state of the trailing edge dimmer based on active voltage periods of the voltage signal for N prior cycles of the voltage signal that occurred prior to a present cycle, wherein N is an integer greater than or equal to 1. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0038" num="38"><claim-text>38. The method of claim 34 wherein the AC voltage signal is rectified AC voltage derived from a phase cut AC input supply voltage. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0039" num="39"><claim-text>39. The method of claim 34 further comprising: controlling the power converter, wherein the power converter is coupled between the trailing edge dimmer and one or more electronic light sources included in the lamp. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0040" num="40"><claim-text>40. The method of claim 34 wherein the lamp comprises a member of a group consisting of: one or more light emitting diodes, one or more compact fluorescent bulbs, and one or more light emitting diodes and one or more compact fluorescent bulbs. </claim-text></claim></claims><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
