<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2679313-A2" country="EP" doc-number="2679313" kind="A2" date="20140101" family-id="49118282" file-reference-id="314271" date-produced="20180823" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146550213" ucid="EP-2679313-A2"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2679313</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-13163420-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154824136" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>13163420</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20130411</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP174952990" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>13163420.6</doc-number><date>20130411</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140454081" ucid="US-201213444126-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>201213444126</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120411</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-2092287164" load-source="docdb">B05C   5/02        20060101AFI20150129BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-2092287384" load-source="docdb">A61F  13/15        20060101ALI20150129BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-2092288539" load-source="docdb">A61F  13/49        20060101ALI20150129BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-2092291225" load-source="docdb">B05C   9/06        20060101ALI20150129BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2042533166" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B05C   5/0241      20130101 LI20150703BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2042534389" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61F  13/15593     20130101 FI20150703BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2042539613" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B32B  37/1292      20130101 LI20150703BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2051726569" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61F  13/49017     20130101 LI20150521BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2051731441" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B05C   9/06        20130101 LI20150521BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2107893162" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B05D   1/42        20130101 LI20141127BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132183123" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Verfahren und Vorrichtung zum Auftragen von Leim auf einem elastischen Faden in einem Einweghygieneprodukt</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132183124" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Method and apparatus for applying adhesive on an elastic strand in a personal disposable hygiene product</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132183125" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Procédé et dispositif permettant d'appliquer un adhésif sur un fil élastique dans un produit d'hygiène jetable</invention-title><citations><patent-citations><patcit mxw-id="PCIT377647313" load-source="docdb" ucid="US-201161474129-P" dnum-type="application"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>201161474129</doc-number><kind>P</kind><date>20110411</date></document-id><sources><source name="APP" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT242655421" load-source="docdb" ucid="US-4785996-A"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>4785996</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>19881122</date></document-id><sources><source name="APP" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT242655422" load-source="docdb" ucid="US-4815660-A"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>4815660</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>19890328</date></document-id><sources><source name="APP" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT242655423" load-source="docdb" ucid="US-7152815-B2"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>7152815</doc-number><kind>B2</kind><date>20061226</date></document-id><sources><source name="APP" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT242655424" load-source="docdb" ucid="US-7578882-B2"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>7578882</doc-number><kind>B2</kind><date>20090825</date></document-id><sources><source name="APP" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit></patent-citations></citations></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918140881" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>NORDSON CORP</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918152145" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>NORDSON CORPORATION</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918992169" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Nordson Corporation</last-name><iid>101095944</iid><address><street>28601 Clemens Road</street><city>Westlake, OH 44145</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918152080" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>HARRIS MICHAEL W</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918133049" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>HARRIS, MICHAEL W.</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918992690" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>HARRIS, MICHAEL W.</last-name><address><street>7140 Berry Patch Drive</street><city>Cumming, GA Georgia 30040</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918985880" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Eisenführ, Speiser &amp; Partner</last-name><iid>100060034</iid><address><street>Patentanwälte Rechtsanwälte PartGmbB Postfach 10 60 78</street><city>28060 Bremen</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548900762" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS548903414" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS548900764" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS548910738" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS548891753" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS548823944" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS548903415" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS548900765" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548823945" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS548823946" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS548904841" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS548910739" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS548810157" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548900838" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548823947" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS548900839" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS548903416" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS548891754" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS548823948" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS548810158" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS548823949" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS548910740" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS548854870" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS548910741" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS548910750" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS548854871" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS548854872" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS548904914" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS548810159" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS548854873" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS548891755" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS548904915" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS548891756" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS548854874" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS548900840" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS548810160" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS548854875" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS548823950" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states><ep-extended-states><ep-extended-state-data><country>BA</country></ep-extended-state-data><ep-extended-state-data><country>ME</country></ep-extended-state-data></ep-extended-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA128670880" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p id="pa01" num="0001">A method of dispensing adhesive onto a stretched elastic strand (28) includes applying a first volume of adhesive (30a) onto a first portion (L1) of the elastic strand, applying a second volume of adhesive (30b) onto a second portion (L2) of the elastic strand, and applying a third volume of adhesive (30c) onto a third portion (L3) of the elastic strand. The second volume is less than the first and third volumes. When the elastic strand (28) is adhered to a substrate (18, 26) to form a personal disposable hygiene product, the first and third portions (L1, L3) of the elastic strand (28) define opposing ends of the elastic strand, which are adhered with a larger amount of adhesive to resist creep at the opposing ends. The reduction of adhesive in the second or central portion (L2) between the opposing ends significantly reduces the adhesive add on in the personal disposable hygiene product.
<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="124" he="99" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA128500253" lang="EN" source="EPO" load-source="docdb"><p>A method of dispensing adhesive onto a stretched elastic strand (28) includes applying a first volume of adhesive (30a) onto a first portion (L1) of the elastic strand, applying a second volume of adhesive (30b) onto a second portion (L2) of the elastic strand, and applying a third volume of adhesive (30c) onto a third portion (L3) of the elastic strand. The second volume is less than the first and third volumes. When the elastic strand (28) is adhered to a substrate (18, 26) to form a personal disposable hygiene product, the first and third portions (L1, L3) of the elastic strand (28) define opposing ends of the elastic strand, which are adhered with a larger amount of adhesive to resist creep at the opposing ends. The reduction of adhesive in the second or central portion (L2) between the opposing ends significantly reduces the adhesive add on in the personal disposable hygiene product.</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES63956310" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001"><b><u>Field of the Invention</u></b></heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention generally relates to a method and apparatus for dispensing adhesive and more particularly, to a method and apparatus for dispensing adhesive onto at least one elastic strand during construction of a personal disposable hygiene product.</p><heading id="h0002"><b><u>Background</u></b></heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">Liquid adhesive, such as hot melt adhesive, is applied onto various components during manufacture of disposable personal hygiene products such as diapers, adult incontinence products, and feminine hygiene products. Dispensing methods and systems have been developed for applying hot melt adhesive onto various components of the disposable personal hygiene product. In one example, these dispensing systems apply a hot melt adhesive filament to one or more stretched elastic strands, which are then adhered to a nonwoven substrate to form an elasticized portion of the disposable personal hygiene product. Downstream of the dispensing system, the various components (e.g., flat substrate layers and elastic strands) pass through a pressure nip to secure the components together.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">Many disposable personal hygiene products include elasticized leg gathers adjacent to leg openings to secure the personal hygiene product against the user's legs and to contain any waste material captured by the personal disposable hygiene product. In these applications, a high level of creep resistance is desirable. "Creep" of an elastic strand is defined as the movement of either end of the elastic strand from an initial location where the end is adhered to a substrate. If an elastic strand undergoes any significant amount of creep after assembly, at least one end of the elastic strand will effectively de-bond from the substrate and reduce the ability of the elasticized portion to remain firmly engaged with the skin surface. To avoid this undesirable creep, a high quality bond must be formed by the adhesive applied to the elastic strand so that the elastic strand does not de-bond from the substrate.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">One well understood method of improving the quality of an adhesive bond and thereby reducing creep is by applying additional adhesive<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> on the substrate or the elastic strand(s). However, applying too much adhesive to the elastic strand locks the elastic strand along its length and thereby reduces the effectiveness of the elastic material to apply force to the substrate. In other words, the elastic strand loses the ability to apply sufficient retraction force to the substrate. Moreover, increasing the amount of adhesive used in disposable personal hygiene product manufacturing significantly increases cost and also reduces the "hand" or softness of the resulting product. Applying too much adhesive material may also lead to "burn through," which occurs when the adhesive material burns or melts through the adhered substrate. Consequently, the amount of adhesive used to adhere elastic strands to substrates should be minimized while also maintaining a high level of creep resistance, a high retraction force, and minimized burn through and stiffness.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">However, conventional dispensing methods and systems for coating elastic strands in personal disposable hygiene products utilize a constant volume or coating of adhesive along the entire length of the elastic strand(s). As described above, the coating must be sufficient to prevent creep at the opposing ends of the elastic strand(s), and thus, the constant coating adds significant add on weight to the final personal disposable hygiene product. As described above, any excess adhesive add on is undesirable for multiple reasons, including reduced force retraction capability and softness and increased manufacturing cost.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">There is a need, therefore, for an adhesive dispensing method and apparatus that addresses one or more of these difficulties and reduces the amount of adhesive used to form elasticized portions of personal disposable hygiene products.</p><heading id="h0003"><b><u>Summary of the Invention</u></b></heading><p id="p0007" num="0007">According to one embodiment of the invention, a method of dispensing adhesive onto at least one stretched elastic strand to be adhered to a substrate to form a personal disposable hygiene product includes moving the stretched elastic strand along a machine direction and applying a first volume of adhesive onto a first portion of the elastic strand. The method also includes applying a second volume of adhesive onto a second portion of the elastic strand located downstream from the first portion relative to the machine direction, and applying a third volume of adhesive onto a third portion of the<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> elastic strand located downstream from the second portion relative to the machine direction. The second volume is less than the first volume and less than the third volume. When the elastic strand is adhered to the substrate, the first and third portions define opposing ends of the elastic strand and the second portion defines a central portion of the elastic strand extending between the opposing ends.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">In one aspect, the first and third portions of the elastic strand collectively define a first length and the second portion of the elastic strand defines a second length longer than the first length. Thus, the second volume of adhesive is applied over a majority of the elastic strand. In another aspect,, applying the first, second, and third volumes of adhesive includes dispensing a first quantity of adhesive onto the first and third portions of the elastic strand, and dispensing a second quantity of adhesive onto the first, second, and third portions of the elastic strand. The second quantity defines the second volume of adhesive on the second portion of the elastic strand. The first and second quantities collectively define the first volume of adhesive on the first portion of the elastic strand and the third volume of adhesive on the third portion of the elastic strand. Alternatively, applying the first, second, and third volumes of adhesive includes dispensing a first quantity of adhesive onto the first and third portions of the elastic strand and dispensing a second quantity of adhesive onto the second portion of the elastic strand. In this alternative, the first quantity of adhesive defines the first volume of adhesive on the first portion of the elastic strand and the third volume of adhesive on the third portion of the elastic strand, while the second quantity of adhesive defines the second volume on the second portion of the elastic strand.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">The first and second quantities of adhesive may be dispensed simultaneously onto the first portion and then onto the third portion of the elastic strand, or one of the first and second quantities may be dispensed onto the elastic strand before the other quantity. In one example, the first and second quantities are dispensed by respective first and second dispensing nozzles, which are fed adhesive at first and second predetermined or adjustable flow rates.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">In another aspect, the first, second, and third volumes of adhesive are dispensed by a single dispensing nozzle including first and second valves that control flow from corresponding first and second adhesive supplies. To this<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> end, the first and second valves are opened to apply the first volume of adhesive to the first portion of the elastic strand. Closing the second valve while leaving the first valve open causes the second volume of adhesive to be applied to the second portion of the elastic strand. Opening the first and second valves causes the third volume of adhesive to be applied to the third portion of the elastic strand. In some embodiments with a single dispensing nozzle, adhesive is pumped at an adjustable first flow rate to the first valve and adhesive is pumped at an adjustable second flow rate to the second valve.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">In another embodiment of the invention, a method of dispensing adhesive onto a plurality of stretched elastic strands to be adhered to a substrate to form a personal disposable hygiene product includes moving each of the stretched elastic strands along a machine direction. The method further includes applying a first volume of adhesive onto a first portion of each of the elastic strands, applying a second volume of adhesive onto a second portion of each of the elastic strands located downstream from the first portion, and applying a third volume of adhesive onto a third portion of each of the elastic strands located downstream from the second portion. The second volume is less than the first volume and less than the third volume. When the elastic strand is adhered to the substrate, the first and third portions define opposing ends of the elastic strand and the second portion defines a central portion of the elastic strand extending between the opposing ends. Applying the first, second, and third volumes of adhesive may include dispensing at least one quantity of adhesive individually onto each of the plurality of elastic strands, or dispensing at least one quantity of adhesive collectively onto all of the plurality of elastic strands.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">In another embodiment, a personal disposable hygiene product includes a nonwoven substrate with first and second longitudinal sides. The hygiene product also includes first and second stretched elastic strands adhered to the nonwoven substrate respectively along the first and second longitudinal sides. Each of the elastic strands includes a first portion defining an end of the elastic strand, a second portion defining a central portion of the elastic strand, and a third portion defining another end of the elastic strand. The first portions are coated with a first volume of adhesive, the second portions are coated with a second volume of adhesive, and the third portions<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> are coated with a third volume of adhesive. The second volume of adhesive is less than each of the first and third volumes of adhesive.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">In yet another embodiment of the invention, a dispensing apparatus applies adhesive to at least one stretched elastic strand including first, second, and third portions along a length of the elastic strand that are to be adhered to a substrate to form a personal disposable hygiene product. The apparatus includes a first dispensing nozzle for dispensing a first volume of adhesive onto the stretched elastic strand at the first portion and for dispensing a third volume of adhesive onto the stretched elastic strand at the third portion. The apparatus also includes a second dispensing nozzle for dispensing a second volume of adhesive onto the stretched elastic strand at a second portion extending between the first and third portions. The second volume of adhesive is less than each of the first and third volumes of adhesive.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">In one aspect, the first dispensing nozzle includes a strand guide, while the second dispensing nozzle does not include a strand guide. In one aspect, the dispensing nozzles may include the same type of dispensing nozzle or different types of dispensing nozzles. The dispensing apparatus also includes a first adhesive supply for pumping adhesive to the first dispensing nozzle, a second adhesive supply for pumping adhesive to the second dispensing nozzle, and a control for selectively actuating the first and second adhesive supplies.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">In another embodiment, a dispensing apparatus applies adhesive to at least one stretched elastic strand including first, second, and third portions along a length of the elastic strand that are to be adhered to a substrate to form a personal disposable hygiene product. The apparatus includes a first dispensing nozzle for dispensing a first quantity of adhesive onto the stretched elastic strand at the first and third portions. The apparatus also includes a second dispensing nozzle for dispensing a second quantity of adhesive onto the stretched elastic strand at the first, second, and third portions. The first and second quantities of adhesive collectively define a first volume of adhesive on the first portion of the elastic strand and a third volume of adhesive on the third portion of the elastic strand. The second quantity of adhesive defines a second volume of adhesive on the second portion of the elastic strand that is less than each of the first and third volumes of adhesive.<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></p><p id="p0016" num="0016">In another embodiment of the invention, a dispensing apparatus applies adhesive to at least one stretched elastic strand that is to be adhered to a substrate to form a personal disposable hygiene product. The apparatus includes a single dispensing nozzle for dispensing adhesive onto the stretched elastic strand at first, second, and third portions located in sequence along the length of the elastic strand. The dispensing apparatus also includes a first valve adapted to control flow from a first adhesive supply through the dispensing nozzle and a second valve adapted to control flow from a second adhesive supply through the dispensing nozzle. The first and second valves are opened to apply a first volume of adhesive on the first portion or to apply a third volume of adhesive on the third portion. The first valve is opened while the second valve is closed to apply a second volume of adhesive on the second portion that is less than the first or third volumes of adhesive.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">Various additional features and advantages of the invention will become more apparent to those of ordinary skill in the art upon review of the following detailed description of the illustrative embodiments taken in conjunction with the accompanying drawings.</p><heading id="h0004"><b><u>Brief Description of the Drawings</u></b></heading><p id="p0018" num="0018">The accompanying drawings, which are incorporated in and constitute a part of this specification, illustrate embodiments of the invention and, together with a general description of the invention given above, and the detailed description of the embodiments given below, serve to explain the principles of the invention.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019"><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a partially exploded perspective view of a personal disposable hygiene product according to one embodiment of the current invention.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020"><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> is a schematic side view of a dispensing apparatus for applying adhesive to a plurality of stretched elastic strands according to one embodiment of the current invention.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021"><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 3</figref> is a schematic top view of the dispensing apparatus of <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022"><figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 4</figref> is a schematic top view of another embodiment of a dispensing apparatus for applying adhesive to elastic strands.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p><p id="p0023" num="0023"><figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 5</figref> is a schematic side view of another embodiment of a dispensing apparatus for applying adhesive to elastic strands.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024"><figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 6</figref> is a schematic top view of the dispensing apparatus of <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 5</figref>.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025"><figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 7</figref> is a schematic top view of yet another embodiment of a dispensing apparatus for applying adhesive to elastic strands.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026"><figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 8</figref> is a schematic top view of another embodiment of a dispensing apparatus for applying adhesive to elastic strands.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027"><figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 9</figref> is a schematic top view of yet another embodiment of a dispensing apparatus for applying adhesive to elastic strands.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028"><figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 10</figref> is a schematic top view of yet another embodiment of a dispensing apparatus for applying adhesive to elastic strands.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029"><figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 11</figref> is a schematic top view of another embodiment of a dispensing apparatus for applying adhesive to elastic strands, the dispensing apparatus including two nozzles in parallel.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030"><figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 12A</figref> is a schematic front view of the dispensing apparatus of <figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 11</figref> during a dispensing operation.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031"><figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 12B</figref> is a schematic side view of another embodiment of a dispensing apparatus similar to the dispensing apparatus of <figref idrefs="f0007">FIGS. 11 and 12A</figref>.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032"><figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 13</figref> is a schematic top view of yet another embodiment of a dispensing apparatus for applying adhesive to elastic strands.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033"><figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 14</figref> is a schematic front view of the dispensing apparatus of <figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 13</figref>, showing a first set of valves in phantom.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034"><figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 15</figref> is a schematic front view of the dispensing apparatus of <figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 13</figref>, showing a second set of valves in phantom.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035"><figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 16</figref> is a schematic top view of another embodiment of a dispensing apparatus for applying adhesive to elastic strands.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036"><figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 17</figref> is a schematic top view of yet another embodiment of a dispensing apparatus for applying adhesive to elastic strands.</p><heading id="h0005"><b><u>Detailed Description of the Illustrative Embodiments</u></b></heading><p id="p0037" num="0037"><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> illustrates one embodiment of a disposable personal hygiene product 10 manufactured using an exemplary method and apparatus of the invention. The disposable personal hygiene product 10 is a disposable diaper 10 including first and second ends 12, 14 configured to wrap around the<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> waist of the user and a central portion 16 configured to extend between the legs of the user. The diaper 10 includes a flat nonwoven substrate 18, leg gathers 20 formed along each longitudinal side 22, 24 of the diaper 10 between the first and second ends 12, 14, and a second flat substrate 26 secured to the nonwoven substrate 18 to enclose the leg gathers 20. The second flat substrate 26 is another nonwoven substrate in the illustrated embodiment. The leg gathers 20 are formed by one or more elastic strands 28 that are secured to the nonwoven substrate 18 in a stretched condition so as to provide the diaper 10 with elasticity around the legs of the user. The nonwoven substrate 18, leg gathers 20, and second substrate 26 are secured to each other with hot melt adhesive 30.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">More particularly, each of the elastic strands 28 is advantageously adhered to the nonwoven substrate 18 by a varying amount of hot melt adhesive 30 applied along the length of the elastic strand 28. As described in further detail below, this varying amount of adhesive 30 may be applied by first and second dispensing nozzles in series, wherein the first dispensing nozzle may include a strand guide in some embodiments while the second dispensing nozzle cannot include a strand guide. To this end, each elastic strand 28 includes a first portion 32 adjacent the first end 12, a second portion 34 extending from the first portion 32 and adjacent the central portion 16, and a third portion 36 located adjacent to the second portion 34 and the second end 14. To this end, the first and third portions 32, 36 define opposing ends of the elastic strand 28 when adhered to the nonwoven substrate 18, while the second portion 34 defines a central portion of the elastic strand 28 during adherence. The first portion 32 is coated with a first volume of adhesive 30a, the second portion 34 is coated with a second volume of adhesive 30b, and the third portion 36 is coated with a third volume of adhesive 30c. The second volume of adhesive 30b is less than each of the first and third volumes of adhesive 30a, 30c. As well understood, the elastic strands 28 also include small free ends 38 beyond the first and second end portions 32, 34 that are not coated with adhesive 30 and thus retract or curl up when the remainder of the elastic strands 28 is adhered to the substrate 18. In the preceding and following description, the term "volume" is used as shorthand to describe an average volume of adhesive per unit length over the corresponding strand portion. Thus, the average volume of adhesive per unit length applied to the first and<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> third portions 32, 36 of the elastic strand 28 is higher than the average volume of adhesive per unit length applied to the second portion 34.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">With continued reference to <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, the higher first and second volumes of adhesive 30a, 30c along the first and third portions 32, 36 are schematically shown as a thicker spiral filament while a thinner spiral filament is shown at the second portion 34 to indicate the lessened second volume of adhesive 30b. It will be appreciated that the actual pattern applied to the elastic strands 28 may vary in other embodiments, such as by being applied as a plurality of discrete masses of adhesive that produce discrete bond points when adhering the elastic strands 28 to the nonwoven substrate 18. It will also be understood that while the volume per unit length is described as roughly constant over the entire length of a corresponding strand portion 32, 34, 36 in the exemplary embodiments below, the volume per unit length may vary over the length of one or more of the strand portions 32, 34, 36 without departing from the scope of the invention (i.e., as long as the "volume" or average volume per unit length remains lesser for the second portion 34 than the first and third portions 32, 36). In addition, the adhesive application patterns shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> and the following figures on the elastic strands 28 are schematic artist's renderings of these patterns, as it will be understood that these patterns may vary in appearance significantly in a practical setting.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">Also as shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, the first portion 32 of the elastic strand 28 defines a first length L1, the second portion 34 defines a second length L2, and the third portion 36 defines a third length L3. The second length L2 is larger than the first and third lengths L1, L3 combined so that the second volume of adhesive 30b is applied over a majority of the total length of the elastic strand 28. Thus, the first and third volumes of adhesive 30a, 30c, each of which is high enough to produce a high quality bond with desirable creep resistance, are only applied onto the first and third portions 32, 36 of the elastic strand 28 where such a level of creep resistance is necessary. This higher average volume of adhesive per unit length is not used in the second portion 34 of the elastic strand 28 where creep resistance is less of a concern. Considering that this second portion 34 includes a majority of the elastic strand 28, the total amount of adhesive 30 used to adhere the elastic strand 28 to the substrate 18 is significantly reduced compared to a constant coating over the entire length of the elastic strand 28. Thus, the diaper 10 of this embodiment<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> advantageously minimizes the amount of adhesive add on necessary to produce a high quality bond or construction of the various components of the diaper 10.</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">Turning to <figref idrefs="f0002">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, one embodiment of a dispensing apparatus 40 is shown for producing the disposable personal hygiene product 10 described above. The dispensing apparatus 40 includes a first dispensing nozzle 42 and a second dispensing nozzle 44 arranged in series along a machine direction indicated by arrow 46. The plurality of elastic strands 28 moves along the machine direction 46 past the first dispensing nozzle 42 and then past the second dispensing nozzle 44. The first and second dispensing nozzles 42, 44 operate to dispense hot melt adhesive 30 onto the elastic strands 28 so as to coat the elastic strands 28 with the first, second, and third volumes of adhesive 30a, 30b, 30c as described above. As described in further detail below, the elastic strands 28 run continuously through the dispensing apparatus 40 and are cut into separate elastic strands 28 downstream from the dispensing apparatus 40. To enable this cutting separation, the adjacent free ends 38 of two elastic strands 28 in series are not coated with any adhesive material. Consequently, each of the first and second dispensing nozzles 42, 44 cycles on and off repeatedly during operation of the dispensing apparatus 40.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">In the illustrated embodiment, the first dispensing nozzle 42 is incorporated into a first dispensing module 48 and the second dispensing nozzle 44 is incorporated into a second dispensing module 50 separate from the first dispensing module 48. In this embodiment, the first dispensing module 48 includes a contact nozzle and the second dispensing module includes a non-contact nozzle, each nozzle being configured to apply a filament, bead, coating, or other amount of adhesive (hereinafter referred to as a "quantity") to the elastic strands 28. More specifically, the first dispensing nozzle 42 shown is a contact nozzle as described in <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US61474129A"><text>U.S. Patent Application No. 61/474,129 to Saine, filed April 11, 2011</text></patcit>, which is assigned to the assignee of the current invention and the entire disclosure of which is hereby incorporated by reference herein. The second dispensing nozzle 44 shown is a non-contact swirl nozzle such as the Universal™ CF nozzle commercially available from Nordson Corporation of Westlake, Ohio, which is described in <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="US4785996A"><text>U.S. Patent No. 4,785,996 to Ziecker et al.</text></patcit>, the entire disclosure of which is hereby incorporated by reference herein.<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --></p><p id="p0043" num="0043">It will be understood that other types of non-contact nozzles (e.g., the Signature™ and Summitt™ Mini Swirl nozzles commercially available from Nordson Corporation of Westlake, Ohio) or other types of contact nozzles such as slot coaters may be used in other embodiments within the scope of this invention. Furthermore, even though the first and second dispensing nozzles 42, 44 are illustrated as different types of nozzles in this embodiment, it will be appreciated that the first dispensing nozzle 42 may be the same type of nozzle as the second dispensing nozzle 44 in other embodiments of the invention, assuming both dispensing nozzles 42, 44 are non-contact nozzles. Some of these alternatives are presented in further detail below with reference to <figref idrefs="f0003 f0004 f0005 f0006 f0007">FIGS. 4-12</figref>.</p><p id="p0044" num="0044">With continued reference to <figref idrefs="f0002">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, the first dispensing module 48 receives hot melt adhesive 30 from a first adhesive supply 52 and the second dispensing module 50 receives hot melt adhesive 30 from a second adhesive supply 54. The first and second adhesive supplies 52, 54 operate to pump heated liquid adhesive 30 to the first and second dispensing nozzles 42, 44. In one example, the first adhesive supply 52 includes a first individually adjustable pump 52 for supplying an adjustable flow of adhesive 30 to the first dispensing nozzle 42. The second adhesive supply 54 includes a second individually adjustable pump 54 separate from the first pump 52 for supplying another adjustable flow of adhesive 30 to the second dispensing nozzle 44. Alternatively, the first and second adhesive supplies 52, 54 may be first and second output streams of a common dual stream pump. In these embodiments with a dual stream pump, each adhesive supply 52, 54 delivers a predetermined flow of adhesive to each of the first and second dispensing nozzles 42, 44. Therefore, although the first and second adhesive supplies 52, 54 are illustrated as separate elements in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, it will be understood that the first and second adhesive supplies 52, 54 may be generated from a single dual stream pump or separate pumps without departing from the scope of the invention. Additionally, it will be understood that this and each of the following embodiments of the dispensing apparatus 40 may also include a control 55 for selectively actuating (e.g., turning on and off) the first and second adhesive supplies 52, 54.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045">The operation of the dispensing apparatus 40 is shown schematically in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>. In this regard, the plurality of stretched,<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> uncoated elastic strands 28 passes the first dispensing nozzle 42 while moving along the machine direction 46. The first dispensing nozzle 42 operates to dispense a first quantity 56 of adhesive onto each of the plurality of elastic strands 28. More specifically, a first quantity 56 is dispensed onto the first portion 32 and the third portion 36 of each elastic strand 28. As described in further detail in <patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="US61474129A"><text>U.S. Patent Application No. 61/474,129 to Saine</text></patcit>, the first quantity 56 is a quantity applied by contacting the elastic strand 28 with an extruded adhesive 30 and then blowing air onto the elastic strand 28 to spread the adhesive 30 around the elastic strand 28. As described briefly above, the elastic strands 28 are cut from a continuous elastic line stock downstream of the dispensing apparatus 40, so the first dispensing nozzle 42 cycles on and off to leave gaps with no adhesive 30 at the second portions 34 and at the free ends 38 between applications of adhesive to the first portions 32 and to the third portions 36.</p><p id="p0046" num="0046">In a similar manner, the plurality of elastic strands 28 coated with the first quantity 56 of adhesive then passes the second dispensing nozzle 44 while moving along the machine direction 46. The second dispensing nozzle 44 operates to dispense a second quantity 58 of adhesive onto the plurality of elastic strands 28 at the second portion 34. In this embodiment, the second quantity 58 is a filament forming a swirl pattern extending across all of the elastic strands 28. The second dispensing nozzle 44 is cycled on and off to apply the second quantity 58 onto the second portions 34 of the elastic strands 28, leaving the first and third portions 32, 36 and the free ends 38 substantially uncoated with the second quantity 58.</p><p id="p0047" num="0047">As shown schematically in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref>, the first quantity 56 of adhesive forms the first volume of adhesive 30a on the first portion 32 of each elastic strand 28 as well as the third volume of adhesive 30c on the third portion 36 of each elastic strand 28. The second quantity 58 of adhesive forms the second volume of adhesive 30b on the second portion 34 of each elastic strand 28. In this regard, the dispensing apparatus 40 operates to apply the first volume of adhesive 30a onto the first portion 32, apply the second volume of adhesive 30b onto the second portion 34, and apply the third volume of adhesive 30c onto the third portion 36. As described above, the first and third volumes of adhesive 30a, 30c are sufficient to provide a high quality bond with desirable creep resistance at the first and third portions 32, 36 of the elastic<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> strands 28, while the second volume of adhesive 30b is less than the first or third volumes 30a, 30c of adhesive to advantageously minimize adhesive add on in the disposable personal hygiene product 10.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048">In one example, the first dispensing nozzle 42 is configured to dispense a coating that defines a volume (i.e., an average volume per unit length) of 0.2 g/m or 0.2 mg/mm on each elastic strand 28. The second dispensing nozzle 44 is configured to dispense a coating that defines a volume of 0.1 g/m or 0.1 mg/mm on each elastic strand 28. As a result, the first and third portions 32, 36 are coated with a volume of 0.2 mg/mm, while the second portion 34 is coated with a volume of 0.1 mg/mm. In other words, the first and third volumes of adhesive 30a, 30c are equivalent to 0.2 mg/mm and the second volume of adhesive 30b is equivalent to 0.1 mg/mm. Assuming approximate lengths of L1=L3=50 mm for the first and third portions 32, 36 and L2=300 mm for the second portion 34, the total adhesive add on per elastic strand is 50 mg of adhesive: (0.2 mg/mm)*(50 mm) = 10 mg for each of the first and third portions 32, 36; plus (0.1 mg/mm)*(300 mm) = 30 mg for the second portion 34.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">By contrast, a conventional constant volume coating having the same bond strength at the first and third portions 32, 36 would require a volume of 0.2 mg/mm over the entire 400 mm length of the elastic strand, which equates to 80 mg of adhesive add on per strand. Thus, the dispensing apparatus 40 of the current invention advantageously reduces the adhesive add on by nearly 40% in this example compared to an analogous conventional coating. It will be understood that the relative values of the first, second, and third volumes 30a, 30b, 30c and the relative lengths of the strand portions 32, 34, 36 may be modified in other examples within the scope of the invention to produce adhesive savings of 40%-60% or even more, depending on the application. This level of adhesive reduction significantly reduces the manufacturing cost for each disposable personal hygiene product 10 and increases the hand or softness of the product 10 while maintaining the same high quality bonds as in conventional methods and dispensing apparatuses.</p><p id="p0050" num="0050">The first and second dispensing nozzles 42, 44 are controlled by internal valves (not shown in this embodiment) in the first and second dispensing modules 48, 50, as well understood in the art. These valves are operable to cycle on and off for the required lengths of time to dispense the first<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> and second quantities 56, 58 onto enough continuous elastic strand stock to form 400-1500 products (diapers) per minute. Assuming the same portion lengths as described above with a 25 mm gap defining the free ends 38, the valves would operate as follows for producing 500 products (diapers) per minute. The valve of the first dispensing module 48 would open for about 14 milliseconds to apply adhesive 30 to each first portion 32 and each third portion 36, separated by closed times of about 85 milliseconds for each second portion 34 and about 7 milliseconds for each free end 38 location. The valve of the second dispensing module 50 would open for about 85 milliseconds to apply adhesive 30 to each second portion 34, separated by closed times of about 35 milliseconds for the other portions 32, 36, 38 of the elastic strands 28. It will be understood that the cycling rates of the valves may be modified in other embodiments without departing from the scope of the invention.</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">As described in further detail in <patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="US61474129A"><text>U.S. Patent Application No. 61/474,129 to Saine</text></patcit>, the first dispensing nozzle 42 may be connected to the first dispensing module 48 by a clamping mechanism 60 or a similar device. The first dispensing nozzle 42 defines a strand guide portion 62 for guiding each of the elastic strands 28 past the corresponding air and adhesive outlets (not shown) of the first dispensing nozzle 42. These strand guide portions 62 also align the plurality of strands 28 for passage under the air and adhesive outlets (not shown) of the second dispensing nozzle 44 because the second dispensing nozzle 44 cannot include a strand guide portion (e.g., such a strand guide portion would strip adhesive from the first dispensing nozzle 42 from the elastic strands 28). Further details of each of the first and second dispensing nozzles 42, 44 of this embodiment are described in the corresponding documents incorporated by reference above, and thus no further explanation of structure is provided here. It will be understood that in this and other embodiments described below, the first dispensing nozzle 42 may selectively include a strand guide portion 62, but the second dispensing nozzle 44 will not include a strand guide portion 62, regardless of the type of dispensing nozzles used in those embodiments. Examples of this arrangement are shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIGS. 2</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0003">5</figref>.</p><p id="p0052" num="0052">Although the embodiment of the dispensing apparatus 40 shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIGS. 2 and 3</figref> is an exemplary embodiment of a dispensing apparatus for applying varying volumes of adhesive along the length of elastic strands 28,<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> several modifications to the apparatus are also included within the scope of the current invention. With reference to <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 4</figref>, another embodiment of a dispensing apparatus 140 for applying varying volumes of adhesive along the length of elastic strands 28 in accordance with the invention is shown. Similar to the previous embodiment, the dispensing apparatus 140 shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 4</figref> includes a first dispensing module 148 and a second dispensing module 150 arranged in series along the machine direction 46. The first dispensing module 148 of this embodiment includes a contact nozzle as described in <patcit id="pcit0005" dnum="US61474129A"><text>U.S. Patent Application No. 61/474,129 to Saine</text></patcit>. The second dispensing module 150 of this embodiment includes a non-contact swirl nozzle such as the Summitt™ Mini Swirl nozzle commercially available from Nordson Corporation of Westlake, Ohio, which is described in <patcit id="pcit0006" dnum="US4815660A"><text>U.S. Patent No. 4,815,660</text></patcit> to Boger, the entire disclosure of which is hereby incorporated by reference herein.</p><p id="p0053" num="0053">More particularly, and as described in further detail in <patcit id="pcit0007" dnum="US61474129A"><text>U.S. Patent Application No. 61/474,129 to Saine</text></patcit>, the first dispensing module 148 applies a first quantity 156 of adhesive, which is a quantity applied by contacting the elastic strand 28 with an extruded adhesive 30 and then blowing air onto the elastic strand 28 to spread the adhesive 30 around the elastic strand 28. The second dispensing module 150 applies a second quantity 158 of adhesive, which is a miniature swirled filament of adhesive 30, onto each elastic strand 28 individually. Thus, unlike the previous embodiment, each of the first and second dispensing modules 148, 150 in this embodiment apply adhesive 30 individually onto each elastic strand 28.</p><p id="p0054" num="0054">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 4</figref>, the first and second dispensing modules 148, 150 receive adhesive material from corresponding adhesive supplies 152, 154. Similar to the embodiments described above, the adhesive supplies 152, 154 may include separate individually adjustable pumps for each dispensing module 148, 150 or a shared dual stream pump for both dispensing modules 148, 150. Similar to the previous embodiment, the first dispensing module 148 dispenses the first quantity 156 onto the first and third portions 32, 36 of the elastic strands 28, while the second dispensing module 150 dispenses the second quantity 158 onto the second portions 34 of the elastic strands 28 only. Thus, as shown by the adhesive patterns shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 4</figref>, the first and third portions 32, 36 are coated with first and third volumes of adhesive 30a, 30c that are larger than a second volume of adhesive 30b coating the second portions 34. As with the<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> previously described embodiment, the dispensing apparatus 140 advantageously applies a higher volume of adhesive 30 to the end portions 32, 36 of the elastic strands 28 than to the central portions 34, thereby significantly reducing adhesive use while maintaining similar high bond quality.</p><p id="p0055" num="0055">With reference to <figref idrefs="f0003">FIGS. 5</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0004">6</figref>, another embodiment of a dispensing apparatus 240 for applying varying volumes of adhesive along the length of elastic strands 28 in accordance with the invention is shown. Similar to the previous embodiment, the dispensing apparatus 240 shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIGS. 5</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0004">6</figref> includes a first dispensing module 248 and a second dispensing module 250 arranged in series along the machine direction 46. The first dispensing module 248 of this embodiment includes a first dispensing nozzle 242 that is a SureWrap® nozzle commercially available from Nordson Corporation of Westlake, Ohio, which is described in <patcit id="pcit0008" dnum="US7578882B"><text>U.S. Patent No. 7,578,882 to Harris et al.</text></patcit>, the entire disclosure of which is hereby incorporated by reference herein. The second dispensing module 250 of this embodiment includes a second dispensing nozzle such as the Universal™ CF nozzle commercially available from Nordson Corporation of Westlake, Ohio.</p><p id="p0056" num="0056">More particularly, and as described in further detail in <patcit id="pcit0009" dnum="US7578882B"><text>U.S. Patent No. 7,578,882 to Harris</text></patcit>, the first dispensing nozzle 242 applies a first quantity 256 of adhesive formed by a filament impacted by a plurality of air jets to each elastic strand 28. The elastic strands 28 move faster than the first quantity 256 of adhesive, which causes the quantity 256 to stretch out during application onto the strands 28. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIGS. 5</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0004">6</figref>, this stretching of the first quantity 256 tends to separate or break the adhesive 30 into discrete localized increased masses 74 on the strands 28 that are separated from one another by thinner areas 76 of adhesive 30 running between adjacent masses 74. It will be understood that the thinner areas 76 may also break between adjacent increased masses 74, leaving no adhesive 30 between adjacent masses 74. Each of these discrete masses 74 of adhesive becomes a discrete bond point when the elastic strands 28 are adhered to the substrate 18. The second dispensing nozzle 244 applies a second quantity 258 of adhesive, which is a swirled filament of adhesive 30, onto all of the elastic strands 28 collectively. Thus, unlike the previous embodiment, the first dispensing nozzle 242 applies adhesive individually onto each elastic strand 28, while the second dispensing nozzle 244 applies adhesive collectively onto all of the elastic strands 28.<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></p><p id="p0057" num="0057">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIGS. 5</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0004">6</figref>, the first and second dispensing modules 248, 250 receive adhesive material from corresponding adhesive supplies 252, 254. Similar to the embodiments described above, the adhesive supplies 252, 254 may include separate individually adjustable pumps for each dispensing module 248, 250 or a shared dual stream pump for both dispensing modules 248, 250. Similar to the previous embodiment, the first dispensing nozzle 242 dispenses the first quantity 256 onto the first and third portions 32, 36 of the elastic strands 28, while the second dispensing nozzle 244 dispenses the second quantity 258 onto the second portions 34 of the elastic strands 28 only. Thus, as shown by the adhesive patterns shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIGS. 5</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0004">6</figref>, the first and third portions 32, 36 are coated with first and third volumes of adhesive 30a, 30c that are larger than a second volume of adhesive 30b coating the second portions 34. As with the previously described embodiment, the dispensing apparatus 240 advantageously applies a higher volume of adhesive 30 to the end portions 32, 36 of the elastic strands 28 than to the central portions 34, thereby significantly reducing adhesive use while maintaining similar high bond quality.</p><p id="p0058" num="0058">With reference to <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 7</figref>, yet another embodiment of a dispensing apparatus 340 for applying varying volumes of adhesive along the length of elastic strands 28 in accordance with the invention is shown. Similar to the previous embodiment, the dispensing apparatus 340 shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 7</figref> includes a first dispensing module 348 and a second dispensing module 350 arranged in series along the machine direction 46. The first dispensing module 348 of this embodiment includes a SureWrap® nozzle commercially available from Nordson Corporation of Westlake, Ohio, which is described in <patcit id="pcit0010" dnum="US7578882B"><text>U.S. Patent No. 7,578,882 to Harris et al</text></patcit>. The second dispensing module 350 of this embodiment includes a non-contact swirl nozzle such as the Summitt™ Mini Swirl nozzle commercially available from Nordson Corporation of Westlake, Ohio, which is described in <patcit id="pcit0011" dnum="US4815660A"><text>U.S. Patent No. 4,815,660 to Boger</text></patcit>.</p><p id="p0059" num="0059">More particularly, and as described in further detail in <patcit id="pcit0012" dnum="US7578882B"><text>U.S. Patent No. 7,578,882 to Harris</text></patcit>, the first dispensing module 348 applies a first quantity 356 of adhesive formed by a filament impacted by a plurality of air jets to each elastic strand 28. The elastic strands 28 move faster than the first quantity 356 of adhesive, which causes the first quantity 356 to stretch out during application into discrete localized increased masses 74 on the strands 28 that are<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> separated from one another by thinner (or broken) areas 76 of adhesive 30 running between adjacent masses 74. The second dispensing module 350 applies a second quantity 358 of adhesive, which is a miniature swirled filament of adhesive 30, onto each elastic strand 28 individually. Thus, unlike the previous embodiment, each of the first and second dispensing modules 348, 350 in this embodiment apply adhesive 30 individually onto each elastic strand 28.</p><p id="p0060" num="0060">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 7</figref>, the first and second dispensing modules 348, 350 receive adhesive material from corresponding adhesive supplies 352, 354. Similar to the embodiments described above, the adhesive supplies 352, 354 may include separate individually adjustable pumps for each dispensing module 348, 350 or a shared dual stream pump for both dispensing modules 348, 350. Similar to the previous embodiment, the first dispensing module 348 dispenses the first quantity 356 onto the first and third portions 32, 36 of the elastic strands 28, while the second dispensing module 350 dispenses the second quantity 358 onto the second portions 34 of the elastic strands 28 only. Thus, as shown by the adhesive patterns shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 7</figref>, the first and third portions 32, 36 are coated with first and third volumes of adhesive 30a, 30c that are larger than a second volume of adhesive 30b coating the second portions 34. As with the previously described embodiment, the dispensing apparatus 340 advantageously applies a higher volume of adhesive 30 to the end portions 32, 36 of the elastic strands 28 than to the central portions 34, thereby significantly reducing adhesive use while maintaining similar high bond quality.</p><p id="p0061" num="0061">With reference to <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 8</figref>, another embodiment of a dispensing apparatus 440 for applying varying volumes of adhesive along the length of elastic strands 28 in accordance with the invention is shown. Similar to the previous embodiment, the dispensing apparatus 440 shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 8</figref> includes a first dispensing module 448 and a second dispensing module 450 arranged in series along the machine direction 46. The first dispensing module 448 of this embodiment includes a non-contact swirl nozzle such as the Universal™ CF nozzle commercially available from Nordson Corporation of Westlake, Ohio. The second dispensing module 450 of this embodiment also includes a non-contact swirl nozzle such as the Universal™ CF nozzle commercially available from Nordson Corporation of Westlake, Ohio.<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --></p><p id="p0062" num="0062">More particularly, the first dispensing module 448 applies a first quantity 456 of adhesive which is formed by a filament swirled by air jets onto all of the elastic strands 28 collectively. Similarly, the second dispensing module 450 applies a second quantity 458 of adhesive which is formed by a filament swirled by air jets onto all of the elastic strands 28 collectively. Thus, unlike the previous embodiment, each of the first and second dispensing modules 448, 450 in this embodiment apply adhesive 30 collectively onto all of the elastic strands 28.</p><p id="p0063" num="0063">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 8</figref>, the first and second dispensing modules 448, 450 receive adhesive material from corresponding adhesive supplies 452, 454. Similar to the embodiments described above, the adhesive supplies 452, 454 may include separate individually adjustable pumps for each dispensing module 448, 450 or a shared dual stream pump for both dispensing modules 448, 450. Similar to the previous embodiment, the first dispensing module 448 dispenses the first quantity 456 onto the first and third portions 32, 36 of the elastic strands 28, while the second dispensing module 450 dispenses the second quantity 458 onto the second portions 34 of the elastic strands 28. Thus, as shown by the thicker and thinner adhesive patterns shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 8</figref>, the first and third portions 32, 36 are coated with first and third volumes of adhesive 30a, 30c that are larger than a second volume of adhesive 30b coating the second portions 34. As with the previously described embodiment, the dispensing apparatus 440 advantageously applies a higher volume of adhesive 30 to the end portions 32, 36 of the elastic strands 28 than to the central portions 34, thereby significantly reducing adhesive use while maintaining similar high bond quality.</p><p id="p0064" num="0064">With reference to <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 9</figref>, yet another embodiment of a dispensing apparatus 540 for applying varying volumes of adhesive along the length of elastic strands 28 in accordance with the invention is shown. Similar to the previous embodiment, the dispensing apparatus 540 shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 9</figref> includes a first dispensing module 548 and a second dispensing module 550 arranged in series along the machine direction 46. The first dispensing module 548 of this embodiment includes a non-contact swirl nozzle such as the Summitt™ Mini Swirl nozzle commercially available from Nordson Corporation of Westlake, Ohio. The second dispensing module 550 of this embodiment includes a non-contact swirl nozzle such as the Universal™ CF nozzle commercially available from Nordson Corporation of Westlake, Ohio.<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --></p><p id="p0065" num="0065">More particularly, the first dispensing module 548 applies a first quantity 556 of adhesive, which is a miniature swirled filament of adhesive 30, onto each elastic strand 28 individually. The second dispensing module 550 applies a second quantity 558 of adhesive, which is formed by a filament swirled by air jets onto all of the elastic strands 28 collectively. Thus, unlike the previous embodiment, the first dispensing module 548 applies adhesive collectively onto all of the elastic strands 28, while the second dispensing module 550 applies adhesive individually onto each elastic strand 28.</p><p id="p0066" num="0066">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 9</figref>, the first and second dispensing modules 548, 550 receive adhesive material from corresponding adhesive supplies 552, 554. Similar to the embodiments described above, the adhesive supplies 552, 554 may include separate individually adjustable pumps for each dispensing module 548, 550 or a shared dual stream pump for both dispensing modules 548, 550. Similar to the previous embodiment, the first dispensing module 548 dispenses the first quantity 556 onto the first and third portions 32, 36 of the elastic strands 28, while the second dispensing module 550 dispenses the second quantity 558 onto the second portions 34 of the elastic strands 28. Thus, as shown by the adhesive patterns shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 9</figref>, the first and third portions 32, 36 are coated with first and third volumes of adhesive 30a, 30c that are larger than a second volume of adhesive 30b coating the second portions 34. As with the previously described embodiment, the dispensing apparatus 540 advantageously applies a higher volume of adhesive 30 to the end portions 32, 36 of the elastic strands 28 than to the central portions 34, thereby significantly reducing adhesive use while maintaining similar high bond quality.</p><p id="p0067" num="0067">With reference to <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 10</figref>, another embodiment of a dispensing apparatus 570 for applying varying volumes of adhesive along the length of elastic strands 28 in accordance with the invention is shown. Similar to the previous embodiment, the dispensing apparatus 570 shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 10</figref> includes a first dispensing module 578 and a second dispensing module 580 arranged in series along the machine direction 46. The first dispensing module 578 of this embodiment includes a non-contact swirl nozzle such as the Summitt™ Mini Swirl nozzle commercially available from Nordson Corporation of Westlake, Ohio. The second dispensing module 580 of this embodiment also includes a non-contact swirl nozzle such as the Summitt™ Mini Swirl nozzle commercially available from Nordson Corporation of Westlake, Ohio.<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --></p><p id="p0068" num="0068">More particularly, the first dispensing module 578 applies a first quantity 586 of adhesive, which is a miniature swirled filament of adhesive 30, onto each elastic strand 28 individually. The second dispensing module 580 applies a second quantity 588 of adhesive, which is a miniature swirled filament of adhesive 30, onto each elastic strand 28 individually. Thus, unlike the previous embodiment, each of the first dispensing module 578 and the second dispensing module 580 applies adhesive individually onto each elastic strand 28.</p><p id="p0069" num="0069">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 10</figref>, the first and second dispensing modules 578, 580 receive adhesive material from corresponding adhesive supplies 582, 584. Similar to the embodiments described above, the adhesive supplies 582, 584 may include separate individually adjustable pumps for each dispensing module 578, 580 or a shared dual stream pump for both dispensing modules 578, 580. Similar to the previous embodiment, the first dispensing module 578 dispenses the first quantity 586 onto the first and third portions 32, 36 of the elastic strands 28, while the second dispensing module 580 dispenses the second quantity 588 onto the second portions 34 of the elastic strands 28. Thus, as shown by the adhesive patterns shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 10</figref>, the first and third portions 32, 36 are coated with first and third volumes of adhesive 30a, 30c that are larger than a second volume of adhesive 30b coating the second portions 34. As with the previously described embodiment, the dispensing apparatus 570 advantageously applies a higher volume of adhesive 30 to the end portions 32, 36 of the elastic strands 28 than to the central portions 34, thereby significantly reducing adhesive use while maintaining similar high bond quality.</p><p id="p0070" num="0070"><figref idrefs="f0007">FIGS. 11 and 12A</figref> show another embodiment of a dispensing apparatus 640 according to the invention. In this dispensing apparatus 640, a first dispensing module 648 and a second dispensing module 650 are arranged generally in parallel along the machine direction 46 defined by the movement of the elastic strands 28. The first and second dispensing modules 648, 650 include corresponding first and second dispensing nozzles 642, 644 that are non-contact swirl nozzles such as the Universa™ CF nozzle commercially available from Nordson Corporation of Westlake, Ohio. Thus, the first and second dispensing nozzles 642, 644 apply respective first and second quantities 656, 658 of adhesive simultaneously onto the first portion 32 and then the third portion 36 of the plurality of elastic strands 28. In contrast to<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> previous embodiments, the first dispensing nozzle 642 dispenses the first quantity 656 onto the first and third portions 32, 36 of the strands 28, while the second dispensing nozzle 644 dispenses the second quantity 658 onto the first, second, and third portions 32, 34, 36. Thus, as shown schematically by the overlaid spiral patterns in <figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 11</figref>, the first and third portions 32, 36 are coated with first and third volumes of adhesive 30a, 30c, respectively, that are larger than a second volume of adhesive 30b coating the second portion 34. It will be understood that any of the embodiments of the dispensing apparatus shown herein may dispense overlapping quantities of adhesive 30 onto the first and third portions 32, 36 as shown in <figref idrefs="f0007">FIGS. 11 and 12A</figref>, or may dispense a completely separate first quantity on the first and third portions 32, 36 and a second quantity on the second portions 34 as shown in <figref idrefs="f0002 f0003 f0004 f0005 f0006">FIGS. 2 through 10</figref>.</p><p id="p0071" num="0071">Similar to the previous embodiment, the first dispensing nozzle 642 receives adhesive material pumped from a first adhesive supply 652 and the second dispensing nozzle 644 receives adhesive material pumped from a second adhesive supply 654. As described above, these first and second adhesive supplies 652, 654 may be separate individually adjustable pumps or may be the two output streams of a single dual stream pump. It will be understood that the first and second dispensing nozzles 642, 644 may be the same type of dispensing nozzle or different types of dispensing nozzles in various embodiments in accordance with the invention.</p><p id="p0072" num="0072">The simultaneous dispensing of the first and second quantities 656, 658 of adhesive is schematically shown from a front view in <figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 12A</figref>. Each of the first and second dispensing nozzles 642, 644 may include corresponding first and second adhesive outlets 680, 682 that are angled slightly towards one another. As a result, the first and second quantities 656, 658 may entangle together slightly as they swirl towards the plurality of elastic strands 28. However, it will be appreciated that such entanglement of the quantities 656, 658 is only schematically shown in <figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 12A</figref> and may be less complex than illustrated. As with the previously described embodiment, the dispensing apparatus 640 advantageously applies more volume of adhesive to the end portions 32, 36 of the elastic strands 28 than to the central portion 34, thereby significantly reducing adhesive use while maintaining similar high bond quality.<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --></p><p id="p0073" num="0073">It will be understood that while the first and second dispensing modules 648, 650 and the first and second adhesive outlets 680, 682 are shown as directly parallel along the machine direction 46 in <figref idrefs="f0007">FIGS. 11 and 12A</figref>, another slightly modified embodiment of the dispensing apparatus 740 may include slightly offset elements along the machine direction 46. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 12B</figref>, this dispensing apparatus 740 again includes first and second dispensing modules 748, 750 having first and second dispensing nozzles 742, 744 with first and second adhesive outlets 780, 782. The first dispensing module 748 is slightly offset forwards from the second dispensing module 750, which reduces or eliminates the entanglement of first and second filaments 756, 758 of adhesive during flight to the elastic strands 28. In all other respects, the dispensing apparatus 740 of <figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 12B</figref> operates in an identical manner as the dispensing apparatus 640 of <figref idrefs="f0007">FIGS. 11 and 12A</figref>, and thus no further explanation is provided here.</p><p id="p0074" num="0074">Although the previous embodiments of the dispensing apparatus have included two separate dispensing modules and dispensing nozzles, it will be understood that the same method of applying more adhesive at the end portions 32, 34 of elastic strands 28 may be performed by a single dispensing module connected to an adjustable supply of adhesive 30 or multiple supplies of adhesive 30. In this regard, <figref idrefs="f0008 f0009">FIGS. 13-17</figref> illustrate various embodiments of a dispensing apparatus 840, 940, 1040 that only include a single dispensing module and a single dispensing nozzle. These single module embodiments may include various types of dispensing nozzles, as described in further detail below.</p><p id="p0075" num="0075">With reference to <figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 13</figref>, another embodiment of a dispensing apparatus 840 for applying varying volumes of adhesive along the length of elastic strands 28 in accordance with the invention is shown. Unlike previous embodiments, the dispensing apparatus 840 shown in <figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 13</figref> includes only a single dispensing module 848. The dispensing module 848 of this embodiment includes a contact dispensing nozzle 842 as described in <patcit id="pcit0013" dnum="US61474129A"><text>U.S. Patent Application No. 61/474,129 to Saine</text></patcit>. More particularly, and as described in further detail in <patcit id="pcit0014" dnum="US61474129A"><text>U.S. Patent Application No. 61/474,129 to Saine</text></patcit>, the dispensing nozzle 848 applies a quantity 856, 858 of adhesive, which is a quantity applied by contacting the elastic strand 28 with an extruded adhesive 30 and then blowing air onto the elastic strand 28 to spread the adhesive 30 around the<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --> elastic strand 28. Thus, in this embodiment, the dispensing nozzle 842 applies adhesive 30 individually onto each elastic strand 28. The quantity 856, 858 includes a first adhesive portion 856 that is thicker or includes more adhesive 30 than a second adhesive portion 858, as described in further detail below.</p><p id="p0076" num="0076">In order to apply these adhesive portions 856, 858 with different amounts of adhesive 30, the dispensing module 848 receives adhesive from two adhesive supplies 852, 854. Similar to the embodiments described above, the adhesive supplies 852, 854 may include separate individually adjustable pumps or a shared dual stream pump, depending on the particular application. The dispensing module 848 includes first and second valves 890, 892 configured to control whether a dispensing outlet 880 of the dispensing nozzle 842 receives adhesive from one, both, or neither of the adhesive supplies 852, 854. One alternative arrangement of the first and second valves 890, 892 is shown in <figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 14</figref>, and another arrangement of the first and second valves 890a, 892a is shown in <figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 15</figref>. It will be understood that the particular arrangement of the valves 890, 892 may be modified in other manners without departing from the scope of the invention.</p><p id="p0077" num="0077">Turning to the arrangement shown in <figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 14</figref>, the first valve 890 is positioned in a first angled passage 894 that receives adhesive 30 from the first adhesive supply 852. The second valve 892 is positioned in a second angled passage 896 receiving adhesive 30 from the second adhesive supply 854. Each of the first and second angled passages 894, 896 terminates in close proximity to the dispensing outlet 880, which is advantageous because this arrangement limits the passage space between the shutoff valves 890, 892 and the dispensing outlet 880. Thus, the amount of adhesive 30 that may drip or leak out of the dispensing nozzle 842 after the valves 890, 892 are closed is minimized. Additionally, the first and second valves 890, 892 are arranged in parallel within the dispensing module 848 such that each valve 890, 892 independently controls the on/off supply of adhesive 30 from the corresponding adhesive supplies 852, 854. This parallel arrangement of valves 890, 892 is similar to that arrangement which is described in <patcit id="pcit0015" dnum="US7152815B"><text>U.S. Patent No. 7,152,815 to Harris et al.</text></patcit>, the entire disclosure of which is hereby incorporated by reference herein. To this end, when both of the valves 890, 892 are open, a maximum flow of adhesive 30 is extruded through the dispensing outlet 880. When only one of the valves 890, 892 is open with the other closed, a lesser flow of<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --> adhesive 30 is extruded through the dispensing outlet 880. Thus, by controlling the operation of the valves 890, 892, the relative thickness of the coating formed by the quantity 856, 858 may be modified.</p><p id="p0078" num="0078">More particularly, the dispensing module 848 opens both valves 890, 892 to apply a thicker first adhesive portion 856 at the first and third portions 32, 36 of the elastic strands 28. The dispensing module 848 then closes one of the valves 890, 892 to apply a thinner second adhesive portion 858 at the second portion 34 of the elastic strands 28. When both valves 890, 892 are closed, substantially no adhesive 30 is extruded onto the elastic strands 28, such as for example at the free ends 38. Thus, as shown by the adhesive patterns shown in <figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 13</figref>, the first and third portions 32, 36 are coated with first and third volumes of adhesive 30a, 30c that are larger than a second volume of adhesive 30b coating the second portions 34. As with the previously described embodiment, the dispensing apparatus 840 advantageously applies a higher volume of adhesive 30 to the end portions 32, 36 of the elastic strands 28 than to the central portions 34, thereby significantly reducing adhesive use while maintaining similar high bond quality.</p><p id="p0079" num="0079">Turning to <figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 15</figref>, an alternative arrangement of the first and second valves 890a, 892a is shown. In this embodiment, the first valve 890a and the second valve 892a are arranged in series within the dispensing module 848. To this end, the first valve 890a is positioned in a first passage 894a that receives adhesive 30 from the first adhesive supply 852. The second valve 892a is positioned in a second passage 896a receiving adhesive 30 from the second adhesive supply 854. Contrary to the previous valve arrangement, the first passage 894a terminates into the second passage 896a just upstream of the second valve 892a. Thus, the second valve 892a operates to control on/off flow of both adhesive supplies 852, 854 into the dispensing outlet 880 simultaneously, while the first valve 890a only controls whether the flow past the second valve 892a originates from one or two adhesive supplies 852, 854.</p><p id="p0080" num="0080">In operation, opening both valves 890a, 892a again causes a maximum flow of adhesive 30 to be extruded through the dispensing outlet 880. When only the second valve 892a is open with the first valve 890a closed, a lesser flow of adhesive 30 is extruded through the dispensing outlet 880. When the second valve 892a is closed, substantially no adhesive 30 is extruded through the dispensing outlet 880 from either adhesive supply 852, 854.<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> Consequently, the valve arrangement shown in <figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 15</figref> is operable to produce the same advantageous pattern of adhesive on the elastic strands 28 as described in regard to <figref idrefs="f0008">FIGS. 13 and 14</figref>.</p><p id="p0081" num="0081">With reference to <figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 16</figref>, another embodiment of a dispensing apparatus 940 for applying varying volumes of adhesive along the length of elastic strands 28 in accordance with the invention is shown. As in the previous embodiment, the dispensing apparatus 940 shown in <figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 16</figref> includes only a single dispensing module 948. The dispensing module 948 of this embodiment includes a SureWrap® nozzle commercially available from Nordson Corporation of Westlake, Ohio. More particularly, the dispensing nozzle applies a quantity 956, 958 of adhesive formed by a filament impacted by a plurality of air jets to each elastic strand 28. The elastic strands 28 move faster than the quantity 956, 958 of adhesive, which causes the quantity 956, 958 to stretch out during application into discrete localized increased masses 74 on the strands 28 that are separated from one another by thinner (or broken) areas 76 of adhesive 30 running between adjacent masses 74. Thus, in this embodiment, the dispensing module 948 applies adhesive 30 individually onto each elastic strand 28. The quantity 956, 958 includes a first adhesive portion 956 that includes more adhesive 30 than a second adhesive portion 958, as indicated schematically by closer spaced masses 74 of adhesive 30 in the first adhesive portion 956.</p><p id="p0082" num="0082">In order to apply these adhesive portions 956, 958 with different amounts of adhesive 30, the dispensing module 948 receives adhesive from two adhesive supplies 952, 954. Similar to the embodiments described above, the adhesive supplies 952, 954 may include separate individually adjustable pumps or a shared dual stream pump, depending on the particular application. The dispensing module 948 includes first and second valves (not shown) configured to control whether a dispensing outlet (not shown) of the dispensing nozzle receives adhesive from one, both, or neither of the adhesive supplies 952, 954, as described above. Additionally, the dispensing module 948 also receives pressurized process air from two air supplies 953, 955. The pressurized air from these air supplies 953, 955 may be selectively controlled by similar valves as the adhesive 30, as well understood in the art. Accordingly, a higher amount of pressurized air may be used when a higher amount of adhesive 30 is being applied by the dispensing module 948. It will also be<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --> appreciated that the dispensing module 948 may receive a single adjustable pressurized air supply in other embodiments consistent with the scope of the invention. As with the previously described embodiments, the dispensing apparatus 940 advantageously applies more volume of adhesive to the end portions 32, 36 of the elastic strands 28 than to the central portion 34, thereby significantly reducing adhesive use while maintaining similar high bond quality.</p><p id="p0083" num="0083">With reference to <figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 17</figref>, still another embodiment of a dispensing apparatus 1040 for applying varying volumes of adhesive along the length of elastic strands 28 in accordance with the invention is shown. As in the previous embodiment, the dispensing apparatus 1040 shown in <figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 17</figref> includes only a single dispensing module 1048. The dispensing module 1048 of this embodiment includes a Universal™ CF nozzle commercially available from Nordson Corporation of Westlake, Ohio. More particularly, the dispensing nozzle applies a quantity 1056, 1058 of adhesive formed by a swirled filament to all of the elastic strands 28 collectively. The quantity 1056, 1058 includes a first adhesive portion 1056 that includes more adhesive 30 than a second adhesive portion 1058, as indicated schematically by thicker and thinner swirl patterns shown in <figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 17</figref>.</p><p id="p0084" num="0084">In order to apply these adhesive portions 1056, 1058 with different amounts of adhesive 30, the dispensing module 1048 receives adhesive from two adhesive supplies 1052, 1054. Similar to the embodiments described above, the adhesive supplies 1052, 1054 may include separate individually adjustable pumps or a shared dual stream pump, depending on the particular application. The dispensing module 1048 includes first and second valves (not shown) configured to control whether a dispensing outlet (not shown) of the dispensing nozzle receives adhesive from one, both, or neither of the adhesive supplies 1052, 1054, as described above. When both valves are open, the dispensing module 1048 applies the thicker first adhesive portion 1056 to the elastic strands 28. When only one of the valves is open, the dispensing module 1048 applies the thinner second adhesive portion 1058 to the elastic strands 28. As such, the dispensing apparatus 1040 advantageously applies more volume of adhesive to the end portions 32, 36 of the elastic strands 28 than to the central portion 34, thereby significantly reducing adhesive use while maintaining similar high bond quality.<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --></p><p id="p0085" num="0085">A method of dispensing adhesive onto a stretched elastic strand includes applying a first volume of adhesive onto a first portion of the elastic strand, applying a second volume of adhesive onto a second portion of the elastic strand, and applying a third volume of adhesive onto a third portion of the elastic strand. The second volume is less than the first and third volumes. When the elastic strand is adhered to a substrate to form a personal disposable hygiene product, the first and third portions of the elastic strand define opposing ends of the elastic strand, which are adhered with a larger amount of adhesive to resist creep at the opposing ends. The reduction of adhesive in the second or central portion between the opposing ends significantly reduces the adhesive add on in the personal disposable hygiene product.</p><p id="p0086" num="0086">While the present invention has been illustrated by the description of specific embodiments thereof, and while the embodiments have been described in considerable detail, it is not intended to restrict or in any way limit the scope of the appended claims to such detail. The various features discussed herein may be used alone or in any combination. Additional advantages and modifications will readily appear to those skilled in the art.<br/>
The invention is further described by the following embodiments:
<ul><li>Embodiment 1. A method of dispensing adhesive onto at least one stretched elastic strand to be adhered to a substrate to form a personal disposable hygiene product, the method comprising:
<ul><li>moving the stretched elastic strand in a machine direction;</li><li>applying a first volume of adhesive onto a first portion of the elastic strand;</li><li>applying a second volume of adhesive onto a second portion of the elastic strand located downstream from the first portion of the elastic strand relative to the machine direction; and</li><li>applying a third volume of adhesive onto a third portion of the elastic strand located downstream from the second portion of the elastic strand relative to the machine direction,</li><li>wherein the second volume of adhesive is less than the first volume of adhesive, and the second volume of adhesive is less than the third volume of adhesive, and<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --></li><li>wherein the first and third portions of the elastic strand define opposing ends of the elastic strand when adhered to the substrate, and the second portion of the elastic strand defines a central portion of the elastic strand extending between the opposing ends when adhered to the substrate.</li></ul></li><li>Embodiment 2. The method with the features of embodiment 1, wherein the first and third portions of the elastic strand collectively define a first length and the second portion of the elastic strand defines a second length larger than the first length such that the second volume of adhesive is applied over a majority of the elastic strand.</li><li>Embodiment 3. The method with the features of embodiment 1, wherein applying the first, second, and third volumes of adhesive to the elastic strand further comprises:
<ul><li>dispensing a first quantity of adhesive onto the first and third portions of the elastic strand; and</li><li>dispensing a second quantity of adhesive onto the second portion of the elastic strand,</li><li>wherein the first quantity of adhesive defines the first volume of adhesive on the first portion of the elastic strand and the third volume of adhesive on the third portion of the elastic strand, and the second quantity of adhesive defines the second volume of adhesive on the second portion of the elastic strand.</li></ul></li><li>Embodiment 4. The method with the features of embodiment 3, wherein the first quantity of adhesive is dispensed by a first dispensing nozzle, the second quantity of adhesive is dispensed by a second dispensing nozzle, and the method further comprises:
<ul><li>pumping adhesive at an adjustable first flow rate to the first dispensing nozzle; and</li><li>pumping adhesive at an adjustable second flow rate to the second dispensing nozzle.</li></ul></li><li>Embodiment 5. The method with the features of embodiment 3, wherein the first quantity of adhesive is dispensed by a first dispensing nozzle,<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --> the second quantity of adhesive is dispensed by a second dispensing nozzle, and the method further comprises:
<ul><li>pumping adhesive at a predetermined flow rate to each of the first and second dispensing nozzles.</li></ul></li><li>Embodiment 6. The method with the features of embodiment 1, wherein applying the first, second, and third volumes of adhesive to the elastic strand further comprises:
<ul><li>dispensing a first quantity of adhesive onto the first and third portions of the elastic strand; and</li><li>dispensing a second quantity of adhesive onto the first, second, and third portions of the elastic strand,</li><li>wherein the second quantity of adhesive defines the second volume of adhesive on the second portion of the elastic strand, the first and second quantities of adhesive collectively define the first volume of adhesive on the first portion of the elastic strand, and the first and second quantities of adhesive collectively define the third volume of adhesive on the third portion of the elastic strand.</li></ul></li><li>Embodiment 7. The method with the features of embodiment 6, wherein dispensing the first and second quantities of adhesive further comprises:
<ul><li>dispensing the first and second quantities of adhesive simultaneously onto the first portion of the elastic strand, then dispensing the second quantity of adhesive onto the second portion of the elastic strand, and then dispensing the first and second quantities of adhesive simultaneously onto the third portion of the elastic strand.</li></ul></li><li>Embodiment 8. The method with the features of embodiment 6, wherein dispensing the first and second quantities of adhesive further comprises:
<ul><li>dispensing the first quantity of adhesive onto the elastic strand before or after dispensing the second quantity of adhesive onto the elastic strand.</li></ul><!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --></li><li>Embodiment 9. The method with the features of embodiment 1, wherein the first, second, and third volumes of adhesive are dispensed by a single dispensing nozzle including first and second valves controlling flow from corresponding first and second adhesive supplies, and wherein applying the first, second, and third volumes of adhesive to the elastic strand further comprises:
<ul><li>opening the first and second valves to apply the first volume of adhesive to the first portion of the elastic strand;</li><li>closing the second valve while leaving the first valve open to apply the second volume of adhesive to the second portion of the elastic strand; and</li><li>opening the first and second valves to apply the third volume of adhesive to the third portion of the elastic strand.</li></ul></li><li>Embodiment 10. The method with the features of embodiment 9, wherein applying the first, second, and third volumes of adhesive to the elastic strand further comprises:
<ul><li>pumping adhesive at an adjustable first flow rate to the first valve; and</li><li>pumping adhesive at an adjustable second flow rate to the second valve.</li></ul></li><li>Embodiment 11. A method of dispensing adhesive onto a plurality of stretched elastic strands to be adhered to a substrate to form a personal disposable hygiene product, the method comprising:
<ul><li>moving each of the plurality of stretched elastic strands in a machine direction;</li><li>applying a first volume of adhesive onto a first portion of each of the elastic strands;</li><li>applying a second volume of adhesive onto a second portion of each of the elastic strands located downstream from the first portion of the elastic strands relative to the machine direction; and</li><li>applying a third volume of adhesive onto a third portion of each of the elastic strands located downstream from the second portion of the elastic strands relative to the machine direction,<!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --></li><li>wherein the second volume of adhesive is less than the first volume of adhesive, and the second volume of adhesive is less than the third volume of adhesive, and</li><li>wherein the first and third portions of the elastic strands define opposing ends of the elastic strands when adhered to the substrate, and the second portion of the elastic strands defines a central portion of the elastic strands extending between the opposing ends when adhered to the substrate.</li></ul></li><li>Embodiment 12. The method with the features of embodiment 11, wherein applying the first, second, and third volumes of adhesive to the plurality of elastic strands further comprises:
<ul><li>dispensing at least one quantity of adhesive individually onto each of the plurality of elastic strands.</li></ul></li><li>Embodiment 13. The method with the features of embodiment 11, wherein applying the first, second, and third volumes of adhesive to the plurality of elastic strands further comprises:
<ul><li>dispensing at least one quantity of adhesive collectively onto all of the plurality of elastic strands.</li></ul></li><li>Embodiment 14. The method with the features of embodiment 13, wherein applying the first, second, and third volumes of adhesive to the plurality of elastic strands further comprises:
<ul><li>dispensing at least one quantity of adhesive individually onto each of the plurality of elastic strands.</li></ul></li><li>Embodiment 15. A personal disposable hygiene product, comprising:
<ul><li>a nonwoven substrate including first and second longitudinal sides; and</li><li>first and second stretched elastic strands adhered to said nonwoven substrate respectively proximate to said first and second longitudinal sides, each of said stretched elastic strands including a first portion defining an end of the elastic strand, a second portion defining a central portion of the elastic strand, and a third portion defining another end of the elastic strand,<!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --></li><li>wherein said first portions are coated with a first volume of adhesive, said second portions are coated with a second volume of adhesive which is less than the first volume of adhesive, and said third portions are coated with a third volume of adhesive which is more than the second volume of adhesive.</li></ul></li><li>Embodiment 16. The personal disposable hygiene product with the features of embodiment 15, wherein said first and third portions of each elastic strand collectively define a first length and said second portion of each elastic strand defines a second length larger than the first length such that the second volume of adhesive is applied over a majority of said elastic strands.</li><li>Embodiment 17. The personal disposable hygiene product with the features of embodiment 15, wherein a plurality of first stretched elastic strands are adhered to said nonwoven substrate proximate to said first longitudinal side, and a plurality of second stretched elastic strands are adhered to said nonwoven substrate proximate to said second longitudinal side.</li><li>Embodiment 18. A dispensing apparatus for applying adhesive to at least one stretched elastic strand to be adhered to a substrate to form a personal disposable hygiene product, each elastic strand including first, second, and third portions along a length of the elastic strand, the dispensing apparatus comprising:
<ul><li>a first dispensing nozzle for dispensing a first volume of adhesive onto the stretched elastic strand at the first portion and for dispensing a third volume of adhesive onto the stretched elastic strand at the third portion; and</li><li>a second dispensing nozzle for dispensing a second volume of adhesive onto the stretched elastic strand at the second portion,</li><li>wherein the second volume of adhesive is less than the first volume of adhesive, and the second volume of adhesive is less than the third volume of adhesive, and</li><li>wherein the first and third portions of the elastic strand define opposing ends of the elastic strand when adhered to the substrate, and the second portion of the elastic strand defines a central portion of the elastic strand extending between the opposing ends when adhered to the substrate.</li></ul><!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --></li><li>Embodiment 19. The dispensing apparatus with the features of embodiment 18, wherein said first dispensing nozzle and said second dispensing nozzle include the same type of dispensing nozzle.</li><li>Embodiment 20. The dispensing apparatus with the features of embodiment 18, wherein said first dispensing nozzle and said second dispensing nozzle include different types of dispensing nozzles.</li><li>Embodiment 21. The dispensing apparatus with the features of embodiment 18, further comprising:
<ul><li>a first adhesive supply for pumping adhesive to said first dispensing nozzle;</li><li>a second adhesive supply for pumping adhesive to said second dispensing nozzle; and</li><li>a control operable to selectively actuate said first and second adhesive supplies.</li></ul></li><li>Embodiment 22. The dispensing apparatus with the features of embodiment 18, wherein the first dispensing nozzle includes a strand guide for guiding the stretched elastic strand, and wherein the second dispensing nozzle does not include a strand guide.</li><li>Embodiment 23. A dispensing apparatus for applying adhesive to at least one stretched elastic strand to be adhered to a substrate to form a personal disposable hygiene product, each elastic strand including first, second, and third portions along a length of the elastic strand, the dispensing apparatus comprising:
<ul><li>a first dispensing nozzle for dispensing a first quantity of adhesive onto the stretched elastic strand at the first and third portions; and</li><li>a second dispensing nozzle for dispensing a second quantity of adhesive onto the stretched elastic strand at the first, second, and third portions,</li><li>wherein the first and second quantities of adhesive collectively define a first volume of adhesive on the first portion of the elastic strand, the<!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --> second quantity of adhesive defines a second volume of adhesive on the second portion of the elastic strand that is less than the first volume of adhesive, and the first and second quantities of adhesive collectively define a third volume of adhesive on the third portion of the elastic strand that is more than the second volume of adhesive, and</li><li>wherein the first and third portions of the elastic strand define opposing ends of the elastic strand when adhered to the substrate, and the second portion of the elastic strand defines a central portion of the elastic strand extending between the opposing ends when adhered to the substrate.</li></ul></li><li>Embodiment 24. The dispensing apparatus with the features of embodiment 23, wherein the first dispensing nozzle includes a strand guide for guiding the stretched elastic strand, and wherein the second dispensing nozzle does not include a strand guide.</li><li>Embodiment 25. A dispensing apparatus for applying adhesive to at least one stretched elastic strand to be adhered to a substrate to form a personal disposable hygiene product, each elastic strand including first, second, and third portions along a length of the elastic strand, the dispensing apparatus comprising:
<ul><li>a single dispensing nozzle for dispensing adhesive onto the stretched elastic strand at each of the first, second, and third portions;</li><li>a first valve adapted to control flow from a first adhesive supply through said dispensing nozzle; and</li><li>a second valve adapted to control flow from a second adhesive supply through said dispensing nozzle,</li><li>wherein the first and third portions of the elastic strand define opposing ends of the elastic strand when adhered to the substrate, and the second portion of the elastic strand defines a central portion of the elastic strand extending between the opposing ends when adhered to the substrate, and</li><li>wherein said first and second valves are opened to apply a first volume of adhesive on the first portion and a third volume of adhesive on the third portion, and the first valve is opened when the second valve is closed to<!-- EPO <DP n="36"> --> apply a second volume of adhesive on the second portion that is less than the first volume of adhesive and less than the third volume of adhesive.</li></ul></li></ul></p><p id="p0087" num="0087">The invention in its broader aspects is therefore not limited to the specific details, representative apparatus and methods and illustrative examples shown and described. Accordingly, departures may be made from such details without departing from the scope or spirit of the general inventive concept. What is claimed is:</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56977240" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="37"> --><claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A method of dispensing adhesive onto at least one stretched elastic strand to be adhered to a substrate to form a personal disposable hygiene product, the method comprising:
<claim-text>moving the stretched elastic strand in a machine direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>applying a first volume of adhesive onto a first portion of the elastic strand;</claim-text>
<claim-text>applying a second volume of adhesive onto a second portion of the elastic strand located downstream from the first portion of the elastic strand relative to the machine direction; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>applying a third volume of adhesive onto a third portion of the elastic strand located downstream from the second portion of the elastic strand relative to the machine direction,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second volume of adhesive is less than the first volume of adhesive, and the second volume of adhesive is less than the third volume of adhesive, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first and third portions of the elastic strand define opposing ends of the elastic strand when adhered to the substrate, and the second portion of the elastic strand defines a central portion of the elastic strand extending between the opposing ends when adhered to the substrate.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The method of claim 1, wherein the first and third portions of the elastic strand collectively define a first length and the second portion of the elastic strand defines a second length larger than the first length such that the second volume of adhesive is applied over a majority of the elastic strand.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The method of claim 1, wherein applying the first, second, and third volumes of adhesive to the elastic strand further comprises:
<claim-text>dispensing a first quantity of adhesive onto the first and third portions of the elastic strand; and<!-- EPO <DP n="38"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>dispensing a second quantity of adhesive onto the second portion of the elastic strand,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first quantity of adhesive defines the first volume of adhesive on the first portion of the elastic strand and the third volume of adhesive on the third portion of the elastic strand, and the second quantity of adhesive defines the second volume of adhesive on the second portion of the elastic strand.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The method of claim 3, wherein the first quantity of adhesive is dispensed by a first dispensing nozzle, the second quantity of adhesive is dispensed by a second dispensing nozzle, and the method further comprises:
<claim-text>pumping adhesive at an adjustable first flow rate to the first dispensing nozzle; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>pumping adhesive at an adjustable second flow rate to the second dispensing nozzle.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The method of claim 3, wherein the first quantity of adhesive and the second quantity of adhesive is dispensed by a single dispensing nozzle and the method further comprises:
<claim-text>pumping adhesive at maximum flow rate to the dispensing nozzle;</claim-text>
<claim-text>pumping adhesive at a lesser flow rate to the dispensing nozzle</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The method of claim 1, wherein applying the first, second, and third volumes of adhesive to the elastic strand further comprises:
<claim-text>dispensing a first quantity of adhesive onto the first and third portions of the elastic strand; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>dispensing a second quantity of adhesive onto the first, second, and third portions of the elastic strand,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second quantity of adhesive defines the second volume of adhesive on the second portion of the elastic strand, the first and second quantities of adhesive collectively define the first volume of adhesive on the first portion of the elastic strand, and the first and second quantities of adhesive collectively define the third volume of adhesive on the third portion of the elastic strand.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="39"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The method of claim 6, wherein dispensing the first and second quantities of adhesive further comprises:
<claim-text>dispensing the first and second quantities of adhesive simultaneously onto the first portion of the elastic strand, then dispensing the second quantity of adhesive onto the second portion of the elastic strand, and then dispensing the first and second quantities of adhesive simultaneously onto the third portion of the elastic strand.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The method of claim 6, wherein dispensing the first and second quantities of adhesive further comprises:
<claim-text>dispensing the first quantity of adhesive onto the elastic strand before or after dispensing the second quantity of adhesive onto the elastic strand.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The method of claim 1, wherein the first, second, and third volumes of adhesive are dispensed by a single dispensing nozzle including first and second valves controlling flow from corresponding first and second adhesive supplies, and wherein applying the first, second, and third volumes of adhesive to the elastic strand further comprises:
<claim-text>opening the first and second valves to apply the first volume of adhesive to the first portion of the elastic strand;</claim-text>
<claim-text>closing the second valve while leaving the first valve open to apply the second volume of adhesive to the second portion of the elastic strand; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>opening the first and second valves to apply the third volume of adhesive to the third portion of the elastic strand.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The method of claim 9, wherein applying the first, second, and third volumes of adhesive to the elastic strand further comprises:
<claim-text>pumping adhesive at an adjustable first flow rate to the first valve; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>pumping adhesive at an adjustable second flow rate to the second valve.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="40"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>The method of at least one of claims 1 - 10, for dispensing adhesive onto a plurality of stretched elastic strands to be adhered to a substrate to form a personal disposable hygiene product, the method comprising:
<claim-text>moving each of the plurality of stretched elastic strands in a machine direction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>applying a first volume of adhesive onto a first portion of each of the elastic strands;</claim-text>
<claim-text>applying a second volume of adhesive onto a second portion of each of the elastic strands located downstream from the first portion of the elastic strands relative to the machine direction; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>applying a third volume of adhesive onto a third portion of each of the elastic strands located downstream from the second portion of the elastic strands relative to the machine direction,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second volume of adhesive is less than the first volume of adhesive, and the second volume of adhesive is less than the third volume of adhesive, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first and third portions of the elastic strands define opposing ends of the elastic strands when adhered to the substrate, and the second portion of the elastic strands defines a central portion of the elastic strands extending between the opposing ends when adhered to the substrate.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>The method of claim 11, wherein applying the first, second, and third volumes of adhesive to the plurality of elastic strands further comprises:
<claim-text>dispensing at least one quantity of adhesive individually onto each of the plurality of elastic strands.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>The method of claim 11, wherein applying the first, second, and third volumes of adhesive to the plurality of elastic strands further comprises:
<claim-text>dispensing at least one quantity of adhesive collectively onto all of the plurality of elastic strands.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>The method of claim 13, wherein applying the first, second, and third volumes of adhesive to the plurality of elastic strands further comprises:<!-- EPO <DP n="41"> -->
<claim-text>dispensing at least one quantity of adhesive individually onto each of the plurality of elastic strands.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>A personal disposable hygiene product, comprising:
<claim-text>a nonwoven substrate including first and second longitudinal sides; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first plurality and a second plurality of stretched elastic strands adhered to said nonwoven substrate respectively proximate to said first and second longitudinal sides, each of said stretched elastic strands including a first portion defining an end of the elastic strand, a second portion defining a central portion of the elastic strand, and a third portion defining another end of the elastic strand,</claim-text>
<claim-text>said first portions are coated with a first volume of adhesive, said second portions are coated with a second volume of adhesive which is less than the first volume of adhesive, and said third portions are coated with a third volume of adhesive which is more than the second volume of adhesive, and said first and third portions of each elastic strand collectively define a first length and said second portion of each elastic strand defines a second length larger than the first length such that the second volume of adhesive is applied over a majority of said elastic strands within said first and second plurality of stretched elastic strands.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0016" num="0016"><claim-text>A dispensing apparatus for applying adhesive to at least one stretched elastic strand to be adhered to a substrate to form a personal disposable hygiene product, each elastic strand including first, second, and third portions along a length of the elastic strand, the dispensing apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a first dispensing nozzle for dispensing a first volume of adhesive onto the stretched elastic strand at the first portion and for dispensing a third volume of adhesive onto the stretched elastic strand at the third portion; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second dispensing nozzle for dispensing a second volume of adhesive onto the stretched elastic strand at the second portion,<!-- EPO <DP n="42"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second volume of adhesive is less than the first volume of adhesive, and the second volume of adhesive is less than the third volume of adhesive, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first and third portions of the elastic strand define opposing ends of the elastic strand when adhered to the substrate, and the second portion of the elastic strand defines a central portion of the elastic strand extending between the opposing ends when adhered to the substrate.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0017" num="0017"><claim-text>The dispensing apparatus of claim 16, further comprising:
<claim-text>a first adhesive supply for pumping adhesive to said first dispensing nozzle;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second adhesive supply for pumping adhesive to said second dispensing nozzle; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a control operable to selectively actuate said first and second adhesive supplies.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0018" num="0018"><claim-text>A dispensing apparatus for applying adhesive to at least one stretched elastic strand to be adhered to a substrate to form a personal disposable hygiene product, each elastic strand including first, second, and third portions along a length of the elastic strand, the dispensing apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a first dispensing nozzle for dispensing a first quantity of adhesive onto the stretched elastic strand at the first and third portions; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second dispensing nozzle for dispensing a second quantity of adhesive onto the stretched elastic strand at the first, second, and third portions,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first and second quantities of adhesive collectively define a first volume of adhesive on the first portion of the elastic strand, the second quantity of adhesive defines a second volume of adhesive on the second portion of the elastic strand that is less than the first volume of adhesive, and the first and second quantities of adhesive collectively define a third volume of adhesive on the third portion of the elastic strand that is more than the second volume of adhesive, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first and third portions of the elastic strand define opposing ends of the elastic strand when adhered to the substrate, and the<!-- EPO <DP n="43"> --> second portion of the elastic strand defines a central portion of the elastic strand extending between the opposing ends when adhered to the substrate.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0019" num="0019"><claim-text>A dispensing apparatus for applying adhesive to at least one stretched elastic strand to be adhered to a substrate to form a personal disposable hygiene product, each elastic strand including first, second, and third portions along a length of the elastic strand, the dispensing apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a single dispensing nozzle for dispensing adhesive onto the stretched elastic strand at each of the first, second, and third portions;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a first valve adapted to control flow from a first adhesive supply through said dispensing nozzle; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second valve adapted to control flow from a second adhesive supply through said dispensing nozzle.</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first and third portions of the elastic strand define opposing ends of the elastic strand when adhered to the substrate, and the second portion of the elastic strand defines a central portion of the elastic strand extending between the opposing ends when adhered to the substrate, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein said first and second valves are opened to apply a first volume of adhesive on the first portion and a third volume of adhesive on the third portion, and the first valve is opened when the second valve is closed to apply a second volume of adhesive on the second portion that is less than the first volume of adhesive and less than the third volume of adhesive.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16667953" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="44"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="165" he="209" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="45"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2,3"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="151" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="46"> --><figure id="f0003" num="4,5"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="151" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="47"> --><figure id="f0004" num="6,7"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="146" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="48"> --><figure id="f0005" num="8"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="88" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="49"> --><figure id="f0006" num="9,10"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="145" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="50"> --><figure id="f0007" num="11,12A,12B"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="153" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="51"> --><figure id="f0008" num="13,14,15"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="157" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="52"> --><figure id="f0009" num="16,17"><img id="if0009" file="imgf0009.tif" wi="150" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
