<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-1912012-B1" country="EP" doc-number="1912012" kind="B1" date="20140101" family-id="37708715" file-reference-id="314265" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146553590" ucid="EP-1912012-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>1912012</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-06781921-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154827513" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>06781921</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20060728</date><lang>JA</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140447096" ucid="JP-2005225712-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>JP</country><doc-number>2005225712</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20050803</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140452547" ucid="JP-2006315011-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>JP</country><doc-number>2006315011</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20060728</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130718</date></intention-to-grant-date><search-report-dispatch-date><date>20110803</date></search-report-dispatch-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988104319" load-source="ipcr">F16L  41/08        20060101AFI20110728BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988108340" load-source="ipcr">F16L  23/024       20060101ALI20110728BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988112092" load-source="ipcr">F16L  23/026       20060101ALI20110728BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988114128" load-source="ipcr">F16L  23/028       20060101ALI20110728BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988099728" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F16L  41/086       20130101 FI20131008BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988101285" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B60H   1/00571     20130101 LI20130927BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132193254" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">ROHRVERBINDUNG</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132193255" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">PIPE FITTING</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132193256" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">RACCORD POUR TUBE</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918154247" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>EAGLE IND CO LTD</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918137221" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>EAGLE INDUSTRY CO., LTD.</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918156038" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>FUJIWARA YASUSHI</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918141240" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>FUJIWARA, YASUSHI</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918997267" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>FUJIWARA, Yasushi c/o Eagle Industry co., Ltd.</last-name><address><street>1-12-15, Shiba-Daimon Minato-ku</street><city>Tokyo 1058587</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918159541" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>MATSUKI TAKUJI</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918151185" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>MATSUKI, TAKUJI</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918997268" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>MATSUKI, Takuji c/o Eagle Industry co., Ltd.</last-name><address><street>1-12-15, Shiba-Daimon Minato-ku</street><city>Tokyo 1058587</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918997270" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Eagle Industry Co., Ltd.</last-name><iid>100114034</iid><address><street>1-12-15, Shiba-Daimon, Minato-ku</street><city>Tokyo 105-8587</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918997269" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Wiebusch, Manfred</last-name><suffix>et al</suffix><iid>100745835</iid><address><street>Ter Meer Steinmeister &amp; Partner GbR Artur-Ladebeck-Strasse 51</street><city>33617 Bielefeld</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="JP-2006315011-W"><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>2006315011</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20060728</date><lang>JA</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2007015434-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2007015434</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20070208</date><lang>JA</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548978896" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548978937" load-source="docdb">FR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63957287" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">This invention relates to a pipe joint preferably used for connecting a hose to equipments such as compressors and the like in a car air-conditioner and the like.</p><heading id="h0002">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading><p id="p0002" num="0002"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="DE10010529A1"><text>DE 100 10 529 A1</text></patcit> describes a device for connecting a pipe to a connection opening of a body in accordance with the preamble of claim 1. A fitting is connecting an end portion of the pipe and the connection opening of the body. An O-ring seals the fitting and the body. The fitting is inserted into a connecting member that is inserted into a holding plate. The holding plate is fixedly joint to the body using one bolt.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">A conventional pipe joint for a compressor of a car air-conditioner and the like, is shown in <figref idrefs="f0012">Fig. 12</figref>, wherein a pipe joint comprising a connected hose 2 for supplying refrigerant, and a flange 20' having a communication passage 26 communicating through into the hose 2, is fixedly joined to a block 3 wherein the flange 20 is fixedly joined to the block of a compressor by using one bolt 30.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">In a pipe joint 1' of this kind, a rubber made O-ring 70 is provided at an outer circumference of a protrusion portion 25 of the flange 20' which is joined to a connection opening 3a of the block 3. By the O-ring 70, a connecting portion of the communication passage 26 and the connection opening 3a is sealed to an external portion.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p><p id="p0005" num="0005">In the meantime, in recent years, as refrigerant for a car air-conditioner, carbon dioxide gas (CO<sub>2</sub>) has been used instead of chlorofluorocarbon gas. When carbon dioxide gas is used as refrigerant, compared with chlorofluorocarbon gas, a pressure of gas flowing in the pipe joint 1' becomes 10 times higher or so, and there is a problem that the gas leaks through the O-ring 70.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">Consequently, as a method for eliminating such gas leakage, it is considered to use a metal seal instead of the O-ring. However, when a metal seal is used, to fix the metal seal, it is necessary to press in parallel by a large tightening force using more than two bolts which deteriorates fixing operation. As a result, the number of man-hours required increases compared with the conventionally known pipe joint 1'.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p><heading id="h0003">DISCLOSURE OF THE INVENTION</heading><heading id="h0004">PROBLEMS TO BE SOLVED BY THE INVENTION</heading><p id="p0007" num="0007">The object of the present invention is to provide a pipe joint which is suitable to prevent leakage of high-pressure gas and has high fixing operability.</p><heading id="h0005">MEANS FOR SOLVING THE PROBLEM</heading><p id="p0008" num="0008">The present invention is made to solve the above mentioned technical problem, and means for solving the problem are constituted as follows.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">A pipe joint of the present invention is a pipe joint for connecting a pipe with a connection opening of a body to be connected comprising;<br/>
a fitting connected to an end portion of the pipe and provided with a communication passage communicating into the pipe;<br/>
a flange having a through hole into which said fitting is suitable to be inserted, said flange pressingly holding said fitting inserted into said through hole towards said body;<br/>
a tightening means for fixing tightly said flange to said body;<br/>
an O-ring for sealing a connecting portion of said fitting and said body externally; and<br/>
an insertion opening formed in said flange for inserting said tightening means; wherein<br/>
a metal seal is provided between said fitting and said body so as to seal a joined portion of said communication passage and said connection opening externally,<br/>
said metal seal is composed of a ring member having a "C" shaped cross section, which includes an opening groove in an<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> inner circumference;<br/>
said O-ring comprises a first O-ring provided between said fitting and said flange, and<br/>
a second O-ring provided between said flange and said body;<br/>
a projecting portion is formed on a facing surface of said flange which is opposed to said body, said projecting portion is formed at an area opposite to an area, where said through hole into which the fitting is inserted is formed, with respect to a center axis of said insertion opening, said projection portion projects from said facing surface of said flange towards said body; and<br/>
a tip of said fitting inserted into said through hole projects towards said body from said face of said flange.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">In the present invention, initially, the metal seal is provided between the fitting and the body so as to seal externally the joint portion of the connection opening of the body and the communication passage of the pipe joint. Thereby, leakage of the high pressure gas such as carbon dioxide gas and the like through the seal portion can be prevented.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">Also, in the present invention, the metal seal is composed of a ring-member having a C-shaped cross-section. Thereby, a tightening force is accumulated as a resilient repulsion force and the connection portion can be sealed securely<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> with a small tightening force even using the metal seal. Also, since the tightening force is small, damage such as an impression on a sealing face of the body caused by the metal seal can be prevented.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">Further, in the present invention, the fitting to which a piping is connected, and the flange to be connected with the body are composed of different members. Thereby, the piping and the body composed by different metallic materials can easily be connected, since the fitting can be composed by the same material as the piping and the flange can be composed by the same metallic material as the body. Furthermore, since a direction of the piping can be adjusted after a temporary joint of the fitting with the body, an operating ability is increased. For example, it is particularly advantageous when the piping is rigid and even formed as an L-shape.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">Also, in the present invention, on a facing surface of the flange opposed to said body, a projecting portion is formed, said projecting portion is formed at an area opposite to an area where said through hole is formed with respect to a center axis of an insertion opening, and the projection portion projects from said facing surface of said flange towards said body. Thereby, when fastening the flange with the body by the tightening means, a tightening force is applied to the projected portion in a concentrated manner. The tightening force applied to the projected portion is also applied to the tip of the fitting in a concentrated manner by the principle of leverage wherein a fulcrum is the tightening means. Thus, even if the flange is fixed to the body by one bolt, the metal seal can be pressurized in parallel and an excellent workability can be maintained.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">Further, in the present invention, a first O-ring is provided between the fitting and the flange, and a second O-ring is provided between the flange and the body, for sealing<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> externally a connection portion of the fitting and the body. Thereby, in the case that the fitting and the body are composed by different metal materials, intrusion of water such as rainwater and the like from an outside can be prevented and occurrences of galvanic corrosion (bimetallic corrosion) between the fitting and the body can be prevented.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">Preferably, in the pipe joint of the present invention, said metal seal is tin plated on its surface. Thereby, damage such as an impression made on the seal face of the body caused by fastening the metal seal can be prevented, since the surface of the metal seal can be softened to a moderate degree.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">Preferably, in the pipe joint of the present invention, a holding portion having a convex or a concave shape suitable to hold the metal seal is formed at a tip of said fitting.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">Thereby, the pipe joint can be fitted to the body with a condition of holding the metal seal within the pipe joint, and since a release of the metal seal during installation can be prevented, workability is increased. Also, in the case of releasing the pipe joint from the body, since the pipe joint can be released with a holding condition of the metal seal within the pipe joint, workability is increased too.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">According to the present invention, it is possible to prevent permeation leakage of high pressure gas, and a pipe joint with high workability can be provided.</p><heading id="h0006">Brief description of drawings</heading><p id="p0019" num="0019"><!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --><ul><li>[<figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1] Fig. 1</figref> is a vertical cross sectional view showing a pipe joint according to a first embodiment of the present invention.</li><li>[<figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2] Fig. 2</figref> is a plan view of the pipe joint shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>.</li><li>[<figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3] Fig. 3</figref> is an enlarged cross sectional view of a portion III of <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>.</li><li>[<figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4] Fig. 4</figref> is a cross sectional view along a line IV-IV of <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>.</li><li>[<figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 5] Fig. 5</figref> is a bottom view of a flange used for the pipe joint shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>.</li><li>[<figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 6] Fig. 6</figref> is a vertical cross sectional view of a metal seal used for the pipe joint shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>.</li><li>[<figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 7] Fig. 7</figref> is a transverse cross sectional view of a tip of fitting and a metal seal of a pipe joint according to a second embodiment of the present invention.</li><li>[<figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 8] Fig. 8</figref> is a vertical cross sectional view of a tip of fitting and a metal seal of a pipe joint according to a third embodiment of the present invention.</li><li>[<figref idrefs="f0009">Fig. 9] Fig. 9</figref> is a transverse cross sectional view along a line IX-IX of <figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 8</figref>.</li><li>[<figref idrefs="f0010">Fig. 10] Fig. 10</figref> is a transverse sectional view of a tip of fitting and a metal seal of a pipe joint according to a fourth embodiment of the present invention.</li><li>[<figref idrefs="f0011">Fig. 11] Fig. 11</figref> is a transverse sectional view of a tip of fitting and a metal seal of a pipe joint according to fifth embodiment of the present invention.</li><li>[<figref idrefs="f0012">Fig. 12] Fig. 12</figref> is a vertical cross sectional view showing a conventional pipe joint.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0007">BEST MODE FOR CARRYING THE INVENTION</heading><p id="p0020" num="0020">Below, embodiments of the present invention will<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> be described based on drawings.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">A pipe joint 1 according to a first embodiment of the present invention shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is used for connecting a hose 2 for supplying a refrigerant with a connection opening 3a formed on a block 3 provided with a compressor of a car air-conditioner. The block 3 is composed of metallic materials such as aluminum and the like. The hose 2 is composed of metallic materials such as stainless steel and the like. Therefore, the block 3 and the hose 2 are composed of different metallic materials. Although it is not particularly shown in drawings, the block 3 is fixed to the compressor body using a bolt and the like.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig 1</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>, the pipe joint 1 comprises a fitting 10 connected to an end portion of a hose 2 having a communication passage 11 which communicates into the hose 2, a flange 20 having a through hole 21 within which the fitting 10 is suitable to be inserted and pressingly holding the fitting 10 inserted into the through hole 21 towards a block 3, a bolt 30 for fixing tightly the flange 20 to the block 3, a metal seal 40 provided between the fitting 10 and the block 3 so as to seal a joined portion of said communication passage 11 and a connection opening 3a externally, and first and second O-rings 50, 60 for sealing externally a connecting portion of the fitting 10 and the block 3.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">The fitting 10 is a substantially cylindrical body composed of metal materials such as stainless steel and the like, and is composed of similar metal materials which constitute the hose 2. At one end portion of the fitting 10 (an upper side end portion in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>), an end portion of the hose 2 is connected by means, such as welding, brazing and the like, and the communication passage 11 penetrating into the fitting 10 communicates into the hose 2. By composing the fitting 10 with similar metal materials as the hose 2, these can easily be<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> joined.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">At an outer circumference of the other end portion of the fitting 10 (a lower side end portion in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>), a gap portion 12 having a convex shape constituted by an enlarged outer diameter of the fitting 10 is formed. When the fitting 10 is inserted into the through hole 21 of the flange 20, the flange 20 is available to press the fitting 10 toward the block 3 by the convex shape gap portion 12 which is latched at a concave shape gap portion 21b formed on the through hole 21.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">Further, at a tip of the fitting 10, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4</figref>, a holding portion 13a, having only an outer circumference thereof projected toward the block 3, is formed. By pressingly inserting the metal seal 40 into the holding portion 13a having a concave shape, the metal seal 40 can be held by the fitting 10. Thereby, since the pipe joint 1 can be attached with the block 3 with a condition of maintaining the metal seal 40 within the fitting 10, workability is increased. Also, when maintenance and the like is required, because the pipe joint can be detached from the block 3 with a condition of maintaining the fitting 10 with the metal seal 40, workability can be increased.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">The flange 20 is, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>, a substantially rectangular parallelepiped body composed of metal materials such as aluminum and the like which are metal materials similar with the block 3. By composing the flange 20 and the block 3 with similar metal materials, galvanic corrosion occurred by intrusion of water such as rainwater and the like can be prevented.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">In this flange 20, the through hole 21 for inserting the fitting 10 and an insertion opening 22 for inserting the bolt 30 are formed.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">The through hole 21 of the flange 20 has a diameter<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> into which the fitting 10 can be inserted so as to penetrate from one face (a lower face in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>) to an opposite face (an upper face in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>) of the flange 20. A gap portion 21b having concave shape composed by an enlarged inner diameter of the through hole 21 is formed at one end portion of the through hole 21 (a lower end in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>). As stated above, by the convex shape gap portion 12 of the fitting 10 latched at the concave shape gap portion 21b, the fitting 10 is suitable to be pressed toward the block 3 by the flange 20.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">Also, at an inner circumference face of the other end portion of the through hole 21 (an upper side end portion in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>), an annular groove 21a for inserting the first O-ring 50 is formed. By the first O-ring 50 inserted into the annular groove 21a that seals between the fitting 10 and the flange 20, the intrusion of water such as rainwater and the like between the fitting 10 and the block 3, which are composed by different materials, can be prevented.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">Also, in the present embodiment, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 5</figref>, at a lower face 23 of the flange 20 (a face opposed to the block 3), a projection portion 24 is formed. The projection portion 24 is formed at an area opposite to an area where the through hole 21 to which the fitting 10 is inserted, is formed with respect to a center axis of the insertion opening 22 into which the bolt 30 is inserted. The projection portion 24 is projected from the lower face 23 of the flange 20. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, the projected portion 24 projects with a height L3 towards the block 3 from the lower face 23 of the flange 20.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">Further, in the present embodiment, a tip of the fitting 10 projects towards the block 3 side instead of a lower face 23 of the flange 20, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, in a condition that the convex shape gap portion 12 is latched to the concave shape gap portion 21b.<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --></p><p id="p0032" num="0032">The metal seal 40 is a ring member composed of a metal material, for example stainless steel and the like. The metal seal 40 has a "C" shaped cross section having an opening groove 41 at an inner circumference, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 6</figref>. In the present embodiment, on a surface of the metal seal 40, a tin layer is formed by electroplating. A thickness of the tin layer is preferably 20 to 35µm, thereby damage such as an impression on a sealing face of the block 3 caused by the metal seal 40 can be prevented. As a specific method for forming the tin layer, for example, a hanging plating method wherein metal seals are hanged singly at a shelf and dipped into a electroplating bath or a barrel plating method wherein a plurality of metal seals loaded into a barrel are put into an electroplating bath as a whole, can be exemplified.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">In the present embodiment, it is possible to prevent leakage of high pressure gas, such as carbon dioxide gas which penetrates the sealed portion, by using the metal seal 40 between the fitting 10 and the block 3. Also, by making the "C" shaped cross section of the metal seal 40, it is suitable to seal securely even with a small tightening force, since the tightening force by the bolt 30 is accumulated as a resilient repulsion force. Also, since the tightening force is small, damage such as an impression on a sealing face of the block 3 caused by the metal seal 40 can be prevented. Further, by forming a tin layer on a surface of the metal seal 40, the surface of the metal seal 40 can be softened to a moderate degree, and damage to the seal face of the block 3 by tightening the metal seal 40 can be prevented further.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>, the metal seal 40 is pressingly inserted into a gripping portion 13a of the fitting 10 so as to arrange the opening groove 41 facing towards inside. By adopting such an arrangement, high pressure carbon dioxide gas intrudes into an internal space of the "C" shaped cross section to expand<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> the cross section. Thereby, since the pressure of the gas acts to increase the surface pressure of the seal face, the sealing performance is improved.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, in the block 3 of the present embodiment, a diameter of an opening portion 3c of a connection opening 3a is expanded so as to insert the metal seal 40 and the fitting 10. Further, at a circumference of the opening portion 3c, an annular groove 3d is formed to put in a second O-ring 60. By sealing between the flange 20 and the block 3 with the second O-ring 60 in the annular groove 3d, intrusion of water such as rainwater and the like between the fitting 10 and the block 3, which are composed by different materials, through an outer circumference face of the fitting 10 and the opening portion 3c is prevented.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">Also, in the block 3, there is provided a bolt securing hole 3b having an internal thread to which the bolt 30 can be threaded. By threading the bolt 30 which is inserted into the insertion opening 22 of the flange 20, with the bolt securing hole 3b, it is possible to tightly fix the flange 20 with the block 3.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">A method for connecting the hose 2 with the connection opening 3a of the block 3 of a compressor by using the above stated pipe joint 1 will be specified below;</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">Firstly, the metal seal 40 is pressingly inserted into the holding portion 13a formed at a tip end of the fitting 10, and the fitting 10 is joined with an end portion of the hose 2 so as to communicate with a communication passage 11 in the hose 2. Then, the fitting 10 is inserted into the through hole 21 of the flange 20 from a lower side in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, with the first O-ring 50 placed in the annular groove 21a of the through hole 21.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">Next, the tip end of the fitting 10 and the metal<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> seal 40 are inserted into the opening portion 3c of the connection opening 3a with the second O-ring 60 placed in the annular groove 3d formed in the block 3. Then, by inserting the bolt 30 into the through hole 22 of the flange 20 and threading with the bolt securing hole 3b of the block 3, the flange 20 is tightly fixed to the block 3 by the bolt 30.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">In the present embodiment, since the fitting 10 and the flange 20 are composed of different individual members and the fitting 10 is freely rotatable to the flange 20, it is possible to adjust the direction of the fitting 10 when the flange 20 is temporarily joined to the block 3. Thereby, operability is improved, since it is not necessary to predetermine a direction of the hose 2 to the flange 20.</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">At final tightening of the flange 20 to the block 3 by the bolt 30, a tightening force of the bolt 30 is intensively applied to the projection portion 24, since the projection portion 24 projects to the block 3 side at a facing surface 23 of the flange 20. Also, since the fitting 10 projects toward the block 3 at an opposite side with respect to a center axis of the insertion opening 22, the tightening force is applied to the tip of the fitting 10 in a concentrated manner by the principle of leverage wherein the bolt 30 is a fulcrum. Thereby, the metal seal 40 can be compressed in parallel by tightening of the bolt 30, and an advanced installation function can be maintained.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">Note that, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, a tightening torque can be set arbitrarily by changing a ratio of a length L1 from a centerline of the through hole 21 to a centerline of the insertion opening 22 and a length L2 from a centerline of the projection portion 24 to a centerline of the insertion opening 22.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">In the pipe joint assembled as above, contact portions of the fitting 10 and the block 3 are sealed by the<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> first and the second O-rings 50 and 60. Thereby, galvanic corrosion caused by the intrusion of water such as rainwater and the like between the fitting 10 and the block 3, composed of different metallic materials, can be prevented.</p><p id="p0044" num="0044"><figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 7</figref> is a transverse cross sectional view along the line IV-IV of <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> showing a tip of a fitting and a metal seal of a pipe joint according to a second embodiment of the present invention. In the second embodiment of the present invention, as with the holding portion 13a of the first embodiment, a holding portion 13b, wherein only an outer circumference portion projects toward the block 3, is formed at a tip of the fitting 10. The holding portion 13b in the second embodiment, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 7</figref>, is not formed at the whole circumference of the tip of the fitting 10, and is formed at only four locations of the outer circumference of the tip of the fitting 10 toward the block 3 which is different from the first embodiment. In this manner, by projecting the holding portion 13b partially, the metal seal 40 can easily be pressingly inserted to the holding portion.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045"><figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 8</figref> is a vertical cross sectional view showing a tip of a fitting and a metal seal of a pipe joint according to a third embodiment of the present embodiment, and <figref idrefs="f0009">Fig. 9</figref> is a transverse sectional view along a line IX-IX of <figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 8</figref>. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 8</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0009">Fig. 9</figref>, a holding portion 13c wherein only an inner circumference projects toward the block 3, may be formed at the tip of the fitting 10. In the present embodiment, the holding portion 13c having a convex shape is pressingly inserted into an inner opening of the metal seal 40, and thereby the fitting holds the metal seal 40.</p><p id="p0046" num="0046"><figref idrefs="f0010">Fig. 10</figref> is a transverse cross sectional view showing a tip of fitting and a metal seal of a pipe joint according to a fourth embodiment of the present invention and a cross sectional view along a line corresponding to the line IX-IX of<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> <figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 8</figref>. In the fourth embodiment of the present invention, as similar to the holding portion 13c in the third embodiment, a holding portion 13d is formed at a tip of the fitting 10, wherein only an inner circumference portion of the holding portion 13d projects toward the block 3. The holding portion 13d in the fourth embodiment, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0010">Fig. 10</figref>, is not formed at the whole circumference of the tip of the fitting 10, and is formed at only four locations of the inner circumference of the tip of the fitting 10 so as to project toward the block 3. In this manner, by projecting the holding portion 13d partially, the metal seal 40 can easily be pressingly inserted into the holding portion.</p><p id="p0047" num="0047"><figref idrefs="f0011">Fig. 11</figref> is a transverse cross sectional view showing a tip of a fitting and a metal seal of a pipe joint according to a fifth embodiment of the present invention, and is a cross sectional view along a line corresponding to the line IX-IX of <figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 8</figref>. In the fifth embodiment of the present invention, a holding portion 13c is formed at a tip of the fitting 10, wherein only an inner circumference portion of the holding portion 13c projects toward the block 3. This is similar to the third embodiment, however, a protruding portion 42 projecting toward the holding portion 13c is formed at an inner circumference face of the metal seal 40'. As the metal seal 40' partially contacts with the holding portion 13c at the protrusion portion 42 only, the metal seal 40 can easily be pressingly inserted into the holding portion.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048">Note that the above mentioned embodiments are described for easily understanding the present invention and are not described to limit the present invention. Accordingly, the respective elements disclosed in the above embodiments are intended to cover various modifications and equivalent arrangements included in the scope of the present invention.<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></p><heading id="h0008">Industrial applicability</heading><p id="p0049" num="0049">A pipe joint of the present invention is useful as a pipe joint for connecting a hose for supplying a refrigerant to various equipments such as compressors, evaporators and the like, in a car air conditioner. A pipe joint of the present invention is also useful as a pipe joint for connecting pipes and equipments in a fuel cell treating hydrogen gas having high permeation property.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56979350" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Rohrverbindung zur Verbindung eines Rohres (2) mit einer Verbindungsöffnung (3a) eines anzuschließenden Körpers (3), mit<br/>
einem Fitting (10), das mit einem Endabschnitt des Rohres (2) verbunden ist und einen Verbindungskanal (11) aufweist, der eine Verbindung in das Rohr (2) herstellt,<br/>
einem Flansch (20), der ein durchgehendes Loch (21) aufweist, in welches das Fitting (10) einsetzbar ist, und der das Fitting (10) im Presssitz in Richtung auf den genannten Körper in das durchgehende Loch (21) eingesetzt hält,<br/>
einem Spannmittel (30) zum engen Fixieren des Flansches (20) an dem Körper (3),<br/>
einem O-Ring zur äußeren Abdichtung eines Verbindungsteils des Fittings (10) und des Körpers (3), und<br/>
einer in dem Flansch (20) gebildeten Einsetzöffnung (22) zum Einsetzen des Spannmittels (30),<br/>
<b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b><br/>
zwischen dem Fitting (10) und dem Körper (3) eine Metalldichtung (40) vorgesehen ist, um einen Fügebereich des Verbindungskanals (11) und der Verbindungsöff nung (3a) nach außen abzudichten,<br/>
wobei die Metalldichtung (40) durch ein Ringelement mit C-förmigem Querschnitt gebildet wird, dass an seinem inneren Umfang eine offene Nut (41) aufweist,<br/>
wobei der genannte O-Ring einen ersten O-Ring (50) aufweist, der zwischen dem Fitting (10) und dem Flansch (20) angeordnet ist, und<br/>
ein zweiter O-Ring (60) zwischen dem Flansch (20) und dem Körper (3) vorgesehen ist,<br/>
wobei an einer dem Körper (3) zugewandten Gegenfläche (23) des Flansches (20) ein vorspringender Teil (24) gebildet ist, der in einem Bereich gebildet ist, der in Bezug auf eine Mittelachse der Einsetzöffnung (22) einem Bereich entgegengesetzt ist,<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> in welchem das durchgehende Loch (21) gebildet ist, in das das Fitting (10) eingesetzt ist, wobei dieser vorspringende Teil (24) von der genannten Gegenfläche (23) des Flansches (20) in Richtung auf den Körper (3) vorspringt, und<br/>
ein Ende des Fittings (10), das in das durchgehende Loch (21) eingesetzt ist, in Richtung auf den Körper (3) von dieser Fläche des Flansches (20) vorspringt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Rohrverbindung nach Anspruch 1, bei der die Metalldichtung (40) an ihrer Oberfläche verzinkt ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Rohrverbindung nach Anspruch 1 oder 2, bei der ein Halteteil (13a), der eine konkave Form oder eine konvexe Form hat, verfügbar zum Halten der Metalldichtung (40), an einem Ende des Fittings (10) gebildet ist.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56979351" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A pipe joint for connecting a pipe (2) with a connection opening (3a) of a body (3) to be connected comprising;<br/>
a fitting (10) connected to an end portion of the pipe (2) and provided with a communication passage (11) communicating into the pipe (2);<br/>
a flange (20) having a through hole (21) into which said fitting (10) is suitable to be inserted, said flange (20) pressingly holding said fitting (10) inserted into said through hole (21) towards said body (3);<br/>
a tightening means (30) for fixing tightly said flange (20) to said body (3);<br/>
an O-ring for sealing a connecting portion of said fitting (10) and said body (3) externally; and<br/>
an insertion opening (22) formed in said flange (20) for inserting said tightening means (30);<br/>
<b>characterized in that</b><br/>
a metal seal (40) is provided between said fitting (10) and said body (3) so as to seal a joined portion of said communication passage (11) and said connection opening (3a) externally;<br/>
said metal seal (40) is composed of a ring member having a "C" shaped cross section, which includes an opening groove (41) in an inner circumference;<br/>
said O-ring comprises a first O-ring (50) provided between said fitting (10) and said flange (20), and<br/>
a second O-ring (60) provided between said flange (20) and said body (3);<br/>
a projecting portion (24) is formed on a facing surface<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> (23) of said flange (20) which is opposed to said body (3), said projecting portion (24) is formed at an area opposite to an area, where said through hole (21) into which the fitting (10) is inserted is formed, with respect to a center axis of said insertion opening (22), said projection portion (24) projects from said facing surface (23) of said flange (20) towards said body (3); and<br/>
a tip of said fitting (10) inserted into said through hole (21) projects towards said body (3) from said face of said flange (20).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The pipe joint according to claim 1, wherein said metal seal (40) is tin plated on its surface.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The pipe joint according to claim 1 or 2, wherein a holding portion (13a) having a concave shape or a convex shape available to hold said metal seal (40), is formed on a tip of said fitting (10).</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56979352" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Jonction de tube pour raccorder un tube (2) avec une ouverture de raccordement (3a) d'un corps (3) à raccorder, comportant :
<claim-text>un raccord (10) relié à une partie d'extrémité du tube (2) et muni d'un passage de communication (11) communiquant dans le tuyau (2),</claim-text>
<claim-text>une bride (20) ayant un trou traversant (21) dans lequel ledit raccord (10) est adapté à être inséré, ladite bride (20) maintenant de manière pressante ledit raccord (10) inséré dans ledit trou traversant (21) en direction dudit corps (3),</claim-text>
<claim-text>des moyens de serrage (30) pour fixer solidement ladite bride (20) audit corps (3),</claim-text>
<claim-text>un joint torique pour assurer l'étanchéité d'une partie de jonction dudit raccord (10) et dudit corps (3) en externe, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>une ouverture d'insertion (22) formée dans ladite bride (20) pour une insertion dans lesdits moyens de serrage (30),</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>caractérisée en ce que</b></claim-text>
<claim-text>un joint d'étanchéité métallique (40) est disposé entre ledit raccord (10) et ledit corps (3) de manière à assurer l'étanchéité d'une partie reliée dudit passage de communication (11) et de ladite ouverture de raccordement (3a) en externe,</claim-text>
<claim-text>ledit joint d'étanchéité métallique (40) est composé d'un élément annulaire ayant une section transversale en forme de "C", qui comprend une rainure d'ouverture (41) dans une circonférence intérieure,</claim-text>
<claim-text>ledit joint torique comporte un premier joint torique (50) disposé entre ledit raccord (10) et ladite bride (20), et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un second joint torique (60) disposé entre ladite bride (20) et ledit corps (3),<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>une partie en saillie (24) est formée sur une face (23) de ladite bride (20) qui est opposée audit corps (3), ladite partie en saillie (24) étant formée au niveau d'une zone opposée à une zone, où ledit trou traversant (21) dans lequel le raccord (10) est inséré est formé, par rapport à un axe central de ladite ouverture d'insertion (21), ladite partie en saillie (24) faisant saillie depuis ladite face (23) de ladite bride (20) en direction dudit corps (3), et</claim-text>
<claim-text>une extrémité dudit raccord (10) inséré dans ledit trou traversant (21) fait saillie en direction dudit corps (3) à partir de ladite face de ladite bride (20).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Jonction de tube selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle ledit joint d'étanchéité métallique (40) est plaqué à l'étain sur sa surface.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Jonction de tube selon la revendication 1 ou 2, dans laquelle une partie de maintien (13a) ayant une forme concave ou une forme convexe disponible pour maintenir ledit joint d'étanchéité métallique (40), est formée sur une extrémité dudit raccord (10).</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16668842" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="153" he="171" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="128" he="129" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="95" he="177" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --><figure id="f0004" num="4"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="128" he="113" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --><figure id="f0005" num="5"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="128" he="117" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --><figure id="f0006" num="6"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="110" he="83" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --><figure id="f0007" num="7"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="135" he="130" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --><figure id="f0008" num="8"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="98" he="165" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --><figure id="f0009" num="9"><img id="if0009" file="imgf0009.tif" wi="141" he="142" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --><figure id="f0010" num="10"><img id="if0010" file="imgf0010.tif" wi="146" he="139" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --><figure id="f0011" num="11"><img id="if0011" file="imgf0011.tif" wi="138" he="132" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --><figure id="f0012" num="12"><img id="if0012" file="imgf0012.tif" wi="136" he="152" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
