<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2133865-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2133865" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="40785483" file-reference-id="318269" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146588970" ucid="EP-2133865-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2133865</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-09161768-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154851162" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>09161768</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20090603</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140552515" ucid="JP-2008152772-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>JP</country><doc-number>2008152772</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20080611</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130801</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989327225" load-source="ipcr">G10H   1/00        20060101AFI20130719BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989327226" load-source="ipcr">H04R   5/027       20060101ALI20130719BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989327227" load-source="ipcr">H04S   7/00        20060101ALN20130719BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989625896" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04S   7/302       20130101 FI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989634353" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04R   5/027       20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989635695" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G10H   1/0091      20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989646596" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G10H2210/301       20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132371543" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Tongenerator</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132371544" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Sound synthesizer</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132371545" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Synthétiseur de sons</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919512184" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>YAMAHA CORP</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919507354" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>YAMAHA CORPORATION</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919523152" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>KAYAMA HIRAKU</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919506880" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>KAYAMA, HIRAKU</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919025690" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>KAYAMA, HIRAKU</last-name><address><street>Yamaha Corporation 10-1, Nakazawa-cho Naka-ku</street><city>Hamamatsu-shi Shizuoka 430-8650</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919025691" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Yamaha Corporation</last-name><iid>101022690</iid><address><street>10-1, Nakazawa-cho Naka-ku</street><city>Hamamatsu-shi, Shizuoka 430-8650</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919025692" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Ascherl, Andreas</last-name><suffix>et al</suffix><iid>101300364</iid><address><street>KEHL, ASCHERL, LIEBHOFF &amp; ETTMAYR Patentanwälte - Partnerschaft Emil-Riedel-Strasse 18</street><city>80538 München</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549889730" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549806767" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549792265" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549874689" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549926011" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549889731" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549806768" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549926012" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549926013" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549882948" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549792266" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549792267" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549806769" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549926014" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549806770" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549889732" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549874694" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549806771" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549792268" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549926015" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549790190" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549889737" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549790191" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549790192" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549898581" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS549898582" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549806772" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549792285" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549790205" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549874695" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549806773" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549790206" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549874696" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549792286" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549926016" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63961386" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading><heading id="h0002">[Technical Field of the Invention]</heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to a technology for synthesizing a sound.</p><heading id="h0003">[Description of the Related Art]</heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">A technology has been proposed for synthesizing a desired sound using sound data representing features of sounds that were previously recorded. For example, Patent Reference 1 or Patent Reference 2 describes a technology in which a frequency spectrum specified from sound data is expanded or contracted along the frequency axis according to a desired pitch, and an envelope of the expanded or contracted frequency spectrum is adjusted to synthesize a desired sound.<br/>
[Patent Reference 1] Japanese Patent Application Publication No. <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="JP2007240564A"><text>2007-240564</text></patcit><br/>
[Patent Reference 2] Japanese Patent Application Publication No. <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="JP2003255998A"><text>2003-255998</text></patcit></p><p id="p0003" num="0003">However, the technology of Patent Reference 1 or Patent Reference 2 synthesizes a sound that would be received at a sound collecting point (i.e., at the mounting position of a<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> sound collecting device) where sounds used to generate the sound data were recorded. Thus, the technology cannot synthesize a sound that would be heard at a position which the user designates inside a space in which sounds were recorded. <patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="WO2005036523A1"><text>WO 2005/036523 A1</text></patcit> describes that an audio signal is processed according to a position of microphone and a position of sound source. <patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="US2008056517A1"><text>US 2008/056517 A1</text></patcit> discloses a stereo recorder/player, wherein the sound is synthesized depending on the rotational position detected by a head tracker which is worn by a listener. The sound data originates from recording sound by a microphone array.</p><heading id="h0004">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading><p id="p0004" num="0004">The invention has been made in view of these circumstances, and it is an object of the invention to generate a sound that would be heard at a position desired by the user inside a space in which sounds used to generate sound data were recorded.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">In order to achieve the above object, a sound synthesizer according to claim 1 is provided.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">According to this configuration, it is possible to generate a sound that would be heard at a position (i.e., a virtual sound receiving point) desired by the user inside an environment in which sounds used to generate sound data were recorded, since a sound is synthesized by processing each of the plurality of the sound data according to a relation between the position of the sound collecting point corresponding to the sound data and the position of the sound receiving point indicated by the user.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p><p id="p0007" num="0007">In a preferable embodiment of the invention, the sound synthesis unit synthesizes a sound by processing each of the plurality of the sound data according to a distance (for example, a corresponding one of the distances L[1] to L[N] in <figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 8</figref>) between the sound collecting point corresponding to the sound data and the sound receiving point. According to this embodiment, it is possible to synthesize a sound closer to sounds inside the environment in which the sounds used to generate the sound data were recorded, since changes of sounds according to the distance of the sound receiving point from each sound collecting point are reflected in the synthesized sound.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">In a preferable embodiment of the invention, the setting unit variably sets a directionality attribute (for example, a directionality mode t<sub>U</sub> or a sound receiving direction d<sub>U</sub>) of the sound receiving point according to an instruction from a user, and the sound synthesis unit synthesizes a sound by processing each of the plurality of the sound data according to sensitivity that the directionality attribute represents for a direction of the sound collecting point corresponding to the sound data from the sound receiving point.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">According to this embodiment, it is possible to synthesize a sound more precisely closer to sounds inside the environment<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> in which sounds used to generate the sound data were recorded, since changes of sounds according to the direction of the sound receiving point from each sound collecting point are reflected in the synthesized sound. In this embodiment, for example, the setting unit sets at least one of a sound receiving direction and a directionality type (for example, the directionality mode t<sub>U</sub> in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3B</figref>) as a directionality attribute of the sound receiving point.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">In a preferable embodiment of the invention, the sound synthesis unit weights an envelope of a frequency spectrum of a sound represented by each of the plurality of the sound data by a factor (for example, a corresponding one of the weights W[1] to W[N] in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 6</figref>) according to a relation between the position of the sound collecting point corresponding to the sound data and the position of the sound receiving point, then calculates a new envelope (for example, an envelope E<sub>A</sub> in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 6</figref>) by summing the weighted envelopes (for example, envelopes E[1] to E[N] in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 6</figref>) of the frequency spectrums of the sounds represented respectively by the plurality of the sound data, and synthesizes the sound based on the new envelope.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">In this embodiment, the relation between the position of each sound collecting point and the position of the sound receiving point is reflected in the envelope of the synthesized sound. However, the synthesis method that the<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> sound synthesis unit uses to synthesize a sound or the details of processing performed on the sound data are diverse in the invention.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">The sound synthesizer according to each of the above embodiments may not only be implemented by hardware (electronic circuitry) such as a Digital Signal Processor (DSP) dedicated to musical sound synthesis but may also be implemented through cooperation of a general arithmetic processing unit such as a Central Processing Unit (CPU) with a program. A program as defined in claim 6 is thus also provided according to the invention. The program achieves the same operations and advantages as those of the sound synthesizer according to each of the above embodiments. The program of the invention may be provided to a user through a machine readable recording medium storing the program and then be installed on a computer and may also be provided from a server device to a user through distribution over a communication network and then be installed on a computer.</p><heading id="h0005">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading><p id="p0013" num="0013"><ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a block diagram of a sound synthesizer according to a first embodiment of the invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> is a conceptual diagram illustrating generation of<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> sound data.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">FIGS. 3A and 3B</figref> are schematic diagrams of music information and sound receiving information.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 4</figref> is a schematic diagram of a music editing image.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 5</figref> is a schematic diagram of a sound receiving setting image.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></li><li><figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 6</figref> is a schematic diagram illustrating the operation of a sound synthesis unit (an adjustment unit).</li><li><figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 7</figref> is a schematic diagram illustrating the operation of the sound synthesis unit.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 8</figref> is a schematic diagram illustrating calculation of a factor α[i].</li><li><figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 9</figref> is a schematic diagram illustrating calculation of a factor β[i].</li><li><figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 10</figref> is a schematic diagram of a sound receiving setting image in a second embodiment of the invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 11</figref> is a schematic diagram of sound receiving information.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0010">FIG. 12</figref> is a block diagram of a sound synthesizer according to a third embodiment of the invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0011">FIG. 13</figref> is a schematic diagram of a music editing image.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0006">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading><heading id="h0007">&lt;A: First Embodiment&gt;</heading><p id="p0014" num="0014"><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a block diagram of a sound synthesizer according to the first embodiment of the invention. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, a sound synthesizer 100 is implemented as a computer system including a control device 10, a storage device 12, an input device 22, a display device 24, and a sound output device 26.<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> -->The control device 10 is an arithmetic processing unit that executes a program stored in the storage device 12. The control device 10 of this embodiment functions as a plurality of elements such as an information generation unit 32, a display controller 34, a sound synthesis unit 42, and a setting unit 44 for generating a sound signal S<sub>OUT</sub> representing the waveform of a sound such as a sound of singing. The plurality of elements that the control device 10 implements may each be mounted in a distributed manner on a plurality of devices such as integrated circuits or may each be implemented by an electronic circuit such as a DSP dedicated to generating the sound signal S<sub>OUT</sub>.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">The storage device 12 stores a program that is executed by the control device 10 and a variety of data that is used by the control device 10. Any known recording medium such as a semiconductor storage device or a magnetic storage device may be used as the storage device 12. The storage device 12 of this embodiment stores a sound data group G including N sound data D (or N pieces of sound data D) (D[1],[2], ..., D[N]) where N is a natural number. The sound data D represents features of a sound that has been previously collected and stored. More specifically, the sound data D includes a plurality of sound element data D<sub>S</sub> (or a plurality of pieces of sound element data D<sub>S</sub>), each corresponding to an individual<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> sound element. Each sound element data D<sub>S</sub> includes a frequency spectrum S of a sound element and an envelope E of the frequency spectrum S. The sound element is a phoneme, which is the smallest unit that can be aurally distinguished, or a phoneme chain which is a series of connected phonemes.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016"><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> is a conceptual diagram illustrating a method for generating sound data D. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>, N sound collecting devices M (M[1], M[2], ..., M[N]) are arranged at different positions P (P[1], P[2], ..., P[N]) in a space R. Each sound collecting device M is a nondirectional microphone that collects sounds such as choral sounds that a plurality of persons u located at a specific position in the space R generate in parallel.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">A sound collected by a sound collecting device M[i] disposed at a position P[i] (i = 1-N) is used to generate sound data D[i]. Specifically, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>, a sound (specifically, a mixture of vocal sounds generated by a plurality of persons) collected by the sound collecting device M[i] is divided into sound elements, and sound data D[i] is then generated by incorporating, as sound element data D<sub>S</sub> of each sound element, a frequency spectrum S and an envelope E which are specified by performing frequency analysis (for example, Fourier transform) on the sound element. As shown in<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGS. 1</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0002">2</figref>, the position P[i] of the sound collecting device M[i], at which the sound has been collected, is added to the sound data D[i]. The position P[i] is defined by coordinates (xi, yi) on an x-y plane set in the space R. The above procedure is performed on each of the sound collecting devices M[1] to M[N] to generate N sound data D[1] to D[N] which constitute the sound data group G. Thus, N sound data D[1] to D[N], which constitute the sound data group G, represent the features of sounds that have been collected in parallel at the individual positions P[1] to P[N] when common sounds such as choral sounds have been simultaneously generated in the space R.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">The input device 22 in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a device (for example, a mouse or keyboard) that the user operates to input an instruction for the sound synthesizer 100. The display device (for example, a liquid crystal display) 24 displays a variety of images based on control of the control device 10 (specifically, by means of the display controller 34). The sound output device 26 is a sound emitting device (for example, a speaker or headphones) which emits a sound wave according to the sound signal S<sub>OUT</sub> provided from the control device 10.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">The information generation unit 32 in the control device 10 generates or edits music information Q<sub>A</sub> such as score data,<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> which is used to synthesize a sound, according to an operation that the user performs on the input device 22 and then stores the music information Q<sub>A</sub> in the storage device 12. <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3A</figref> is a schematic diagram illustrating contents of the music information Q<sub>A</sub>. The music information Q<sub>A</sub> is a data sequence that is used to designate a plurality of sounds (hereinafter, referred to as "designated sounds") to be synthesized by the sound synthesizer 100 in chronological order. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3A</figref>, in the music information Q<sub>A</sub>, a pitch (i.e., a note), sound generation time (specifically, the start and end times of generation of the sound), and a sound element are designated for each of the plurality of designated sounds that are arranged in chronological order.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">The display controller 34 in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> generates and displays an image on the display device 24. For example, the display controller 34 displays a music editing image shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 4</figref>, which allows the user to edit (create) or check the music information Q<sub>A</sub>, or a sound receiving setting image shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 5</figref>, which allows the user to variably set a virtual sound receiving position of the synthesized sound, on the display device 24.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">When the user performs an operation for starting editing of the music information Q<sub>A</sub> on the input device 22, the display<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> controller 34 displays the music editing image of <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 4</figref> on the display device. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 4</figref>, the music editing image 50 includes a work area 52 in the form of a piano roll in which a vertical axis corresponding to the pitch and a horizontal axis corresponding to the time are set. The user designates a pitch and sound generation time of each designated sound by appropriately operating the input device 22 while viewing the music editing image 50. The display controller 34 arranges marks C<sub>A</sub> corresponding to the sounds designated by the user in the work area 52. In the following description, the marks are referred to as "indicators". A position of the indicator C<sub>A</sub> in the direction of the vertical axis (pitch) of the work area 52 is selected according to a pitch designated by the user and a position or size of the indicator C<sub>A</sub> in the direction of the horizontal axis (time) is selected according to the sound generation time (specifically, a sound generation time point or time length) designated by the user.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">Each time the user selects a designated sound, the information generation unit 32 stores a pitch and sound generation time indicated by the user, as a pitch and sound generation time of the designated sound in the music information Q<sub>A</sub>, in the storage device 12. The user designates a lyric character of each indicator C<sub>A</sub> (i.e., each designated<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> sound) in the work area 52 by appropriately operating the input device 22. The information generation unit 32 stores a sound element corresponding to the character, which the user has designated for the designated sound, in the music information Q<sub>A</sub> in association with the designated sound.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">The sound synthesis unit 42 of <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> synthesizes a sound (specifically, a sound signal S<sub>OUT</sub>) using the sound data group G. More specifically, the sound synthesis unit 42 synthesizes a sound that would be received by a virtual sound receiving point (specifically, a virtual sound receiving device) assuming that the virtual sound receiving point was disposed in the space R when the sound of the sound data group G was recorded. The setting unit 44 sets and stores sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub>, which defines the virtual sound receiving point, in the storage device 12 according to an operation that the user performs on the input device 22. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3B</figref>, the sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub> includes the position P<sub>U</sub>, the directionality type t<sub>U</sub> as a directionality attribute (hereinafter referred to as a "directionality mode"), sound receiving sensitivity h<sub>U</sub>, and a sound receiving direction d<sub>U</sub> of the sound receiving point. Setting of each variable of the sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub> will be described later.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">When the user performs an operation for starting<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> generation or editing of the sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub> on the input device 22, the display controller 34 displays the sound receiving setting image 60 of <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 5</figref> on the display device 24. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 5</figref>, the sound receiving setting image 60 includes a work area 62 and an operating area 64. An identifier (a file name "My Mic" in the example of <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 5</figref>) of the sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub> which is to be actually edited (or generated) is displayed in a region 641 in the operating area 64. By changing the identifier in the region 641 through operation of the input device 22, the user can select sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub> that is to be edited (generated) through the setting unit 44.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">The work area 62 is a region having a shape corresponding to the space R of <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> used when the sound data group G is recorded. The user arbitrarily selects a position P<sub>U</sub>, at which a virtual sound receiving point U is to be disposed, in the work area 62 by appropriately operating the input device 22. The position P<sub>U</sub> is defined by coordinates (xU, yU) in the x-y plane set in the work area 62.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">The user variably designates the directionality mode t<sub>U</sub> at the sound receiving point U (i.e., a directionality attribute of the virtual sound receiving device disposed at the position P<sub>U</sub>) through operation of the input device 22. For<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> example, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 5</figref>, the display controller 34 displays a list 622 of candidates for the directionality mode t<sub>U</sub> (such as ultra cardioid and hyper cardioid) on the display device 24. When the user selects one directionality mode t<sub>U</sub> from the list 622 by operating the input device 22, the display controller 34 disposes a mark C<sub>B</sub> visually indicating the directionality mode t<sub>U</sub> selected by the user at the position P<sub>U</sub> in the work area 62. In the following description, the mark C<sub>B</sub> visually indicating the directionality mode t<sub>U</sub> is referred to as a "directionality pattern". For example, when the user has selected unidirectionality (i.e., cardioid), a directionality pattern C<sub>B</sub> having a cardioid shape (i.e., a heart shape) representing the unidirectionality is disposed at the position P<sub>U</sub> as shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 5</figref>.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">In addition, the user also variably designates the sound receiving sensitivity h<sub>U</sub> at the sound receiving point U (i.e., the gain of the virtual sound receiving device disposed at the position P<sub>U</sub>) and the sound receiving direction d<sub>U</sub> at the sound receiving point U (i.e., a directionality attribute of the virtual sound receiving device disposed at the position P<sub>U</sub>) through operation of the input device 22. The display controller 34 rotates the directionality pattern C<sub>B</sub> to the sound receiving direction d<sub>U</sub> designated by the user as shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 5</figref>.<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></p><p id="p0028" num="0028">Each time the user operates an operator (Add) 642 in <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 5</figref>, the setting unit 44 reflects the variables such as the position P<sub>U</sub>, the directionality mode t<sub>U</sub>, the sound receiving sensitivity h<sub>U</sub>, and the sound receiving direction d<sub>U</sub> indicated by the user in sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub> corresponding to the identifier in the region 641. That is, the setting unit 44 variably sets the sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub> stored in the storage device 12 according to an instruction from the user. Although the user directly designates the sound receiving sensitivity h<sub>U</sub> in the above example, it is also possible to employ a configuration wherein the setting unit 44 specifies a numerical value of the sound receiving sensitivity h<sub>U</sub> from an option that the user has selected from a plurality of options (for example, multiple options including high sensitivity, middle sensitivity, and low sensitivity).</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">When an operator (Delete) 643 is operated, the setting unit 44 deletes sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub> corresponding to the identifier in the region 641 from the storage device 12. When an operator (Play) 644 is operated, the sound synthesis unit 42 synthesizes a sound signal S<sub>OUT</sub> of a predetermined sound element using the sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub> that is being edited. The user can generate desired sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub> by editing the sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub><!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> while listening to, as needed, the synthesized sound reproduced through the sound output device 26. On the other hand, when an operator (OK) 645 is selected, the sound receiving setting image 60 is removed after the sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub> that is being edited is fixed, and, when an operator (Cancel) 646 is operated, the sound receiving setting image 60 is removed without reflecting the setting performed after the immediately previous operation of the operator 642 in the sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub>.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">The sound synthesis unit 42 in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> synthesizes a sound (i.e., a sound signal S<sub>OUT</sub>) using the sound data group G (including sound data D[1] to D[N]), the music information Q<sub>A</sub>, and the sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub>. More specifically, the sound synthesis unit 42 sequentially selects each designated sound (hereinafter referred to as a "selected designated sound") in the order of sound generation time in the music information Q<sub>A</sub> and acquires sound element data D<sub>S</sub>, corresponding to a sound element designated for the selected designated sound in the music information Q<sub>A</sub>, from each of the N sound data D[1] to D[N] of the sound data group G in the storage device 12. The sound synthesis unit 42 generates a sound signal S<sub>OUT</sub> using the N sound element data D<sub>S</sub> acquired from the storage device 12 according to the sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub>. In the case where a plurality of sound<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> receiving information Q<sub>B</sub> has been stored in the storage device 12, the sound synthesis unit 42 uses sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub>, which the user has selected using the input device 22, to synthesize the sound.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031"><figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 6</figref> illustrates N sound element data D<sub>S</sub> (D<sub>S</sub>[1] to D<sub>S</sub>[N]) acquired from the storage device 12 according to the sound element of the selected designated sound. Sound element data D<sub>S</sub>[i] extracted from sound data D[i] represents a frequency spectrum S[i] and an envelope E[i]. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 6</figref>, the sound synthesis unit 42 includes an adjustment unit 46 that generates an envelope E<sub>A</sub> from the envelopes E[1] to E[N] and also generates a frequency spectrum S<sub>A</sub> from the frequency spectrums S[1] to S[N] as shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 6</figref>. Detailed operations of the adjustment unit 46 will be described later.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032"><figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 7</figref> is a conceptual diagram illustrating the operation of the sound synthesis unit 42. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 7(A)</figref>, in the frequency spectrum S<sub>A</sub> generated by the adjustment unit 46, a local peak pk is present at each of a fundamental frequency (pitch) P0 and harmonics of the sound. The sound synthesis unit 42 detects local peaks pk from the frequency spectrum S<sub>A</sub> generated by the adjustment unit 46 and specifies a distribution A for each local peak pk in the frequency spectrum S<sub>A</sub> such that the distribution A spans a predetermined<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> bandwidth, centered on the local peak pk in the frequency axis. In the following description, the distribution A is referred to as a "local peak distribution".</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">The sound synthesis unit 42 sequentially performs a pitch conversion process and a magnitude adjustment process. The pitch conversion process is a process for expanding or contracting the frequency spectrum S<sub>A</sub> in the direction of the frequency axis. That is, the sound synthesis unit 42 calculates a conversion rate k by dividing a pitch PX that is designated for the selected designated sound in the music information Q<sub>A</sub> by the fundamental frequency P<sub>0</sub> of the frequency spectrum S<sub>A</sub> (i.e., k=Px/P0) and expands (when the conversion rate k is greater than "1") or contracts (when the conversion rate k is less than "1") the frequency spectrum S<sub>A</sub> in the direction of the frequency axis by a ratio corresponding to the conversion rate k to generate a frequency spectrum S<sub>B</sub> as shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 7(B)</figref>. For example, the sound synthesis unit 42 generates the frequency spectrum S<sub>B</sub> by moving each local peak distribution A of the frequency spectrum S<sub>A</sub> along the frequency axis such that each local peak pk of the frequency spectrum S<sub>A</sub> is located at a frequency which is the product of the frequency of the local peak pk and the conversion rate k and expanding or contracting components of an interval between each local peak distribution A, which has not been moved,<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> along the frequency axis, and then disposing the expanded or contracted component between each local peak distribution A which has been moved.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">The magnitude adjustment process is a process for adjusting the magnitude (i.e., amplitude) of the frequency spectrum S<sub>B</sub> that has been expanded or contracted to generate a frequency spectrum S<sub>C</sub>. The magnitude adjustment process uses the envelope E<sub>A</sub> generated by the adjustment unit 46. More specifically, the sound synthesis unit 42 generates the frequency spectrum S<sub>C</sub> by increasing or decreasing the magnitude of each local peak distribution A of the frequency spectrum S<sub>B</sub> such that a curve connecting each local peak pk of the frequency spectrum S<sub>B</sub> matches the envelope E<sub>A</sub> as shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 7C</figref> (i.e., such that the top of each local peak pk is located on the envelope E<sub>A</sub>). That is, the sound synthesis unit 42 adjusts the magnitude of each local peak pk of the frequency spectrum S<sub>B</sub> so as to be equal to the magnitude of a frequency corresponding to the local peak pk in the envelope E<sub>A</sub>. The sound synthesis unit 42 generates a sound signal S<sub>OUT</sub> by converting (i.e., inverse Fourier transforming) the frequency spectrum S<sub>C</sub> generated through the above procedure into time-domain waveform signals and connecting the converted signals along the time axis. Details of the sound synthesis method illustrated above are also described in Japanese Patent<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> Application Publication No. <patcit id="pcit0005" dnum="JP2007240564A"><text>2007-240564</text></patcit>.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">The following is a detailed description of how the adjustment unit 46 calculates the envelope E<sub>A</sub> and the frequency spectrum S<sub>A</sub>. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 6</figref>, the adjustment unit 46 calculates, as the envelope E<sub>A</sub>, a weighted sum of the envelopes E[1] to E[N] represented by N sound element data D<sub>S</sub>[1] to D<sub>S</sub>[N] corresponding to the sound element of the selected designated sound in the sound data group G. More specifically, a magnitude VE(f) at each frequency f in the envelope E<sub>A</sub> is defined as the sum (i.e., a weighted sum) of the magnitudes vE_i(f) of the frequency f of envelopes E[i] multiplied by weights W[i] for N envelopes E[1] to E[N] (i.e., for all i from 1 to N) as represented in the following Equation (1). That is, the adjustment unit 46 generates the envelope E<sub>A</sub> corresponding to the envelopes E[1] to E[N] by performing calculation of the following Equation (1). <maths id="math0001" num="(1)"><math display="block"><mi>VE</mi><mfenced><mi mathvariant="normal">f</mi></mfenced><mo>=</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">W</mi><mfenced open="[" close="]"><mn mathvariant="normal">1</mn></mfenced><mo>⋅</mo><mi>vE_</mi><mn mathvariant="normal">1</mn><mfenced><mi mathvariant="normal">f</mi></mfenced><mo>+</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">W</mi><mfenced open="[" close="]"><mn mathvariant="normal">2</mn></mfenced><mo>⋅</mo><mi>vE_</mi><mn mathvariant="normal">2</mn><mfenced><mi mathvariant="normal">f</mi></mfenced><mo>+</mo><mn>.....</mn><mo>+</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">W</mi><mfenced open="[" close="]"><mi mathvariant="normal">N</mi></mfenced><mo>⋅</mo><mi>vE_N</mi><mfenced><mi mathvariant="normal">f</mi></mfenced></math><img id="ib0001" file="imgb0001.tif" wi="156" he="11" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0036" num="0036">Similarly, the adjustment unit 46 calculates, as the frequency spectrum S<sub>A</sub>, a weighted sum of the frequency spectrums S[1] to S[N] represented by N sound element data D<sub>S</sub>[1] to D<sub>S</sub>[N] corresponding to the sound element of the selected designated sound in the sound data group G. More specifically, a magnitude VS(f) at each frequency f in the<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> frequency spectrum S<sub>A</sub> is defined as the sum (i.e., a weighted sum) of the magnitudes vS_i(f) of the frequency f of frequency spectrums S[i] multiplied by weights W[i] for N envelopes S[1] to S[N] (i.e., for all i from 1 to N) as represented in the following Equation (2). That is, the adjustment unit 46 generates the frequency spectrum S<sub>A</sub> corresponding to the frequency spectrums S[1] to S[N] by performing calculation of the following Equation (2). <maths id="math0002" num="(2)"><math display="block"><mi>VS</mi><mfenced><mi mathvariant="normal">f</mi></mfenced><mo>=</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">W</mi><mfenced open="[" close="]"><mn mathvariant="normal">1</mn></mfenced><mo>⋅</mo><mi>vS_</mi><mn mathvariant="normal">1</mn><mfenced><mi mathvariant="normal">f</mi></mfenced><mo>+</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">W</mi><mfenced open="[" close="]"><mn mathvariant="normal">2</mn></mfenced><mo>⋅</mo><mi>vS_</mi><mn mathvariant="normal">2</mn><mfenced><mi mathvariant="normal">f</mi></mfenced><mo>+</mo><mn>.....</mn><mo>+</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">W</mi><mfenced open="[" close="]"><mi mathvariant="normal">N</mi></mfenced><mo>⋅</mo><mi>vS_N</mi><mfenced><mi mathvariant="normal">f</mi></mfenced></math><img id="ib0002" file="imgb0002.tif" wi="155" he="10" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0037" num="0037">The weight W[i] applied to both the magnitude vE_i(f) of the envelope E[i] in Equation (1) and the magnitude vS_i(f) of the frequency spectrum S[i] in Equation (2) is determined according to the sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub> set by the setting unit 44 and the position P[i] designated in the sound data D[i] (i.e., the position of the sound collecting device M[i] at which the sound was recorded). More specifically, the weight W[i] is determined to be the product of a factor α[i] and a factor β[i] (W[i] =α[i]·β[i]). The factor α[i] is calculated according to the distance between the position P[i] and the position P<sub>U</sub> of the virtual sound receiving point U. The factor β[i] is calculated according to the direction of the position P[i] from the position P<sub>U</sub> and the directionality attributes of sound reception at the sound receiving point U such as the directionality mode t<sub>U</sub>, the sound receiving<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> sensitivity h<sub>U</sub>, and the sound receiving direction d<sub>U</sub>. The adjustment unit 46 calculates the factor α[i] and the factor β [i] in the following manner.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">First, a description is given of the calculation of the factor α [i]. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 8</figref>, the adjustment unit 46 calculates the distance L[i] between the position P[i] of the sound collecting device M[i] in the space R at which the sound was recorded and the position P<sub>U</sub> of the sound receiving point U specified in the sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub> for each of the N positions P[1] to P[N]. For example, the distance L[i] is a Euclidean distance calculated from the coordinates (xi, yi) of the position P[i] and the coordinates (xU, yU) of the position P<sub>U</sub> in the x-y plane. The adjustment unit 46 calculates, as the factor α [i], the ratio of the inverse of the distance L[i] to the total sum of the inverses of the distances L[1] to L[N] calculated respectively for the N positions P[1] to P[N] as defined by the following Equation (3). <maths id="math0003" num="(3)"><math display="block"><mi>α</mi><mfenced open="[" close="]"><mi>i</mi></mfenced><mo>=</mo><mfrac><mfrac><mn>1</mn><mrow><mi>L</mi><mfenced open="[" close="]"><mi>i</mi></mfenced></mrow></mfrac><mrow><mstyle displaystyle="true"><munderover><mo>∑</mo><mrow><mi>n</mi><mo>=</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mi>N</mi></munderover></mstyle><mfrac><mn>1</mn><mrow><mi>L</mi><mfenced open="[" close="]"><mi>n</mi></mfenced></mrow></mfrac></mrow></mfrac></math><img id="ib0003" file="imgb0003.tif" wi="59" he="35" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths><br/>
As can be understood from Equation (3), the factor α[i] increases as the position P<sub>U</sub> of the sound receiving point U and<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --> the position P[i] of the sound collecting device M[i] at which the sound was recorded get closer to each other (i.e., as the distance L[i] decreases). Accordingly, the influence of the sound element data D<sub>S</sub>[i] of the sound data D[i] (i.e., the influence of the envelope E[i] and the frequency spectrum S[i]) upon the envelope E<sub>A</sub> or the frequency spectrum S<sub>A</sub> generated by the adjustment unit 46 increases as the position P[i] at which the sound data D[i] is recorded gets closer to the sound receiving point U (i.e., the position P<sub>U</sub>) designated by the user.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">Next, a description is given of the calculation of the factor β[i]. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 9</figref>, the adjustment unit 46 calculates the angle of elevation θ[i] between the direction of the position P[i] of each sound collecting device M[i] from the position P<sub>U</sub> of the sound receiving point U designated in the sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub> and the sound receiving direction d<sub>U</sub> designated in the sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub> for each of the N positions P[1] to P[N]. The sound receiving direction d<sub>U</sub> is a reference direction from which the angle θ[i] is measured (i.e., the angle θ[i] of the sound receiving direction d<sub>U</sub> is 0). The angle θ[i] is calculated using both the position P<sub>U</sub> (coordinates (xU, yU)) designated in the sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub> and the position P[i] (coordinates (xi, yi)) designated in the sound data D[i].<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --></p><p id="p0040" num="0040">The adjustment unit 46 then calculates a sensitivity r[i] of a sound wave that arrives at the sound receiving point U at the angle θ[i] using a sensitivity function corresponding to the directionality mode t<sub>U</sub> designated in the sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub>. The sensitivity function defines the sensitivity of a sound wave arriving at the sound receiving point U in each direction. For example, a sensitivity function of Equation (4A) is used when unidirectionality (i.e., cardioid) has been designated as the directionality mode t<sub>U</sub>, a sensitivity function of Equation (4B) is used when omnidirectionality has been designated as the directionality mode t<sub>U</sub>, and a sensitivity function of Equation (4C) is used when bidirectionality has been designated as the directionality mode t<sub>U</sub>. <maths id="math0004" num="(4A)"><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">r</mi><mfenced open="[" close="]"><mi mathvariant="normal">i</mi></mfenced><mo>=</mo><mn mathvariant="normal">1</mn><mo>/</mo><mn mathvariant="normal">2</mn><mo>⋅</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">cosθ</mi><mfenced open="[" close="]"><mi mathvariant="normal">i</mi></mfenced><mo>+</mo><mn mathvariant="normal">1</mn><mo>/</mo><mn mathvariant="normal">2</mn></math><img id="ib0004" file="imgb0004.tif" wi="88" he="9" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> <maths id="math0005" num="(4B)"><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">r</mi><mfenced open="[" close="]"><mi mathvariant="normal">i</mi></mfenced><mo>=</mo><mn mathvariant="normal">1</mn></math><img id="ib0005" file="imgb0005.tif" wi="54" he="8" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths> <maths id="math0006" num="(4C)"><math display="block"><mi mathvariant="normal">r</mi><mfenced open="[" close="]"><mi mathvariant="normal">i</mi></mfenced><mo>=</mo><mi mathvariant="normal">cosθ</mi><mfenced open="[" close="]"><mi mathvariant="normal">i</mi></mfenced></math><img id="ib0006" file="imgb0006.tif" wi="66" he="9" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0041" num="0041">The adjustment unit 46 calculates, as the factor β[i], the product of the sound receiving sensitivity h<sub>U</sub> designated in the sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub> and the ratio of the sensitivity r[i] to the total sum of the sensitivities r[1] to r[N] calculated respectively for the N positions P[1] to P[N] as defined by the following Equation (5).<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> <maths id="math0007" num="(5)"><math display="block"><mi>β</mi><mfenced open="[" close="]"><mi>i</mi></mfenced><mo>=</mo><mi mathvariant="italic">hU</mi><mo>⋅</mo><mfrac><mrow><mi>r</mi><mfenced open="[" close="]"><mi>i</mi></mfenced></mrow><mrow><mstyle displaystyle="true"><munderover><mo>∑</mo><mrow><mi>n</mi><mo>=</mo><mn>1</mn></mrow><mi>N</mi></munderover></mstyle><mi>r</mi><mfenced open="[" close="]"><mi>n</mi></mfenced></mrow></mfrac></math><img id="ib0007" file="imgb0007.tif" wi="86" he="37" img-content="math" img-format="tif"/></maths></p><p id="p0042" num="0042">The factor β[i] increases as the sensitivity r[i] increases as can be understood from Equation (5). Accordingly, the influence of the sound element data D<sub>S</sub>[i] of the sound data D[i] (i.e., the influence of the envelope E[i] and the frequency spectrum S[i]) upon the envelope E<sub>A</sub> or the frequency spectrum S<sub>A</sub> generated by the adjustment unit 46 increases as the sensitivity of sound reception at the sound receiving point U (i.e., at the position P<sub>U</sub>) increases, for which the user has designated the directionality mode t<sub>U</sub> and the sound receiving direction d<sub>U</sub>, in the direction from the position P[i] at which the sound data D[i] was collected.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">As described above, in this embodiment, the envelope E[i] or the frequency spectrum S[i] specified by the sound element data D<sub>S</sub>[i] is used to generate the envelope E<sub>A</sub> or the frequency spectrum S<sub>A</sub> after the envelope E[i] or the frequency spectrum S[i] is weighted according to relations (such as the distance L[i] and the angle θ[i]) between the position P[i] of the sound collecting point (i.e., the sound collecting device<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --> M[i]) in the space R and the position P<sub>U</sub> designated by the user. Accordingly, it is possible to synthesize a sound that would be received by a virtual sound receiving point U assuming that the virtual sound receiving point U was disposed at the position P<sub>U</sub> in the space R. In addition, since sound receiving attributes at the sound receiving point U such as the directionality mode t<sub>U</sub>, the sound receiving sensitivity h<sub>U</sub>, and the sound receiving direction d<sub>U</sub> are variably set according to an instruction from the user, this embodiment has an advantage in that it is possible to synthesize a sound that would be received by a sound receiving device having characteristics desired by the user when the sound receiving device is virtually disposed in the space R.</p><heading id="h0008">&lt;B: Second Embodiment&gt;</heading><p id="p0044" num="0044">The following is a description of the second embodiment of the invention. In each of the following embodiments, the same elements as those of the first embodiment are denoted by the same reference numerals and a detailed description thereof is appropriately omitted.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045"><figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 10</figref> is a schematic diagram of a sound receiving setting image 60 in this embodiment. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 10</figref>, a plurality of (K) sound receiving points U are disposed in a work area 62 according to an operation that the user performs<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --> on the input device 22. For each of the K sound receiving points U, the setting unit 44 individually sets a position P<sub>U</sub>, a directionality mode t<sub>U</sub>, a sound receiving sensitivity h<sub>U</sub>, and a sound receiving direction d<sub>U</sub> of the sound receiving point U according to an operation performed on the input device 22. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 11</figref>, sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub> stored in the storage device 12 includes variables such as the position P<sub>U</sub>, the directionality mode t<sub>U</sub>, the sound receiving sensitivity h<sub>U</sub>, and the sound receiving direction d<sub>U</sub> that the setting unit 44 have set for each of the K sound receiving points U (U1, U2, ..., UK).</p><p id="p0046" num="0046">For each of the K sound receiving points U, the adjustment unit 46 generates an envelope E<sub>A</sub> and a frequency spectrum S<sub>A</sub> according to variables corresponding to the sound receiving point U in the sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub> using the same method as that of the first embodiment. For each of the K sound receiving points U, the sound synthesis unit 42 generates a sound signal S<sub>OUT</sub> according to the envelope E<sub>A</sub> and the frequency spectrum S<sub>A</sub> that the adjustment unit 46 has calculated for the sound receiving point U using the same method as that of the first embodiment. The K sound signals S<sub>OUT</sub> generated in this manner are output to the sound output device 26 after being mixed together through the sound synthesis unit 42. In addition to the same advantages as those<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --> of the first embodiment, this embodiment has an advantage in that it is possible to synthesize sounds that would be received by a plurality of sound receiving points U in the space R.</p><heading id="h0009">&lt;C: Third Embodiment&gt;</heading><p id="p0047" num="0047"><figref idrefs="f0010">FIG. 12</figref> is a block diagram of a sound synthesizer 100 according to the third embodiment of the invention. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0010">FIG. 12</figref>, a storage device 12 of this embodiment stores a plurality of sound data groups G and a plurality of sound data Do. Each of the plurality of the sound data groups G is individually generated from each of a plurality of sounds having different characteristics (for example, vocal sounds generated by different persons u or vocal sounds generated in different spaces R), and includes a plurality of sound data Do representing the features of sounds that have been collected in parallel at individual positions, similar to the first embodiment. Similar to the sound data D, each of the plurality of the sound data Do includes a plurality of sound element data D<sub>S</sub> respectively representing the features of a plurality of sound elements of a sound received by a single sound collecting device.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048"><figref idrefs="f0011">FIG. 13</figref> is a schematic diagram of a music editing image 50. The user allocates a desired sound data group G or sound<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --> data Do to each indicator C<sub>A</sub> (each designated sound) in a work area 52 by appropriately operating an input device 22. An information generation unit 32 stores the identifier of the sound data group G or sound data Do, which the user has allocated to the designated sound, in music information Q<sub>A</sub> in association with the designated sound. For each selected designated sound for which the identifier of the sound data group G is set in the music information Q<sub>A</sub>, a sound synthesis unit 42 synthesizes a sound signal S<sub>OUT</sub> using the sound data group G and sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub> according to the same method as that of the first embodiment. For each selected designated sound for which the identifier of the sound data Do is set in the music information Q<sub>A</sub>, the sound synthesis unit 42 synthesizes a sound signal S<sub>OUT</sub> using an envelope E and a frequency spectrum S represented by sound element data D<sub>S</sub> of the sound data Do as an envelope E<sub>A</sub> and a frequency spectrum S<sub>A</sub> according to the same method as that of <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 7</figref>.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0011">FIG. 13</figref>, a display controller 34 displays each indicator C<sub>A</sub> to which a sound data group G has been allocated and each indicator C<sub>A</sub> to which sound data Do has been allocated on a display device 24 in different modes. The modes of the indicator C<sub>A</sub> are states of the indicator C<sub>A</sub> which allow the user to visually identify the indicator C<sub>A</sub>. Typical examples of the modes of the indicator C<sub>A</sub> include display color<!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --> attributes (such as hue, brightness, and saturation), shapes, or sizes of the indicator C<sub>A</sub>. By identifying the mode of each indicator C<sub>A</sub>, the user can discriminate between each designated sound to which a sound data group G has been allocated and each designated sound to which sound data Do has been allocated. This embodiment achieves the same advantages as those of the first embodiment.</p><heading id="h0010">&lt;D: Modifications&gt;</heading><p id="p0050" num="0050">Various modifications can be made to each of the above embodiments. The following are specific examples of such modifications. It is also possible to optimally select and combine two or more from the above embodiments or the following modifications.</p><heading id="h0011">(1) Modification 1</heading><p id="p0051" num="0051">Although each of the above embodiments has been exemplified by the case where a plurality of persons u generate vocal sounds in the space R when a sound data group G is generated (i.e., the case where a sound data group G of choral sounds is generated), it is also preferable to employ a configuration wherein a sound data group G is generated from a (solo) vocal sound generated by one person u. Although a human vocal sound is collected to generate sound data D (sound data Do in the third embodiment) in each of the above embodiments,<!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --> it is also possible to employ a configuration wherein the sound data D (Do) represents a sound played by an instrument.</p><heading id="h0012">(2) Modification 2</heading><p id="p0052" num="0052">Although each of the above embodiments has been exemplified by the case where sound collecting points (sound collecting devices M[i]) are disposed in plane (i.e., in two dimensions) in the space R, each of the above embodiments is applied in the same manner to the case where sound collecting points (sound collecting devices M[i]) are disposed in three dimensions in the space R. In the case where sound collecting points (sound collecting devices M[i]) are disposed in three dimensions, each position P[i] is defined by 3-dimensional coordinates in an x-y-z space R.</p><heading id="h0013">(3) Modification 3</heading><p id="p0053" num="0053">The sound synthesis unit 42 may use any known technology to synthesize a sound. A method for reflecting the sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub> in the synthesized sound is appropriately selected according to the synthesis method used by the sound synthesis unit 42 (specifically, according to variables used for synthesis). In addition, although sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub> (specifically, weights W[1] to W[N]) is reflected in both the envelopes E[1] to E[N] and the frequency spectrums S[1] to S[N] in each of the above<!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --> embodiments, it is also possible to employ, for example, a configuration wherein the envelope E<sub>A</sub> is generated according to the sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub> using the method of <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 6</figref> while one of the frequency spectrums S[1] to S[N] (or the average of the frequency spectrums S[1] to S[N]) is used as the frequency spectrum S<sub>A</sub> of <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 7</figref>.</p><heading id="h0014">(4) Modification 4</heading><p id="p0054" num="0054">The contents of the sound receiving information Q<sub>B</sub> are changed appropriately from the above examples. For example, at least one of the directionality mode t<sub>U</sub>, the sound receiving sensitivity h<sub>U</sub>, and the sound receiving direction d<sub>U</sub> is omitted. Only one type of sensitivity function is applied to calculate the factor β[i] in a configuration wherein the directionality mode t<sub>U</sub> is omitted and the variable hU of Equation (5) is set to a predetermined value (for example, "1") in a configuration wherein the sound receiving sensitivity h<sub>U</sub> is omitted. It is also preferable to employ a configuration wherein the calculation of Equation (1) or (2) is performed using only one of the factors α[i] and β[i] as the weight W[i]. As understood from the above examples, the invention preferably employs a configuration wherein a sound is synthesized by processing each of the plurality of the sound data D (D[1] to D[N]) according to the relation (such as the distance L[i] or the angle θ[i]) between the position P<sub>U</sub> of the sound receiving<!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --> point U and the sound collecting position P[i] corresponding to the sound data D[i].</p><p id="p0055" num="0055">(5) Modification 5<br/>
The contents of the sound element data D<sub>S</sub> are not limited to the above examples such as the frequency spectrum S and the envelope E. For example, it is also possible to employ a configuration wherein the sound element data D<sub>S</sub> represents a waveform of the sound element on the time axis. In the case where the sound element data D<sub>S</sub> represents the waveform of the sound element, the sound synthesis unit 42 uses, for example, the sound element data D<sub>S</sub> to synthesize the sound after calculating the frequency spectrum S or the envelope E by performing frequency analysis including discrete Fourier transform on the sound element data D<sub>S</sub>.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56986898" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="40"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Klangsynthesizer (100), aufweisend:
<claim-text>einen Speicher (12), in dem mehrere Klangdaten gespeichert sind, die entsprechend mehrere Klänge repräsentieren, die von verschiedenen Klangsammelpunkten (P) in einem Raum (R) gesammelt wurden, die den mehreren Klangdaten entsprechen; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Klangsyntheseeinheit (42),</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die Klangsyntheseeinheit ferner aufweist:
<claim-text>eine Einstelleinheit (44), die eine Position eines virtuellen Klangempfangspunkts (U) in dem Raum (R) gemäß einem Befehl von einem Benutzer variabel einstellt;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Anzeigesteuerung (34) zum Steuern einer Anzeigevorrichtung (24) zum Anzeigen der Klangsammelpunkte (P) und der Position des virtuellen Klangempfangspunkts darauf, und</claim-text>
<claim-text>dass die Klangsyntheseeinheit (42) durch Verarbeiten eines jeden der mehreren Klangdaten gemäß einer Beziehung zwischen einer Position des den Klangdaten entsprechenden Klangsammelpunkts (P) und der Position des virtuellen Klangempfangspunkts (U) einen Klang synthetisiert.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Klangsynthesizer (100) gemäß Anspruch 1,<br/>
wobei die Klangsyntheseeinheit (42) den Klang durch Verarbeiten eines jeden der mehreren Klangdaten gemäß einem Abstand zwischen dem den Klangdaten entsprechenden Klangsammelpunkt (P) und dem virtuellen Klangempfangspunkt (U) synthetisiert.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Klangsynthesizer (100) gemäß Anspruch 1 oder 2,<br/>
wobei die Einstelleinheit (44) ein Richtungsabhängigkeitsattribut des virtuellen Klangempfangspunkts (U) gemäß einem Befehl von einem Benutzer variabel einstellt, und<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="41"> -->die Klangsyntheseeinheit (42) den Klang durch Verarbeiten eines jeden der mehreren Klangdaten gemäß einer Empfindlichkeit synthetisiert, die das Richtungsabhängigkeitsattribut für eine von dem virtuellen Klangempfangspunkt (U) ausgehende Richtung des den Klangdaten entsprechenden Klangsammelpunkts (P) repräsentiert.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Klangsynthesizer (100) gemäß Anspruch 3,<br/>
wobei die Einstelleinheit (44) mindestens entweder eine Klangempfangsrichtung oder einen Richtungsabhängigkeitstyp als das Richtungsabhängigkeitsattribut des virtuellen Klangempfangspunkts (U) einstellt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Klangsynthesizer (100) gemäß einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 4,<br/>
wobei die Klangsyntheseeinheit (42) eine Hüllkurve eines Frequenzspektrums eines Klangs, der von jedem der mehreren Klangdaten repräsentiert wird, um einen Faktor gemäß einer Beziehung zwischen der Position des den Klangdaten entsprechenden Klangsammelpunkts (P) und der Position des virtuellen Klangempfangspunkts (U) gewichtet, dann durch Summieren der gewichteten Hüllkurven der Frequenzspektren der Klänge, die entsprechend von den mehreren Klangdaten repräsentiert werden, eine neue Hüllkurve berechnet und den Klang auf der Grundlage der neuen Hüllkurve synthetisiert.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Maschinenlesbares Aufzeichnungsmedium zur Verwendung in einem Computer, der einen Prozessor, eine Anzeigevorrichtung (24) und einen Speicher aufweist, in dem mehrere Klangdaten gespeichert sind, die entsprechend mehrere Klänge repräsentieren, die von verschiedenen Klangsammelpunkten (P) in einem Raum (R) gesammelt wurden, die den mehreren Klangdaten entsprechen, wobei das Medium Programmbefehle enthält, die von dem Prozessor ausführbar sind, um einen Klangsyntheseprozess und einen Anzeigesteuerungsprozess zum Steuern der Anzeigevorrichtung (24) zum Anzeigen der Klangsammelpunkte (P) durchzuführen,<br/>
<b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> das Medium ferner Programmbefehle enthält, die von dem Prozessor ausführbar sind, um<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="42"> -->einen Einstellprozess zum variablen Einstellen einer Position eines virtuellen Klangempfangspunkts (U) in dem Raum (R) gemäß einem Befehl von einem Benutzer auf der Anzeigevorrichtung (24) durchzuführen; und<br/>
dadurch dass der Klangsyntheseprozess durch Verarbeiten eines jeden der mehreren Klangdaten gemäß einer Beziehung zwischen einer Position des den Klangdaten entsprechenden Klangsammelpunkts (P) und der Position des virtuellen Klangempfangspunkts (U) synthetisiert.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56986899" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A sound synthesizer (100) comprising:
<claim-text>a storage (12) that stores a plurality of sound data respectively representing a plurality of sounds collected by different sound collecting points (P) in a space (R)<br/>
corresponding to the plurality of the sound data; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a sound synthesis unit (42),<br/>
<b>characterized in that</b> said sound synthesizer further comprises</claim-text>
<claim-text>a setting unit (44) that variably sets a position of a virtual sound receiving point (U) in said space (R) according to an instruction from a user;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a display controller (34) for controlling a display device (24) to display thereon the<br/>
sound collecting points (P) and the position of the virtual sound receiving point and</claim-text>
<claim-text>that said sound synthesis unit (42) synthesizes a sound by processing each of the plurality of the sound data according to a relation between a position of the sound collecting point (P) corresponding to the sound data and the position of the virtual sound receiving point (U).</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="36"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The sound synthesizer (100) according to claim 1, wherein the sound synthesis unit (42) synthesizes the sound by processing each of the plurality of the sound data according to a distance between the sound collecting point (P) corresponding to the sound data and the virtual sound receiving point (U).<!-- EPO <DP n="37"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The sound synthesizer (100) according to claim 1 or 2, wherein the setting unit (44) variably sets a directionality attribute of the virtual sound receiving point (U) according to an instruction from a user, and<br/>
the sound synthesis unit (42) synthesizes the sound by processing each of the plurality of the sound data according to sensitivity that the directionality attribute represents for a direction of the sound collecting point (P) corresponding to the sound data from the virtual sound receiving point (U).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The sound synthesizer (100) according to claim 3, wherein the setting unit (44) sets at least one of a sound receiving direction and a directionality type as the directionality attribute of the virtual sound receiving point (U).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The sound synthesizer (100) according to any one of claims 1 to 4, wherein the sound synthesis unit (42) weights an envelope of a frequency spectrum of a sound represented by each of the plurality of the sound data by a factor according to a relation between the position of the sound collecting point (P) corresponding to the sound data<!-- EPO <DP n="38"> --> and the position of the virtual sound receiving point (U), then calculates a new envelope by summing the weighted envelopes of the frequency spectrums of the sounds represented respectively by the plurality of the sound data, and synthesizes the sound based on the rew envelope.<!-- EPO <DP n="39"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>A machine readable recording medium for use in a computer having a processor, a display device(24) and a storage that stores a plurality of sound data respectively representing a plurality of sounds collected by different sound collecting points (P) in a space (R) corresponding to the plurality of the sound data, the medium containing program instructions executable by the processor to perform a sound synthesis process and a display control process of controlling the display device (24) to display the sound collecting points (P),<br/>
<b>characterized in that</b> the medium further contains program instructions executable by the processor to perform<br/>
a setting process to variably set on the display device (24) a position of a virtual sound receiving point (U) in said space (R) according to an instruction from a user; and<br/>
<b>in that</b> said sound synthesis process synthesizes a sound by processing each of the plurality of the sound data according to a relation between a position of the sound collecting point (P) corresponding to the sound data and the position of the virtual sound receiving point (U).</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56986900" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="43"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Synthétiseur de sons (100) comprenant :
<claim-text>une mémoire (12) qui stocke une pluralité de données sonores représentant respectivement une pluralité de sons collectés par différents points de collecte de son (P) dans un espace (R) correspondant à la pluralité des données sonores ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>une unité de synthèse de sons (42),<br/>
<b>caractérisé en ce que</b> ledit synthétiseur de sons comprend en outre :</claim-text>
<claim-text>une unité de réglage (44) qui règle de façon variable une position d'un point virtuel de réception de son (U) dans ledit espace (R) selon une instruction émanant d'un utilisateur ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un dispositif de commande d'affichage (34) destiné à commander un dispositif d'affichage (24) afin que celui-ci affiche les points de collecte de son (P) et la position du point virtuel de réception de son et</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>en ce que</b> ladite unité de synthèse de sons (42) synthétise un son par traitement de chacune de la pluralité des données sonores selon une relation entre une position du point de collecte de son (P)<!-- EPO <DP n="44"> --> correspondant à la donnée sonore et la position du point virtuel de réception de son (U).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Synthétiseur de sons (100) selon la revendication 1, dans lequel l'unité de synthèse de sons (42) synthétise le son par traitement de chacune de la pluralité des données sonores en fonction d'une distance entre le point de collecte de son (P) correspondant à la donnée sonore et le point virtuel de réception de son (U).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Synthétiseur de sons (100) selon la revendication 1 ou 2, dans lequel l'unité de réglage (44) règle de façon variable un attribut de directivité du point virtuel de réception de son (U) selon une instruction émanant d'un utilisateur, et<br/>
l'unité de synthèse de sons (42) synthétise le son par traitement de chacune de la pluralité des données sonores selon la sensibilité que l'attribut de directivité représente pour une direction du point de collecte de son (P) correspondant à la donnée sonore à partir du point virtuel de réception de son (U).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Synthétiseur de sons (100) selon la revendication 3, dans lequel l'unité de réglage (44) règle au moins soit une direction de réception de son, soit un type de directivité, comme attribut de directivité du point virtuel de réception de son (U).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Synthétiseur de sons (100) selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 4, dans lequel l'unité de synthèse de sons (42) pondère une enveloppe d'un spectre fréquentiel d'un son représenté par chacune de la pluralité des données sonores d'un certain facteur selon une relation entre la position du<!-- EPO <DP n="45"> --> point de collecte de son (P) correspondant à la donnée sonore et la position du point virtuel de réception de son (U), puis calcule une nouvelle enveloppe par sommation des enveloppes pondérées des spectres fréquentiels des sons représentés respectivement par la pluralité des données sonores, et synthétise le son sur la base de la nouvelle enveloppe.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Support d'enregistrement lisible par machine et destiné à être utilisé dans un ordinateur ayant un processeur, un dispositif d'affichage (24) et une mémoire qui stocke une pluralité de données sonores représentant respectivement une pluralité de sons collectés par différents points de collecte de son (P) dans un espace (R) correspondant à la pluralité des données sonores, le support contenant des instructions de programme pouvant être exécutées par le processeur pour effectuer un procédé de synthèse de sons et un procédé de commande d'affichage consistant à ordonner au dispositif d'affichage (24) d'afficher les points de collecte de son (P),<br/>
<b>caractérisé en ce que</b> le support contient en outre des instructions de programme pouvant être exécutées par le processeur pour effectuer<br/>
un procédé de réglage destiné à régler de façon variable sur le dispositif d'affichage (24) une position d'un point virtuel de réception de son (U) dans ledit espace (R) selon une instruction émanant d'un utilisateur ; et<br/>
<b>en ce que</b> ledit procédé de synthèse de sons synthétise un son par traitement de chacune de la pluralité des données sonores selon une relation entre<!-- EPO <DP n="46"> --> une position du point de collecte de son (P) correspondant à la donnée sonore et la position du point virtuel de réception de son (U).</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16672587" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="47"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="149" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="48"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="165" he="165" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="49"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3A,3B,4"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="165" he="219" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="50"> --><figure id="f0004" num="5"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="157" he="224" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="51"> --><figure id="f0005" num="6"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="165" he="223" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="52"> --><figure id="f0006" num="7(A),7(B),7(C)"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="165" he="216" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="53"> --><figure id="f0007" num="8,9"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="165" he="210" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="54"> --><figure id="f0008" num="10"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="148" he="219" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="55"> --><figure id="f0009" num="11"><img id="if0009" file="imgf0009.tif" wi="130" he="231" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="56"> --><figure id="f0010" num="12"><img id="if0010" file="imgf0010.tif" wi="144" he="231" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="57"> --><figure id="f0011" num="13"><img id="if0011" file="imgf0011.tif" wi="165" he="152" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
