<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2116382-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2116382" kind="B1" date="20140101" family-id="40973166" file-reference-id="315033" date-produced="20180822" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146554109" ucid="EP-2116382-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2116382</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-09005654-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154828032" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>09005654</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20090422</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140449859" ucid="JP-2008122393-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>JP</country><doc-number>2008122393</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20080508</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130704</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988095880" load-source="ipcr">B41J  11/00        20060101AFI20090831BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988104910" load-source="ipcr">B41J  13/28        20060101ALI20090831BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988110283" load-source="ipcr">B41J  13/10        20060101ALI20090831BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988097048" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B41J  11/007       20130101 FI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988098674" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B41J  13/103       20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988122968" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B41J  13/28        20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132194811" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Aufzeichnungsvorrichtung</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132194812" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Recording apparatus</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132194813" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Appareil d'enregistrement</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918151516" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>CANON KK</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918146519" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>CANON KABUSHIKI KAISHA</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918143258" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>HIRAI YASUYUKI</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918173862" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>HIRAI, YASUYUKI</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918998834" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>HIRAI, YASUYUKI</last-name><address><street>c/o Canon Kabushiki Kaisha, 30-2, Shimomaruko 3-chome, Ohta-ku</street><city>Tokyo</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918998836" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>CANON KABUSHIKI KAISHA</last-name><iid>100094804</iid><address><street>30-2, Shimomaruko 3-chome Ohta-ku</street><city>Tokyo</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918998835" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Weser, Wolfgang</last-name><iid>100006441</iid><address><street>Weser &amp; Kollegen Patentanwälte Radeckestrasse 43</street><city>81245 München</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548831665" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS548992400" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS548984702" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS548874559" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS548990511" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS548831666" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS548887147" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548992401" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS548990512" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS548987517" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS548984703" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS548984704" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548887148" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548992402" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS548992403" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS548990517" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS548874560" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS548992404" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS548984705" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS548990518" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS548887149" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS548831667" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS548887150" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS548887151" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS548985444" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS548985445" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS548987518" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS548984706" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS548987519" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS548984707" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS548987520" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS548987525" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS548874561" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS548985450" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS548990519" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63957608" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading><heading id="h0002">Field of the Invention</heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to a recording apparatus having a conveying belt which absorbs a recording sheet fed by a paper feed section to record on the recording sheet absorbed by the conveying belt.</p><heading id="h0003">Related Background Art</heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">Conventionally, in a recording apparatus which conveys a recording sheet by driving a belt that absorbs the recording sheet onto the belt surface by static electricity, a power feed roller abutting against the belt surface has generated electric charges on the belt surface.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">Japanese Patent Application Laid-Open No. <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="JP2000143026A"><text>2000-143026</text></patcit> discloses an arrangement for generating electric charges on a belt by applying a voltage to a driving roller which drives the belt, as an arrangement without the use of a power feed roller.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">Meanwhile, the recording apparatus is required to correct skew feeding of a recording sheet before conveying the recording sheet to an area opposite to a recording head in order to prevent the recording sheet from being conveyed in an inclined condition when the recording head starts a recording operation. In a recording apparatus having a belt<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> conveying section which conveys the recording sheet absorbed on the belt surface, a paper feed section has been provided with a guide member for aligning both widthwise edges of the recording sheet in order to prevent an occurrence of skew feeding in a paper feed stage. Moreover, in another arrangement, a registration roller pair has been provided to correct skew feeding of the recording sheet upstream from the belt conveying section.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">In recent years, the recording apparatus has been required to support recording sheets of various sizes such as business card, A4, A3, rolled letter paper, and other sizes. In the above-described arrangement in which the paper feed section is provided with the guide member for aligning both widthwise edges of the recording sheet, the guide member is effective to reduce the occurrence of skew feeding, in the case of feeding a large-sized recording sheet, due to the long dimension of the recording sheet guided by the guide member. On the other hand, in the case of feeding a small-sized recording sheet, the guide member is ineffective to prevent the occurrence of skew feeding because the recording sheet comes off the guide member when the recording sheet is conveyed to the belt conveying section due to the short dimension of the recording sheet guided by the guide member. Moreover, the arrangement provided with the foregoing<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> registration roller pair has a problem that the provision increases the number of parts and the size of apparatus.</p><heading id="h0004">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading><p id="p0006" num="0006">In view of the above problems, an object of the present invention is to provide a recording apparatus capable of reliably correcting skew feeding of a recording sheet in an arrangement for conveying the recording sheet absorbed by a belt surface.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">To achieve the above object, the present invention provides the recording apparatus according to claims 1 or 11.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p><p id="p0008" num="0008">The other claims relate to further developments.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">According to the present invention, a recording apparatus is provided which is capable of reliably correcting skew feeding of a recording sheet in an arrangement for conveying the recording sheet absorbed by a belt surface.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">Further features of the present invention will become apparent from the following description of exemplary embodiments with reference to the attached drawings.</p><heading id="h0005">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading><p id="p0011" num="0011"><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a side view of a recording apparatus<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> according to a first embodiment of the present invention.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012"><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> is a side view illustrating a conveying section and a paper delivery section of the recording apparatus according to the first embodiment of the present invention.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013"><figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> is a side view illustrating a belt conveying section of the recording apparatus according to the first embodiment of the present invention.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014"><figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 4</figref> is a side view illustrating a drive section of the conveying section and that of the paper delivery section of the recording apparatus according to the first embodiment of the present invention.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015"><figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 5</figref> is a side view illustrating a carriage section of the recording apparatus according to the first embodiment of the present invention.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016"><figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 6</figref> is a side view illustrating an operation of correcting skew feeding of the recording apparatus according to the first embodiment of the present invention.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017"><figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 7</figref> is a side view of a recording apparatus according to a second embodiment of the present invention.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018"><figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 8</figref> is a side view of a recording apparatus according to a third embodiment of the present invention.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019"><figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 9</figref> is a side view of a recording<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> apparatus according to a fifth embodiment of the present invention.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020"><figref idrefs="f0010">FIG. 10</figref> is a side view of a recording apparatus according to a sixth embodiment of the present invention.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021"><figref idrefs="f0011">FIG. 11</figref> is a plan view illustrating the configuration of a pinching roller holder according to the sixth embodiment of the present invention.</p><heading id="h0006">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENTS</heading><p id="p0022" num="0022">An embodiment of the present invention will be described in detail below with reference to accompanying drawings.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">(First embodiment)</p><p id="p0024" num="0024"><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> shows a side view of a recording apparatus according to a first embodiment of the present invention. The recording apparatus 1 according to the first embodiment includes a paper feed section 100 for feeding a recording sheet P and a conveying section 200 for conveying the recording sheet P fed from the paper feed section 100 in the recording area. Moreover, the recording apparatus 1 includes a paper delivery section 300 disposed on the downstream side of the conveying section 200 in the recording sheet conveying direction for delivering the recording sheet where recording is completed to the outside of the apparatus. The recording apparatus 1 further includes a movable carriage section 400 which is<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> equipped with a recording head H for recording on the recording sheet P.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">A paper feed motor, which is not shown, drives the paper feed section 100. Upon driving of the paper feed motor, a pressure plate 101 on which recording sheets are stacked rises and thereby the top recording sheet P abuts against a paper feed roller 102. The paper feed roller 102 then rotates in the X direction shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> to pick up the recording sheet P. One recording sheet is then separated by the paper feed roller 102 and a separation roller 103 which abuts against the paper feed roller 102. The separated recording sheet P is guided by paper guides 104 and 105 and a pinching roller holder 211 and conveyed up to a conveying section 200.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026"><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> shows a side view illustrating a conveying section and a paper delivery section of the recording apparatus according to the first embodiment of the present invention. <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> shows a side view illustrating a belt conveying section of the recording apparatus according to the first embodiment of the present invention. The side views in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIGS. 2</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0003">3</figref> each show the recording apparatus viewed from the right side thereof. In the conveying section 200 a conveying belt 203 is wound around between a driving roller 201 and a driven roller 202. The driving roller 201 is supported by a platen 206 via a driving roller bearing<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> 204. The driven roller 202 is supported by the platen 206 via a driven roller bearing 205. Moreover, the driven roller 202 is biased in a direction of applying a tension to the conveying belt 203 by means of a driven roller spring 207 which is a compression spring. The driving roller 201 is biased by means of a pinching roller 208 via the conveying belt 203. The recording sheet P is able to be conveyed with being pinched between the conveying belt 203 wound around the driving roller 201 and the pinching roller 208. A discharging roller 209 abuts against the conveying belt 203 on the downstream side of the pinching roller 208 in the recording sheet conveying direction. The discharging roller 209 is rotatable following the movement of the conveying belt 203. The discharging roller 209 is capable of electrically discharging the surface of the conveying belt 203 or the recording surface of the recording sheet P.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">The driving roller 201 has a first roller 201a made of a metallic material and a second roller 201b made of an elastic material such as rubber along the axial direction. The first roller 201a is formed into a small-diameter roller relative to the second roller 201b. As a rubber material for forming the second roller 201b, for example, conductive rubber based on EPDM (ethylene-propylene-diene terpolymer) is used and the rubber hardness is preferably on the order of 50°<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> to 90°. Alternatively, materials having a relatively high friction coefficient may be used such that the second roller 201b is formed of a metal pipe, which is coated with conductive EPDM on the outer peripheral surface or with conductive urethane elastomer or conductive urethane coating applied on the outer peripheral surface.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">The driven roller 202 is made of a metallic material, having a first roller 202a and a second roller 202b along the axial direction. The first roller 202a is formed into a small-diameter roller relative to the second roller 202b. The second roller 202b may be formed of a pipe for weight saving purposes.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">The conveying belt 203 has a two-layer structure with an insulating layer on its front face and a conductive layer on its rear face. Alternatively, it is possible to use a single-layer belt having a high resistance and a high dielectric constant.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">The pinching roller 208 and the discharging roller 209 are supported by the pinching roller holder 211 made of a conductive material. The pinching roller holder 211 is attached to a chassis 500 made of a metallic material. The chassis 500 is grounded, thereby enabling the pinching roller 208 and the discharging roller 209 to be grounded. The pinching roller 208 has a first roller 208a made of a metallic material and a second roller 208b made of an elastic<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> material such as rubber along the axial direction. The first roller 208a is formed into a small-diameter roller relative to the second roller 208b. As a rubber material for forming the second roller 208b, for example, conductive rubber based on EPDM is used and the rubber hardness is preferably on the order of 50° to 90°. The discharging roller 209 is made of a metallic material, having a first roller 209a and a second roller 209b along the axial direction. Moreover, the first roller 209a is formed into a small-diameter roller relative to the second roller 209b. A conductive plastic material may be employed for both of the pinching roller 208 and the discharging roller 209. The pinching roller 208 and the discharging roller 209 are pressed to the conveying belt 203 by means of a pinching roller spring 212 and a discharging roller spring, which is not shown, respectively.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">The platen 206 has a plurality of ribs in the recording sheet conveying direction and in a direction intersecting with the conveying direction. The conveying belt 203 is guided by the ribs while rotating. The ribs define a distance between the conveying belt 203 and the recording head H.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032"><figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 4</figref> shows a side view illustrating a drive section of the conveying section and that of the paper delivery section of the recording apparatus according to the first embodiment of the present invention. The<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> side view in <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 4</figref> shows the recording apparatus viewed from the left side thereof. In <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 4</figref>, a conveyance motor 221 is used to drive the driving roller 201. The drive of the conveyance motor 221 is transmitted to the driving roller 201 via a driving belt 222 and a driving roller pulley 223. A rotary encoder 224 is attached to the shaft of the driving roller 201. The rotary encoder 224 is used to detect an amount of rotation of the driving roller 201. A slit is printed on the rotary encoder 224 and an encoder sensor 225 reads the slit. Moreover, a metal plate 210 connected to a power supply abuts against the side surface of the first roller 201a of the driving roller 201. A voltage is applied to the driving roller 201 via the metal plate 210.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">The paper delivery section 300 has a paper delivery roller 301, a spur 302 which is driven by the paper delivery roller 301 to rotate, and a spur holder 303 which rotatably supports the spur 302. The paper delivery section 300 has a spur stay 304 which is attached to the chassis 500 to support the spur holder 303.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">The paper delivery roller 301 has a first roller 301a made of a metallic material and a second roller 301b made of an elastic material such as rubber along the axial direction. The first roller 301a is formed into a small-diameter roller relative to the<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> second roller 301b. As a rubber material for forming the second roller 301b, for example, conductive rubber based on EPDM is used and the rubber hardness is preferably on the order of 50° to 90°. Alternatively, materials having a relatively high friction coefficient may be used such that the second roller 301b is coated with urethane elastomer or urethane coating applied on the surface. Further, coating containing ceramic particles may be applied to the surface of the second roller 301b. A paper delivery roller pulley 232 is provided on the shaft of the paper delivery roller 301. In addition, a paper delivery driving belt 231 is wound around between the driving roller pulley 223 and the paper delivery roller pulley 232. The paper delivery roller 301 is driven via the paper delivery driving belt 231 and the paper delivery roller pulley 232.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035"><figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 5</figref> shows a side view illustrating the carriage section 400 of the recording apparatus according to the first embodiment of the present invention. The side view in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 5</figref> shows the recording apparatus viewed from the right side thereof. The carriage section 400 moves the recording head H to record on the recording sheet P. The carriage section 400 includes a carriage 401 for mounting the recording head H and a driving member of the carriage 401. The carriage 401 is guided by a guide shaft 402 and a guide rail 403 which are attached to the chassis 500 when<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> moving in the width direction of the recording sheet P.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">The recording apparatus 1 moves the carriage 401 according to a recording signal to record on the recording sheet P. Moreover, the recording apparatus 1 intermittently conveys the recording sheet P by rotating the driving roller 201 to move the conveying belt 203. The recording apparatus 1 records on the entire recording sheet P by repeating these operations. Upon completion of the recording, the recording sheet P is pinched between the paper delivery roller 301 and the spur 302 and conveyed so as to be delivered to the outside of the recording apparatus.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037"><figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 6</figref> shows a side view illustrating an operation of correcting skew feeding of the recording apparatus according to the first embodiment of the present invention. In <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 6</figref>, a paper feed motor, which is not shown, is driven to rotate the paper feed roller 102 in the X direction indicated by an arrow in the figure, thereby feeding one of the recording sheets P stacked on the pressure plate 101. The fed recording sheet P is fed toward the pinching section formed by the driving roller 201 and the pinching roller 208 via the conveying belt 203. During this operation, the driving roller 201 is standing still. The front edge of the recording sheet P strikes against the pinching section formed by the driving roller 201 and the pinching roller 208. Thereafter, an additional<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> rotation of the paper feed roller 102 aligns the front edge of the recording sheet P along the pinching section. In other words, the skew feeding of the recording sheet P is corrected and thus the recording sheet P is registered.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">After the correction of the skew feeding of the recording sheet P, the recording apparatus 1 applies a voltage to the driving roller 201 via the metal plate 210. Thereby, electric charges appear on the surface of the conveying belt 203 and thereby the conveying belt 203 charges with electricity. This enables the conveying belt 203 to absorb the front edge of the recording sheet P. While the applied voltage is variable according to the type of the recording sheet, temperature, humidity and other operating environments, generally about 2 kV is applied. In this embodiment, the driving roller for driving the conveying belt is used to generate electric charges on the conveying belt and to perform registration for correcting the skew feeding of the fed recording sheet. Moreover, the skew feeding of the recording sheet is corrected before generating the electric charges on the conveying belt, thereby enabling a reliable correction of the skew feeding of the recording sheet.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">After the correction of the skew feeding of the recording sheet and the generation of the electric charges on the conveying belt 203, the recording<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> apparatus 1 rotates the driving roller 201 to convey the recording sheet up to the recording start position and then performs recording by means of the recording head H. The conveying belt 203 conveys the recording sheet in an area from a portion in contact with the driving roller 201 to a portion in contact with the driven roller 202. The driving roller 201 is located at the upstream end of the conveying portion of the conveying belt 203. This configuration prevents a delay in the start of moving the recording sheet P, in response to the start of driving the driving roller 201, due to the expansion and contraction of the belt or flip-flop thereof when the conveyance of the recording sheet P is started after the correction of the skew feeding of the recording sheet P.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">(Second embodiment)</p><p id="p0041" num="0041"><figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 7</figref> shows a side view of a recording apparatus according to a second embodiment of the present invention. In the second embodiment, the recording apparatus 1 has a wiper 251 for removing dirt and foreign substances attached to the surface of the conveying belt 203.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">The wiper 251 is formed of a plate-like rubber material such as urethane or of a thin plastic plate and is attached to a wiper holder 252. The wiper holder 252 is rotatable around the center of rotation. A biasing force of a wiper spring 253 presses an edge<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> 251a of the wiper 251 to the conveying belt 203. In this regard, the wiper 251 abuts against the conveying belt 203 in the counter direction to the conveying direction of the conveying belt 203. This configuration enables the efficient removal of the dirt and foreign substances attached to the conveying belt 203.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">On the other hand, the wiper 251 friction-slides the surface of the conveying belt 203. This electrically charges the surface of the conveying belt 203 that has passed through the wiper 251 as indicated by broken lines in <figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 7</figref>. In the case where the front edge of the recording sheet P abuts against the pinching section formed by the driving roller 201 and the pinching roller 208 in a state where the surface of the conveying belt 203 is strongly electrically charged, the recording sheet P could be absorbed by the conveying belt 203. In that case, the skew feeding correction might not be able to be fully performed.</p><p id="p0044" num="0044">Therefore, in this embodiment, the recording apparatus 1 rotates the driving roller 201 in the opposite direction to the conveying direction of the recording sheet P so that the portion electrically discharged by the discharging roller 209 of the conveying belt 203 comes to the pinching section formed by the driving roller 201 and the pinching roller 208. Thereafter, the front edge of the recording sheet P is<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> set to abut against the pinching section formed by the driving roller 201 and the pinching roller 208. In this embodiment, the recording apparatus 1 is able to reliably correct the skew feeding of the recording sheet by preventing the recording sheet from being absorbed by the conveying belt during the correction of the skew feeding of the recording sheet also in the arrangement with the wiper for friction-sliding the surface of the conveying belt.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045">(Third embodiment)</p><p id="p0046" num="0046"><figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 8</figref> shows a side view of a recording apparatus according to a third embodiment of the present invention. The recording apparatus 1 of the third embodiment is provided with a discharge brush in a path for feeding the recording sheet P between the paper feed section and the conveying section.</p><p id="p0047" num="0047">The recording sheet P fed by the paper feed roller 102 is guided by the paper guides 104 and 105 and the pinching roller holder 211 so as to be conveyed up to the conveying section 200. In this regard, the recording sheet P is electrically charged due to a contact between the recording sheet P and the paper guides 104 and 105. If the front edge of the electrically charged recording sheet P strikes against the pinching section formed by the driving roller 201 and the pinching roller 208, the conveying belt 203 could absorb the recording sheet P. In that case, the<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> skew feeding correction might not be able to be fully performed.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048">Therefore, the recording apparatus 1 of this embodiment is provided with a discharge brush 241 for discharging the electrically-charged recording sheet P due to abutment with the recording sheet P between the paper feed section 100 and the pinching section formed by the driving roller 201 and the pinching roller 208. According to this arrangement, the recording sheet P has already been electrically discharged when the front edge of the recording sheet P abuts against the pinching section formed by the driving roller 201 and the pinching roller 208, and therefore the conveying belt 203 does not absorb the recording sheet P. This arrangement enables the recording apparatus to reliably correct the skew feeding of the recording sheet. Moreover, the discharge brush 241 may be movably disposed in a position to abut against the fed recording sheet and in a position to be spaced apart from the recording sheet. The discharge brush 241 may move to such a position as to abut against the recording sheet P during feeding of the recording sheet P in order to electrically discharge the recording sheet P and then move to such a position as to be spaced apart from the recording sheet P after the skew feeding of the recording sheet P is corrected and the recording sheet P is absorbed by the conveying belt 203.<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --></p><p id="p0049" num="0049">(Fourth embodiment)</p><p id="p0050" num="0050">In the first to third embodiments, with the driving roller 201 in a stopped state, the recording apparatus 1 corrects the skew feeding of the recording sheet by abutting the front edge of the recording sheet P against the pinching section formed by the driving roller 201 and the pinching roller 208. In the fourth embodiment, the recording apparatus 1 corrects the skew feeding of the recording sheet by abutting the front edge of the recording sheet P against the driving roller 201 rotating in the opposite direction to the recording sheet conveying direction.</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">The recording sheet P fed by the paper feed roller 102 is fed toward the pinching section formed by the driving roller 201 and the pinching roller 208. The front edge of the recording sheet P is abutted against the pinching section formed by the driving roller 201, which is rotating in the opposite direction (in the direction indicated by an arrow B in <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 6</figref>) to the recording sheet conveying direction, and the pinching roller 208, which is rotating in the opposite direction following the driving roller 201. Thereafter, the paper feed roller 102 is further rotated, by which the front edge of the recording sheet P is aligned along the pinching section. In other words, the skew feeding of the recording sheet P is corrected and thereby the registration of the recording sheet P is<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> performed.</p><p id="p0052" num="0052">After the skew feeding correction of the recording sheet P, the recording apparatus 1 applies a voltage to the driving roller 201 via the metal plate 210. Thereby, electric charges appear on the surface of the conveying belt 203, thus enabling the conveying belt 203 to absorb the front edge of the recording sheet P. After the skew feeding correction of the recording sheet P and the electric charge generation on the conveying belt 203, the rotation of the driving roller 201 conveys the recording sheet up to the recording start position and then the recording apparatus 1 performs recording by means of the recording head H.</p><p id="p0053" num="0053">(Fifth embodiment)</p><p id="p0054" num="0054"><figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 9</figref> shows a side view of a recording apparatus according to a fifth embodiment of the present invention. In the fifth embodiment, the front edge of the recording sheet P is once passed through the pinching section formed by the driving roller 201 and the pinching roller 208 and then the rotation of the driving roller 201 is reversed to correct the skew feeding of the recording sheet.</p><p id="p0055" num="0055">The recording sheet P fed by the paper feed roller 102 is fed toward the pinching section formed by the driving roller 201 and the pinching roller 208. Upon detecting that the front edge of the recording<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> sheet P reaches the position, which is upstream from and a distance Y apart from the pinching section, by means of a sensor or the like, the recording apparatus 1 starts the driving of the conveyance motor 221 so that the driving roller 201 rotates in the recording sheet conveying direction. The Y value is determined according to the type and size of the recording sheet P and the operating environments. While the driving roller 201 is rotating in the direction indicated by an arrow A in <figref idrefs="f0009">FIG. 9</figref>, the recording apparatus 1 applies a voltage to the driving roller 201 via the metal plate 210. Thereby, electric charges appear on the surface of the conveying belt 203.</p><p id="p0056" num="0056">When the front edge of the recording sheet P reaches the pinching section formed by the driving roller 201 and the pinching roller 208, the recording sheet P is absorbed by the conveying belt 203 and passes through the pinching section to be conveyed to a recording area. Upon detecting that the front edge of the recording sheet P reaches the position a distance Z apart from the pinching section by means of a sensor or the like, the recording apparatus 1 stops the driving of the conveyance motor 221 and a paper feed motor, which is not shown. The Z value is determined according to the type and size of the recording sheet P and the operating environments, too.</p><p id="p0057" num="0057">Thereafter, the recording apparatus 1 rotates<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> the driving roller 201 in the opposite direction to the recording sheet conveying direction by reversing the direction of rotation of the conveyance motor 221 with the paper feed motor stopped. During this rotation, any voltage is not applied to the driving roller 201. Thereby, the recording sheet P is conveyed in the opposite direction and the front edge of the recording sheet P disengages from the pinching section formed by the driving roller 201 and the pinching roller 208. In this state, the rear part of the recording sheet P is pressed by the paper feed roller 102 which is stopped and therefore the front edge of the recording sheet P is aligned along the pinching section formed by the driving roller 201 and the pinching roller 208. In other words, the skew feeding of the recording sheet P is corrected and thereby the registration of the recording sheet.P is performed.</p><p id="p0058" num="0058">After the skew feeding correction of the recording sheet P, the recording apparatus 1 applies a voltage to the driving roller 201 via the metal plate 210. Thereby, electric charges appear on the surface of the conveying belt 203, thus enabling the conveying belt 203 to absorb the front edge of the recording sheet P. After the skew feeding correction of the recording sheet P and the electric charge generation on the conveying belt 203, the recording apparatus 1 rotates the driving roller 201 to convey the recording<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> sheet P up to the recording start position and performs recording by means of the recording head H.</p><p id="p0059" num="0059">(Sixth embodiment)</p><p id="p0060" num="0060">In the first to fifth embodiments, the recording apparatus 1 applies a voltage to the driving roller 201 to generate electric charges on the surface of the conveying belt 203 and to ground the pinching roller 208. In a sixth embodiment, the recording apparatus 1 applies a voltage to the pinching roller 208 to generate electric charges on the surface of the conveying belt 203 and to ground the driving roller 201.</p><p id="p0061" num="0061"><figref idrefs="f0010">FIG. 10</figref> shows a side view of a recording apparatus according to the sixth embodiment of the present invention. <figref idrefs="f0011">FIG. 11</figref> shows a plan view illustrating the configuration of a pinching roller holder according to the sixth embodiment of the present invention.</p><p id="p0062" num="0062">In <figref idrefs="f0011">FIG. 11</figref>, a non-conductive material is used to form the pinching roller holder 211 for rotatably supporting the pinching roller 208 in this embodiment. A metal plate 213, which is connected to the power supply, abuts on the side surface of the first roller 208a of the pinching roller 208. A voltage is applied to the pinching roller 208 via the metal plate 213.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980313" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Aufzeichnungsvorrichtung, umfassend:
<claim-text>einen Papierzuführabschnitt (100) zum Zuführen eines Aufzeichnungsbogens (P);</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Transportriemen (203) zum Aufnehmen und Transportieren des Aufzeichnungsbogens;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Antriebsrolle (201) zum Antreiben des um die Antriebsrolle geschlungenen Transportriemens und zum elektrischen Aufladen des Transportriemens durch Anlegen einer Spannung; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Andrückrolle (208), die an der Antriebsrolle über den Transportriemen anliegt;</claim-text>
<claim-text>derart konfiguriert, dass:
<claim-text>die Aufzeichnungsvorrichtung eine Aufzeichnung auf dem vom Transportriemen aufgenommenen Aufzeichnungsbogen ausführt; und <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die Aufzeichnungsvorrichtung weiterhin derart konfiguriert ist, dass</claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Andrückabschnitt, der durch die Antriebsrolle und die Andrückrolle gebildet wird, eine Schrägzufuhr des vom Papierzuführabschnitt zugeführten Aufzeichnungsbogens korrigiert, und dass anschließend die Spannung an die Antriebsrolle gelegt wird, um den Transportriemen elektrisch aufzuladen.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Aufzeichnungsvorrichtung nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Andrückrolle geerdet ist.<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Aufzeichnungsvorrichtung nach Anspruch 1, derart konfiguriert, dass die Schrägzufuhr des Aufzeichnungsbogens korrigiert wird durch Anlegen der Vorderkante des Aufzeichnungsbogens an den Andrückabschnitt, der durch die Antriebsrolle und die Andrückrolle gebildet wird, die angehalten werden.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Aufzeichnungsvorrichtung nach Anspruch 1, derart konfiguriert, dass die Schrägzufuhr des Aufzeichnungsbogens korrigiert wird durch Anlegen der Vorderkante des Aufzeichnungsbogens an den Andrückabschnitt, der durch die Antriebsrolle und die Andrückrolle gebildet wird, die in Gegenrichtung gedreht werden.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Aufzeichnungsvorrichtung nach Anspruch 3, wobei eine Entladungsrolle (209), die am Transportriemen anliegt, auf der in Transportrichtung des Aufzeichnungsbogens nachgelagerten Seite der Andrückrolle angeordnet ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Aufzeichnungsvorrichtung nach Anspruch 5, weiterhin umfassend einen Abstreifer (251), der am Transportriemen anliegt, um am Transportriemen haftende Fremdsubstanzen zu beseitigen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Aufzeichnungsvorrichtung nach Anspruch 6, derart konfiguriert, dass der Transportriemen in die zur Transportrichtung des Aufzeichnungsbogens entgegengesetzte Richtung bewegt wird, so dass ein von der Entladungsrolle elektrisch entladener Teil zum Andrückabschnitt gelangt, und anschließend die Vorderkante des Aufzeichnungsbogens an den Andrückabschnitt angelegt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Aufzeichnungsvorrichtung nach Anspruch 1, derart konfiguriert, dass die Vorderkante des Aufzeichnungsbogens einmal durch den durch die Antriebsrolle und die Andrückrolle gebildeten Andrückabschnitt geleitet wird, anschließend die Antriebsrolle in Rückwärtsrichtung gedreht wird, um den<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --> Aufzeichnungsbogen in die zur Transportrichtung des Aufzeichnungsbogens entgegengesetzte Richtung zu transportieren, und die Vorderkante des Aufzeichnungsbogens an den Andrückabschnitt angelegt wird, um die Schrägzufuhr des Aufzeichnungsbogens zu korrigieren.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Aufzeichnungsvorrichtung nach Anspruch 1, weiterhin umfassend eine Entladungsbürste (241) zum Entladen des elektrisch aufgeladenen Aufzeichnungsbogens, die zwischen dem Papierzuführabschnitt und dem durch die Antriebsrolle und die Andrückrolle gebildeten Andrückabschnitt angeordnet ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Aufzeichnungsvorrichtung nach Anspruch 9, wobei die Entladungsbürste beweglich angeordnet ist, um in einer Position am transportierten Aufzeichnungsbogen anzuliegen, und in einer Position vom Aufzeichnungsbogen beabstandet zu sein.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Aufzeichnungsvorrichtung, umfassend:
<claim-text>einen Papierzuführabschnitt (100) zum Zuführen eines Aufzeichnungsbogens;</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Transportriemen (203) zum Aufnehmen und Transportieren des Aufzeichnungsbogens;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Antriebsrolle (201) zum Antreiben des um die Antriebsrolle geschlungenen Transportriemens; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Andrückrolle (208), die über den Transportriemen an der Antriebsrolle anliegt und geeignet ist zum elektrischen Aufladen des Transportriemens durch Anlegen einer Spannung; derart konfiguriert, dass</claim-text>
<claim-text>die Aufzeichnungsvorrichtung eine Aufzeichnung auf dem vom Transportriemen aufgenommenen Aufzeichnungsbogen ausführt, <b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> die Aufzeichnungsvorrichtung weiterhin derart konfiguriert ist, dass ein Andrückabschnitt, der durch die Antriebsrolle und<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --> die Andrückrolle gebildet wird, eine Schrägzufuhr des vom Papierzuführabschnitt zugeführten Aufzeichnungsbogens korrigiert, und dass anschließend die Spannung an die Andrückrolle gelegt wird, um den Transportriemen elektrisch aufzuladen.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980314" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A recording apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a paper feed section (100) for feeding a recording sheet (P);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a conveying belt (203) for absorbing and conveying the recording sheet;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a driving roller (201) for driving the conveying belt wound around the driving roller and for electrically charging the conveying belt by application of a voltage; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pinching roller (208) abutting against the driving roller via the conveying belt;<br/>
configured such that:</claim-text>
<claim-text>the recording apparatus performs recording on the recording sheet absorbed by the conveying belt; and <b>characterised in that</b> the recording apparatus is further configured such that a pinching section, which is formed by the driving roller and the pinching roller, corrects skew feeding of the recording sheet fed from the paper feed section and that thereafter the voltage is applied to the driving roller to electrically charge the conveying belt.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The recording apparatus according to claim 1, wherein the pinching roller is grounded.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The recording apparatus according to claim 1, configured such that the skew feeding of the recording sheet is corrected by abutting the front edge of the recording sheet against the pinching section formed by the driving roller and the pinching roller, which are stopped.<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The recording apparatus according to claim 1, configured such that the skew feeding of the recording sheet is corrected by abutting the front edge of the recording sheet against the pinching section formed by the driving roller and the pinching roller, which are rotating in a reverse direction.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The recording apparatus according to claim 3, wherein a discharging roller (209) abutting against the conveying belt is disposed on the downstream side of the pinching roller in a recording sheet conveying direction.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The recording apparatus according to claim 5, further comprising a wiper (251) which abuts against the conveying belt to remove foreign substances attached to the conveying belt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The recording apparatus according to claim 6, configured such that the conveying belt is moved in the opposite direction to the recording sheet conveying direction so that a part electrically discharged by the discharging roller comes to the pinching section and then the front edge of the recording sheet is abutted against the pinching section.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The recording apparatus according to claim 1, configured such that the front edge of the recording sheet is once passed through the pinching section formed by the driving roller and the pinching roller, the driving roller is then rotated in the reverse direction to convey the recording sheet in the opposite direction to the recording sheet conveying direction, and the front edge of the recording sheet is abutted against the pinching section to correct the skew feeding of the recording sheet.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The recording apparatus according to claim 1, further comprising a discharge brush (241) for discharging the electrically charged recording<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> sheet, which is disposed between the paper feed section and the pinching section formed by the driving roller and the pinching roller.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The recording apparatus according to claim 9, wherein the discharge brush is movably disposed in a position to abut against the fed recording sheet and in a position to be spaced apart from the recording sheet.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>A recording apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a paper feed section (100) for feeding a recording sheet;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a conveying belt (203) for absorbing and conveying the recording sheet;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a driving roller (201) for driving the conveying belt wound around the driving roller; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pinching roller (208) abutting against the driving roller via the conveying belt and suitable for electrically charging the conveying belt by application of a voltage; configured such that</claim-text>
<claim-text>the recording apparatus performs recording on the recording sheet<br/>
absorbed by the conveying belt; and <b>characterised in that</b> the recording apparatus is further configured such that a pinching section, which is formed by the driving roller and the<br/>
pinching roller, corrects skew feeding of the recording sheet fed from the paper feed section and that thereafter the voltage is applied to the pinching roller to electrically charge the conveying belt.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980315" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Appareil d'enregistrement comprenant :
<claim-text>une section (100) d'alimentation en papier pour alimenter une feuille d'enregistrement (P) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une courroie transporteuse (203) pour absorber et transporter la feuille d'enregistrement ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un rouleau d'entraînement (201) pour entraîner la courroie transporteuse enroulée autour du rouleau d'entraînement et pour charger électriquement la courroie transporteuse par application d'une tension ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un rouleau de pincement (208) venant en butée contre le rouleau d'entraînement par l'intermédiaire de la courroie transporteuse ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>configuré de telle sorte que :
<claim-text>l'appareil d'enregistrement effectue un enregistrement sur la feuille d'enregistrement absorbée par la courroie transporteuse ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>caractérisé en ce que</b> l'appareil d'enregistrement est en outre configuré de telle sorte que</claim-text>
<claim-text>une section de pincement, qui est formée par le rouleau d'entraînement et le rouleau de pincement, corrige une alimentation en biais de la feuille d'enregistrement alimentée à partir de la section d'alimentation en papier et de telle sorte que la tension soit par la suite appliquée au rouleau d'entraînement pour charger électriquement la courroie transporteuse.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Appareil d'enregistrement selon la revendication 1, dans lequel le rouleau de pincement est mis à la terre.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Appareil d'enregistrement selon la revendication 1, configuré de telle sorte que l'alimentation en biais de la feuille d'enregistrement soit corrigée en mettant le bord avant de la feuille d'enregistrement en butée contre la section de pincement formée par le rouleau d'entraînement et le rouleau de pincement, qui sont arrêtés.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Appareil d'enregistrement selon la revendication 1, configuré de telle sorte que l'alimentation en biais de la<!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --> feuille d'enregistrement soit corrigée en mettant le bord avant de la feuille d'enregistrement en butée contre la section de pincement formée par le rouleau d'entraînement et le rouleau de pincement, qui sont en rotation dans une direction inverse.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Appareil d'enregistrement selon la revendication 3, dans lequel un rouleau d'évacuation (209) venant en butée contre la courroie transporteuse est disposé sur le côté en aval du rouleau de pincement dans une direction de transport de la feuille d'enregistrement.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Appareil d'enregistrement selon la revendication 5, comprenant en outre un essuyeur (251) qui vient en butée contre la courroie transporteuse pour éliminer les substances étrangères fixées à la courroie transporteuse.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Appareil d'enregistrement selon la revendication 6, configuré de telle sorte que la courroie transporteuse soit déplacée dans la direction opposée à la direction de transport de feuille d'enregistrement de telle sorte qu'une partie électriquement déchargée par le rouleau de déchargement atteigne la section de pincement et ensuite le bord avant de la feuille d'enregistrement soit en butée contre la section de pincement.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Appareil d'enregistrement selon la revendication 1, configuré de telle sorte que le bord avant de la feuille d'enregistrement passe une fois à travers la section de pincement formée par le rouleau d'entraînement et le rouleau de pincement, le rouleau d'entraînement est ensuite mis en rotation dans la direction inverse pour transporter la feuille d'enregistrement dans la direction opposée à la direction de transport de la feuille d'enregistrement, et le bord avant de la feuille d'enregistrement vient en butée contre la section de pincement pour corriger une alimentation en biais de la feuille d'enregistrement.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Appareil d'enregistrement selon la revendication 1, comprenant en outre une brosse de décharge (241) pour décharger la feuille d'enregistrement électriquement<!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --> chargée, qui est disposée entre la section d'alimentation en papier et la section de pincement formée par le rouleau d'entraînement et le rouleau de pincement.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Appareil d'enregistrement selon la revendication 9, dans lequel la brosse de décharge est disposée en mobilité dans une position pour venir en butée contre la feuille d'enregistrement alimentée et dans une position qui doit être écartée de la feuille d'enregistrement.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Appareil d'enregistrement comprenant :
<claim-text>une section (100) d'alimentation en papier pour alimenter une feuille d'enregistrement ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une courroie transporteuse (203) pour absorber et transporter la feuille d'enregistrement ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un rouleau d'entraînement (201) pour entraîner la courroie transporteuse enroulée autour du rouleau d'entraînement ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un rouleau de pincement (208) venant en butée contre le rouleau d'entraînement par l'intermédiaire de la courroie transporteuse et étant adapté pour charger électriquement la courroie transporteuse par une application d'une tension ; configuré de telle sorte que</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'appareil d'enregistrement effectue un enregistrement sur la feuille d'enregistrement absorbée par la courroie transporteuse ;</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>caractérisé en ce que</b> l'appareil d'enregistrement est en outre configuré de telle sorte que</claim-text>
<claim-text>une section de pincement, qui est formée par le rouleau d'entraînement et le rouleau de pincement, corrige une alimentation en biais de la feuille d'enregistrement alimenté à partir de la section d'alimentation en papier et de telle sorte que la tension soit par la suite appliquée au rouleau de pincement pour charger électriquement la courroie transporteuse.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16669120" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="157" he="193" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="162" he="187" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="36"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="121" he="210" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="37"> --><figure id="f0004" num="4"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="164" he="172" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="38"> --><figure id="f0005" num="5"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="157" he="165" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="39"> --><figure id="f0006" num="6"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="141" he="212" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="40"> --><figure id="f0007" num="7"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="149" he="211" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="41"> --><figure id="f0008" num="8"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="149" he="211" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="42"> --><figure id="f0009" num="9"><img id="if0009" file="imgf0009.tif" wi="149" he="211" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="43"> --><figure id="f0010" num="10"><img id="if0010" file="imgf0010.tif" wi="149" he="211" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="44"> --><figure id="f0011" num="11"><img id="if0011" file="imgf0011.tif" wi="135" he="169" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
