<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2959805-A1" country="EP" doc-number="2959805" kind="A1" date="20151230" family-id="51410245" file-reference-id="318334" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="160452296" ucid="EP-2959805-A1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2959805</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20151230</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-15162947-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP193867560" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>15162947</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20150409</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP193867561" load-source="patent-office" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>15162947.4</doc-number><date>20150409</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC162033172" ucid="GB-201411474-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>GB</country><doc-number>201411474</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20140627</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC162033073" ucid="GB-201502192-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>GB</country><doc-number>201502192</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20150210</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1988520523" load-source="docdb">F25D  25/02        20060101ALI20150911BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1988525617" load-source="docdb">A47F   3/04        20060101AFI20150911BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1988527484" load-source="docdb">F25D  17/08        20060101ALI20150911BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1832231643" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F25D  17/08        20130101 LI20150831BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1832231644" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F25D  25/02        20130101 LI20150831BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1953498202" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A47F   3/0469      20130101 LI20160405BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1953498401" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A47F2003/046       20130101 LA20160404BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1984699606" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A47F   3/0447      20130101 FI20160106BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT165548354" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">OFFENER GEKÜHLTER AUSLAGEKASTEN UND STRÖMUNGSSTABILISIERUNGSVORRICHTUNG</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT165548355" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">AN OPEN REFRIGERATED DISPLAY CASE AND A FLOW STABILISING DEVICE</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT165548356" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">VITRINE RÉFRIGÉRÉE OUVERTE ET DISPOSITIF DE STABILISATION DE COURANT</invention-title><citations><patent-citations><patcit mxw-id="PCIT335963487" load-source="docdb" ucid="JP-2011188889-A"><document-id format="epo"><country>JP</country><doc-number>2011188889</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20110929</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="A" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT335963488" load-source="docdb" ucid="JP-2014108180-A"><document-id format="epo"><country>JP</country><doc-number>2014108180</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20140612</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="X" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT335963485" load-source="docdb" ucid="JP-S5758884-U"><document-id format="epo"><country>JP</country><doc-number>S5758884</doc-number><kind>U</kind><date>19820407</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="X" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT382230029" load-source="docdb" ucid="JP-S59174588-U"><document-id format="epo"><country>JP</country><doc-number>S59174588</doc-number><kind>U</kind><date>19841121</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="XA" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit></patent-citations></citations></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR1103343961" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>WIRTH RES LTD</last-name><address><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR1103330369" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>WIRTH RESEARCH LIMITED</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR1101645954" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Wirth Research Limited</last-name><iid>101518619</iid><address><street>Unit A11 Telford Road</street><city>Bicester, Oxfordshire OX26 4LD</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1103323737" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>WIRTH NICHOLAS</last-name><address><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1103329187" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>Wirth, Nicholas</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1101650017" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Wirth, Nicholas</last-name><address><street>Sholebroke Farmhouse</street><city>Whittlebury, Northamptonshire NN12 8TF</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR1101649456" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Chapman, Patrick</last-name><iid>101340632</iid><address><street>Haseltine Lake LLP Redcliff Quay 120 Redcliff Street</street><city>Bristol BS1 6HU</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS660716315" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS660705159" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS660716317" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS660622143" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS660787584" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS660700227" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS660705160" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS660716318" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS660700228" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS660700229" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS660619980" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS660622144" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS660622145" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS660716327" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS660700230" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS660716328" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS660705161" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS660787585" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS660716329" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS660622146" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS660700235" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS660621739" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS660705162" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS660621740" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS660621741" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS660699530" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS660699535" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS660716330" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS660622155" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS660716335" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS660787586" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS660716336" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS660787587" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS660716337" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS660787588" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS660621747" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS660621748" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS660700236" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states><ep-extended-states><ep-extended-state-data><country>BA</country></ep-extended-state-data><ep-extended-state-data><country>ME</country></ep-extended-state-data></ep-extended-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA166480666" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p id="pa01" num="0001">An open refrigerated display case 2 comprising: a refrigerated display area 15 comprising one or more shelves 17; an air outlet 20 and an air inlet 18 opening into the display area 15 and spaced from one another; a duct 16 fluidically coupling the air inlet 18 to the air outlet 20, the duct 16 being configured to direct air flow out of the air outlet 20 across the display area 15 and toward the air inlet 18 to form an air curtain 26 across the display area 15; wherein each of the one or more shelves are provided with an associated flow stabilising device 28; wherein each flow stabilising device 28 comprises a pair of stabilising beams which are spaced from one another so as to define an innermost stabilising beam 38b and an outermost stabilising beam 38a; wherein a first slot 39a is formed between the innermost and the outermost stabilising beams, the first slot extending transversely across the display area 15 perpendicular to the direction of the air flow within the air curtain 26, the first slot having a stabilising inlet, a stabilising outlet and a stabilising throat disposed therebetween; wherein the innermost stabilising beam is spaced from the adjacent shelf so as to form a second slot 39b between the innermost stabilising beam and the shelf; and wherein the one or more flow stabilising devices 28 are each positioned so that the stabilising inlet of the first slot receives the air curtain 26, the stabilising throat being configured to stabilise the air flow within the air curtain 26 which exits the flow stabilising device via the stabilising outlet.
<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="83" he="62" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA166760478" lang="EN" source="EPO" load-source="docdb"><p>An open refrigerated display case 2 comprising: a refrigerated display area 15 comprising one or more shelves 17; an air outlet 20 and an air inlet 18 opening into the display area 15 and spaced from one another; a duct 16 fluidically coupling the air inlet 18 to the air outlet 20, the duct 16 being configured to direct air flow out of the air outlet 20 across the display area 15 and toward the air inlet 18 to form an air curtain 26 across the display area 15; wherein each of the one or more shelves are provided with an associated flow stabilising device 28; wherein each flow stabilising device 28 comprises a pair of stabilising beams which are spaced from one another so as to define an innermost stabilising beam 38b and an outermost stabilising beam 38a; wherein a first slot 39a is formed between the innermost and the outermost stabilising beams, the first slot extending transversely across the display area 15 perpendicular to the direction of the air flow within the air curtain 26, the first slot having a stabilising inlet, a stabilising outlet and a stabilising throat disposed therebetween; wherein the innermost stabilising beam is spaced from the adjacent shelf so as to form a second slot 39b between the innermost stabilising beam and the shelf; and wherein the one or more flow stabilising devices 28 are each positioned so that the stabilising inlet of the first slot receives the air curtain 26, the stabilising throat being configured to stabilise the air flow within the air curtain 26 which exits the flow stabilising device via the stabilising outlet.</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES98405367" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><p id="p0001" num="0001">The invention relates to an open refrigerated display case and a flow stabilising device for an open refrigerated display case.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002">The display of chilled or frozen items is commonplace in many retail environments, most notably in supermarkets. Conventionally, such items have been displayed in refrigerated display cases having glass doors to allow customers to browse items before opening the doors to access the items. However, the presence of such doors has been seen as problematic in that they make it difficult for several customers to access the contents of the case, as well as providing an obstruction when open, narrowing the usable aisle space.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">It is therefore common for supermarkets to use open-fronted display cases (Open Refrigerated Display Cases; herein "ORDCs"). ORDCs utilise an air curtain which is cooled to below ambient temperature and propelled downward, across the open front of the display case. The air curtain separates the refrigerated interior of the display case from the ambient air surrounding the display case. The air curtain thus keeps the cool air inside the display case from spilling out due to buoyancy effects, and also provides a barrier from other external motions of air around the display case. ORDCs therefore do not need any physical barrier separating customers from the contents of the display case. Accordingly, ORDCs provide a desirable method of displaying food and other perishable goods as they allow both easy access and clear visibility of merchandise.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">However, as a direct consequence of their open design, ORDCs do have significantly higher energy consumption compared to the closed-fronted alternative. The main energy losses occur within the air curtain, and are caused by the entrainment of warm ambient air into the air curtain and the turbulent mixing which occurs within the air curtain itself. The entrainment of warm ambient air causes an increase in temperature within the air curtain, and this warmer air must be cooled as it re-circulates through the system. It has been estimated that 70% to 80% of the cooling load of an ORDC is due to such effects.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">In recent years, multi-decked designs have become commonplace to maximise the display space per unit of floor space. Consequently, the air curtains of such ORDCs<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> must seal a larger display area. This has exacerbated entrainment issues and the resulting energy losses, as well as making the design of air curtains more challenging, particularly in respect of ensuring product integrity and temperature homogeneity while attempting to minimize their energy consumption.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">The invention thus seeks to improve the efficiency of ORDCs by reducing entrainment within the air curtain.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">According to an aspect of the invention there is therefore provided an open refrigerated display case comprising: a refrigerated display area comprising one or more shelves; an air outlet and an air inlet opening into the display area and spaced from one another; a duct fluidically coupling the air inlet to the air outlet, the duct being configured to direct air flow out of the air outlet across the display area and toward the air inlet to form an air curtain across the display area; wherein each of the one or more shelves are provided with an associated flow stabilising device disposed; wherein each flow stabilising device comprises a pair of stabilising beams which are spaced from one another so as to define an innermost stabilising beam and an outermost stabilising beam; wherein a first slot is formed between the innermost and the outermost stabilising beams, the first slot extending transversely across the display area perpendicular to the direction of the air flow within the air curtain, the first slot having a stabilising inlet, a stabilising outlet and a stabilising throat disposed therebetween; wherein the innermost stabilising beam is spaced from the adjacent shelf so as to form a second slot between the innermost stabilising beam and the shelf; and wherein the one or more flow stabilising devices are each positioned so that the stabilising inlet of the first slot receives the air curtain, the stabilising throat being configured to stabilise the air flow within the air curtain which exits the flow stabilising device via the stabilising outlet.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">The stabilising inlet may be wider than the stabilising outlet and the stabilising throat may converge from the stabilising inlet to the stabilising outlet.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">The stabilising throat may converge at greater than 0° and less than 20°.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">The flow stabilising devices may be spaced from the air outlet and/or one another by a distance which corresponds to approximately 4 to 6 times a width of the air outlet.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p><p id="p0011" num="0011">The flow stabilising devices may be spaced by a distance which corresponds to approximately 5 times a width of the air outlet.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">Each flow stabilising device may be connected to the one or more shelves.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">Each flow stabilising device may be pivotably connected to the one or more shelves.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">Each flow stabilising device may be configured so as to allow a distance between the shelf and the stabilising inlet of the first slot to be varied.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">The flow stabilising device may further comprise a pair of arms which connect the stabilising beams to the open refrigerated display case.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">The stabilising beams may be transparent.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">The outermost stabilising beam may be provided with a product information strip.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">The open refrigerated display case may further comprise an injector port which is configured to introduce additional air into the air curtain.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">The injector port may be connected to the duct.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">According to another aspect of the invention there is therefore provided a flow stabilising device for stabilising an air curtain of an open refrigerated display case, the flow stabilising device comprising: a pair of stabilising beams which are spaced from one another so as to define an innermost stabilising beam and an outermost stabilising beam; wherein a first slot is formed between the innermost and the outmost stabilising beams, the first slot having a stabilising inlet, a stabilising outlet and a stabilising throat disposed therebetween; wherein the flow stabilising device is configured to be positioned so that: a second slot is formed between the innermost stabilising beam and an adjacent shelf of the open refrigerated display case; and the stabilising inlet of the first slot receives the air curtain, the stabilising throat being configured to stabilise the air flow within the air curtain which exits the flow stabilising device via the stabilising outlet.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p><p id="p0021" num="0021">The stabilising inlet may be wider than the stabilising outlet and the stabilising throat may converge from the stabilising inlet to the stabilising outlet.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">The stabilising throat may converge at greater than 0° and less than 20°.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">The flow stabilising device may be configured to be connected to a shelf of the open refrigerated display case.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">The flow stabilising device may be configured to be pivotably connected to the shelf.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">The flow stabilising device may be configured so as to allow a distance between the shelf and the stabilising inlet to be varied.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">The flow stabilising device may further comprise a pair of arms which are configured to connect the stabilising beams to the open refrigerated display case.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">The stabilising beams may be transparent.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">The outermost stabilising beam may be provided with a product information strip.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">The flow stabilising device may further comprise an injector port which is configured to introduce additional air into the air curtain.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">For a better understanding of the invention, and to show more clearly how it may be carried into effect, reference will now be made, by way of example, to the accompanying drawings, in which:-
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> is a side cross-sectional view of a conventional open refrigerated display case (ORDC);</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref> is a perspective view of a shelf having a flow stabilising device according to an embodiment of the invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3</figref> is a side cross-section view of an ORDC according to an embodiment of the invention having a plurality of shelves with flow stabilising devices as shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref>;<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 4</figref> schematically shows air flow from the conventional ORDC of <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>; and</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 5</figref> schematically shows air flow from the ORDC of <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3</figref>.</li></ul></p><p id="p0031" num="0031"><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> shows a conventional ORDC 2. The ORDC 2 comprises a cabinet portion formed by a lower wall 4, a back wall 6, an upper wall 8, and left and right side walls (not shown). A lower panel 10, a back panel 12 and an upper panel 14 are disposed within the cabinet portion.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">The lower, back and upper panels 10, 12, 14 form a display area 15 which is provided with a plurality of shelves 17 (six are shown) on which items may be displayed. The shelves 17 are affixed to the back panel 12.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">As shown, the lower, back and upper panels 10, 12, 14 are spaced from the respective lower, back and upper walls 4, 6, 8 to form a duct 16. An intake grille 18 is provided at the lower panel 10 to form an inlet to the duct 16. Similarly, a discharge grille 20 is provided at the upper panel 14 to form an outlet from the duct 16. The intake grille 18 and the discharge grille 20 are thus fluidically coupled to one another by the duct 16. The intake grille 18 and the discharge grille 20 are spaced from the back panel 12 toward the front of the cabinet portion and ahead of the shelves 17.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">A fan 22 and a heat exchanger 24 are located within the duct 16 adjacent to the intake grille 18 and thus are disposed between the lower wall 4 and the lower panel 10. The fan 22 draws air into the duct 16 via the intake grille 18 which then passes through the heat exchanger 24 where it is cooled to well below the ambient temperature.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">After passing through the heat exchanger 24, the air continues through the duct 16 between the back wall 6 and the back panel 12. The back panel 12 is perforated allowing air to pass from the duct 16 into the display area 15 where it cools items located on the shelves 17 and on the lower panel 10.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">The remaining air flows through the duct 16 to the discharge grille 20. The air is ejected from the discharge grille 20 and descends over the open front of the display area 15 to form an air curtain 26. The air curtain 26 passes from the discharge grille 20 to the intake grille 18, where it is drawn in by the fan 22 and re-circulated through the<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> duct 16. The air curtain 26 thus forms a non-physical barrier which separates the display area 15 from the ambient air surrounding the ORDC 2.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>, the air curtain 26 may be angled away from vertical by around 5-10°. This may be achieved by angling the discharge grille 20. In particular, the discharge grille 20 may be provided with a honeycomb panel (not shown) which rectifies the air flow as it exits the discharge grille 20 to provide laminar flow. The air curtain 26 may also deviate away from the back panel 12 as a result of the air passing through the perforations in the back panel 12. The intake grille 18 is therefore offset from the discharge grille 20 to allow for this.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038"><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref> shows a flow stabilising device 28 according to an embodiment of the invention which is fitted to one of the shelves 17 of the ORDC 2.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref>, each shelf 17 comprises a shelf portion 30 and a pair of brackets 32 which support the shelf portion 30 and are configured to be received within slots in the back panel 12 of the ORDC 2. A product information strip 34 extends across a front surface of the shelf portion 30 and has a channel for receiving tickets displaying information regarding the products on the shelf portion 30, such as the product's price.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">The flow stabilising device 28 comprises a pair of arms 36a, 36b. The arms 36a, 36b are affixed to either lateral side of the shelf 17 such that they are spaced from one another across the width of the shelf 17. Each of the arms 36a, 36b is connected at one end to the shelf 17 and extends away from the shelf 17 in a cantilevered manner to a free end. The arms 36a, 36b thus lie in the same plane as the shelf 17. The arms 36a, 36b may be connected to the shelf 17 in any suitable manner, such as via attachment to the shelf portion 30, the brackets 32 or the product information strip 34.</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">A pair of stabilising beams 38a, 38b extend between the arms 36a, 36b. The stabilising beams 38a, 38b are spaced from one another and run parallel to one another across the full width of the shelf 17 (and the display area 15). The stabilising beams 38a, 38b are arranged so that their widths extend in a vertical direction, substantially perpendicular to the shelf 17. The stabilising beams 38a, 38b are, however, angled relative to one another so that the gap between the stabilising beams 38a, 38b tapers toward the lower end of the stabilising beams 38a, 38b. The stabilising beams 38a, 38b thus define a first slot 39a having a vertical extent (length). The first<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> slot 39a comprises an inlet at an upper end and an outlet at a lower end. The inlet has a greater width than the outlet and a convergent throat is disposed between the inlet and the outlet. The stabilising beams 38a, 38b may taper at an angle of greater than 0° and less than 20° to the vertical. The angle may, however, differ between the two stabilising beams 38a, 38b within a single flow stabilising device 28. In particular, as shown, the outermost stabilising beam 38a may be arranged vertically and the innermost stabilising beam 38b angled relative to the outermost stabilising beam 38a.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">The outermost stabilising beam 38a may be provided with a product information strip which can be used to display information regarding the products on the shelf portion 30 if the product information strip 34 of the shelf 17 itself is obscured by the stabilising beams 38a, 38b. Alternatively, the stabilising beams 38a, 38b may be transparent to allow the product information strip 34 of the shelf 17 to be viewed. This may also prevent the stabilising beams 38a, 38b from blocking light from a light source within the ORDC 2 and thus ensure proper illumination of the products within the ORDC.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3</figref>, each of the shelves 17 is provided with a flow stabilising device 28. The stabilising beams 38a, 38b of each shelf 17 are spaced from the shelf 17 so as to form a second slot 39b between the innermost stabilising beam 38b and the shelf 17. The stabilising beams 38a, 38b are positioned such that the majority of the air curtain 26 passes between the stabilising beams 38a, 38b, through the first slot 39a. A portion of the air curtain 26 may pass between the innermost stabilising beam 38b and the shelf 17, through the second slot 39b, or beyond the exterior surface of the outermost stabilising beam 38a. As described previously, the back panel 12 is perforated to allow air to pass from the duct 16 into the display area 15 where it cools items located on the shelves 17 and on the lower panel 10. The direction of air flow from the back panel 12 is thus predominantly perpendicular to that of the air curtain 26. The air from the back panel 12 is entrained with the portion of the air curtain 26 passing through the second slot 39a which turns the air flow towards the direction of the air curtain 26. This reduces the effect the air flow from the back panel 12 has on the air curtain 26.</p><p id="p0044" num="0044">As described previously, the air curtain 26 may be angled away from vertical and the stabilising beams 38a, 38b may be spaced progressively further from the shelf 17 (or, where the shelves are of different lengths, from the back panel 12) from the uppermost shelf 17 to the lowermost shelf 17 so as to be aligned with the air curtain 26. The<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> spacing between the stabilising beams 38a, 38b may increase from the uppermost flow stabilising device 28 to the lowermost flow stabilising device 28 to account for the air curtain 26 becoming thicker as it passes down the front of the ORDC 2.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045">As described previously, the intake grille 18 is not directly aligned with the discharge grille 20. To counteract this, the stabilising beams 38a, 38b of the uppermost flow stabilising device 28 are curved so that the air curtain 26 is turned slightly as it passes through this flow stabilising device 28. As shown, the stabilising beams 38a, 38b of the uppermost flow stabilising device 28 may also run parallel to one another such that they do not converge.</p><p id="p0046" num="0046"><figref idrefs="f0004">Figures 4 and 5</figref> provide a comparison of the flow characteristics of the air curtain 26 without the flow stabilising devices 28 of the invention (<figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 4</figref>) and with the flow stabilising devices 28 (<figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 5</figref>).</p><p id="p0047" num="0047">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 4</figref>, the air leaves the discharge grille 20 as a coherent jet 40. However, without the flow stabilising devices 28, the jet 40 soon becomes unstable in region 42, and begins to separate. This causes a high level of turbulent mixing in region 44 which warms the air curtain 26 considerably, thus warming the ORDC 2.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">Figure 5</figref>, with the flow stabilising devices 28 attached to the shelves 17, the air again exits the discharge grille 20, but before the air curtain 26 can become unstable the flow stabilising device 28 acts to re-stabilise the flow. As described previously, the stabilising beams 38a, 38b converge such that, as a result of the Venturi effect, the air is accelerated as it passes through the first slot 39a of the flow stabilising device 28. The acceleration acts to further stabilise the air curtain 26. The width of the air curtain 26 is also reduced which helps maintain a thin shear layer throughout the length of the air curtain 26. The second slot 39b formed between the innermost stabilising beam 38b and the shelf 17 further promotes stabilisation of the air curtain 26 by drawing air from the back panel 12 into the air curtain 26.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">The shelves 17 may be configured so as to allow the shelf portion 30 to be positioned at different angles. This may be beneficial for displaying different types of products. To allow for this, each flow stabilising device 28 may be pivotably connected to the shelf 17 so that the flow stabilising device 28 remains horizontal (or at some other predetermined orientation). For example, the arms 36a, 36b may be pivotably connected to the shelf 17. Alternatively, the arms 36a, 36b may each comprise first<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> and second members connected to one another at an articulated joint. The arms 36a, 36b may also allow the distance of the stabilising beams 38a, 38b from the shelf 17 to be varied. In particular, as the shelf 17 is angled away from horizontal, its horizontal extent will reduce so that the stabilising beams 38a, 38b are located closer to the back panel 12. The arms 36a, 36b may therefore allow for this to be counteracted so that the stabilising beams 38a, 38b remain in the correct position for the air curtain 26. For example, the arms 36a, 36b may allow the stabilising beams 38a, 38b to be located in a plurality of positions (e.g. defined by discrete mounting holes or a continuous slot) or the arms 36a, 36b themselves may be connected to the shelf 17 in a plurality of positions. Alternatively, the arms 38a, 38b may comprise a telescoping arrangement to alter their length.</p><p id="p0050" num="0050">An initial study using Computational Fluid Dynamics has shown that the flow stabilising device 28 of the invention could provide a reduction of around 40% in convective heat losses.</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">Although not shown, the flow stabilising device 28 may comprise an injector port which receives additional air. For example, the injector port may be connected to the duct 16 via a conduit or the injector port may receive air which passes through the perforated back panel 12. The injector port may be located adjacent the inlet of the flow stabilising device 28. The Venturi effect creates an area of low pressure within the flow stabilising device 28 as the air curtain 26 is accelerated. This acts to draw in the additional air from the injector port which further increases the velocity of the air curtain, thus helping it to remain stable and intact in extreme ambient conditions.</p><p id="p0052" num="0052">The flow stabilising devices 28 can be connected to a standard shelf 17 and thus allow the flow stabilising devices 28 to be retrofit to existing ORDCs. The flow stabilising devices 28 may, however, be integrally formed with the shelves 17 or the ORDC 2.</p><p id="p0053" num="0053">Although each shelf 17 of the ORDC 2 has been described as having a flow stabilising device 28, this need not be the case and only some of the shelves 17 may be provided with flow stabilising devices 28. It is, however, desirable that the flow stabilising devices 28 are provided at regular spacings of between 120mm and 190mm, which corresponds to approximately 4 to 6 times the width of the discharge grille 20, and preferably at spacings of around 160mm (5 times the width of the discharge grille 20).<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> Although the flow stabilising devices 28 have been described as being connected directly to the shelves 17, they may instead be connected to other parts of the ORDC 2. For example, the arms 36a, 36b of the flow stabilising devices 28 may connect to the back panel 12 such that the flow stabilising devices 28 are positioned between adjacent shelves 17 (or between the lowermost shelf 17 and the lower panel 10). In particular, the flow stabilising devices 28 may be positioned just below each of the shelves 17. Alternatively, the flow stabilising devices 28 may be connected to the left and right side walls of the ORDC 2. In this case, the arms 36a, 36b can be omitted and the stabilising beams 38a, 38b connected directly to the ORDC 2.</p><p id="p0054" num="0054">The stabilising beams 38a, 38b also need not lie in the plane of the shelf 17. For example, the stabilising beams 38a, 38b may be offset from the shelf 17 such that they are not aligned with the product information strip 34, thus allowing the product information strip 34 to be viewed. This may be achieved by using arms which are stepped or otherwise configured so that the connection to the shelf 17 and the connection to the stabilising beams 38a, 38b are offset from one another.</p><p id="p0055" num="0055">In certain embodiments, the stabilising beams 38a, 38b may not converge and are instead arranged parallel to one another. Such parallel stabilising beams 38a, 38b may guide the air flow and prevent expansion of the air curtain, thus still re-stabilising the flow.</p><p id="p0056" num="0056">The invention is not limited to the embodiments described herein, and may be modified or adapted without departing from the scope of the present invention.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM90460328" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --><claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>An open refrigerated display case comprising:
<claim-text>a refrigerated display area comprising one or more shelves;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an air outlet and an air inlet opening into the display area and spaced from one another;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a duct fluidically coupling the air inlet to the air outlet, the duct being configured to direct air flow out of the air outlet across the display area and toward the air inlet to form an air curtain across the display area;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each of the one or more shelves are provided with an associated flow stabilising device;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each flow stabilising device comprises a pair of stabilising beams which are spaced from one another so as to define an innermost stabilising beam and an outermost stabilising beam;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a first slot is formed between the innermost and the outermost stabilising beams, the first slot extending transversely across the display area perpendicular to the direction of the air flow within the air curtain, the first slot having a stabilising inlet, a stabilising outlet and a stabilising throat disposed therebetween;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the innermost stabilising beam is spaced from the adjacent shelf so as to form a second slot between the innermost stabilising beam and the shelf; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the one or more flow stabilising devices are each positioned so that the stabilising inlet of the first slot receives the air curtain, the stabilising throat being configured to stabilise the air flow within the air curtain which exits the flow stabilising device via the stabilising outlet.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>An open refrigerated display case as claimed in claim 1, wherein the flow stabilising devices are spaced from the air outlet and/or one another by a distance which corresponds to approximately 4 to 6 times a width of the air outlet.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>An open refrigerated display case as claimed in claim 2, wherein the flow stabilising devices are spaced by a distance which corresponds to approximately 5 times a width of the air outlet.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>An open refrigerated display case as claimed in any preceding claim, wherein each flow stabilising device is connected to the one or more shelves.<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>An open refrigerated display case as claimed in claim 4, wherein each flow stabilising device is pivotably connected to the one or more shelves.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>An open refrigerated display case as claimed in any preceding claim, wherein the flow stabilising device further comprises a pair of arms which connect the stabilising beams to the open refrigerated display case.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>A flow stabilising device for stabilising an air curtain of an open refrigerated display case, the flow stabilising device comprising:
<claim-text>a pair of stabilising beams which are spaced from one another so as to define an innermost stabilising beam and an outermost stabilising beam;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a first slot is formed between the innermost and the outmost stabilising beams, the first slot having a stabilising inlet, a stabilising outlet and a stabilising throat disposed therebetween;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the flow stabilising device is configured to be positioned so that:
<claim-text>a second slot is formed between the innermost stabilising beam and an adjacent shelf of the open refrigerated display case; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>the stabilising inlet of the first slot receives the air curtain, the stabilising throat being configured to stabilise the air flow within the air curtain which exits the flow stabilising device via the stabilising outlet.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>A flow stabilising device as claimed in claim 7, wherein the flow stabilising device is configured to be pivotably connected to the shelf.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>A flow stabilising device as claimed in claim 7 or 8, wherein the flow stabilising device further comprises a pair of arms which are configured to connect the stabilising beams to the open refrigerated display case.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>An open refrigerated display case as claimed in any of claims 1 to 6 or a flow stabilising device as claimed in any of claims 7 to 9, wherein the stabilising inlet is wider than the stabilising outlet and the stabilising throat converges from the stabilising inlet to the stabilising outlet.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>An open refrigerated display case or flow stabilising device as claimed in claim 10, wherein the stabilising throat converges at greater than 0° and less than 20°.<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>An open refrigerated display case or a flow stabilising device as claimed in any preceding claim, wherein the flow stabilising device is configured so as to allow a distance between the shelf and the stabilising inlet of the first slot to be varied.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>An open refrigerated display case or a flow stabilising device as claimed in any preceding claim, wherein the stabilising beams are transparent.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>An open refrigerated display case or a flow stabilising device as claimed in any preceding claim, wherein the outermost stabilising beam is provided with a product information strip.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>An open refrigerated display case or a flow stabilising device as claimed in any preceding claim, further comprising an injector port which is configured to introduce additional air into the air curtain, the injector port preferably being connected to the duct of the open refrigerated display case.</claim-text></claim></claims><amended-claims mxw-id="PCLM90460327" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office" amended-claim-type="EPC"><heading id="h0001">Amended claims in accordance with Rule 137(2) EPC.</heading><claim id="ac-en-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>An open refrigerated display case (2) comprising:
<claim-text>a refrigerated display area (15) comprising one or more shelves (17);</claim-text>
<claim-text>an air outlet (20) and an air inlet (18) opening into the display area and spaced from one another;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a duct (16) fluidically coupling the air inlet to the air outlet, the duct being configured to direct air flow out of the air outlet across the display area and toward the air inlet to form an air curtain (26) across the display area;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each of the one or more shelves are provided with an associated flow stabilising device (28);</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein each flow stabilising device comprises a pair of stabilising beams (38a, 38b) which are spaced from one another so as to define an innermost stabilising beam (38b) and an outermost stabilising beam (38a);</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a first slot (39a) is formed between the innermost and the outermost stabilising beams, the first slot extending transversely across the display area perpendicular to the direction of the air flow within the air curtain, the first slot having a stabilising inlet, a stabilising outlet and a stabilising throat disposed therebetween; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the one or more flow stabilising devices are each positioned so that the stabilising inlet of the first slot receives the air curtain, the stabilising throat being configured to stabilise the air flow within the air curtain which exits the flow stabilising device via the stabilising outlet; and</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>characterised in that</b> the innermost stabilising beam is spaced from the adjacent shelf so as to form a second slot (39b) between the innermost stabilising beam and the shelf through which a portion of the air curtain can pass.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="ac-en-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>An open refrigerated display case as claimed in claim 1, wherein the flow stabilising devices are spaced from the air outlet and/or one another by a distance which corresponds to approximately 4 to 6 times a width of the air outlet.</claim-text></claim><claim id="ac-en-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>An open refrigerated display case as claimed in claim 2, wherein the flow stabilising devices are spaced by a distance which corresponds to approximately 5 times a width of the air outlet.</claim-text></claim><claim id="ac-en-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>An open refrigerated display case as claimed in any preceding claim, wherein each flow stabilising device is connected to the one or more shelves.</claim-text></claim><claim id="ac-en-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>An open refrigerated display case as claimed in claim 4, wherein each flow stabilising device is pivotably connected to the one or more shelves.</claim-text></claim><claim id="ac-en-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>An open refrigerated display case as claimed in any preceding claim, wherein the flow stabilising device further comprises a pair of arms (36a, 36b) which connect the stabilising beams to the open refrigerated display case.</claim-text></claim><claim id="ac-en-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>A flow stabilising device (28) for stabilising an air curtain (26) of an open refrigerated display case (2), the flow stabilising device comprising:
<claim-text>a pair of stabilising beams (38a, 38b) which are spaced from one another so as to define an innermost stabilising beam (38b) and an outermost stabilising beam (38a);</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein a first slot (39a) is formed between the innermost and the outmost stabilising beams, the first slot having a stabilising inlet, a stabilising outlet and a stabilising throat disposed therebetween; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the flow stabilising device is connectable to the open refrigerated display case such that:
<claim-text>the stabilising inlet of the first slot receives the air curtain, the stabilising throat being configured to stabilise the air flow within the air curtain which exits the flow stabilising device via the stabilising outlet; and</claim-text></claim-text>
<claim-text><b>characterized in that</b> the flow stabilising device is connectable to the open refrigerated display case such that:
<claim-text>a second slot (39b) is formed between the innermost stabilising beam and an adjacent shelf of the open refrigerated display case through which a portion of the air curtain can pass.</claim-text></claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="ac-en-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>A flow stabilising device as claimed in claim 7, wherein the flow stabilising device is configured to be pivotably connected to the shelf.</claim-text></claim><claim id="ac-en-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>A flow stabilising device as claimed in claim 7 or 8, wherein the flow stabilising device further comprises a pair of arms (36a, 36b) which are configured to connect the stabilising beams to the open refrigerated display case.</claim-text></claim><claim id="ac-en-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>An open refrigerated display case as claimed in any of claims 1 to 6 or a flow stabilising device as claimed in any of claims 7 to 9, wherein the stabilising inlet is wider than the stabilising outlet and the stabilising throat converges from the stabilising inlet to the stabilising outlet.</claim-text></claim><claim id="ac-en-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>An open refrigerated display case or flow stabilising device as claimed in claim 10, wherein the stabilising throat converges at greater than 0° and less than 20°.</claim-text></claim><claim id="ac-en-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>An open refrigerated display case or a flow stabilising device as claimed in any preceding claim, wherein the flow stabilising device is configured so as to allow a distance between the shelf and the stabilising inlet of the first slot to be varied.</claim-text></claim><claim id="ac-en-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>An open refrigerated display case or a flow stabilising device as claimed in any preceding claim, wherein the stabilising beams are transparent.</claim-text></claim><claim id="ac-en-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>An open refrigerated display case or a flow stabilising device as claimed in any preceding claim, wherein the outermost stabilising beam is provided with a product information strip (34).</claim-text></claim><claim id="ac-en-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>An open refrigerated display case or a flow stabilising device as claimed in any preceding claim, further comprising an injector port which is configured to introduce additional air into the air curtain, the injector port preferably being connected to the duct of the open refrigerated display case.</claim-text></claim></amended-claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW20422998" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="161" he="226" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="165" he="146" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="157" he="203" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --><figure id="f0004" num="4,5"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="120" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><search-report-data><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="159" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="159" he="233" type="tif"/></search-report-data><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
