<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2681919-A1" country="EP" doc-number="2681919" kind="A1" date="20140108" family-id="45998625" file-reference-id="312919" date-produced="20180823" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146586369" ucid="EP-2681919-A1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2681919</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-12716110-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154848561" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12716110</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120227</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP220440076" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12716110.7</doc-number><date>20120227</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140547803" ucid="US-201113037302-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>201113037302</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20110228</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140552808" ucid="US-2012026722-W" linkage-type="W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>2012026722</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20120227</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989316781" load-source="docdb">H04N  21/442       20110101ALI20120918BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989317651" load-source="docdb">H04N  21/4425      20110101ALI20120918BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989317770" load-source="docdb">H04N  21/658       20110101ALI20120918BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989320113" load-source="docdb">H04N  17/04        20060101AFI20120918BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989321846" load-source="docdb">H04N  21/488       20110101ALI20120918BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1836143483" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04N  21/4425      20130101 LI20170316BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1836143484" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04N  17/04        20130101 FI20170316BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1836143485" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04N  21/6582      20130101 LI20170316BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1836143486" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04N  21/4882      20130101 LI20170316BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1836143487" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04N  21/4424      20130101 LI20170316BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1836143488" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04N  21/4223      20130101 LI20170316BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1836143489" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04N  21/4126      20130101 LI20170316BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132363740" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">VERFAHREN UND SYSTEM ZUR ÜBERTRAGUNG VON INFORMATIONEN ÜBER DEN ZUSTAND UND DIE KONFIGURATION EINES DIGITALEMPFÄNGERS</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132363741" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">METHOD AND SYSTEM FOR COMMUNICATING SET-TOP BOX HEALTH AND CONFIGURATION INFORMATION</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132363742" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">PROCÉDÉ ET SYSTÈME DE COMMUNICATION D'INFORMATIONS DE FONCTIONNEMENT ET DE CONFIGURATION DE BOÎTIER DÉCODEUR</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919518680" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>ECHOSTAR TECHNOLOGIES LLC</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919505945" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>ECHOSTAR TECHNOLOGIES L.L.C.</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919018021" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Echostar Technologies L.L.C.</last-name><iid>101170537</iid><address><street>100 Inverness Terrace East</street><city>Englewood, CO 80112</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919539390" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>SCHAEFER GERMAR</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919544681" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>SCHAEFER, GERMAR</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919016177" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>SCHAEFER, GERMAR</last-name><address><street>620 Portland Road</street><city>Monument Colorado 80132</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919541602" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>MINNICK DAN J</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919512616" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>MINNICK, DAN J.</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919014456" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>MINNICK, DAN J.</last-name><address><street>10442 South Lions Path</street><city>Littleton Colorado 80124</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919006373" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Bebbington, Nicholas Paul</last-name><iid>100834219</iid><address><street>Beck Greener Fulwood House 12 Fulwood Place</street><city>London WC1V 6HR</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="US-2012026722-W"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2012026722</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20120227</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2012118733-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2012118733</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20120907</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549837702" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS549760202" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549914549" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549851326" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549837579" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549914550" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549769978" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549837703" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549914551" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549914552" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549837312" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549851327" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549851328" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549837704" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549914553" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549837705" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549769979" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549837580" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549914554" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549851329" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549914555" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549837706" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549760203" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549851334" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549851335" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549760204" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS549760209" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549760210" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549837581" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549760211" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549837313" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549759777" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549837318" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS549760212" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549837707" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549837606" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549837607" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS549914556" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA99831554" ref-ucid="WO-2012118733-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p num="0000">Disclosure is directed to determining a condition of the television receiver and communicating information regarding that condition to end-points that are external to the television receiver. The television receiver may create a two-dimensional barcode with information regarding the receiver condition and output the two-dimensional barcode for display on a display device. Once displayed on the display device, the two-dimensional barcode may be scanned into a mobile device where the information regarding the receiver condition may be stored, processed and/or forwarded to another location or device.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA100328377" ref-ucid="WO-2012118733-A1" lang="EN" source="national office" load-source="docdb"><p>Disclosure is directed to determining a condition of the television receiver and communicating information regarding that condition to end-points that are external to the television receiver. The television receiver may create a two-dimensional barcode with information regarding the receiver condition and output the two-dimensional barcode for display on a display device. Once displayed on the display device, the two-dimensional barcode may be scanned into a mobile device where the information regarding the receiver condition may be stored, processed and/or forwarded to another location or device.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA99831555" ref-ucid="WO-2012118733-A1" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><p num="0000">L'invention concerne la détermination d'un état du récepteur de télévision et la communication d'informations concernant cet état à des points d'extrémité qui sont externes au récepteur de télévision. Le récepteur de télévision peut créer un code à barres bidimensionnel contenant des informations concernant l'état du récepteur et émettre le code à barres bidimensionnel pour qu'il soit affiché sur un dispositif d'affichage. Une fois affiché sur le dispositif d'affichage, le code à barres bidimensionnel peut être balayé dans un dispositif mobile dans lequel les informations concernant l'état du récepteur peuvent être stockées, traitées et/ou transférées à un autre emplacement ou dispositif.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA100328378" ref-ucid="WO-2012118733-A1" lang="FR" source="national office" load-source="docdb"><p>L'invention concerne la détermination d'un état du récepteur de télévision et la communication d'informations concernant cet état à des points d'extrémité qui sont externes au récepteur de télévision. Le récepteur de télévision peut créer un code à barres bidimensionnel contenant des informations concernant l'état du récepteur et émettre le code à barres bidimensionnel pour qu'il soit affiché sur un dispositif d'affichage. Une fois affiché sur le dispositif d'affichage, le code à barres bidimensionnel peut être balayé dans un dispositif mobile dans lequel les informations concernant l'état du récepteur peuvent être stockées, traitées et/ou transférées à un autre emplacement ou dispositif.</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES51232643" ref-ucid="WO-2012118733-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="3"/>--><p id="p0001" num="0001"> METHOD AND SYSTEM FOR COMMUNICATING SET -TOP BOX HEALTH AND CONFIGURATION INFORMATION </p><p id="p0002" num="0002">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </p><p id="p0003" num="0003">This Patent Cooperation Treaty patent application claims priority to United States application No. 13/037,302, which was filed on February 28, 2011 , and entitled "Set-Top Box Health And Configuration", the contents of which are incorporated herein by reference in their entirety. </p><p id="p0004" num="0004">TECHNICAL FIELD </p><p id="p0005" num="0005">Embodiments discussed herein are generally directed to determining a condition of the television receiver and communicating information regarding that condition by a two- dimensional barcode that is displayed on a display device associated with the television receiver. </p><p id="p0006" num="0006">BACKGROUND </p><p id="p0007" num="0007">Cable television, satellite television, and other providers of program services typically provide customers with a television receiver that is adapted to receive and output program service content. The television receiver (one example of which is a set-top box) may, from time to time, malfunction or fail due to aging, normal wear and tear, or other causes. These malfunctions or failures may be an inconvenience to customers whose service may be interrupted while the television receiver is being repaired or replaced. In some cases, a customer may program his or her television receiver with recoding timers or certain customizable settings that may be lost when the receiver malfunctions or fails. Accordingly, there is a need to provide a user with a mechanism for anticipating and/or mitigating the effects of receiver failure or malfunction. </p><p id="p0008" num="0008">SUMMARY Embodiments discussed herein are generally directed to determining a condition of the television receiver and communicating information regarding that condition to end-points that are external to the television receiver. The receiver condition may be, for example, an error condition encountered in the operation of the receiver, or a receiver configuration or setting programmed by the user. The television receiver may create a two-dimensional barcode with information regarding the receiver condition and output the two-dimensional barcode for display on a display device. Once displayed on the display device, the two- dimensional barcode may be scanned into a mobile device where the information regarding 
<!-- EPO <DP n="4"/>-->
 the receiver condition may be stored, processed and/or forwarded to another location or device. For error conditions, the mobile device may forward the two-dimensional barcode or information encoded in the two-dimensional barcode to an appropriate party who may effect repairs. For receiver configurations or settings, the mobile device may store the </p><p id="p0009" num="0009">configuration or settings for later user by the television receiver. </p><p id="p0010" num="0010">One embodiment is directed to a method of managing a television receiver, comprising: sensing a condition of a television receiver; in response to sensing the condition of the television receiver, creating a two-dimensional barcode with information corresponding to the condition of the television receiver; and outputting the two-dimensional barcode form the television receiver for display on a display device; wherein, when the two-dimensional barcode is scanned from the display device into a mobile device, the two-dimensional barcode conveys the information corresponding to the condition of the television receiver to the mobile device. </p><p id="p0011" num="0011">Another embodiment is directed to a television receiver, comprising: a tuner operable to receive a program service transmission having a plurality of channels, the tuner operable to select one of the channels and to prepare the channel to be output in a data signal to a display device; a memory connected to the tuner, the memory including a tangible storage medium operable to store computer readable data and instructions; a processor connected to the memory operable to run computer executable code stored in the memory; a sensing module configured to execute on the processor to sense a condition of a television receiver; an encoding module configured to execute on the processor to create a two-dimensional barcode with information corresponding to the condition of the television receiver; and an output module configured to execute on the processor to output the two-dimensional barcode from the television receiver for display on the display device; wherein, when the two-dimensional barcode is scanned from the display device into a mobile device, the two- dimensional barcode conveys the information corresponding to the condition of the television receiver to the mobile device. </p><p id="p0012" num="0012">Another embodiment is directed to a method, comprising: scanning a two- dimensional barcode into a mobile device, the two-dimensional barcode being displayed on a display device associated with television receiver; and transmitting information regarding the error condition from the mobile device to a service provider; wherein the service provider utilizes the information regarding the error condition to initiate repair of the television receiver. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="5"/>-->
 Another embodiment is directed to a method, comprising: scanning a two- dimensional barcode into a mobile device, the two dimensional barcode being displayed on a display device associated with television receiver; decoding the two-dimensional barcode at the mobile device to determine one or more configuration settings for the television receiver; and storing the one or more configuration settings for later use in reconfiguring the television receiver. </p><p id="p0013" num="0013">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </p><p id="p0014" num="0014">Fig. 1 is a schematic diagram showing a sample system, components and implementations discussed herein; Fig. 2 is a flow chart that illustrates a method executed by the television receiver illustrated in Fig. 1 ; </p><p id="p0015" num="0015">Fig. 3A-3C are illustrations of outputs shown on a display device in connection with the operation of the method illustrated in Fig. 2; </p><p id="p0016" num="0016">Fig. 4 is a flow chart that illustrates a method executed by the mobile device illustrated in Fig. 1 ; </p><p id="p0017" num="0017">Fig. 5 is a flow chart that illustrates another method executed by the television receiver illustrated in Fig. 1 ; </p><p id="p0018" num="0018">Fig. 6 is a flow chart that illustrates another method executed by the mobile device illustrated in Fig. 1; Fig. 7A-7B are illustrations of output shown on a display device in connection with the operation of the method illustrated in Fig. 5; and </p><p id="p0019" num="0019">Fig. 8 is a flow chart that illustrates another method executed by the television receiver illustrated in Fig. 1. </p><p id="p0020" num="0020">DETAILED DESCRIPTION Fig. 1 is a schematic illustration of a general operating environment showing components and features of embodiments discussed herein. Fig. 1 includes a television receiver, generally identified by reference numeral 108. Embodiments discussed herein are generally directed to determining a condition of the television receiver 108 and </p><p id="p0021" num="0021">communicating information regarding that condition to end-points that are external to the television receiver 108. In certain instances, communicating information regarding receiver 
<!-- EPO <DP n="6"/>-->
 conditions is directed towards mitigating the inconveniences associated with malfunctions and/or failures of the television receiver 108. For example, in order to expedite repairs of the television receiver 108, the receiver may communicate information regarding error conditions that are encountered or otherwise sensed in the receiver's operations. In order to facilitate recovery from a catastrophic failure, the television receiver 108 may communicate information regarding settings or configurations that have been programmed by the user. The television receiver 108 may also communicate information regarding user-programmed configurations or settings in order to facilitate transfer of these configurations or settings into a different television receiver 108. The receiver 108 depicted in Fig. 1 may be configured to communicate with or receive signals from a service provider 104 that broadcasts, transmits, or otherwise delivers a content service to a receiver 108. The receiver 108 can include a set-top box (STB), a digital video recorder (DVR), a cable receiver, a general purpose computing device, and so on. The receiver 108 may also include a cable modem that receives streaming video and/or audio. Generally, a "receiver" may be any device capable of receiving video and/or audio content included in a broadcast or other content service transmission from a service provider 104. </p><p id="p0022" num="0022">The receiver 108 may be associated with an individual, business or other entity, user or subscriber that receives a content service transmission from the service provider 104. Generally the terms "user" and/or "subscriber" refer to an individual or company who receives a content service transmission. This may include those who have purchased a subscription to the content service transmission. Alternatively or additionally, the terms "user" and/or "subscriber" may refer to individuals who have been given access to the content service transmission through promotional offers and/or other non-fee-based agreements. </p><p id="p0023" num="0023">As used herein, a "service provider" may include any service that provides a content transmission to a receiver 108 such as, without limitation, a satellite television service, a direct television service or a cable television service, or a streaming video delivered across a network such as the Internet. Accordingly, a "content service transmission" encompasses transmission of information across a cable network (for example from a cable headend to a cable receiver), an Internet or other computer-accessible medium (including a local area network, wide-area network, and so on), including Internet protocol television transmissions, a wireless network such as a radio frequency or infrared network, and so on. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="7"/>-->
 In connection with embodiments that operate in the context of a satellite television service, the service provider 104 may provide a content service transmission through an uplink center. Such a satellite television service may utilize a direct broadcast satellite (DBS) system, which can incorporate packetized transmission signals according to an appropriate standard, such as the MPEG-2 and/or PEG-4 standards. The uplink center may include a transmitter or other equipment operable to transmit a modulated signal having data representing audio and/or visual content. The modulated signal may be received at a satellite, which in turn retransmits the modulated signal to be received at one or more terrestrial locations. The retransmitted signal may be received from the satellite at one or more satellite dishes, which are typically associated with one or more receivers 108. In connection with embodiments that operate in the context of a cable television service, the service provider 104 may provide a content service transmission to a headend, which, in turn, delivers the content service transmission to the receiver 108. </p><p id="p0024" num="0024">The receiver 108 may include a tuner 124 operable to receive the content service transmission signal from the service provider 104 and a decoder 128 to decode the received signal. The decoder 128 may be programmed to decrypt, demodulate, demultiplex or otherwise decode some or all of the received signals in accordance with purchases and selections made by a user. Output from the decoder 128 may be directed to an audio visual (A/V) processing module or other signal output portion, which may process the video and audio streams using digital-to-analog conversion techniques, or compressed digital to uncompressed digital conversion techniques, to produce one or more output signals. The output signals may be sent to a display device 140, such as a television or monitor in order to display content to a user. </p><p id="p0025" num="0025">The receiver 108 may include or be associated with a recorder 136, such as a digital video recorder (DVR). The recorder 136 may be integrated into the receiver 108 or may be a stand alone device. The recorder 136 may be operated by a user who programs the device or receiver function to record a particular program at a specified time. When the program occurs, the recorder 136 will record and store the program, which can then be viewed later. In addition to this functionality, the recorder 136 may buffer a certain amount of content during a live transmission. Buffering a live transmission allows a user to pause and/or rewind the content of the transmission and to then display the content in a non-live or delayed manner. </p><p id="p0026" num="0026">The receiver 108 may include or be associated with a memory or other storage device 152, such as magnetic or optical storage. The storage device 152 may be operable to store data received from the decoded content transmission signal. The storage device 
<!-- EPO <DP n="8"/>-->
 152 may be volatile or non-volatile memory implemented using any suitable technique or technology such as, for example, random access memory (RAM), disk storage, flash memory, solid state and so on. The storage device 152 may be located within the receiver 108 or separately from the receiver 108. The storage device 152 may removable. The stored data set may include audio and/or visual content to be transmitted and output through a display device, such as a television or monitor. Generally, audio/visual content may include still images, video images, animation and/or audio. Portable Network Graphics (PNG) or other appropriate formats, such as for example, Tagged Image File Format (TIFF), Joint Photographic Experts Group (JPEG), Motion Picture Experts Group (MPEG) -2, MPEG-4 may be used to display an image or video. </p><p id="p0027" num="0027">The receiver 08 may additionally include a processor 132 operable to run executable code in connection with various functions associated with the receiver 108. For example, the processor 132 may display graphics, images, animations or other content through an output device, such as a television or monitor. The storage device 152 may store an application, file, or other data that is useable by the processor 132. As used herein, an application includes processor executable code that may be run to carry out one or more functions associated with the receiver 108. "Processor executable code" includes any computer-readable media or commands that may be ultimately interpreted by a processor, such as HTML or XML files that are rendered into user-viewable applications by an application executed by the processor 132. </p><p id="p0028" num="0028">The processor 132 may also perform such tasks as executing commands received from a user. User commands may be sent to the receiver 108 through a user input device 1 4 such as remote or other wireless device. As used herein, a "user input device" may include any device operable to receive input from a user and to convey the input to the receiver 108. In one embodiment, the user input device 144 may be a hand-held device having a number of buttons or keys that when actuated by a user cause the user input device to covey information to the receiver 108 using a suitable communication means, such as an infrared signal. The user input device 144 may include a pointing device or functionality that allows the user to control the position of a cursor that is displayed on an output device. For example, the user input device 144 may include a track ball or glide plane that may be manipulated to control cursor movements. The user input device 144 may include a motion sensor or accelerometer that allows a user to control displayed items or graphics, such as a cursor, through movements of his or her hand or arm that cause a displacement of the user input device 144. It should be appreciated that other input devices such as a computer mouse or touch screen may be used and other communication means, 
<!-- EPO <DP n="9"/>-->
 wired or wireless, may be used. Information sent to the receiver 108 may include, for example, a command to change the output channel. Commands sent to the receiver 108 may be entered through a dedicated display menu. </p><p id="p0029" num="0029">The storage device 152 may store units of processor executable code in the form of one or more modules configured to implement certain functions described herein. </p><p id="p0030" num="0030">Embodiments discussed herein are directed to determining a condition of a television receiver 104 and communicating that condition to a mobile device 156. In determining the condition of the television receiver 104, the storage device 152 may include a condition sensing module 110 that is configured to detect a receiver condition such as an error that occurs during the operation of the receiver 104. In some instances, receiver condition sensed by the condition sensing module 110 may be a user-configurable setting such as a favorite channel list or recordings timers. </p><p id="p0031" num="0031">In communicating with the mobile device 156, the television receiver 108 typically encodes a two-dimensional barcode with at least information regarding the receiver condition and outputs the two-dimensional barcode for display on a display device 140. As used herein, a "two-dimensional barcode" is a machine readable representation of data that includes a pattern of bars, squares, dots, hexagons or other geometric forms. The geometric forms are arranged within the two-dimensional barcode to form a message according to a predefined symbology that defines the meaning of various symbols. In some implementations, the two-dimensional barcode may arrange symbols in a grid or matrix. In other implementations, the symbols of the two-dimensional barcode may be arranged in a circular patterns. In still other implementations, steganography techniques may be used to encode symbols within an image in such a way that a viewer is not aware of the symbols. One example of a two-dimensional barcode is QR code, developed by the Denso-Wave corporation of Japan. Another example of a two-dimensional barcode is Aztec code, developed by Andrew Longacre, Jr. and Robert Hussey. </p><p id="p0032" num="0032">The receiver 104 may include an encoding module 112 configured to create a two- dimensional barcode with one or more codes corresponding to the receiver condition sensed by the condition sensing module 110. Once the encoding module 112 create the appropriate information in a two-dimensional barcode, an output module 1 6 may output the two- dimensional barcode from the television receiver 104 for display on the display device 140. Once displayed on the display device 140, the two-dimensional barcode may be scanned into the mobile device 156 where the information regarding the receiver condition may be stored, processed and/or forwarded to another location or device. In accordance with certain embodiments, the output module 116 may be configured to output the two- 
<!-- EPO <DP n="10"/>-->
 dimensional barcode to a printer device. For example, the output module 116 may print the two-dimensional barcode if a television or other display device 1 0 is unavailable (e.g., the display device 140 may be broken or malfunctioning). Once the two-dimensional barcode is printed to a piece of paper, the mobile device 156 may scan the paper to aquire the two- dimensional bar code. </p><p id="p0033" num="0033">Generally, the mobile device 156 may include a processor 164 operable to load and store various processor-executable modules stored in the storage device 160. The mobile device 148 may additionally include an input device, such a keypad or keyboard, and an output device, such as an LED or LCD screen. In addition to processor-executable code, the storage device 160 may store data associated with two-dimensional barcodes that are scanned into the mobile device 156 from the receiver 108. In this regard, the mobile device 156 may include a scanner 168 that is operable to scan or otherwise read a two-dimensional barcode. In one embodiment, the scanner 168 may be a photo-sensor or laser scanner that operates by sweeping a beam of light across a surface that displays the two-dimensional barcode. In other embodiments, the scanner 168 may be charge-coupled device, such a digital camera, that is operable to capture an image of the two-dimensional barcode. In connection with capturing an image of the two-dimensional barcode, the mobile device 156 may be configured to extract information contained in the two-dimensional barcode using digital signal processing or other appropriate techniques. The mobile device 156 may be operable to transfer content across a network 176 to a database 180 or to the service provider 104. Network transactions may be conducted through the operation of a network interface 172, such as a modem network interface card, cable plug or jack, and so on. Using the interface, the mobile device 156 may communicate over a network 176, such as a packet switched network or a circuit switched network, one example of which is the public switched telephone network (PSTN). It should be appreciated that the network 176 may be any type of network capable of data communication, such as, for example, a local or wide area network or the Internet. The mobile device 156 may communicate through a network connection using any suitable communication protocol such as TCP/IP. The type of receiver condition that is communicated by the television receiver 104 may determine the type of action taken by the mobile device 156 once the mobile device 156 scans the two-dimensional barcode. In one instance, the television receiver 104 may communicate an error condition that has occurred or is occurring in the operations of the television receiver 104. In this instance, the mobile device 156 may forward the two- dimensional barcode or information encoded in the two-dimensional barcode to an 
<!-- EPO <DP n="11"/>-->
 appropriate party who may effect repairs. In another instance, the television receiver 104 may communicate one or more configuration settings for the television receiver or a user input device 144 associated with the television receiver 108. In this instance, the mobile device 156 may store the configuration settings for later user by the television receiver 108. The receiver 108 may additionally include a configuration module 120 that may be utilized in those instances where configuration settings for the television receiver 108 or the user input device 1 4 are communicated to the mobile device 156. Specifically, the configuration module 120 may re-configure the television receiver 108 and/or the user input device 144 according to settings that have been previously stored by the mobile device 156. For example, the configuration module 120 may be utilized to recover from a catastrophic failure by reloading configuration settings lost in the failure. Here, the configuration module may connect to a storage medium used by the mobile device 156 to store configuration settings and then download the stored settings for use in reconfiguring the television receiver 108 or the user input device 144. Fig. 2 is a flow chart that illustrates a method of communicating an error condition that is present in a television receiver 108. Initially, in operation 204, the condition sensing module 110 receives an indication of an error condition occurring in the television receiver 108. The error condition may be, for example, the failure of a particular part or component of the television receiver 108. Following operation 204, operation 208 may be executed. In operation 208, the condition sensing module 110 determines an error code that corresponds to the error condition sensed in operation 204. The condition sensing module 110 may be configured to include a list or table of various error codes that classify the various errors which are known to occur in a television receiver 108. The error codes used in operation 208 may be used to facilitate rapid and accurate recognition of the error condition by technicians or other personnel who will be called upon to repair the television receiver 108. The error codes may be specific to a particular service provider who provides content service transmission to the television receiver 108. Alternatively, the error codes may be a generally recognized scheme of error classification recognized by various service providers within the cable and/or satellite television industry. Following operation 208, operation 212 may be executed. </p><p id="p0034" num="0034">In operation 212, the encoding module 112 creates a two-dimensional barcode with the error code corresponding to the error condition as determined or classified in operation 208. Following operation 212, operation 216 may be executed. In operation 216, the encoding module 112 may incorporate routing information into the two-dimensional barcode. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="12"/>-->
 Following operation 216, operation 220 may be executed. In operation 220, the output module 1 16 may output the two-dimensional barcode which is created in operations 212 and 216 from the television receiver 108 for display on the display device 140. The routing information incorporated in operation 216 may be used by the mobile device 156 in order to properly direct or otherwise route the error code information from the mobile device to the service provider 104. In one embodiment, the routing information may include a uniform resource locater (URL), which may be used by the mobile device 156 to access a particular website through a browser or other web interface operating on the mobile device 156. </p><p id="p0035" num="0035">Through the website accessed through the URL, the mobile device 156 may enter an error code such that the error code is transmitted across the network 176 to be received by the service provider 104. </p><p id="p0036" num="0036">Figs. 3A-3C are illustrations of output mechanisms such as graphical user interfaces and/or prompts that may be used to communicate an error condition from a television receiver using a two-dimensional barcode. Fig. 3A includes a graphical illustration of output shown or visible on the display device 140. In Fig. 3A, the display device 140 shows program content 304, which is received by the television receiver 108 from the service provider 104 and output on the display device 140. Additionally in Fig. 3A, the display device 140 shows a "pop up" or icon 308 that is overlaid on top of the program content 304. The icon 308 includes an error message that informs the user or viewer that the television receiver 108 has detected an internal error or error condition. The icon 308 may include a message that specifies the manner in which the user may take action to learn more about the error condition and/or to mitigate the error condition. For example, the icon 308 may include a message that says, for example, press info or select to receive more information. </p><p id="p0037" num="0037">Fig. 3B is an illustration of output from the display device 140 that may be displayed in response to a user selecting or otherwise responding to the icon displayed in Fig. 3A. The menu displayed in Fig. 3B may be a graphical user interface or other menu that takes up a substantial portion of the display device 140. In certain embodiments, a portion of the surface area of the display device 140 may be reserved for a scaled down or smaller window that displays the normal program content. As shown in Fig. 3B, the window 312 includes program contents otherwise visible during display of normal programming. The error detection menu 314 shown in Fig. 3B may include error message 316 that provides more detailed information concerning the error detected within the television receiver 108. (It should be appreciated that in certain embodiments all information related to the error condition may displayed to the user through one or more messages that are overlaid over broadcast content.) Additionally, the message 316 may include directions or other 
<!-- EPO <DP n="13"/>-->
 instructions for a user to scan a two-dimensional barcode 320 that is displayed on the display device 140. As discussed in connection with Fig. 2, the two-dimensional barcode 320 may include an encoding of an error code corresponding to the error condition and/or routing information usable to direct the error code to the proper service provider 104 through network transactions initiated across the network 176. In connection with the display of the two-dimensional barcode 320, a user may scan the two-dimensional barcode 320 into his or her mobile device 156. As described above, scanning the two-dimensional barcode 320 may include photographing the two-dimensional barcode 320 using a camera or scanner 168 incorporated into the mobile device 156. In certain instances, the error condition sensed in operation 204 may be sufficiently critical to the function of the television receiver 108 that the condition sensing module 110 may determine that a failure of the television receiver is imminent. In such circumstances, the output module 116 may be configured to stop other programming content from being output to the display device 140 and instead output only a two-dimensional barcode encoded with the error condition determined in operation 204. Such an output is shown in Fig. 3C. As shown in Fig. 3C, the display device 140 includes a two-dimensional barcode 320 displayed by itself in a central location on the display device 140. In response to such a display, the user may scan or photograph the two-dimensional barcode 320 and </p><p id="p0038" num="0038">communicate the information contained therein to the service provider 104, as appropriate. Fig. 4 is a flow chart that illustrates a method of receiving the two-dimensional barcode 320 from a television receiver 108 into a mobile device 156 and for communicating the information contained therein to the service provider 104. Initially, in operation 404, the mobile device 156 may scan the displayed two-dimensional barcode 320. In operation 404 a specifically designed two-dimensional barcode scanner or a camera may scan or photograph the two-dimensional barcode as it is displayed on the display device 104. </p><p id="p0039" num="0039">Following operation 404 operation, 408 may be executed. </p><p id="p0040" num="0040">In operation 408, the mobile device 156 may connect to the service provider 104 using routing information contained in the two-dimensional barcode received in operation 408. Connecting to the service provider may include initiating a network transaction across the network 176 using TCP/IP protocol or other appropriate methods of network </p><p id="p0041" num="0041">communication. Additionally, operation 408 may include formatting a message which is to be sent across the network 176. Such messages may include e-mail or M S-type messaging formats. Following operation 408, operation 412 may be executed. In operation 412, the mobile device 156 may transmit error codes from the mobile device to the service 
<!-- EPO <DP n="14"/>-->
 provider 104. Alternatively or in combination, operation 412 may include transmitting a scanned image of the two-dimensional barcode such as in an email or MMS message. </p><p id="p0042" num="0042">Fig. 5 is a flow chart that illustrates a method of communicating a configuration setting associated with a television receiver 108. Initially, in operation 504, the condition sensing module 110 senses the state or other configuration of the television receiver 108. As used herein, the configuration of the television receiver may include such user- programmable or adjustable settings as favorite channels, specific recording timers, and so on. Operation 504 may additionally include sensing a configuration of a programmable remote control or other input device 144. Specifically, the input device 144 may include certain buttons or other input mechanisms that are programmed by a user to have a specific function. Such user-programmed characteristics of the television receiver 108 and/or remote 144 are sensed and recorded by the condition sensing module 1 0 in operation 504. </p><p id="p0043" num="0043">Following operation 504, operation 508 may be executed. </p><p id="p0044" num="0044">In operation 508, the encoding module 112 may create the television receiver 108 and/or remote 144 configuration into a two-dimensional barcode. Following operation 508, operation 512 may be executed. In operation 512, the output module 116 may output the two-dimensional barcode createed in operation 508 from the television receiver 108 to the display device 140. </p><p id="p0045" num="0045">Fig. 6 is a flow chart that illustrates a method of receiving configuration information and storing that configuration information by a mobile device 176. Initially, in operation 604, the mobile device 156 scans the two-dimensional barcode into the mobile device 156. </p><p id="p0046" num="0046">Operation 604 may include the use of a scanner or camera 168 that scans or photographs the two-dimensional barcode as it is displayed on the display device 140. Following operation 604, operation 608 may be executed. In operation 608, the mobile device 156 may connect to a storage medium. The storage medium in one embodiment may include the storage device 160 incorporated internally into the mobile device 156. In other embodiments, the storage medium may be a database 180 that is accessed by the mobile device 156 through a network transaction occurring across the network 176. Following operation 608, operation 612 may be executed. In operation 612, the mobile device 156 may store the configuration information in the storage medium accessed in operation 608. </p><p id="p0047" num="0047">Figs. 7A and 7B are illustrations of graphical user interfaces or menus used to program various features of the television receiver 108 and/or remote control 144, and to 
<!-- EPO <DP n="15"/>-->
 store those configurations in a location that is separate from the television receiver 104. Fig. 7a includes a configuration menu 708 that includes a window 712 which includes a scaled or reduced version of the program content typically output from the display device 140. The configuration menu 720 additionally includes a number of sub menus that may be used to program various features of the television receiver 104. For example, the configuration menu 702 may include favorite channels sub-menu 704 that may be used to compile a list of channels that the user typically views during the day. The favorite channels menu 704 may be accessed when needed to view the user's favorite channels in an efficient and speedy manner. The configuration menu 702 may additionally include a recording timers sub-menu 708. The recording timers sub-menu 708 may include a listing of certain events or programs that the user has programmed or scheduled to be recorded by the recorder 136. The configuration menu 702 may additionally include a remote settings sub-menu 716. The remote settings sub-menu 716 may be used to program certain buttons or other input mechanisms on the user input device 144 with specific user defined functionality. The configuration menu 702 may additionally include a message 724 that instructs the user to select a certain button or enter a certain command to generate a two-dimensional barcode that will preserve the various settings established through the use of the configuration menu 702. </p><p id="p0048" num="0048">Fig. 7B includes a subsequent menu or screen utilized by the configuration menu 702. The screen or menu shown in Fig. 7B is displayed in response to a user selecting or instructing the generation of the two-dimensional barcode. The menu 702 shown in Fig. 7B includes a message that informs the user that the two-dimensional barcode has been generated and/or instructs the user to scan the two-dimensional barcode 720 into his or her mobile device 156. Fig. 8 is a flow chart illustrating method of preserving the configurations associated with television receiver and/or remote control. Initially, in operation 804, the configuration sensing module 110 receives an indication that the television receiver 108 and/or remote 144 is to be reconfigured. Reconfiguring may occur, for example, when the television receiver 108 is reprogrammed or updated in a way that erases previous settings. </p><p id="p0049" num="0049">Alternatively, the receiver 108 may have experienced a catastrophic failure that requires reconfiguring. In other instances, the service provider 104 may in fact replace the user's existing television receiver 108 with a more updated or improved receiver. Following operation 804, operation 808 may be executed. </p><p id="p0050" num="0050">In operation 808, the television receiver 108 establishes a connection between a television receiver 108 and a configuration data source. The configuration data source may, 
<!-- EPO <DP n="16"/>-->
 in one embodiment, be the storage device 160 associated with the mobile device 156. In other embodiments, the configuration data source may be the database 180. Establishing the connection may include initiating a network connection across the network 176, if the receiver 108 has such functionality. In other embodiments, the connection may be established through a USB port or other communication port associated with the receiver 108. </p><p id="p0051" num="0051">Following operation 808, operation 812 may be executed. In operation 812, the television receiver 108 downloads the configuration data into the television receiver 108. Following operation 812, operation 816 may be executed. In operation 816, the television receiver may configure itself or the remote 144 according to the configuration data acquired in operation 812. </p><p id="p0052" num="0052">By way of example and not limitation, some system elements described herein such as the condition sensing module 110, the encoding module 112, the output module 116 and the configuration module 120 are depicted in the figures as processor executable software or code elements that are stored in a stored in a storage device 152. However, it should be appreciated that some system designs consistent with the teachings described herein may implement separate modules within a television receiver that serve the functions </p><p id="p0053" num="0053">implemented by the illustrated condition sensing module 1 10, the encoding module 112, the output module 116 and the configuration module 120. Such modules may include hardware and/or software elements that are implemented apart from the storage device 152. In some embodiments, such separate modules may utilize the storage device 152 for such purposes as loading and/or storing data. </p><p id="p0054" num="0054">While embodiments are discussed herein in connection with a exemplary satellite or cable broadcast system, it should be appreciated that embodiments may be used in connection other types of networks or content delivery mechanisms. Generally, the disclosure includes content delivered from a provider to a receiver across or over a network. The network across which content may be delivered may include satellite or cable system. Alternatively, the network may include a local area network, wide area network or the Internet. In connection with certain embodiments, a receiver may include a general purpose computer operable to receive data or other content across a network, such as a wide area network of the internet. In such embodiments, the computer may be configured so that a provider can access a web site, a file transfer protocol (FTP) site, a file sharing system or site, and so on. Moreover, the order of method operations, such those shown in Fig. 2, Fig. 4, Fig. 5, Fig. 6 and Fig. 8, described herein is by way of example and limitation. Certain 
<!-- EPO <DP n="17"/>-->
 implementations may reorder method operations without departing from the spirit and scope of the disclosure. 
</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM44851795" ref-ucid="WO-2012118733-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><claim-statement><!-- EPO <DP n="18"/>-->Claims: </claim-statement><claim id="clm-0001" num="1"><claim-text>1. A method of managing a television receiver, comprising: </claim-text><claim-text> sensing a condition of a television receiver; </claim-text><claim-text> in response to sensing the condition of the television receiver, creating a two- dimensional barcode with information corresponding to the condition of the television receiver; and </claim-text><claim-text> outputting the two-dimensional barcode form the television receiver for display on a display device; </claim-text><claim-text> wherein, when the two-dimensional barcode is scanned from the display device into a mobile device, the two-dimensional barcode conveys the information regarding the condition of the television receiver to the mobile device. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0002" num="2"><claim-text>2. The method of claim 1 , wherein the condition of the television receiver is an error condition occurring during an operation of the television receiver. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0003" num="3"><claim-text>3. The method of claim 2, further comprising: </claim-text><claim-text> displaying an icon on the display device such that the icon overlays program content also displayed on the display device, the icon including an error message and a prompt selectable by the user; </claim-text><claim-text> receiving input at the television receiver, the input selecting the prompt displayed on the display device; </claim-text><claim-text> in response to receiving the input at the television receiver, outputting a graphical user interface from television receiver for display on the display device, the graphical user interface including further information regarding the error condition and including the two- dimensional barcode. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0004" num="4"><claim-text>4. The method of claim 2, further comprising: </claim-text><claim-text> determining that the error condition will result in a catastrophic failure of the television receiver; and </claim-text><claim-text> in response, outputting the two-dimensional barcode without further user input such that the display device displays the two-dimensional barcode without other content. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0005" num="5"><claim-text>5. The method of claim 2, further comprising: </claim-text><claim-text> encoding the two-dimensional barcode with routing information, wherein the mobile device uses the routing information to direct information regarding the error condition to a service provider capable of mitigating the error condition. <!-- EPO <DP n="19"/>--> </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0006" num="6"><claim-text>6. The method of claim 5, wherein: </claim-text><claim-text> the routing information includes a uniform resource locator configured to access a website through a browser operating on the mobile device; and </claim-text><claim-text> the website is configured to communicate the error condition to the service provider using information obtained by scanning the two-dimensional barcode. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0007" num="7"><claim-text>7. The method of claim 5, wherein the routing information causes the mobile device to automatically launch an application that is configured to communicate with the service provider. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0008" num="8"><claim-text>8. The method of claim 1 , wherein: </claim-text><claim-text> the condition is one or more user adjustable settings for the television receiver; the operation of sensing the condition of the television receiver is executed in response to receiving a user request at the television receiver to save the one or more user adjustable settings; and </claim-text><claim-text> the mobile device is configured to store the one or more user adjustable settings for later use by the television receiver. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0009" num="9"><claim-text>9. The method of claim 8, further comprising: </claim-text><claim-text> receiving a request to reconfigure the television receiver according to the one or more user adjustable settings stored by the mobile device; </claim-text><claim-text> establishing a connection from the television receiver to a storage medium on which the mobile device has stored the one or more user adjustable settings; </claim-text><claim-text> transferring the one or more user adjustable settings from the storage medium to the television receiver; and </claim-text><claim-text> configuring the television receiver according to the one or more user adjustable settings transferred from the storage medium to the television receiver. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0010" num="10"><claim-text>10. A television receiver, comprising: </claim-text><claim-text> a tuner operable to receive a program service transmission having a plurality of channels, the tuner operable to select one of the channels and to prepare the channel to be output in a data signal to a display device; </claim-text><claim-text> a memory connected to the tuner, the memory including a tangible storage medium operable to store computer readable data and instructions; </claim-text><claim-text> a processor connected to the memory operable to run computer executable code stored in the memory; </claim-text><claim-text> a sensing module configured to execute on the processor to sense a condition of a television receiver; <!-- EPO <DP n="20"/>--> an encoding module configured to execute on the processor to create a two- dimensional barcode with information corresponding to the condition of the television receiver; and </claim-text><claim-text> an output module configured to execute on the processor to output the two- dimensional barcode from the television receiver for display on the display device; </claim-text><claim-text> wherein, when the two-dimensional barcode is scanned from the display device into a mobile device, the two-dimensional barcode conveys the information regarding the condition of the television receiver to the mobile device. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0011" num="11"><claim-text>11. The television receiver of claim 10, wherein the condition of television receiver is a user-programmable configuration setting, and when the two-dimensional barcode is scanned from the display device into a mobile device, the mobile device stores the user-programmable configuration setting for later use by the television receiver, the television receiver further comprising: </claim-text><claim-text> a configuration module configured to execute on the processor to connect to a storage medium used by the mobile device to store the user-programmable configuration setting, to download the user-programmable configuration setting, and to set the television receiver according to the user-programmable configuration setting. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0012" num="12"><claim-text>12. The television receive of claim 11 , further comprising: </claim-text><claim-text> a recorder operable to a record and store a program associated with a channel of the program service transmission; </claim-text><claim-text> wherein the user-programmable configuration settings includes a recording timer configured to cause the recorder to record a particular program. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0013" num="13"><claim-text>13. A method, comprising: </claim-text><claim-text> scanning a two-dimensional barcode into a mobile device, the two-dimensional barcode being displayed on a display device associated with television receiver; and </claim-text><claim-text> transmitting information regarding the error condition from the mobile device to a service provider; </claim-text><claim-text> wherein the service provider utilizes the information regarding the error condition to initiate repair of the television receiver. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0014" num="14"><claim-text>14. The method of claim 13, further comprising: </claim-text><claim-text> decoding the two-dimensional barcode at the mobile device to determine an error condition present in the television receiver; </claim-text><claim-text> wherein the operation of transmitting information includes transmitting the information decoded at the mobile device. <!-- EPO <DP n="21"/>--> </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0015" num="15"><claim-text>15. The method of claim 14, further comprising: </claim-text><claim-text> decoding the two-dimensional barcode at the mobile device to determine routing information associated with an error code for the error condition; </claim-text><claim-text> wherein the operation of transmitting information includes using the routing information to determine a network address for the service provider and sending the information to the service provider at the network address. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0016" num="16"><claim-text>16. The method of claim 13, wherein the operation of scanning the two- dimensional barcode includes taking a photograph of the two dimensional barcode using a camera component of the mobile device. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0017" num="17"><claim-text>17. The method of claim 16, wherein the operation of transmitting information includes sending a picture message to the service provider, the picture message including the photograph of the two-dimensional barcode. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0018" num="18"><claim-text>18. A method, comprising: </claim-text><claim-text> scanning a two-dimensional barcode into a mobile device, the two dimensional barcode being displayed on a display device associated with television receiver; </claim-text><claim-text> decoding the two-dimensional barcode at the mobile device to determine one or more configuration settings for the television receiver; and </claim-text><claim-text> storing the one or more configuration settings for later use in reconfiguring the television receiver. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0019" num="19"><claim-text>19. The method of claim 18, wherein the one or more configuration settings includes a configuration setting for a remote control device associated with the television receiver. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0020" num="20"><claim-text>20. The method of claim 18, wherein the operation of storing the one or more configuration settings comprises: </claim-text><claim-text> establishing a network connection between the mobile device and a storage device that is remote from the mobile device; </claim-text><claim-text> transmitting the one or more configuration settings from the mobile device to the storage device across the network connection; and </claim-text><claim-text> storing the one or more configuration settings at the storage device. </claim-text></claim></claims><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
