<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2106623-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2106623" kind="B1" date="20140101" family-id="39304757" file-reference-id="318254" date-produced="20180822" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146554127" ucid="EP-2106623-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2106623</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-08702453-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154828050" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>08702453</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20080117</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140453372" ucid="EP-07100924-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>07100924</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20070122</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140452481" ucid="EP-08702453-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>08702453</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20080117</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140454917" ucid="IB-2008050167-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>IB</country><doc-number>2008050167</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20080117</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130807</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988121275" load-source="ipcr">H01L  51/52        20060101AFI20130711BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988095578" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01L2251/5361      20130101 LA20130915BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988108178" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01L  51/5212      20130101 FI20130711BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988125906" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01L  51/5228      20130101 LI20130711BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132194865" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">LICHTEMITTIERENDE VORRICHTUNG</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132194866" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">LIGHT EMITTING DEVICE</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132194867" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">DISPOSITIF ÉMETTANT DE LA LUMIÈRE</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918167506" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>PHILIPS INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY</last-name><address><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918159590" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>PHILIPS INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY &amp; STANDARDS GMBH</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918133943" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>KONINKL PHILIPS NV</last-name><address><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918136712" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>KONINKLIJKE PHILIPS N.V.</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918155900" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>ESER JUERGEN</last-name><address><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918161563" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>ESER, JUERGEN</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918998890" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>ESER, Jürgen</last-name><address><street>c/o High Tech Campus 44</street><city>NL-5656 AE Eindhoven</city><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918134856" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>YOUNG EDWARD WILLEM ALBERT</last-name><address><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918171546" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>YOUNG, EDWARD WILLEM ALBERT</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918998888" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>YOUNG, EDWARD WILLEM ALBERT</last-name><address><street>c/o High Tech Campus 44</street><city>NL-5656 AE Eindhoven</city><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918138011" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>KRIJNE JOHANNES</last-name><address><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918136633" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>KRIJNE, JOHANNES</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918998887" load-source="patent-office" sequence="3" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>KRIJNE, JOHANNES</last-name><address><street>c/o High Tech Campus 44</street><city>NL-5656 AE Eindhoven</city><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918145756" load-source="docdb" sequence="4" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>VAN DER PADT ARIE</last-name><address><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918150812" load-source="docdb" sequence="4" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>VAN DER PADT, ARIE</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918998889" load-source="patent-office" sequence="4" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>VAN DER PADT, ARIE</last-name><address><street>c/o High Tech Campus 44</street><city>NL-5656 AE Eindhoven</city><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918998892" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Philips Intellectual Property &amp; Standards GmbH</last-name><iid>100798256</iid><address><street>Lübeckertordamm 5</street><city>20099 Hamburg</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></assignee><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918998893" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Koninklijke Philips N.V.</last-name><iid>101391185</iid><address><street>High Tech Campus 5</street><city>5656 AE Eindhoven</city><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918998891" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Bekkers, Joost J.J</last-name><iid>100055246</iid><address><street>Philips Intellectual Property &amp; Standards P.O. Box 220</street><city>5600 AE Eindhoven</city><country>NL</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="IB-2008050167-W"><document-id><country>IB</country><doc-number>2008050167</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20080117</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2008090493-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2008090493</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20080731</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548874739" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS548992466" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS548832123" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS548990724" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS548992467" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS548874740" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS548887218" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548992468" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS548992469" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS548987809" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS548832124" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS548990725" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548887219" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548992470" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS548887220" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS548874741" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS548990726" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS548992471" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS548832125" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS548992472" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS548832126" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS548984846" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS548832127" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS548832128" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS548984847" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS548987810" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS548985612" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS548987811" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS548832129" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS548874742" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS548987812" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS548990727" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS548985613" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS548984848" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63957620" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001">FIELD OF THE INVENTION</heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">This invention relates to a light emitting device and a method to manufacture such a device.</p><heading id="h0002">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">To generate a favorable climate in a room large area illumination devices are needed. Nowadays often gas discharge lamps are used to generate a homogeneous light, illuminating large parts of the room. Unfortunately, discharge lamps are known to be costly and quite inefficient. To overcome this disadvantage, the use of organic light emitting diodes (OLED) is appropriate. The advantage of the OLED is that it is a homogeneous light source with potentially low costs and high efficiency. Organic light emitting devices (materials and structures) are known in the art, for instant as disclosed in <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="WO2005053053A1"><text>WO2005/053053 A1</text></patcit>.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">However, large size OLEDs suffers the problem of brightness inhomogeneity. The brightness inhomogeneity is due to the fact that the OLEDs comprise thin film electrodes, with a thickness of around a few hundred nm. Therefore, the thin film electrodes have a relative high sheet resistance. As OLEDs are driven at low voltage and high currents, the high sheet resistance results in a voltage drop along the electrodes, causing the brightness inhomogeneity. This disadvantage is getting worse with increasing OLED size.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004"><patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="JP2005267991A"><text>JP 2005 267991 A</text></patcit> discloses a light emitting element having a substrate, a plurality of lower electrodes disposed in a stripe shape, a plurality of transparent counter electrodes disposed in a stripe shape, and a luminescent layer disposed between the lower<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> electrode and the transparent counter electrodes, and the display device having an auxiliary electrode disposed on the transparent counter electrodes and a first insulating layer below the auxiliary electrode and between the transparent counter electrode and the lower electrode.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005"><patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="JP2003123990A"><text>JP 2003 123990 A</text></patcit> discloses an organic electroluminescent element comprising at least a transparent anode layer, an organic light emitting medium layer, and a cathode layer. This element further comprises an auxiliary electrode layer laminated on the cathode layer through an insulating layer in contact with the transparent cathode layer. The auxiliary electrode layer is made of at least one metallic material, and the insulating layer is made of an inorganic insulating film and/or a polymer resin.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006"><patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="US20050248266A1"><text>US 2005/0248266 A1</text></patcit> discloses an active-driving organic EL light emission device comprising an organic EL element comprising an organic luminous medium between an upper electrode and a lower electrode, and a thin film transistor for driving this organic EL element, wherein light emitted from the organic EL element is taken out from the side of the upper electrode, and the upper electrode comprises a main electrode formed of transparent conductive material, and an auxiliary electrode formed of a low-resistance material.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007"><patcit id="pcit0005" dnum="WO2007008946A2"><text>WO 2007/008946 A2</text></patcit> discloses an organic light-emitting diode (OLED) device, comprising: a substrate; an OLED formed on the substrate comprising a first electrode, one or more layers of organic material, one of which emits light, and a transparent second electrode formed over the one or more layers of organic material, the transparent second electrode and layer(s) of organic light-emitting material having a first refractive index range; a transparent cover having a second refractive index; a light scattering layer located between the substrate and cover for scattering light emitted by the light-emitting layer; and an auxiliary electrode grid located above the transparent second electrode.</p><heading id="h0003">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading><!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --><p id="p0008" num="0008">The invention has for its object to eliminate the above mentioned disadvantages. In particular it is an object to the invention to provide a large size OLED with a homogeneous brightness and a method to manufacture such a device.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">The object is achieved by a light-emitting device as taught by claim 1 of the present invention. Advantage embodiments of the light-emitting device are defined in the sub-claims.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">The leading thought of the invention is the use of at least two shunt elements, comprising a larger cross-section than the electrode layer, with which it is connected, and therefore comprising a low sheet resistance. Due to this advantage, the shunt elements can transport the needed current to all parts of the OLED, so that a homogeneous brightness is achieved.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">The light-emitting device comprises a basic layer, serving as a carrier, which may be made of glass or organic material or from non-transmittive material such as metal foils. Onto this basic layer usually a thin layer of a transparent Indium Tin Oxide (ITO) is applied, forming the first electrode layer. Furthermore, organic light emitting diodes consists of at least one thin layer, with a layer thickness of approximately 5 to 500 nm of organic substances. The OLED is regularly covered with a layer of metal, like aluminum, forming the second electrode layer, whereas the metal layer features a thickness of approximately 100 nm and thus a thickness like the ITO-layer. Aluminum of such a thickness works as a mirror, such that the emission is through the transparent ITO first electrode layer and the transparent basic layer only. Unfortunately, the specific resistance of ITO is approximately two orders of magnitude higher than the specific resistance of aluminum. Therefore, the flow of the current in the<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> highly attenuated. To overcome this disadvantage, the first electrode layer may be connected with the shunt element.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">In the context of the invention, the term organic light-emitting layer comprises a single layer of an organic material as well as an element, build of several layers, comprising organic and inorganic material.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">Thin electrode layers used in OLED devices show a sheet resistance leading to a voltage drop across the electrode area, especially for large OLED devices leading to an inhomogeneous brightness distribution. This effect mainly occurs for the second electrode, but also for the first electrode. To overcome this disadvantage, a first preferred embodiment of the light emitting device comprises a first shunt element, connected with the first electrode layer and a second shunt element, connected with the second electrode layer. So both electrode layers, embedded in the light-emitting device, are connected with one shunt element each.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">The shunt element may be a foil like element, being connected with one of the electrode layers. The connection can be done through different methods achieving an electrical connection between the electrode layer and a shunt element, wherein the connection comprises a low transfer resistance. For example this aim can be achieved by gluing or welding the foil like shunt element to the electrode layer. Especially, laser welding, heat sealing, resistant welding or electron beam welding have shown to be advantageous. Apart from this merging, the shunt element can be produced by thin film deposition techniques, such as ion beam deposition, electron beam deposition, chemical vapor deposition, thermal evaporation, plasma beam deposition, sputter deposition and galvanic deposition. As described above the main idea of the invention is the use of a huge shunt element, supporting the electrode layer in the transport of the current. Therefore, the size of the shunt element should be large compared to the electrode layer. In a preferred embodiment, the shunt element comprises a width between 50 µm to 4 mm, preferably between 100 µm to 2 mm, and a height between 20 µm to 800 µm, preferably between 50 µm to 500 µm. Compared with the sheet thicknesses of the electrode layers, the height of the shunt element is up to three orders of magnitude larger. Thus, the sheet resistance is greatly reduced by distributing the current mainly via<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> the shunt elements. The remaining voltage drop across the small electrode areas between the shunt elements is negligible. To enhance this effect, it is preferably, that the shunt element comprises a high electrical conductivity, which is preferably higher than 30x10<sup>6</sup> S/m.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">The shunt element may be a metal selected from Group III or IB metals and transition metals such as silver, gold, copper, aluminum, tungsten, molybdenum, chromium, and the like. Combinations and alloys of these metals are very suitable, such as molybdenum chrome/aluminum/molybdenum chrome (MAM).</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">Due to the large size the shunt element is not embedded in the stack of layers, but sticks out of the plane of the stack of layers. It is therefore visible and may even be palpable above the surface of the other layers. As the electrode layer, most distant from the basic layer, may be covered with a protection layer, last named layer may also cover the shunt element. As the name says, the protection layer's assignment is to protect the stack of layers, building the OLED. Therefore, it is appropriate, that the protection layer may comprise a combination of a metal and/or an isolating polymer. The thickness of this protection layer varies and depends on the type of use for the light-emitting device.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">In a preferred embodiment a metallization element is connected with one of the electrode layers, wherein the metallization element is sandwiched between the electrode layer and the connection-end of the shunt element. Thus, the metallization element acts like a shunt itself, being embedded in the stack of layers. Due to its size, the metallization element itself would not overcome the disadvantages mentioned above. Rather than for the transport of the current, the purpose of the metallization element is that of a connector between the shunt element and the electrode layer. Preferably, the shunt element has a rectangle cross-section, so that the whole underside is labeled the connection-end. The thickness of the metallization element is depending on its main purpose as a connector to the shunt layer. In a preferred embodiment of the described invention, the metallization element comprises a layer thickness of 1 nm to 100 nm. To deposit the metallization element, thin film depositing techniques as those named above may be used.<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></p><p id="p0018" num="0018">In another preferred embodiment the metallization element and the shunt element are connected by solid-state welding. The most popular type of solid-state welding, ultrasonic welding, has shown to be preferable. Nevertheless also other solid-state welding processes, including co-extrusion welding, cold welding; diffusion welding, friction welding, high frequency welding, hot pressure welding, induction welding, and roll welding, have shown to be appropriate. The optional metallization element may comprise a metal such as silver, gold, copper, aluminum, tungsten, molybdenum, chromium, and the like. Also combinations and alloys of these metals are very suitable, such as molybdenum chrome/aluminum/molybdenum chrome (MAM).</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">In another preferred embodiment of the invention, the shunt element and/or the metallization element are patterned. The term patterned in the context of the invention means that either the shunt element or a combination of the shunt element with the metallization element is arranged in a constant way on the stack of layers. For very large area OLEDs it may for example be useful that the shunt element builds a net like structure, overlying the surface of the stack of layers. Aim of this patterned arrangement of the named elements is to achieve a homogeneous flow of current through all parts of the electrode layers of the light-emitting device. It can be appropriate that the shunt element has a comb like structure, whereas those shunt elements, defining the teeth of the comb extend into the surface of the light-emitting device. Furthermore, the shunt element may be arranged in a U-, V- and/or L-style. The chosen kind of configuration is mostly depending on the overall structure of the light-emitting device. If the last named possesses a circular surrounding, the shunt elements may be arranged in a star like pattern. Due to the invention each of the pie slice-like formed segments obtain sufficient current to generate a homogeneous brightness.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">The patterned assembly of the shunt element is supported by another preferred embodiment of the invention, which is characterized in that the first electrode layer, the second electrode layer and the organic light-emitting layer form a lighting tile, wherein a plurality of lighting tiles are deposited on one basic layer. The idea behind this embodiment is to divide a very large OLED in smaller, tile like sections. But all those separated lighting tiles are altogether deposited on one basic layer. Therefore, even very<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> large light emitting devices are easy to handle and there is no danger of a fragmentation in single lighting tiles. Preferably, the lighting tile comprises a size between 20 mm x 20 mm to 250 mm x 250 mm, preferably between 30 mm x 30 mm to 150 mm x 150 mm, preferably between 40 mm x 40 mm to 80 mm x 80 mm.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">To achieve a homogeneous brightness of the light-emitting device a homogeneous flow of current through all electrode layers respectively organic light-emitting layer is necessary, Therefore the lighting tiles are partially isolated against one another. Thus, the combination of the shunt elements with the lighting tiles enables the steady and huge flow of current through smaller subsections of a large light emitting device, and therefore ensuring the homogeneous brightness.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">In another embodiment the shunt element, connected with a first electrode layer, encloses a rectangular lighting tile from three sides, whereas the shunt element, connected with the second electrode layer, borders the lighting tile from one side. In most commonly known OLEDs the first electrode layer consists of ITO, which -as has been mentioned- has a two order of magnitude higher specific resistance than aluminum, mostly used for the second electrode layer. Due to this resistance and the fact that the sheet height of the first and the second electrode layer are mostly more or less identical, the voltage drop along the first electrode layer is far more severe than along the second electrode layer. To achieve a homogeneous flow of current in this embodiment of an OLED, it is appropriate to mainly encircle the lighting tile with a shunt element, being connected to the first electrode layer. The second electrode layer may than be connected to a shunt element bordering a last open side of the lighting tile.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">The present invention also relates to a method to manufacture a light-emitting device according to claim 1 comprising the step gluing or welding the at least one shunt element to the electrode layer. In a preferred embodiment the welding is at least one of the following group of laser welding, heat sealing, resistance welding, electron beam welding or solid-state-welding, preferably ultrasonic welding.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">The aforementioned light emitting device, as well as claimed components and the components to be used in accordance with the invention in the described embodiments, are not subject to any special exceptions with respect to size, shape, or<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> material selection. Technical concepts known in the pertinent field can be applied without limitations. Additional details, characteristics and advantages of the object of the present invention are disclosed in the sub-claims and the following description of the respective figures - which are an exemplary fashion only - shows a preferred embodiment of the light emitting device according to the present invention.</p><heading id="h0004">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading><p id="p0025" num="0025"><ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> shows a cross-section through a light emitting device, and</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref> shows an oversight of the light emitting device.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0005">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading><p id="p0026" num="0026">In <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> a cross-section of a light-emitting device 10 is shown. The light-emitting device 10 comprises a stack of layers 15 with a basic layer 20, e.g. a glass or a polymer substrate. Deposited onto this basic layer 20 is a first electrode layer 30. Above this first electron layer 30 an organic light-emitting layer 50 and a second electrode layer 40, 40', 40" are superimposed onto one another. Each of the three named layers 30, 40, 50 comprises a thickness of less than 500 nm, preferably about 50 nm to 200 nm. Upon application of an electrical current, flowing from the second electrode layer 40, 40', 40" to the first electrode layer 30, the organic light-emitting layer 50 radiates light by recombination of electrons and holes in the organic material. In case of a metal second electrode 40, 40', 40" acting as a mirror, the emitted light radiates through the transparent first electrode layer 30 and the basic layer 20. In case of a transparent second electrode, the light is emitted also through the second electrode to the non-subtrate side of the OLED.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">As the light-emitting device 10 is driven at low voltages and high currents, the thin film first electrode layer 30 and second electrode layer 40 have a high sheet resistance. So due to this high sheet resistance in combination with the high<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> current, a voltage drop along the electrode layers occur, resulting in a brightness inhomogeneity, which is getting worse with increasing size of the light emitting device 10. To overcome this disadvantage, the invention proposes to use at least one shunt element 60, 60'. The shunt element 60, 60' comprises a connection-end 65 and a free-end 66. The connection-end 65 of the shunt element 60, 60' is connected with one of the electrode layers 30, 40. The free-end 66, positioned opposite to the connection-end 65, is protruding out of the stack of layers 15. In an alternative embodiment, the connection-end 65 reaches into the layer stack 15, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>. In other embodiments, the connection end of the shunt element 60, 60' can be arranged at the same height as the second electrode 40, 40', 40" or above or on top of the second electrode 40, 40', 40".</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">In one embodiment a first shunt element 60 is connected with the first electrode layer 30, whereas a second shunt element 60' is connected with the second electrode layer 40. So both electrode layers are in connection with a shunt element 60, 60', which make the needed current available. Depending on this current, the geometric and size of the shunt elements can vary. Preferably the shunt element 60, 60' will comprise a rectangle cross-section, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>. Also circular, triangular or hexagonal cross-sections are appropriate. If sheet like shunt elements 60, 60' are used it is preferably, that they comprise a width 61 between 50 µm to 4 mm and a height 62 between 20 µm to 800 µm. So in contrast to the shown sheet like shunt element 60, 60' the width 61 may be larger than the height 62.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">To ease the connection of the shunt element 60, 60' with the first 30 respectively the second electrode layer 40, a metallization element 70, 70' is enclosed between the electrode layers 30, 40 and the connection-end 65 of the shunt element 60, 60'. The shunt element 60' is connected through the metallization element 70' with the two second electrode layers 40, 40'. The second electrode layer 40" is connected with another - not shown - shunt element 60'. To prevent a short circuit, no direct contact between the first 30 and the second electrode layer 40 is allowed. Therefore, an isolation mean 90 is embedded in the stack of layers 15. The isolation mean 90 prevents a direct current flow from the second electrode layer 40, 40' to the first electrode layer 30. In<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> fact the current has to flow through the organic light-emitting layer 50, generating the desired light.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">The shunt element 60 is connected to the first electrode layer 30. To prevent a short circuit, between the second electrode layers 40, 40' and the shunt element 60, a gap 91 in the stack of layers 15 is embedded. This gap 91 may be filled with an isolation layer, not shown in this embodiment. The isolation layer may not only cover the gap 91, but also the whole stack of layers 15, including the shunt elements 60, 60'.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">The main purpose of the metallization element 70, 70' is the support of the connection of the shunt element 60, 60' to the first 30 respectively second electrode layer 40. Therefore it is appropriate, that the thickness of the metallization element 70, 70' is in the area of the electrode layers 30, 40. Even smaller heights, well down to just a few nm, have shown appropriate for ultrasonic welding of the metallization element 70, 70' with the shunt element 60, 60'. If no metallization element 70, 70' is used, the shunt element 60, 60' may be directly glued to the electrode layers 30, 40. Also thin film depositing techniques may be used to implement the shunt element 60, 60' into the stack of layers 15.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032"><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref> shows an oversight of the light-emitting device 10, with the intersection line I-I for the cross-section shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>. As the light-emitting device 10 is build out of a stack of layers 15, just the top level second electrode layer 40 can be seen, above the basic layer 20. In the shown embodiment the shunt element 60, 60' comprises a patterned arrangement. Onto the first electrode layer 30 the metallization element 70, 70' is deposited. With this metallization element 70, 70' the shunt element 60, 60' is connected. The shunt element 60 being connected with the first electrode layer 30 comprise a comb like structure, whereas the shunt element 60', connected with the second electrode layer 40, comprise a line like structure. As has been shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>, between the second electrode layer 40 and the shunt element 60 an isolation gap 91 is embedded in the stack of layers 15. Furthermore, the second electrode 40 is connected with the line like shunt element 60'. In combination with the comb like arrangement of the shunt element 60 rectangular lighting tiles 80 are established. These lighting tiles 80<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> comprise a cut-out of the light emitting device 10, comprising the first electrode layer 30, the second electrode layer 40 and the organic light-emitting layer 50. In the shown embodiment the four light tiles 80 are all embedded on one basic layer 20, thereby increasing the mechanical stability of the light-emitting device 10.<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></p><heading id="h0006">LIST OF NUMERALS:</heading><p id="p0033" num="0033"><dl id="dl0001" compact="compact"><dt>10</dt><dd>light emitting device</dd><dt>15</dt><dd>stack of layers</dd><dt>20</dt><dd>basic layer,</dd><dt>30</dt><dd>first electrode layer</dd><dt>40,40',40"</dt><dd>second electrode layer</dd><dt>50</dt><dd>organic light-emitting layer</dd><dt>60,60'</dt><dd>shunt element</dd><dt>61</dt><dd>width of shunt element 60,60'</dd><dt>62</dt><dd>height of shunt element 60,60'</dd><dt>65</dt><dd>connection-end</dd><dt>66</dt><dd>free-end</dd><dt>70,70'</dt><dd>metallization element</dd><dt>80</dt><dd>lighting tile</dd><dt>90</dt><dd>isolation mean</dd><dt>91</dt><dd>isolation gap</dd></dl></p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980349" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Licht emittierende Einrichtung (10) mit stapelförmig angeordneten Schichten (15),<br/>
mit einer Basisschicht (20), einer ersten Elektrodenschicht (30) sowie einer zweiten Elektrodenschicht (40),<br/>
wobei eine organische, Licht emittierende Schicht (50) zwischen der ersten (30) und der zweiten Elektrodenschicht (40) angeordnet ist,<br/>
mit mindestens zwei folienartigen Nebenschlusselementen oder Dünnfilm-Nebenschlusselementen (60,60'), die jeweils ein Anschlussende (65) und ein freies Ende (66) umfassen,<br/>
<b><u>dadurch gekennzeichnet,</u> dass</b> das Anschlussende (65) des ersten Nebenschlusselements (60) mit der ersten Elektrodenschicht (30) und das Anschlussende (65) des zweiten Nebenschlusselements (60') mit der zweiten Elektrodenschicht (40) verbunden ist, und<br/>
die freien Enden (66) der Nebenschlusselemente (60,60') aus der Ebene der stapelförmig angeordneten Schichten (15) hervorragen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Licht emittierende Einrichtung (10) nach Anspruch 1,<br/>
<b><u>dadurch gekennzeichnet</u>, dass</b> das Nebenschlusselement (60,60') eine Breite (61) zwischen 50 µm und 4 mm, vorzugsweise zwischen 100 µm und 2 mm, aufweist, und dass das Nebenschlusselement (60,60') eine Höhe (62) zwischen 20 µm und 800 µm, vorzugsweise zwischen 50 µm und 500 µm, aufweist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Licht emittierende Einrichtung (10) nach einem der vorangegangenen Ansprüche,<br/>
<b><u>dadurch gekennzeichnet,</u> dass</b> das Nebenschlusselement (60,60') eine höhere elektrische Leitfähigkeit als 30x10<sup>6</sup> S/m aufweist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Licht emittierende Einrichtung (10) nach einem der vorangegangenen Ansprüche,<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --><b><u>dadurch gekennzeichnet,</u> dass</b> ein Metallisierungselement (70,70') mit einer der Elektrodenschichten (30,40) verbunden ist, wobei das Metallisierungselement (70,70') zwischen der Elektrodenschicht (30,40) und dem Anschlussende (65) des Nebenschlusselements (60,60') angeordnet ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Licht emittierende Einrichtung (10) nach Anspruch 4,<br/>
<b><u>dadurch gekennzeichnet,</u> dass</b> das Metallisierungselement (70,70') eine Schichtdicke von 1 nm bis 100 nm aufweist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Licht emittierende Einrichtung (10) nach einem der vorangegangenen Ansprüche,<br/>
<b><u>dadurch gekennzeichnet,</u> dass</b> die erste Elektrodenschicht (30), die zweite Elektrodenschicht (40) und die organische, Licht emittierende Schicht (50) eine Lichtkachel (80) darstellen, wobei eine Mehrzahl von Lichtkacheln (80) auf einer Basisschicht (20) aufgebracht wird, wobei die Lichtkachel (80) vorzugsweise eine Größe zwischen 20 mm x 20 mm und 250 mm x 250 mm, besser noch zwischen 30 mm x 30 mm und 150 mm x 150 mm, am besten zwischen 40 mm x 40 mm und 80 mm x 80 mm, aufweist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Licht emittierende Einrichtung (10) nach Anspruch 6,<br/>
<b><u>dadurch gekennzeichnet,</u> dass</b> das mit der ersten Elektrodenschicht (30) verbundene Nebenschlusselement (60,60') die Lichtkachel (80) von drei Seiten einschließt, während das mit der zweiten Elektrodenschicht (40) verbundene Nebenschlusselement (60,60') die Lichtkachel (80) von einer Seite begrenzt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Verfahren zur Herstellung einer Licht emittierenden Einrichtung (10) nach Anspruch 1, das den Schritt des
<claim-text>- Aufklebens oder Aufschweißens der mindestens zwei Nebenschlusselemente (60,60') auf die Elektrodenschichten (30,40) umfasst.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 8,<br/>
<b><u>dadurch gekennzeichnet,</u> dass</b> das Schweißen aus mindestens einer der folgenden Gruppen, umfassend Laserschweißen, Wärmeschweißen, Widerstandsschweißen,<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> Elektronenstrahlschweißen oder Festkörperschweißen, vorzugsweise Ultraschallschweißen, ausgewählt wird.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980350" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A light-emitting device (10), comprising a stack of layers (15),<br/>
comprising a basic layer (20), a first electrode layer (30) and a second electrode layer (40),<br/>
wherein an organic light-emitting layer (50) is sandwiched between the first (30) and the second electrode layer (40),<br/>
with at least two foil like shunt elements or thin film shunt elements (60,60'), each comprising a connection-end (65) and a free-end (66),<br/>
<b>characterized in that</b> the connection-end (65) of the first shunt element (60) is connected with the first electrode layer (30) and the connection-end (65) of the second shunt element (60') is connected with the second electrode layer (40), and<br/>
the free-ends (66) of the shunt elements (60,60') stick out of the plane of the stack of layers (15).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>A light-emitting device (10) according to claim 1,<br/>
<b>characterized in that</b> the shunt element (60,60') comprises a width (61) between 50 µm to 4 mm, preferably between 100 µm to 2 mm, and that the shunt element (60,60') comprises a height (62) between 20 µm to 800 µm, preferably between 50 µm to 500 µm.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>A light-emitting device (10) according to any preceding claims,<br/>
<b>characterized in that</b> the shunt element (60,60') comprises an electrical conductivity higher than 30x10<sup>6</sup> S/m.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>A light-emitting device (10) according to any preceding claims,<br/>
<b>characterized in that</b> a metallization element (70,70') is connected with one of the electrode layers (30,40), wherein the metallization element (70,70') is sandwiched between the electrode layer (30,40) and the connection-end (65) of the shunt element (60,60').</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>A light-emitting device (10) according to claim 4,<br/>
<b>characterized in that</b> the metallization element (70,70') comprises a layer thickness of 1 nm to 100 nm.<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>A light-emitting device (10) according to any preceding claims,<br/>
<b>characterized in that</b> the first electrode layer (30), the second electrode layer (40) and the organic light-emitting layer (50) are a lighting tile (80), wherein a plurality of lighting tiles (80) are deposited on one basic layer (20), preferably that the lighting tile (80) comprises a size between 20 mm x 20 mm to 250 mm x 250 mm, preferably between 30 mm x 30 mm to 150 mm x 150 mm, preferably between 40 mm x 40 mm to 80 mm x 80 mm.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>A light-emitting device (10) according to claim 6,<br/>
<b>characterized in that</b> the shunt element (60,60'), connected with the first electrode layer (30), encloses the lighting tile (80) from three sides, whereas the shunt element (60,60'), connected with the second electrode layer (40), borders the lighting tile (80) from one side.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>A method to manufacture a light-emitting device (10) according to claim 1 comprising the step
<claim-text>- gluing or welding the at least two shunt elements (60, 60') to the electrode layers (30, 40)</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>A method according to claim 8,<br/>
<b>characterized in that</b> the welding is at least one of the following group of laser welding, heat sealing, resistance welding, electron beam welding or solid-state-welding, preferably ultrasonic welding.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980351" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Dispositif électroluminescent (10), comprenant un empilage de couches (15),<br/>
comprenant une couche de base (20), une première couche d'électrode (30) et une seconde couche d'électrode (40),<br/>
dans lequel une couche électroluminescente organique (50) est prise en sandwich entre la première couche d'électrode (30) et la seconde couche d'électrode (40),<br/>
avec au moins deux éléments shunts en forme de feuille ou éléments shunts en film mince (60, 60'), chacun comprenant une extrémité de connexion (65) et une extrémité libre (66),<br/>
<b>caractérisé en ce que</b> l'extrémité de connexion (65) du premier élément shunt (60) est connectée avec la première couche d'électrode (30) et l'extrémité de connexion (65) du second élément shunt (60') est connectée avec la seconde couche d'électrode (40), et<br/>
les extrémités libres (66) des éléments shunts (60, 60') dépassent du plan de l'empilage de couches (15).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Dispositif électroluminescent (10) selon la revendication 1, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> l'élément shunt (60, 60') comprend une largeur (61) entre 50 µm à 4 mm, de préférence entre 100 µm et 2 mm, et que l'élément shunt (60, 60') comprend une hauteur (62) entre 20 µm et 800 µm, de préférence entre 50 µm et 500 µm.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Dispositif électroluminescent (10) selon de quelconques revendications précédentes, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> l'élément shunt (60, 60') comprend une conductivité électrique supérieure à 30 x 10<sup>6</sup> S/m.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Dispositif électroluminescent (10) selon de quelconques revendications précédentes, <b>caractérisé en ce qu'</b>un élément de métallisation (70, 70') est connecté avec une des couches d'électrode (30, 40), dans lequel l'élément de métallisation (70, 70') est<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> pris en sandwich entre la couche d'électrode (30, 40) et l'extrémité de connexion (65) de l'élément shunt (60, 60').</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Dispositif électroluminescent (10) selon la revendication 4, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> l'élément de métallisation (70, 70') comprend une épaisseur de couche de 1 nm à 100 nm.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Dispositif électroluminescent (10) selon de quelconques revendications précédentes, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> la première couche d'électrode (30), la seconde couche d'électrode (40) et la couche électroluminescente organique (50) sont un carreau d'éclairage (80), dans lequel une pluralité de carreaux d'éclairage (80) sont déposés sur une couche de base (20), de préférence que le carreau d'éclairage (80) comprend une taille entre 20 mm x 20 mm et 250 mm x 250 mm, de préférence entre 30 mm x 30 mm et 150 mm x 150 mm, de préférence entre 40 mm x 40 mm et 80 mm x 80 mm.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Dispositif électroluminescent (10) selon la revendication 6, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> l'élément shunt (60, 60'), connecté avec la première couche d'électrode (30), enferme le carreau d'éclairage (80) à partir de trois côtés, alors que l'élément shunt (60, 60'), connecté avec la seconde couche d'électrode (40), borde le carreau d'éclairage (80) à partir d'un côté.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Procédé de fabrication d'un dispositif électroluminescent (10) selon la revendication 1, comprenant l'étape de :
<claim-text>- collage ou soudage des au moins deux éléments shunts (60, 60') aux couches d'électrode (30, 40).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 8, <b>caractérisé en ce que</b> le soudage est au moins un parmi le groupe suivant de soudage au laser, thermo-soudage, soudage par résistance, soudage par faisceau d'électrons ou soudage à l'état solide, de préférence soudage ultrasonique.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16669132" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="150" he="222" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="165" he="201" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
