<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2680406-A2" country="EP" doc-number="2680406" kind="A2" date="20140101" family-id="48698923" file-reference-id="269247" date-produced="20180824" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146549664" ucid="EP-2680406-A2"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2680406</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-13173468-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154823587" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>13173468</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20130624</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP191887661" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>13173468.3</doc-number><date>20130624</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140446200" ucid="KR-20120069846-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>KR</country><doc-number>20120069846</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120628</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988132593" load-source="docdb">H02K   3/52        20060101AFI20131025BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1833766671" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H02K2203/09        20130101 LA20170329BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1994220553" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H02K   3/522       20130101 LI20151202BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1991313717" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H02K   5/225       20130101 FI20131226BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132181476" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Motor</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132181477" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Motor</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132181478" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Moteur</invention-title><citations><non-patent-citations><nplcit><text>None</text><sources><source mxw-id="PNPL45132175" load-source="docdb" name="APP"/></sources></nplcit></non-patent-citations></citations></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918133363" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>LG INNOTEK CO LTD</last-name><address><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918163911" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>LG INNOTEK CO., LTD.</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918991573" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>LG Innotek Co., Ltd.</last-name><iid>101287322</iid><address><street>20th Fl. Seoul Square 541, Namdaemunno 5-ga Jung-gu</street><city>Seoul 100-714</city><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918141801" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>RYU WOONGSEON</last-name><address><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918141997" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>RYU, WOONGSEON</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918982322" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>RYU, WOONGSEON</last-name><address><street>LG INNOTEK CO., LTD. 20th Fl. Seoul Square 541 Namdaemunno 5-ga Jung-gu</street><city>Seoul 100-714</city><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918979344" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Cabinet Plasseraud</last-name><iid>100784233</iid><address><street>52, rue de la Victoire</street><city>75440 Paris Cedex 09</city><country>FR</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548880097" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS548893861" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS548880098" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS548806375" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS548846481" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS548899705" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS548899710" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS548878429" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548880099" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS548880104" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS548881124" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS548806376" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS548806377" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548878430" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548880105" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS548878431" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS548899711" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS548846482" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS548880106" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS548806378" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS548880107" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS548878432" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS548893866" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS548806379" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS548878433" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS548893867" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS548893868" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS548880424" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS548878435" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS548880425" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS548806380" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS548899712" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS548806381" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS548880426" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS548846483" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS548878436" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS548878437" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS548893869" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states><ep-extended-states><ep-extended-state-data><country>BA</country></ep-extended-state-data><ep-extended-state-data><country>ME</country></ep-extended-state-data></ep-extended-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA128670333" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p id="pa01" num="0001">Disclosed is a motor, the motor according to an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure including a motor housing 10, a stator 20 mounted inside the motor housing 10 and including a stator core 21 and a coil 22 wound on the stator core 21, a rotor 30 rotatably installed at a center of the stator 20, and a busbar 100 provided with a plurality of circumferentially and straightly protruded busbar terminals 110 mounted at an upper surface of the stator 20, and connected by a coil 21.
<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="136" he="98" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA128499706" lang="EN" source="EPO" load-source="docdb"><p>Disclosed is a motor, the motor according to an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure including a motor housing 10, a stator 20 mounted inside the motor housing 10 and including a stator core 21 and a coil 22 wound on the stator core 21, a rotor 30 rotatably installed at a center of the stator 20, and a busbar 100 provided with a plurality of circumferentially and straightly protruded busbar terminals 110 mounted at an upper surface of the stator 20, and connected by a coil 21.</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES63955763" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001">BACKGROUND OF THE DISCLOSURE</heading><heading id="h0002">1. Field of the Disclosure</heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present disclosure relates to a brushless motor.</p><heading id="h0003">2. Discussion of the Related Art</heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">Generally, almost every vehicle employs an electric power-assist steering system. Such an electric power-assist steering system generates an assist force based on the steering torque and the steering angle in order to enhance the steering performance of the vehicle.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">That is, a steering system that assists a steering force of a vehicle with a separate power is used to enhance the motion stability of a vehicle.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">Conventionally, the auxiliary steering device uses hydraulic pressure, but an Electronic Power Steering (EPS) system adapted to transmit a rotation output of an electric motor to a steering shaft via a speed reduction mechanism has been increasingly employed these days from a viewpoint of a reduction in engine load, a reduction in weight, an enhanced steering stability and a quick restoring force.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">The EPS system is configured such that an Electronic Control Unit (ECU) drives a<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> motor in response to steering conditions detected by a speed sensor, a torque angle sensor and a torque sensor to enhance a steering stability and provide a quick restoring force, whereby a driver can safely steer a vehicle.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">The EPS system is also such that a motor assists a torque manipulating a steering wheel to allow a driver to steer a vehicle with less power, where the motor employs a Brushless Direct Current (BLDC) motor.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">The BLDC motors have been increasingly used because the brushless motors are excellent in maintenance property, have a small size, and are capable of generating a high torque.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">The BLDC motor generally forms an exterior look by coupling of a housing with a cover member, an inner circumferential surface of the housing is provided with a stator, and the stator is centrally formed with a rotor rotatably mounted in electrical interaction with the stator. The rotor is rotatably supported by a rotation shaft, and an upper surface of the rotation shaft is connected by a steering shaft of a vehicle to provide a power assisting the steering of the vehicle as mentioned above. The stator of EPS motor thus configured serves to supply an electric power to a wound coil via busbar.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">The stator includes a core and a coil wound on the core, and in general, a motor used for a vehicle is employed with a plurality of coils connected in parallel for loss reduction. Thus, the coil is extended to an input/output terminal, and integrated and connected at the terminal during parallel connection. In order to integrate and connect the coil arranged in parallel, a busbar is coupled to an upper surface of the stator, and<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> in order to couple the busbar, a coil terminal of coils respectively wound on the upper surface of stator, and the busbar is connected to the coil terminal.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">The busbar is fixedly arranged with a plurality of metal members electrically connected to the coil terminal which is then insulated by an insulator. The busbar takes an approximate shape of a doughnut to correspond to a shape of the stator. The busbar is arranged at a periphery with terminals for connecting the coil terminal.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">The shape of a busbar is change in response to a connected electrical power, and in general, the EPS motor is configured such that respective input/output terminals are sequentially arranged to a periphery of the busbar through a 3-phase circuit.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">However, there is a disadvantage in forming the busbar terminal bent to the busbar in that each busbar terminal must be bent at a predetermined size, and it is too much complicated to insert and fuse the coil into the busbar terminal, frequently generating faulty works.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">Particularly, molds are complicated, and materials are wasted because of complicated shape of a fusing unit and generation of too much of scraps when the busbar terminal is manufactured using a press forming method, in a case the busbar terminal and the coil are fixed by being fused, and fusing unit is formed in a U-shape.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">Another disadvantage is that a large quantity of straight portions of a coil for pulling the coil is required to resultantly waste a large quantity of coils, because the U-shaped ring type busbar terminal must be penetrated through a U-shaped ring, pulled, fused and cut.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p><heading id="h0004">BRIEF SUMMARY</heading><p id="p0015" num="0015">The present disclosure is directed to cope with the abovementioned problems/disadvantages and it is an object of the present disclosure to provide a structure-improved brushless motor configured to improve motor assembly.
<ol><li>1. In one general aspect of the present disclosure, there is provided a motor, the motor comprising:
<ul><li>a motor housing;</li><li>a stator mounted inside the motor housing and including a stator core and a coil wound on the stator core;</li><li>a rotor rotatably installed at a center of the stator; and</li><li>a busbar provided with a plurality of circumferentially and straightly protruded busbar terminals mounted at an upper surface of the stator, and connected by a coil.</li></ul></li><li>2. Preferably, but not necessarily, the busbar may include a resin materialed busbar body, and a busbar terminal protruded to a circumferential direction of the busbar body.</li><li>3. Preferably, but not necessarily, a cross-section of the busbar terminal may take a shape of a rectangle.</li><li>4. Preferably, but not necessarily, the busbar terminal may be a hook groove having a width corresponding to a diameter of the coil.</li><li>5. Preferably, but not necessarily, the busbar terminal may include a through hole having a shape corresponding to that of a periphery of the coil, and a slit having a hitching unit having a width smaller value than that of a diameter of the through hole.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></li><li>6. Preferably, but not necessarily, the slit may be formed with a bottleneck section formed by a width of a connection unit connected to the through hole smaller than a width of an opening connected to an outside of the busbar terminal.</li><li>7. Preferably, but not necessarily, the body may be formed with a resin material to be insert injection molded along with the busbar terminal.</li><li>8. Preferably, but not necessarily, the busbar terminal may be formed in one body with a circularly bent terminal body having a diameter corresponding to the body after press-work of a plate member, and the busbar terminal may be at least twice bent on the terminal body to allow a distal end to a circumferential direction of the body.</li><li>9. Preferably, but not necessarily, the busbar terminal may include a fusing unit formed with a conductive member at an area contacting the coil.</li><li>10. Preferably, but not necessarily, the busbar terminal may be arranged at a first height and at a second height at a periphery of the busbar terminal.</li></ol></p><p id="p0016" num="0016">There is an advantageous effect in the motor according to an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure in that a hook groove is formed at a busbar terminal to allow a coil to be directly hooked and coupled to a busbar terminal by bending the coil, whereby a manufacturing cost can be reduced by decreasing an amount of scraps generated in the course of manufacturing a busbar terminal, and a motor assembly can be improved by completion of connection process in which a stripper at a distal end of the coil is bent and fused by being coupled to a hook groove.</p><heading id="h0005">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading><!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --><p id="p0017" num="0017"><ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG.1</figref> is a partially cut-out cross-sectional view illustrating a motor according to an</li><li>exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG.2</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a busbar according to an exemplary</li><li>embodiment of the present disclosure.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002 f0003">FIGS. 3 to 5</figref> are schematic views view illustrating a shape of a busbar terminal according to first, second and third exemplary embodiments of the present disclosure.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">FIG.6</figref> is a schematic view illustrating a state in which a busbar terminal is formed by press-work of a plate.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">FIG.7</figref> is a schematic view illustrating a one-polarity busbar terminal formed by circularly bending a busbar terminal of <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG.6</figref>.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">FIG.8</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a stator core wound with a coil.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 9</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a state in which a distal end of a coil wound on the stator core of <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG.8</figref> is stripped, and inserted with a busbar according to an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 10</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a state in which a portion of a stripped coil protruded to an upper surface of the busbar of <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG.9</figref> is cut out according to the exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0007">FIG.11</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a state in which the stripped portion of the coil in <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 10</figref> is bent and hooked to a busbar terminal.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0008">FIG.12</figref> a perspective view illustrating a state in which an upper surface of a plate module of <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG.9</figref> is soldered by a conductive member.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0006">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading><p id="p0018" num="0018">Now, a motor according to the exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure will be described in detail with reference to the accompanying drawings.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p><p id="p0019" num="0019"><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG.1</figref> is a partially cut-out cross-sectional view illustrating a motor according to an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure, <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG.2</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a busbar according to an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure, <figref idrefs="f0002 f0003">FIGS. 3 to 5</figref> are schematic views view illustrating a shape of a busbar terminal according to first, second and third exemplary embodiments of the present disclosure, <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG.6</figref> is a schematic view illustrating a state in which a busbar terminal is formed by press-work of a plate, <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG.7</figref> is a schematic view illustrating a one-polarity busbar terminal formed by circularly bending a busbar terminal of <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG.6</figref>, <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG.8</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a stator core wound with a coil, <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 9</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a state in which a distal end of a coil wound on the stator core of <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG.8</figref> is stripped, and inserted with a busbar according to an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure, <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 10</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a state in which a portion of a stripped coil protruded to an upper surface of the busbar of <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG.9</figref> is cut out according to the exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure, <figref idrefs="f0007">FIG.11</figref> is a perspective view illustrating a state in which the stripped portion of the coil in <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 10</figref> is bent and hooked to a busbar terminal and <figref idrefs="f0008">FIG.12</figref> a perspective view illustrating a state in which an upper surface of a plate module of <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG.9</figref> is soldered by a conductive member.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG.1</figref>, an EPS motor according to an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure includes a motor housing (10), a stator (20), and a rotor (30), and may further include a busbar (100) for supplying an electric power to a coil (22) wound on the stator (20).</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">The motor housing (10) takes an approximate shape of a cylinder, and is formed with at an upper surface with an opening and closed at a bottom surface. The motor housing<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> (10) is installed therein with the stator (20), the rotor (30) and a rotation shaft (30a) rotatably supporting the rotor (30). The stator (20) includes a stator core (21), a coil (22) and a coil terminal (25) formed by stripping a distal end of the coil. The stator core (21) may be provided with a plurality of teeth, and the teeth may be circumferentially wound with the coil (22) while the teeth are mounted with an insulator. The distal end of the coil (22) is stripped to form the coil terminal (25), where the coil terminal (25) may be provided in a cylindrical shape having a predetermined length and a predetermined diameter.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">The stator (20) may be assembled at an upper surface with the busbar (100) for supplying an electrical power to the coil (22). The busbar (100) may be formed with a plurality of busbar terminals (110) protruded toward a periphery of the body formed with a resin material as shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG.2</figref>. Characteristic of the present disclosure lies in a shape and a structure of the busbar (110), which will be described later.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">The rotor (30) is rotatably mounted at a center of the stator (20), and is formed by a plurality of magnets being mounted at a periphery of rotor core. The rotation shaft (30a) is coaxially formed with the rotor (30), where one end of the rotation shaft (30a) is rotatably supported by a bottom bearing mounted at a floor surface of the motor housing (10), and the other end of the rotation shaft (30a) is supported by an upper bearing installed on a cover member (not shown).</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">Each of the busbars (100) according to an exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure functions to supply an electric power to the coil (22) wound on the stator core (21), and may include a ring-shaped body (101) having a diameter corresponding to the stator (20), and a plurality of busbar terminals (110) arranged along the<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> periphery of the body (101) each spaced apart at a predetermined gap to supply an electric power having mutually different polarities to the coil (22). The busbar terminal (110) may be provided with a conductive material and may be generally formed with a metal material easy for press work.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">According to a first exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure, the busbar terminal (110) may be formed with a groove-less square plate member as shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG.3</figref>. In this case, the coil (22) may be bent and wound toward an upper side of the busbar terminal (110) and connected by being fused with a contact portion of the coil terminal (25) formed at a distal end of the coil (22).</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">According to a second exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure, the busbar terminal (110) may be formed with a hook groove (111) having a shape corresponding to the coil (22) as illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG.4</figref>, where the coil terminal (25) formed at the distal end of the coil (22) may be accommodated into the hook groove (111), and the busbar terminal (110) may be connected by fusing a contact portion between an inner surface of the hook groove (111) the coil terminal (25).</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">According to a third exemplary embodiment of the present disclosure, the busbar terminal (110) may be provided with a through hole (121) having a shape corresponding to that of the periphery of the coil as illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG.5</figref>, and with a slit (122) forming a hitching unit having a width of a value smaller than a diameter of the through hole (121). In this case, the coil terminal (25) formed at a distal end of the coil may be pushed in through the slit (122) for accommodation into the through hole (121), and the coil terminal (25) may be conductively connected to the busbar terminal (110) by fusing the slit portion.<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></p><p id="p0028" num="0028">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG.6</figref>, the busbar terminal (110) may be configured such that the busbar terminal (110) and a terminal body (112) are formed on one sheet of plate member (P) to remove a space (S) and fold in a circular manner as shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 7</figref>.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">According to the abovementioned configuration, a quantity of scraps cut to the space (S) can be minimized to reduce material that is to be wasted, and folded at the terminal body (112) twice to form the busbar terminal (110), whereby process can be simplified.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">Furthermore, as illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG.2</figref>, the busbar terminal (110) thus configured may be protrusively formed on the ring-shaped body (101) so as to have a first height and a second height. This is to minimize interference between coils (22) hooked on adjacent busbar terminals (110).</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">Now, a coupling method of the busbar (100) according to the present disclosure will be described with reference to <figref idrefs="f0004 f0005 f0006 f0007 f0008">FIGS. 8 to 12</figref>. The present disclosure relates to a brushless motor using a 3-phase (U, V, W) electric power, and a general structure of the stator (20) is the same as that explained in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG.8</figref>, a distal end (23) of the coil (22) wound on the stator core (21) may be arranged in a state of being lengthily stood at an upper surface of the stator core while being wrapped in an insulated coating wrapping the coil (22). At this time, the distal end (23) of the coil may be arranged at an erect state to a direction parallel with a lengthwise direction of the stator core (21), and the distal end (23) of the coil may be arranged near to the busbar terminal (110) protrusively formed to a periphery of the busbar (100).<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --></p><p id="p0033" num="0033">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG.8</figref>, the busbar (100) is installed as shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG.9</figref>, while a coating-stripped distal end (23) of the coil (22) is erected, a strip portion (24) protruded to an upper surface of the busbar (100) is removed as shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 10</figref> to form the coil terminal (25) with an appropriate length, and a portion of the coil terminal (25) may be formed at a position near to the busbar terminal (110) as illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 10</figref>.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">Furthermore, as illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 11</figref>, the coil terminal (25) is bent in a U shape to be accommodated into the hook groove (111) formed on the busbar terminal (110). The coil terminal (25) accommodated into the hook groove (111) may be soldered using a conductive material such as a lead, whereby assembly can be finished.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">As apparent from the foregoing, the motor according to exemplary embodiments of the present disclosure has an advantageous effect in that a busbar (100) excellent in connectivity with the coil (22) over the conventional busbar can be manufactured, and particularly, the amount of scraps generated in the course of manufacturing the busbar terminal (110) can be minimized.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">Another advantageous effect is that, in a case the hook groove (111) is formed at the busbar terminal (110), the coil terminal (25) can be arranged at an accurate position to reduce defects during manufacturing such as the coil terminal (25) being disengaged from or erroneously connected with the busbar terminal (110) during fusing process.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">Although embodiments have been described with reference to a number of illustrative embodiments thereof, it should be understood that numerous other modifications and embodiments can be devised by those skilled in the art that will fall within the spirit and scope of the principles of this disclosure. More particularly, various variations and<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> modifications are possible in the component parts and/or arrangements of the subject combination arrangement within the scope of the disclosure, the drawings and the appended claims.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56976683" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --><claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A motor including a motor housing (10), a stator (20) mounted inside the motor housing (10) and including a stator core (21) and a coil (22) wound on the stator core (21), and a rotor (30) rotatably installed at a center of the stator (20), the motor <b>characterized by</b> a busbar (100) mounted at an upper surface of the stator (20), connected by a coil (22) and provided with a plurality of circumferentially and straightly protruded busbar terminals (110).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The motor of claim 1, <b>characterized in that</b> the busbar (100) includes a resin materialed busbar body (101), and a busbar terminal (110) protruded to a circumferential direction of the busbar body (101).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The motor of claim 2, <b>characterized in that</b> a cross-section of the busbar terminal (110) takes a shape of a rectangle.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The motor of claim 3, <b>characterized in that</b> the busbar terminal (110) is a hook groove (111) having a width corresponding to a diameter of the coil (22).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The motor of claim 3, <b>characterized in that</b> the busbar terminal (110) includes a through hole (121) having a shape corresponding to that of a periphery of the coil (22), and a slit (122) having a hitching unit having a width smaller value than that of a diameter of the through hole.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The motor of claim 5, <b>characterized in that</b> the slit is formed with a bottleneck section formed by a width of a connection unit connected to the through hole (121)<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> smaller than a width of an opening connected to an outside of the busbar terminal (110).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The motor of claim 2, <b>characterized in that</b> the body is formed with a resin material to be insert injection molded along with the busbar terminal.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The motor of claim 2, <b>characterized in that</b> the busbar terminal (110) is formed in one body with a circularly bent terminal body having a diameter corresponding to the body after press-work of a plate member, and the busbar terminal is at least twice bent on the terminal body to allow a distal end to a circumferential direction of the body.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The motor of claim 2, <b>characterized in that</b> the busbar terminal (110) includes a fusing unit formed with a conductive member at an area contacting the coil.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The motor of claim 2, <b>characterized in that</b> the busbar terminal (110) is arranged at a first height and at a second height at a periphery of the busbar terminal.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16667461" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="165" he="140" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2,3,4"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="165" he="204" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --><figure id="f0003" num="5,6,7"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="165" he="222" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --><figure id="f0004" num="8"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="147" he="166" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --><figure id="f0005" num="9"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="140" he="158" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --><figure id="f0006" num="10"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="162" he="152" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --><figure id="f0007" num="11"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="162" he="152" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --><figure id="f0008" num="12"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="131" he="157" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
