<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2378322-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2378322" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="44168117" file-reference-id="315063" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146588504" ucid="EP-2378322-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2378322</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-11153485-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154850696" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>11153485</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20110207</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP213444184" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>11153485.5</doc-number><date>20110207</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140556727" ucid="KR-20100033039-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>KR</country><doc-number>20100033039</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20100410</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140557778" ucid="KR-20100033040-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>KR</country><doc-number>20100033040</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20100410</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130731</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989325835" load-source="docdb">F21V   8/00        20060101AFI20130618BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1906610574" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G02B   6/0076      20130101 LI20160823BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1906610575" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G02B   6/0073      20130101 LA20160823BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1906610576" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G02B   6/0035      20130101 LA20160823BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1906610577" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G02B   6/0023      20130101 FI20160823BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370145" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Lichtquellenvorrichtung</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370146" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Light source device</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370147" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Dispositif de source lumineuse</invention-title><citations><patent-citations><patcit mxw-id="PCIT359096284" load-source="docdb" ucid="WO-2008060469-A2"><document-id format="epo"><country>WO</country><doc-number>2008060469</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20080522</date></document-id><sources><source name="EXA" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT359096285" load-source="docdb" ucid="WO-2010035176-A1"><document-id format="epo"><country>WO</country><doc-number>2010035176</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20100401</date></document-id><sources><source name="EXA" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit></patent-citations></citations></technical-data><related-documents><relation type="division-into"><child-doc ucid="EP-13194373.0"><document-id load-source="patent-office" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>13194373.0</doc-number><date>20131126</date></document-id></child-doc><parent-doc ucid="EP-11153485-A"><document-id load-source="patent-office" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>11153485</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20110207</date></document-id><parent-grant-document ucid="EP-2378322-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2378322</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date></document-id></parent-grant-document></parent-doc></relation></related-documents><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919527338" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>LG INNOTEK CO LTD</last-name><address><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919524668" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>LG INNOTEK CO., LTD.</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919523121" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>KIM YUN HA</last-name><address><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919508768" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>KIM, YUN HA</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919023423" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>KIM, YUN HA</last-name><address><street>Seoul Square 541 Namdaemunno 5-ga Jung-gu</street><city>100-714, Seoul</city><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919538095" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>LEE SANG HOON</last-name><address><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919515117" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>LEE, SANG HOON</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919023422" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>LEE, SANG HOON</last-name><address><street>Seoul Square 541 Namdaemunno 5-ga Jung-gu</street><city>100-714, Seoul</city><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919519238" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>SHIN HYUNHA</last-name><address><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919503939" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>Shin, Hyunha</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919023426" load-source="patent-office" sequence="3" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Shin, Hyunha</last-name><address><street>Seoul Square 541 Namdaemunno 5-ga Jung-gu</street><city>100-714, Seoul</city><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919023425" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>LG Innotek Co., Ltd.</last-name><iid>101182401</iid><address><street>Seoul Square 541, Namdaemunno 5-ga Jung-gu</street><city>Seoul 100-714</city><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919023424" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Cabinet Plasseraud</last-name><iid>100784233</iid><address><street>52, rue de la Victoire</street><city>75440 Paris Cedex 09</city><country>FR</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549786210" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS549880485" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549876044" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549786502" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549924317" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549876045" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549870927" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549786211" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549876050" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549876051" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549803375" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549786503" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549786504" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549786212" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549876052" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549786217" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549870928" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549924318" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549876053" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549786513" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549876058" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549786218" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549880490" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549786514" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549786515" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549880491" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS549880492" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549876059" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549786219" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549876060" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549786516" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549870929" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549786529" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS549876061" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549924319" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549786220" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549786225" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS549880493" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63960924" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001"><b>BACKGROUND</b></heading><heading id="h0002"><b>Field</b></heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">This embodiment relates to a light source device.</p><heading id="h0003"><b>Description of the Related Art</b></heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">In general, an electric bulb or a fluorescent lamp is commonly used as an indoor or outdoor lighting lamp. However, the electric bulb or the fluorescent lamp has a short life span, so that it should be frequently changed. Moreover, a conventional fluorescent lamp is degraded due to elapse of time for its use. As a result, it is often that its illuminance is gradually decreased.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">In order to overcome such problems, a lighting apparatus is now being developed by using a light emitting device (hereinafter, referred to as LED). The LED is easy to control and has a rapid response speed, high electro-optic conversion efficiency, a long life span, low power consumption and high luminance. The LED is also used to create emotional lighting.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">Light emitting device (LED) lighting is next generation lighting. Since the LED lighting uses a semiconductor device and light with a longer wavelength than that of an ultraviolet ray, it is not harmful to human body.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">Therefore, many lighting apparatuses to which the LED is applied are now being developed. However, a lot of parts are required at present to create various colors<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> or a characteristic of light which is a source of lighting, for example, a color rendering index (CRI).</p><heading id="h0004"><b>SUMMARY</b></heading><p id="p0006" num="0006">A light source device according to the embodiment implements a high color rendering property and prevents the color of an object from being distorted.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">A light source device according to the embodiment mixes various colors and creates emotional lighting.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">A light source device according to the embodiment reduces its the weight and thickness and allows the lighting device to be thinner.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">A light source device according to the embodiment reduces the number of its parts, so that manufacturing cost thereof is reduced.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">One aspect of this invention is a light source device. The light source device includes:
<ul><li>a light guide plate;</li><li>a reflector disposed under the light guide plate;</li><li>a light source unit optically coupled to the light guide plate; and</li><li>a photo luminescent film disposed between the light guide plate and the light source unit, wherein the photo luminescent film comprises at least two partitioned areas, and wherein a first fluorescent material comprised in at least one area of the at least two areas is different from a second fluorescent material comprised in the other areas.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0005"><b>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</b></heading><p id="p0011" num="0011"><ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is a perspective view showing a light source device according to an embodiment of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2</figref> is a view showing a light source unit of the light source device according to the<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> embodiment of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 3</figref> is a view showing an arrangement structure of light emitting devices of the light source unit according to the embodiment of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 4</figref> is a view showing a structure of a phosphor luminescent film according to the embodiment of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 5</figref> is a view showing an arrangement structure of a fluorescent material included in the phosphor luminescent film according to the embodiment of the present invention and showing a structure in which the phosphor luminescent film and the light source unit are arranged.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 6</figref> is a perspective view showing another light source device according to an embodiment of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 7</figref> is a view showing a pattern arrangement of a light guide plate according to the embodiment of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 8</figref> is a view showing a light source unit of the light source device according to the embodiment of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004 f0005">Figs. 9a to 9c</figref> are views showing an embodiment of the present invention, that is, arrangement structures of warm white LEDs and cool white LEDs which are included in a first light source unit and a second light source unit respectively.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 10</figref> is a view showing a structure of a phosphor luminescent film according to the embodiment of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 11</figref> is a view showing an arrangement structure of a fluorescent material included in the phosphor luminescent film according to the embodiment of the present invention and showing a structure in which the phosphor luminescent film and the light source<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> unit are arranged.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0006"><b>DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENTS</b></heading><p id="p0012" num="0012">It will be understood that when an element is referred to as being 'on' or "under" another element, it can be directly on/under the element, and one or more intervening elements may also be present. When an element is referred to as being 'on' or 'under', 'under the element' as well as 'on the element' can be included based on the element.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">Hereinafter, an embodiment will be described in detail with reference to the accompanying drawings.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014"><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is a perspective view showing a light source device according to an embodiment of the present invention. <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2</figref> is a view showing a light source unit of the light source device according to the embodiment of the present invention. <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 3</figref> is a view showing an arrangement structure of light emitting devices of the light source unit according to the embodiment of the present invention. <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 4</figref> is a view showing a structure of a phosphor luminescent film according to the embodiment of the present invention.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">First, referring to <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, a light source device 100 includes a light guide plate 110, a reflector 130, a light source unit 150, a photo luminescent film 170, and a diffusing film 190.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">The light guide plate 110 converts a point light source into a surface light source. A pattern 111 is formed on one side of the light guide plate 110 such that light<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> incident on the inside of the light guide plate 110 is emitted to the outside. The pattern 111 functions to diffuse or scatter the light and to emit to the outside. Such a light guide plate 110 may be made of a transparent resin and may be printed by a silk screen printing method and the like.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">The diffuser film 190 is disposed on the light guide plate 110. The diffuser film 190 functions to allow the light incident into the inside of the light guide plate 110 to be uniformly emitted to the outside.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">The reflector 130 is disposed under the light guide plate 110. The reflector 130 prevents the light incident into the inside of the light guide plate 110 from being emitted to the rear of the light guide plate.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">The light source unit 150 is disposed on the side of the light guide plate 110. Any device capable of emitting light can be used as the light source unit 150. In the embodiment of the present invention, a light emitting device is used as the light source unit. The light source unit 150 is optically coupled to the light guide plate 110, so that light generated from the light source unit 150 is incident into the inside of the light guide plate 110.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 2</figref>, the light source unit 150 includes a printed circuit board 151 and a plurality of light emitting devices 152 disposed on the printed circuit board 151. The plurality of the light emitting devices 152 are arranged in a line in the longitudinal direction of the printed circuit board. Though the plurality of the light emitting devices 152 may consist of a blue light emitting device, it is desirable that a white light emitting device with a high color rendering index (CRI) should be used as the plurality of the light emitting devices 152 if possible. The white light emitting<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> device is formed by molding plastic including a yellow fluorescent material on a blue light emitting chip, and creates white light. Here, the plastic may include a silicon resin or an epoxy resin. The white light emitting device may further include a green fluorescent material or a red fluorescent material so as to increase the color rendering index (CRI). That is, plastic including a yellow fluorescent material is mainly molded on the blue light emitting chip, and the green fluorescent material and the red fluorescent material may be included in the plastic in the order listed. The fluorescent material may include at least one of a garnet based material, a silicate based material, a nitride based material and an oxynitride based material. Here, the garnet based material may include YAG (Y<sub>3</sub>Al<sub>5</sub>O<sub>12</sub>:Ce<sup>3+</sup>) material or TAG (Tb<sub>3</sub>Al<sub>5</sub>O<sub>12</sub>:Ce<sup>3+</sup>) material. The silicate based material may include (Sr, Ba, Mg, Ca)<sub>2</sub>SiO<sub>4</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> material. The nitride based material may include CaAlSiN<sub>3</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> material. The oxynitride based material may include Si<sub>6-x</sub>Al<sub>x</sub>OxN<sub>8-x</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> material.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">Meanwhile, in the yellow, green and red fluorescent materials included in the plastic, when the ratio of the yellow fluorescent material is the highest and the ratio of the red fluorescent material is the lowest, the yellow, green and red fluorescent materials may include a garnet based material, a silicate based material and a nitride based material respectively. The yellow, green and red fluorescent materials may include a silicate based material, a silicate based material and a nitride based material respectively. The yellow, green and red fluorescent materials may include a garnet based material, an oxynitride based material and a nitride based material respectively. The yellow, green and red fluorescent materials may include an oxynitride based material, an oxynitride based material and a nitride based material respectively.<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --></p><p id="p0022" num="0022">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 3</figref>, the plurality of the light emitting devices 152 are comprised of a warm white LED 152-a and a cool white LED 152-b. The warm white LED 152-a and the cool white LED 152-b are alternately arranged on the printed circuit board 151. Accordingly, when light is emitted in the form of a surface light source, uniformly mixed light can be emitted from an entire light emitting surface.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">While not shown, when a specific color is required to be generated locally or randomly on the light emitting surface, the warm white LED and the cool white LED may be arranged locally or randomly with the order of the LEDs on the printed circuit board.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">Meanwhile, the warm white LED 152-a emits a correlated color temperature within a range between 2,000 K and 3,000 K, and has warm colors. The cool white LED 152-b emits a correlated color temperature within a range between 5,500 K and 6,500 K, and has cool colors. The warm white LED 152-a and the cool white LED 152-b per se can emit white light without a combination of a red, green and blue light emitting devices. That is, the warm white LED 152-a and the cool white LED 152-b are formed by molding plastic on the blue light emitting chip. The plastic includes a fluorescent material allowing the warm and cool white LEDs 152-a and 152-b to emit light with their corresponding correlated color temperatures. As a result, correlated color temperatures for white light can be emitted.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">As such, since the warm white LED 152-a and the cool white LED 152-b emit the correlated color temperatures respectively and emit mixed white light, the color rendering index (CRI) representing a degree of being close to natural sunlight becomes higher. Therefore, an actual color of an object can be prevented from being distorted<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> and the fatigue of the eyes of users is reduced.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">The photo luminescent film 170 is disposed between the light guide plate 110 and the light source unit 150, and includes various fluorescent materials within the photo luminescent film 170. The photo luminescent film 170 changes a part of a wavelength of light emitted from the light source unit 150, and changes the color of the light.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 4</figref>, the photo luminescent film 170 includes a transparent resin 171 and a fluorescent material 172 included within the transparent resin 171. The fluorescent material may include at least one of a garnet based material, a silicate based material, a nitride based material and an oxynitride based material. Here, the garnet based material may include YAG(Y<sub>3</sub>Al<sub>5</sub>O<sub>12</sub>:Ce<sup>3+</sup>) material or TAG (Tb<sub>3</sub>Al<sub>5</sub>O<sub>12</sub>:Ce<sup>3+</sup>) material. The silicate based material may include (Sr, Ba, Mg, Ca)<sub>2</sub>SiO<sub>4</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> material. The nitride based material may include CaAlSiN<sub>3</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> material. The oxynitride based material may include Si<sub>6-x</sub>Al<sub>x</sub>OxN<sub>8-x</sub>:Eu<sup>2+</sup> material.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">A transparent protective film 173 is stacked on the transparent resin. A silicon resin is mainly used as the transparent resin. Any material having transparency can be used as the transparent resin.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">While not shown, a curing agent or an additive agent may be included within the transparent resin. The curing agent cures the transparent resin. The additive agent disperses uniformly the fluorescent material within the transparent resin. A diffusing agent may be included within the transparent resin. The diffusing agent improves the refractive index of a light source, thus increasing the excitation ratio of the fluorescent material.<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --></p><p id="p0030" num="0030">The transparent protective film 173 disposed on the transparent resin obtains humidity resistance and thermal resistance of the fluorescent material. The transparent protective film 173 is made of colorless and transparent plastic having high optical transmittance. However, there is no limit to the material of the transparent protective film 173. For example, the transparent protective film 173 may be made of polyethylene terephthalate (PET), polyethylene naphthalate), acrylic resin, polycarbonate and polystyrene and the like.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031"><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 5</figref> is a view showing an arrangement structure of a fluorescent material included in the phosphor luminescent film according to the embodiment of the present invention and showing a structure in which the phosphor luminescent film and the light source unit are arranged.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">As shown, the transparent resin 171 of the photo luminescent film 170 includes a first area and a second area. The first area includes a first fluorescent material 172a. The second area includes a second fluorescent material 172b different from the first fluorescent material 172a. The first fluorescent material 172a and the second fluorescent material 172b are partitioned from each other in the photo luminescent film 170. A fluorescent material included in one of the first area and the second area may be different from a fluorescent material included in the other area. The first area and the second area partitioned in the photo luminescent film 170 are alternately arranged in the longitudinal direction of the photo luminescent film 170.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">The first fluorescent material 172a and the second fluorescent material 172b may be arranged locally or randomly in the longitudinal direction of the photo luminescent film 170. When the first fluorescent material 172a and the second<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> fluorescent material 172b are alternately arranged and when light is emitted through the light guide plate in the form of a surface light source, the colors of the light is uniformly mixed. As a result, various colors of the light can be created on the entire light emitting surface.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">The color of light may be created depending on the color of the light emitted from a light emitting device per se. However, it is preferable that the color of light is created depending on the fluorescent material included in the photo luminescent film.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">When the first fluorescent material 172a and the second fluorescent material 172b are alternately disposed, the plurality of the light emitting devices 152 of the light source unit 150 are, as shown, disposed corresponding respectively to the first fluorescent material 172a and the second fluorescent material 172b which are disposed within the photo luminescent film 170. Therefore, alignment characteristic between the plurality of the light emitting devices and the fluorescent materials is satisfactory, thus emitting light having a desired color temperature.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">If the plurality of the light emitting devices have the same color temperature and create the same color, the alignment characteristic between the plurality of the light emitting devices and the fluorescent materials does not affect the characteristic of the desired color. However, when the plurality of the light emitting devices are, for example, comprised of the warm white LED and the cool white LED, and when the warm white LED and the cool white LED are alternately arranged, the alignment characteristic between the fluorescent material and the cool and warm white LEDs may deteriorate. When the alignment characteristic deteriorates, light of an adjacent cool or warm white LED may pass through the fluorescent material. Thus, there occurs a problem that light<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> having an undesired color temperature is emitted.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">Each of the first fluorescent material 172a and the second fluorescent material 172b absorbs light having a specific wavelength and being emitted from the light source unit and converts the light into light having another wavelength. Accordingly, with respect to light emitted outward, it is possible to control the first fluorescent material 172a and the second fluorescent material 172b in accordance with a desired color of light.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">As such, the fluorescent material included in the photo luminescent film can change the color of emitted light, thereby creating light having various colors.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">The light source device according to the embodiment of the present invention substantially reduces the number of the photo luminescent film and the number of the light guide plate, and reduces manufacturing cost. The light source device also prevents the volume of the light source device from being increased by the number of the light guide plate. As a result, a lighting device to which the light source device is applied becomes thinner.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">This embodiment of the present invention includes the shortest optical path. Therefore, a luminous efficiency of this embodiment is improved.</p><p id="p0041" num="0041"><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 6</figref> is a perspective view showing another light source device according to an embodiment of the present invention. <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 7</figref> is a view showing a pattern arrangement of a light guide plate according to the embodiment of the present invention. <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 8</figref> is a view showing a light source unit of the light source device according to the embodiment of the present invention.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 6</figref>, a light source device 100 includes a first light guide plate<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> 110, a second light guide plate 120, a reflector 130, a first light source unit 150, a second light source unit 160, a first photo luminescent film 170 and a second photo luminescent film 180.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">The first light guide plate 110 and the second light guide plate 120 convert a point light source into a surface light source. A first pattern 111 and a second pattern 121 are formed on one sides of the light guide plate 110 and the second light guide plate 120 respectively such that light internally incident is emitted to the outside.</p><p id="p0044" num="0044">The first light guide plate 110 is stacked on the second light guide plate 120. The first pattern 111 and the second pattern 121, which are formed in the first light guide plate 110 and the second light guide plate 120 respectively, function to diffuse or scatter the light and to emit to the outside.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 7</figref>, the first pattern 111 and the second pattern 121 may be disposed such that they are superposed on each other or overlapped with each other. However, it is preferable that the first pattern 111 and the second pattern 121 are formed not to be overlapped with each other on one sides of the first light guide plate 110 and the second light guide plate 120 respectively.</p><p id="p0046" num="0046">The first pattern 111 and the second pattern 121 are formed in such a manner mentioned above, so that the characteristic of diffusion or scatter of incident light can be improved. As a result, the optical path is reduced and luminous efficiency is enhanced.</p><p id="p0047" num="0047">In other words, when light is incident on the inside of the second light guide plate 120 through one side of the second light guide plate 120 at a total reflection angle, the incident light is totally reflected on the other side of the second light guide plate 120, so that the optical path becomes longer. However, when the first pattern is formed on<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> one side of the first light guide plate 110 stacked on the second light guide plate 120, light to be totally reflected on the other side of the second light guide plate 120 is diffused or scattered at the first pattern 111 formed on one side of the first light guide plate 110. As a result, the light is directly emitted to the outside without being totally reflected. Accordingly, the optical path is effectively reduced.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048">The first light guide plate 110 and the second light guide plate 120 may be made of a transparent resin, and may be printed by a silk screen printing method.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">A diffusing film 190 is disposed on the first light guide plate 110. The diffuser film 190 functions to allow the light incident into the insides of the light guide plate 110 and the second light guide plate 120 to be uniformly emitted to the outside.</p><p id="p0050" num="0050">The reflector 130 is disposed under the second light guide plate 120. The reflector 130 prevents the light incident into the inside of the first light guide plate 110 or the second light guide plate 120 from being emitted to the rears of the light guide plates.</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">The first light source unit 150 is disposed on the side of the first light guide plate 110. The second light source unit 160 is disposed on the side of the second light guide plate 120. Any device capable of emitting light can be used as the first light guide plate 110 and the second light guide plate 120. In the embodiment of the present invention, a light emitting diode which is one of light emitting devices is used as the light source unit.</p><p id="p0052" num="0052">The first light source unit 150 and the second light source unit 160 are optically coupled to the first light guide plate 110 and the second light guide plate 120 respectively, so that light generated from the first light source unit 150 is incident on the<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> first light guide plate 110 and light generated from the second light source unit 160 is incident on the second light guide plate 120.</p><p id="p0053" num="0053">The first light source unit 150 and the second light source unit 160 respectively include, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 8</figref>, printed circuit boards 151 and 161, and a plurality of light emitting devices 152 and 162. The plurality of light emitting devices 152 and 162 are disposed on the printed circuit boards 151 and 161 respectively. The plurality of the light emitting devices 152 and 162 are arranged in a line in the longitudinal direction of the printed circuit board. As such, a light emitting device capable of creating white light has various types according to color temperatures. As regards a plurality of light emitting devices used in the embodiment of the present invention, specifically, the plurality of the light emitting device 152 included in the first light source unit 150 are constituted by warm white LEDs and are arranged on the printed circuit board 151. The plurality of the light emitting device 162 included in the second light source unit 160 are constituted by cool white LEDs and are arranged on the printed circuit board 161.</p><p id="p0054" num="0054"><figref idrefs="f0004 f0005">Figs. 9a to 9c</figref> are views showing an embodiment of the present invention, that is, arrangement structures of warm white LEDs and cool white LEDs which are included in a first light source unit and a second light source unit respectively.</p><p id="p0055" num="0055">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 9a</figref>, the warm white LEDs may be arranged in a line on the print circuit board 151 of the first light source unit 150. The cool white LEDs may be arranged in a line on the print circuit board 161 of the second light source unit 160.</p><p id="p0056" num="0056">Also, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 9b</figref>, the warm white LEDs and the cool white LEDs are alternately arranged in a line on the printed circuit board 151 of the first light source unit 150 in a line in the longitudinal direction of the printed circuit board 151. The<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> warm white LEDs and the cool white LEDs are also alternately arranged in a line on the printed circuit board 161 of the second light source unit 160 in a line in the longitudinal direction of the printed circuit board 161. In this case, the warm white LEDs and the cool white LEDs of the first light source unit 150 and the second light source unit 160 are arranged in a grid pattern.</p><p id="p0057" num="0057">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 9c</figref>, the warm white LEDs and the cool white LEDs may be randomly arranged all over both the first light source unit 150 and the entire second light source unit 160.</p><p id="p0058" num="0058">The first photo luminescent film 170 is disposed between the first light guide plate 110 and the first light source unit 150. The second photo luminescent film 180 is disposed between the second light guide plate 120 and the second light source unit 160. The first photo luminescent film 170 and the second photo luminescent film 180 include various fluorescent materials thereinside.</p><p id="p0059" num="0059">The first photo luminescent film 170 changes a part of a wavelength of light emitted from the first light source unit 150, and changes the color of the light. The second photo luminescent film 180 changes a part of wavelength of light emitted from the second light source unit 160, and changes the color of the light.</p><p id="p0060" num="0060"><figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 10</figref> is a view showing a structure of a phosphor luminescent film according to the embodiment of the present invention.</p><p id="p0061" num="0061">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 10</figref>, the photo luminescent films 170 and 180 include a transparent resin 171 and a fluorescent material 172 included within the transparent resin 171. A transparent protective film 173 is stacked on the transparent resin. A silicon resin is mainly used as the transparent resin. Any material having transparency<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> can be used as the transparent resin.</p><p id="p0062" num="0062">Since said first and second photo luminescent films 170 and 180 have been already described in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 4</figref>, detailed description thereof will be omitted.</p><p id="p0063" num="0063"><figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 11</figref> is a view showing an arrangement structure of a fluorescent material included in the phosphor luminescent film according to the embodiment of the present invention and showing a structure in which the phosphor luminescent film and the light source unit are arranged.</p><p id="p0064" num="0064">As shown, the first photo luminescent film 170 includes a first fluorescent material 172a and a second fluorescent material 172b different from the first fluorescent material 172a. The first fluorescent material 172a and the second fluorescent material 172b are partitioned from each other in the first photo luminescent film 170, and are alternately arranged in the longitudinal direction of the photo luminescent film 170.</p><p id="p0065" num="0065">In addition, the second photo luminescent film 180 includes a first fluorescent material 182a and a second fluorescent material 182b different from the first fluorescent material 182a. The first fluorescent material 182a and the second fluorescent material 182b are partitioned from each other in the second photo luminescent film 180, and are alternately arranged in the longitudinal direction of the second photo luminescent film 180. In this case, the first fluorescent materials 172a and 182a and the second fluorescent materials 182a and 182b which are included in both the first photo luminescent film 170 and the second photo luminescent film 180 are arranged in a grid pattern.</p><p id="p0066" num="0066">While not shown, when a desired color of light is required to be emitted or light having a specific color is required to be emitted from a particular point of the light<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> emitting surface, the first fluorescent materials 172a and 182a and the second fluorescent materials 182a and 182b which are included in both the first photo luminescent film 170 and the second photo luminescent film 180 may be locally or randomly arranged in the longitudinal direction of the first photo luminescent film 170 and the second photo luminescent film 180.</p><p id="p0067" num="0067">However, when the first fluorescent materials 172a and 182a and the second fluorescent materials 182a and 182b are alternately arranged and when light is emitted to the outside through the light guide plate in the form of a surface light source, the colors of the light is more uniformly mixed. As a result, various colors of the light can be created on the entire light emitting surface.</p><p id="p0068" num="0068">The color of light may be created depending on the color of the light emitted from a light emitting device per se. However, it is preferable that the color of light is created depending on the fluorescent material included in the photo luminescent film.</p><p id="p0069" num="0069">When the first fluorescent material 172a and the second fluorescent material 172b are alternately disposed, and the first fluorescent material 182a and the second fluorescent material 182b are alternately disposed, the plurality of the light emitting devices 152 of the light source unit 150 are, as shown, disposed corresponding respectively to the first fluorescent material 172a and second fluorescent material 172b which are disposed within the photo luminescent films 170. Also, the plurality of the light emitting devices 162 of the light source unit 160 are, as shown, disposed corresponding respectively to the first fluorescent material 182a and second fluorescent material 182b which are disposed within the photo luminescent films 180. Therefore, alignment characteristic between the plurality of the light emitting devices and the<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> fluorescent materials is satisfactory, thus emitting light having a desired color temperature.</p><p id="p0070" num="0070">The first fluorescent materials 172a and 182a and the second fluorescent materials 172b and 182b absorb respectively light having a specific wavelength and being emitted from the light source units 150 and 160 and convert the light into light having another wavelength. Accordingly, with respect to light emitted outward, it is possible to control the first fluorescent materials 172a and 182a and the second fluorescent materials 172b and 182b in accordance with a desired color of light.</p><p id="p0071" num="0071">As such, the fluorescent material included in the photo luminescent film can change the color of emitted light, thereby creating light having various colors.</p><p id="p0072" num="0072">The features, structures and effects and the like described in the embodiments are included in at least one embodiment of the present invention and are not necessarily limited to one embodiment. Furthermore, the features, structures, effects and the like provided in each embodiment can be combined or modified in other embodiments by those skilled in the art to which the embodiments belong. Therefore, contents related to the combination and modification should be construed to be included in the scope of the present invention.</p><p id="p0073" num="0073">Although embodiments of the present invention were described above, theses are just examples and do not limit the present invention. Further, the present invention may be changed and modified in various ways, without departing from the essential features of the present invention, by those skilled in the art. For example, the components described in detail in the embodiments of the present invention may be modified. Further, differences due to the modification and application should be<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> construed as being included in the scope of the present invention, which is described in the accompanying claims.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56985512" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Lichtquellenvorrichtung, aufweisend:
<claim-text>eine Lichtleitplatte (110);</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Reflektor (130), der unter der Lichtleitplatte angeordnet ist,</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Lichtquelleneinheit (150), die mit der Lichtleitplatte optisch gekoppelt ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen photolumineszierenden Film (170), der zwischen der Lichtleitplatte und der Lichtquelleneinheit angeordnet ist, wobei der photolumineszierende Film (170) zumindest zwei geteilte Bereiche aufweist, und wobei sich ein erstes fluoreszierendes Material (172a), das in zumindest einem Bereich der zumindest zwei Bereiche enthalten ist, von einem zweiten fluoreszierenden Material (172b) unterscheidet, das in den anderen Bereichen enthalten ist, und</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei die Lichtquelleneinheit eine Vielzahl lichtemittierender Vorrichtungen (152) aufweist, und</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei die Vielzahl der lichtemittierenden Vorrichtungen (152) eine erste weiße LED (152-a) und eine zweite weiße LED (152-b) aufweist, wobei die erste weiße LED (152-a) eine korrelierte Farbtemperatur in einem Bereich zwischen 2000 K und 3000 K emittiert, und wobei die zweite weiße LED (152-b) eine korrelierte Farbtemperatur in einem Bereich zwischen 5500 K und 6500 K emittiert.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Lichtquellenvorrichtung nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Lichtleitplatte (110) ein Muster (111) aufweist, das auf einer Seite derselben ausgebildet ist, und wobei das Muster Licht diffundiert oder streut.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Lichtquellenvorrichtung nach Anspruch 1, wobei das erste fluoreszierende Material (172a) und das zweite fluoreszierende Material (172b) alternierend in Längsrichtung des photolumineszierenden Films (170) angeordnet sind.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Lichtquellenvorrichtung nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Vielzahl lichtemittierender Vorrichtungen (152) in einer Linie angeordnet ist, und wobei die Vielzahl lichtemittierender Vorrichtungen (152) derart angeordnet ist, dass sie jeweils mit dem ersten fluoreszierenden Material (172a) oder dem zweiten fluoreszierenden Material (172b) in der Reihenfolge erstes fluoreszierendes Material (172a) - zweites fluoreszierendes Material (172b) - erstes fluoreszierendes Material (172a) - zweites<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --> fluoreszierendes Material (172b) korrespondiert, die in dem photolumineszierenden Film (170) enthalten sind.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Lichtquellenvorrichtung nach Anspruch 1 oder Anspruch 4, wobei die Vielzahl weißer lichtemittierender Vorrichtungen (152) in einer Linie angeordnet ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Lichtquellenvorrichtung nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Lichtleitplatte eine erste Lichtleitplatte (110) und eine zweite Lichtleitplatte (120) aufweist, wobei die Lichtquelleneinheit eine erste Lichtquelleneinheit (150) und eine zweite Lichtquelleneinheit (160) aufweist, wobei der photolumineszierende Film einen ersten photolumineszierenden Film (170) und einen zweiten photolumineszierenden Film (180) aufweist, und wobei der erste photolumineszierende Film (170) zwischen der ersten Lichtleitplatte (110) und der ersten Lichtquelleneinheit (150) angeordnet ist und der zweite photolumineszierende Film (180) zwischen der zweiten Lichtleitplatte (120) und der zweiten Lichtquelleneinheit (160) angeordnet ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Lichtquellenvorrichtung nach Anspruch 6, wobei ein erstes fluoreszierendes Material (172a, 182a) und ein zweites fluoreszierendes Material (172b, 182b), die sowohl im ersten photolumineszierenden Film (170) als auch im zweiten photolumineszierenden Film (180) enthalten sind, geteilt und zufällig angeordnet sind.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Lichtquellenvorrichtung nach Anspruch 6, wobei ein erstes fluoreszierendes Material (172a, 182a) und ein zweites fluoreszierendes Material (172b, 182b), die sowohl im ersten photolumineszierenden Film (170) als auch im zweiten photolumineszierenden Film (180) enthalten sind, in einem Gittermuster angeordnet sind.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Lichtquellenvorrichtung nach Anspruch 6, wobei die erste Lichtleitplatte (110) ein erstes Muster (111) darin und die zweite Lichtleitplatte (120) ein zweites Muster (121) darin aufweist, so dass Licht diffundiert oder gestreut wird, und wobei das erste Muster (111) und das zweite Muster (121) sich nicht überlappen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Lichtquellenvorrichtung nach Anspruch 6, wobei die erste weiße LED in der ersten Lichtquelleneinheit (150) angeordnet ist und die zweite weiße LED in der zweiten Lichtquelleneinheit angeordnet ist.<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Lichtquellenvorrichtung nach Anspruch 6, wobei die Vielzahl der lichtemittierenden Vorrichtungen, die in der ersten Lichtquelleneinheit (150) enthalten sind, mit der ersten weißen LED und der zweiten weißen LED korrespondiert, wobei die Vielzahl der lichtemittierenden Vorrichtungen, die in der zweiten Lichtquelleneinheit (160) enthalten sind, mit der ersten weißen LED und der zweiten weißen LED korrespondiert, wobei die erste weiße LED und die zweite weiße LED, die in der ersten Lichtquelleneinheit enthalten sind, alternierend angeordnet sind, und wobei die erste weiße LED und die zweite weiße LED, die in der zweiten Lichtquelleneinheit (160) enthalten sind, alternierend angeordnet sind.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Lichtquellenvorrichtung nach Anspruch 1 oder 3, wobei der photolumineszierende Film (170) eine transparente Harzschicht (171) aufweist, die das fluoreszierende Material (172) aufweist, und einen Schutzfilm (173) aufweist, der auf der transparenten Harzschicht (171) angeordnet ist, und wobei die transparente Harzschicht (171) ein Diffusionsmittel aufweist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Lichtquellenvorrichtung nach Anspruch 12, wobei das fluoreszierende Material (172) ein Material auf Granatbasis und/oder ein Material auf Silikatbasis und/oder ein Material auf Nitridbasis und/oder ein Material auf Oxynitridbasis aufweist.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56985513" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A light source device comprising:
<claim-text>a light guide plate (110);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a reflector (130) disposed under the light guide plate;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a light source unit (150) optionally coupled to the light guide plate; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a photo luminescent film (170) disposed between the light guide plate and the light source unit, wherein the photo luminescent film (170) comprises at least two partitioned areas, and wherein a first fluorescent material (172a) comprised in at least one area of the at least two areas is different from a second fluorescent (172b) material comprised in the other areas, and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the light source unit comprises a plurality of light emitting devices (152), and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the plurality of the light emitting devices (152) comprise a first white LED (152-a) and a second white LED (152-b), wherein the first white LED (152-a) emits a correlated color temperature within a range between 2,000 K and 3,000 K, and the second white LED (152-b) emits a correlated color temperature within a range between 5,500 K and 6,500 K.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The light source device of claim 1, wherein the light guide plate (110) comprises a pattern (111) formed on one side thereof, and wherein the pattern diffuses or scatters light.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The light source device of claim 1, wherein the first fluorescent material (172a) and the second fluorescent material (172b) are alternately arranged in the longitudinal direction of the photo luminescent film (170).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The light source device of claim 1, wherein the plurality of light emitting devices (152) is arranged in a line, and wherein the plurality of light emitting devices (152) are disposed corresponding respectively to the first fluorescent material (172a) or the second fluorescent material (172b) in the order of the first fluorescent material (172a) - the second fluorescent material (172b)-the<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> first fluorescent material (172a) - the second fluorescent material (172b) which are comprised in the photo luminescent film (170).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The light source device of claim 1 or claim 4, wherein the plurality of white light emitting devices (152) is arranged in a line.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The light source device of claim 1, wherein the light guide plate comprises a first light guide plate (110) and a second light guide plate (120), wherein the light source unit comprises a first light source unit (150) and a second light source unit (160), wherein the photo luminescent film comprises a first photo luminescent film (170) and a second photo luminescent film (180), and wherein the first photo luminescent film (170) is disposed between the first light guide plate (110) and the first light source unit (150), and the second photo luminescent film (180) is disposed between the second light guide plate (120) and the second light source unit (160).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The light source device of claim 6, wherein a first fluorescent material (172a,182a) and a second fluorescent material (172b,182b), which are comprised in both the first photo luminescent film (170) and the second photo luminescent film (180), are partitioned and randomly arranged.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The light source device of claim 6, wherein a first fluorescent material (172a,182a) and a seconde fluorescent material (172b,182b), which are comprised in both the first photo luminescent film (170) and the second photo luminescent film (180), are arranged in a grid pattern.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The light source device of claim 6, wherein the first light guide plate (110) comprise a first pattern (111) and the second light guide plate (120) comprise a second pattern (121) thereinside in order to<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> diffuse or scatter light, and wherein the first pattern (111) and the second pattern (121) are not overlapped with each other.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The light source device of claim 6, wherein the first white LED is disposed in the first light source unit (150), and the second white LED is disposed in the second light source unit.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>The light source device of claim 6, wherein the plurality of the light emitting devices comprised in the first light source unit (150) correspond to the first white LED and the second white LED, wherein the plurality of the light emitting devices comprised in the second light source unit (160) correspond to the first white LED and the second white LED, wherein the first white LED and the second white LED comprised in the first light source unit are alternately arranged, and wherein the first white LED and the second white LED comprised in the second light source unit (160) are alternately arranged.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>The light source device of claim 1 or claim 3, wherein the photo luminescent film (170) comprises a transparent resin layer (171) comprising the fluorescent material (172) and comprises a protective film (173) disposed on the transparent resin layer (171), and wherein the transparent resin layer (171) comprises a diffusing agent.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>The light source device of claim 12, wherein the fluorescent material (172) comprises at least one of a garnet based material, a silicate based material, a nitride based material and an oxynitride based material.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56985514" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Dispositif de source lumineuse comprenant :
<claim-text>une plaque guide de lumière (110) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un réflecteur (130) disposé sous la plaque guide de lumière ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>une unité de source lumineuse (150) couplée optiquement à la plaque guide de lumière ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un film photoluminescent (170) disposé entre la plaque guide de lumière et l'unité de source lumineuse, dans lequel le film photoluminescent (170) comprend au moins deux zones cloisonnées et dans lequel un premier matériau fluorescent (172a) compris dans au moins une zone des au moins deux zones est différent d'un second matériau fluorescent (172b) compris dans les autres zones, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel l'unité de source lumineuse comprend une pluralité de dispositifs émetteurs de lumière (152), et</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans lequel la pluralité des dispositifs émetteurs de lumière (152) comprennent une première DEL blanche (152-a) et une seconde DEL blanche (152-b), dans lequel la première DEL blanche (152-a) émet une température de couleur corrélée dans une plage comprise entre 2 000 K et 3 000 K, et la seconde DEL blanche (152-b) émet une température de couleur corrélée dans une plage comprise entre 5 500 K et 6 500 K.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Dispositif de source lumineuse selon la revendication 1, dans lequel la plaque guide de lumière (110) comprend un motif (111) formé sur un côté de celle-ci, et dans lequel le motif diffuse ou disperse la lumière.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Dispositif de source lumineuse selon la revendication 1, dans lequel le premier matériau fluorescent (172a) et le second matériau fluorescent (172b) sont agencés de manière alternée dans le sens longitudinal du film photoluminescent (170).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Dispositif de source lumineuse selon la revendication 1, dans lequel la pluralité de dispositifs émetteurs de lumière (152) sont agencés selon une ligne, et dans lequel la pluralité de dispositifs émetteurs de lumière (152) sont disposés de manière à correspondre respectivement au premier matériau fluorescent (172a) ou au second matériau fluorescent (172b) dans l'ordre du premier matériau fluorescent (172a) - du second matériau fluorescent (172b) - du premier matériau fluorescent (172a) - du second matériau fluorescent (172b) qui sont compris dans le film photoluminescent (170).<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Dispositif de source lumineuse selon la revendication 1 ou la revendication 4, dans lequel la pluralité de dispositifs émetteurs de lumière blanche (152) sont agencés selon une ligne.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Dispositif de source lumineuse selon la revendication 1, dans lequel la plaque guide de lumière comprend une première plaque guide de lumière (110) et une seconde plaque guide de lumière (120), dans lequel l'unité de source lumineuse comprend une première unité de source lumineuse (150) et une seconde unité de source lumineuse (160), dans lequel le film photoluminescent comprend un premier film photoluminescent (170) et un second film photoluminescent (180), et dans lequel le premier film photoluminescent (170) est disposé entre la première plaque guide de lumière (110) et la première unité de source lumineuse (150), et le second film photoluminescent (180) est disposé entre la seconde plaque guide de lumière (120) et la seconde unité de source lumineuse (160).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Dispositif de source lumineuse selon la revendication 6, dans lequel un premier matériau fluorescent (172a, 182a) et un second matériau fluorescent (172b, 182b), qui sont compris à la fois dans le premier film photoluminescent (170) et dans le second film photoluminescent (180), sont cloisonnés et agencés de manière aléatoire.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Dispositif de source lumineuse selon la revendication 6, dans lequel un premier matériau fluorescent (172a, 182a) et un second matériau fluorescent (172b, 182b), qui sont compris à la fois dans le premier film photoluminescent (170) et dans le second film photoluminescent (180), sont agencés selon un motif de grille.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Dispositif de source lumineuse selon la revendication 6, dans lequel la première plaque guide de lumière (110) comprend un premier motif (111) et la seconde plaque guide de lumière (120) comprend un second motif (121) à l'intérieur afin de diffuser ou de disperser la lumière, et dans lequel le premier motif (111) et le second motif (121) ne se chevauchent pas.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Dispositif de source lumineuse selon la revendication 6, dans lequel la première DEL blanche est disposée dans la première unité de source lumineuse (150) et la seconde DEL blanche est disposée dans la seconde unité de source lumineuse.<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Dispositif de source lumineuse selon la revendication 6, dans lequel la pluralité des dispositifs émetteurs de lumière compris dans la première unité de source lumineuse (150) correspondent à la première DEL blanche et à la seconde DEL blanche, dans lequel la pluralité des dispositifs émetteurs de lumière compris dans la seconde unité de source lumineuse (160) correspondent à la première DEL blanche et à la seconde DEL blanche, dans lequel la première DEL blanche et la seconde DEL blanche comprises dans la première unité de source lumineuse sont agencées de manière alternée, et dans lequel la première DEL blanche et la seconde DEL blanche comprises dans la seconde unité de source lumineuse (160) sont agencées de manière alternée.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Dispositif de source lumineuse selon la revendication 1 ou la revendication 3, dans lequel le film photoluminescent (170) comprend une couche de résine transparente (171) comprenant le matériau fluorescent (172) et comprend un film protecteur (173) disposé sur la couche de résine transparente (171), et dans lequel la couche de résine transparente (171) comprend un agent de diffusion.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Dispositif de source lumineuse selon la revendication 12, dans lequel le matériau fluorescent (172) comprend au moins un matériau parmi un matériau à base de grenat, un matériau à base de silicate, un matériau à base de nitrure et un matériau à base d'oxynitrure.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16672184" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1,2"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="148" he="176" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --><figure id="f0002" num="3,4,5"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="136" he="222" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --><figure id="f0003" num="6,7"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="152" he="202" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --><figure id="f0004" num="8,9a"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="146" he="203" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --><figure id="f0005" num="9b,9c"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="137" he="219" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --><figure id="f0006" num="10,11"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="161" he="200" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
