<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2553379-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2553379" kind="B1" date="20140101" family-id="42228718" file-reference-id="318289" date-produced="20180823" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146552644" ucid="EP-2553379-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2553379</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-11712305-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154826567" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>11712305</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20110323</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140448706" ucid="GB-201005467-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>GB</country><doc-number>201005467</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20100331</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140448398" ucid="GB-2011050572-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>GB</country><doc-number>2011050572</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20110323</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130826</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988104742" load-source="ipcr">F41H  13/00        20060101AFI20111019BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988128368" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F41H  13/0056      20130101 FI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988129532" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F41H  13/0087      20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132190416" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">BLENDER</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132190417" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">DAZZLERS</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132190418" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">DISPOSITIFS D'ÉBLOUISSEMENT</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918145928" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>BAE SYSTEMS PLC</last-name><address><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918167747" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>BAE SYSTEMS PLC</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918172217" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>STACEY CRAIG DANIEL</last-name><address><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918153594" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>STACEY, CRAIG, DANIEL</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918995292" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>STACEY, CRAIG, DANIEL</last-name><address><street>Bae Systems ATC Sowerby PO Box 5</street><city>Filton Bristol South Gloucestershire BS34 7QW</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918158777" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>CHARLTON DAVID WESLEY</last-name><address><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918173608" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>CHARLTON, DAVID, WESLEY</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918995295" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>CHARLTON, DAVID, WESLEY</last-name><address><street>Bae Systems ATC Sowerby PO Box 5 Filton</street><city>Bristol, South Gloucestershire BS34 7QW</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918995293" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>BAE Systems Plc</last-name><iid>101236074</iid><address><street>6 Carlton Gardens</street><city>London SW1Y 5AD</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918995294" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>BAE SYSTEMS plc Group IP Department</last-name><iid>101227539</iid><address><street>P.O. Box 87 Warwick House</street><city>Farnborough Aerospace Centre Farnborough Hampshire GU12 4NS</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="GB-2011050572-W"><document-id><country>GB</country><doc-number>2011050572</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20110323</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2011121333-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2011121333</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20111006</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548824175" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS548952987" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS548824176" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS548878189" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS548963852" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS548953273" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS548952988" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS548824177" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548953278" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS548953279" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS548850014" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS548878190" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS548963853" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548824178" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548953280" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS548824179" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS548952989" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS548850015" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS548953281" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS548878191" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS548953286" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS548878192" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS548959121" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS548878193" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS548878194" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS548959142" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS548959143" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS548959144" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS548953046" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS548959145" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS548953287" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS548966015" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS548953288" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS548959150" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS548824180" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS548953047" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS548953048" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS548850016" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63956882" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><p id="p0001" num="0001">This invention relates to dazzlers.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002">A dazzler is used to emit a beam of high intensity radiation, usually laser, towards a human or animal target temporarily to blind the target or to provide visual distraction or a warning. Typical existing dazzle lasers are of fixed power which places a lower limit on the nominal ocular hazard distance (that is the distance at which the laser becomes eye safe) and therefore the range over which the device is of use. This requires user judgment and, in order to have a practical minimum range, limits the laser power and therefore the upper range limit a laser dazzler is known from <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US20050185403A"><text>US 2005/0185403</text></patcit></p><p id="p0003" num="0003">It is therefore an aim of this invention to provide a dazzle apparatus that at least mitigates the above shortcomings.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">Accordingly, in one aspect, this invention provides a dazzle apparatus comprising a radiation source for emitting a dazzle beam of radiation towards a target to be dazzled, the target being at a variable range, a beam control system to control the strength of the dazzle beam in accordance with the range of said target to deliver to said target radiation of sufficient intensity momentarily to dazzle a user, and a stray detector for detecting approach of a secondary object towards said dazzle beam, or vice versa and, in response to such approach, to reduce the strength of or inhibit the beam.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">In this manner, the dazzle apparatus modulates the strength of the radiation to ensure that the beam is effective to dazzle the target without causing permanent ocular damage, thereby potentially increasing the range over which the dazzler may be effectively used and prevents inadvertent incidence of the dazzle beam on a secondary target which moves towards the dazzle beam or towards which the dazzle beam moves.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">Although the emitter may emit intense visible non-coherent light, it is preferred for the emitter to emit a beam of coherent light such as laser radiation.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">The device may receive target range data from an external device or more preferably from a range finder associated with the dazzler. The range<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> finder may conveniently be a laser range finder. The range finder may use reflections of the dazzle laser suitably attenuated if required to determine the range of the target, or it could use a separate laser.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">The beam control may adjust the strength of the beam by adjusting the source power, by attenuating the beam using e.g. an acousto-optic modulator, or it may adjust the strength of the beam by adjusting the divergence of the beam so as to adjust the intensity or laser power per unit area. The divergence of the beam of radiation may be adjusted by means of an adjustable beam expander.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">The stray detector may include a stray detection beam source for emitting at least one stray detection beam to illuminate an area adjacent said dazzle beam and a stray detection receiver for detecting and processing radiation reflected by said at least one secondary object to determine a position of the secondary object relative to the dazzle beam. Preferably the stray detector source includes a beam shaper whereby the stray detector beam has a flattened shape in which the beam divergence in one plane is similar to that of the dazzle beam and is significantly greater in a perpendicular plane. The beam shaper may be a lens or grating. In addition or alternatively, said stray detector source may emit a plurality of stray detector beams each disposed to illuminate a respective area adjacent said dazzle beam. These may be from a single source or a plurality of sources. In another arrangement said stray detector source may be operable to scan one or more stray detector beams across an area adjacent the dazzle beam.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">In an adaptive version, the stray detector may be operable to track the position of a secondary object and to predict the trajectory thereof, with said beam control system being operable to reduce the strength of, or inhibit, the dazzle beam if the predicted trajectory passes through, or within a preset distance of, the dazzle beam.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">Still further, the beam control system may be operable also to control the angular position of the dazzle beam, and may include a target tracker operable on acquisition or designation of a target to provide to said beam control system<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> data to enable the beam control to lock the dazzle beam on the target. Conveniently the beam control also steers the stray detector beam and the range finder beam if these are separate.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">According to another aspect, this invention provides a dazzle apparatus comprising a radiation source for emitting a dazzle beam to dazzle a target, a stray detector for monitoring an area near said dazzle beam and for inhibiting or reducing the strength of said dazzle beam, on detecting a secondary object adjacent the periphery of said dazzle beam.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">Whilst the invention has been described above it extends to any inventive combination of the features set out above, or in the following description, claims or drawings.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">The invention may be performed in various ways, and various embodiments thereof will now be described by way of example only, reference being made to the accompanying drawings in which:
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref> is a schematic diagram of a laser dazzler in accordance with this invention with provision to control the strength of the radiation incident on a target to ensure momentary dazzling but without causing permanent ocular damage and also with a stray detection system designed to ensure that the dazzle beam is reduced or inhibited should a secondary object, other than the target, approach the dazzle beam;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref> is a schematic diagram of operation of the device showing continuous range monitoring and corresponding control of dazzle power, and</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3</figref> is a schematic diagram of operation showing the stray detector system employing one or more secondary stray detection beams to detect objects at or approaching the periphery of the dazzle laser.</li></ul></p><p id="p0015" num="0015">Referring initially to <figref idrefs="f0001">Figure 1</figref>, the laser dazzle system comprises a dazzle laser 10 designed to emit a beam 11 of laser radiation designed to momentarily dazzle a human user. The strength of the laser beam (and in particular its intensity when received at the target) is adjustable by means of one or more of a power control unit 12, a beam attenuator modulator 14 and a variable beam<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> expander 15, each being under the control of a central controller 16. A laser range finder generally indicated at 18 comprises a range beam emitter 20 and a range beam receiver 22 each under the control of a range detector 23 which receives and processes signals from the range beam receiver 22 to determine the range of a target. The laser range finder 18 is controlled by the central controller 16 which also receives range data from the range detector 23.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">The apparatus also includes one or more stray detector modules indicated generally at 26 comprising a stray detection beam emitter 28 emitting a stray detection beam 29, and a stray beam detection receiver 30. The stray detection beam emitter and the stray beam detection receiver are each under the control of a stray detector 32 which controls them and processes the return information to identify when a stray secondary object is approaching the periphery of the beam emitted by the dazzle laser (or the periphery of the projected beam, if the dazzle laser is quiescent). The stray detector 26 supplies data relating to stray secondary objects to the controller and is also controlled by the controller 16. As to be described in more detail below, the stray detection beam emitter 28 is provided with a beam shaper or beam scanner unit 34.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">Although the above embodiment includes a range beam emitter 22 and a stray detection beam emitter 28 separately from the dazzle laser 10, in modified embodiments one or both may be omitted and the dazzle laser controlled to provided a range finder facility and/or a stray detection facility. For example, operation of the dazzle laser 10 and the range finder 18 and stray detectors 26 may effectively be multiplexed with the dazzle laser intermittently being modified in at least one of laser wavelength, intensity, divergence and beam shape to illuminate the field of view required and for the particular range finding, stray detecting or dazzling function.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">In this arrangement, the controller 16 uses the range finder 18 in order to measure the range to target and then subsequently sets the power of the dazzle laser before it is switched on. Following this, the controller 16 continuously monitors the indication of range determined by the range finder 18 and adjusts the power of the dazzle laser 10 accordingly. This therefore ensures that the optimum laser intensity is generated at the target range, whilst ensuring that the<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> power does not exceed that which would produce permanent ocular damage (retinal damage). As referred to above, the controller may control the effective strength of the laser beam by one or more of the following ways. The laser output power may be adjusted using laser power control 12. The divergence of the dazzle laser beam (since it is the intensity (laser power per unit area) which needs to be controlled at the target range) may be adjusted using an adjustable beam expander 14 at the dazzle laser exit for this purpose. The laser range finder beam is required to be roughly equal to or less than the divergence of the dazzle laser beam in order to ensure that the dazzle power is set according to the laser range finder target. A variable attenuator 15 may be used to attenuate the beam as required.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">The dazzle process is illustrated schematically in <figref idrefs="f0002">Figure 2</figref>. Thus initially the laser range finder 18 is used to measure the range to the required target. The controller 18 then uses this information to set power of the dazzle laser 10 according to laser safety calculations from a suitable look up table or the like. The dazzle laser 10 is then energised at the correct power momentarily to blind the target. The controller continuously monitors the range of the target and varies the dazzle power as necessary. The delay (t) between the laser range measurement acquisition and adjustment of the strength of the dazzle beam needs to be sufficiently short in order to prevent laser ocular overdose if the target moves towards the laser source.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">Turning now to the anti-stray safety mechanism, given the laser intensity levels which could be present within 100 metres of the laser output aperture (particularly if the dazzle power is set for a target at, say, 1km) it is advantageous to have a mechanism whereby the system will either reduce dazzle laser power or shut the laser off completely in the event of a third party wandering inadvertently into the dazzle laser beam or, where the user of the device is swinging the device around to follow a target, where the dazzle laser beam inadvertently approaches a third party. In a basic system the operator may be required to maintain awareness of the environment immediately surrounding that of the laser trajectory. However, in the arrangement described<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> below, a safety mechanism is provided to remove this responsibility from the operator.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">A stray detector module employing range finder technology is provided to monitor the periphery of the dazzle laser. The stray detection beam 29 is co-bore sited with the dazzle beam 11, or positioned closely adjacent, but has a divergence much larger than that of the dazzle beam and operates at a different wavelength in order to avoid cross talk. The divergence of the stray detection beam 29 produces a cone which detects objects which are adjacent but currently outside the dazzle beam, as illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3(a)</figref>. While the dazzle laser 11 is operating, the stray detector continuously monitors the area immediately surrounding the dazzle laser 11. If the stray detector detects a secondary object moving towards the centre of its beam (i.e. the location of the dazzle laser), then the dazzle laser power is immediately reduced or shut down until such time that the stray secondary object has moved on, or that the stray secondary object has become the new target. The acquisition process may then continue as normal.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">The beam shape of the secondary stray detection beam 29 may take various forms. In its simplest, a simple conic shape may be used (i.e. a Gaussian beam as in <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3(a)</figref>) but it will be appreciated that such a beam will strike the ground after perhaps only a short distance. This may produce multiple ground reflections which may overload the stray detector receiver.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">In a modification the stray detector beam emitter 28 incorporates a beam shaper 34. In one arrangement, rather than using optics to uniformly diffract the stray detector beam, a cylindrical lens (or wedge shaped optic) or a grating is used in order to diffract the beam non-uniformly. Thus the beam 29 is expanded in the horizontal plane but left essentially collimated (or at least of similar divergence to the dazzle beam) in the vertical plane. This produces a generally elliptical beam profile in the far-field. This is illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3(b)</figref>. In another arrangement, shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3(c)</figref> a plurality of stray detectors 26 may be positioned either side of the primary dazzle beam 11. Functionally, this is similar to the elliptical beam of <figref idrefs="f0003">Figure 3(b)</figref> but provides a greater range capability<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> because diffracting the beam will spread the energy over a larger area leading to a drop in maximum range capability.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">In a yet further embodiment, a single stray detector beam emitter could be used with a beam scanner 34 designed to continuously scan the pointing direction about the dazzle laser.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">The divergence of the stray detector beam (or the angular deflection of the stray detector beam with respect to the primary dazzle beam) is determined by a trade off between the rate at which the combined system can determine that a stray (and not an inanimate object) has entered the field of view and set the dazzle laser power accordingly, and the reduction in maximum measurable range because of stray detector beam divergence. Thus the beam must be wide enough to detect a stray object in time to reduce dazzle power, but must be narrow enough to be useable at all practical ranges. In this respect it is advantageous that the region of highest dazzle power and therefore the region requiring the highest degree of power control is the range closest to the dazzle laser (0-100 metres). Beyond 100 to 200 metres, the change in dazzle power required for a target at, say, 500 metres compared to 800 metres, is very small.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">The central control includes suitable tracking and discrimination software so that apparatus can discriminate between the background scene and the target or potential targets. Such software is well known to one skilled in the art and will not be described in detail here. Typically, such software may analyse a viewed scene to identify those elements that are moving in the scene. In addition, where the apparatus is designed to be moved itself the software will discount movement due to the change in viewing direction and still analyse for objects moving relative to the background scenery.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">In a yet further embodiment, the controller may be adapted to allow a user to designate a target in the viewed scene and for the control unit to steer the dazzle beam to track a target. Again, such software algorithms are well known to those skilled in the art and will not be described in detail here. In this arrangement the detection axes of the range finger and the stray detector may be moved to follow the axis of the dazzle laser.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></p><p id="p0028" num="0028">The device described herein may be used in a number of different applications but typically will be a portable unit. For example, the unit may be mounted on a rifle, a tripod or a vehicle.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56978135" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Blendervorrichtung, aufweisend:
<claim-text>eine Strahlungsquelle (10) zum Aussenden eines Strahlungsblendstrahls (11) zu einem Ziel, das geblendet werden soll, wobei sich das Ziel in variabler Entfernung befindet, ein Strahlsteuersystem (16, 12, 14, 15) zum Steuern der Stärke des Blendstrahls gemäß der Entfernung des Ziels zum Zuführen zu dem Ziel von Strahlung mit genügender Intensität zum vorübergehenden Blenden eines Benutzers und einen Streudetektor (26) zum Erkennen der Annäherung eines zweiten Objekts an den Blendstrahl (11) oder umgekehrt und, als Reaktion auf derartige Annäherung, zum Reduzieren der Stärke des Strahls oder zum Verhindern des Strahls.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Blendervorrichtung nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Strahlungsquelle (10) einen Laserstrahl aussendet.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Blendervorrichtung nach einem der Ansprüche 1 oder 2, der einen Entfernungsmesser (18) enthält, welcher zum Bestimmen der Entfernung eines Ziels betreibbar ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Blendervorrichtung nach Anspruch 3, wobei der Entfernungsmesser (18) ein Laserentfernungsmesser ist.<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Blendervorrichtung nach Anspruch 4, wobei der Entfernungsmesser einen Entfernungsmesserempfänger (22) enthält, der zum Erkennen und Verarbeiten von Strahlung von der Strahlungsquelle, die vom Ziel reflektiert ist, betreibbar ist, um dadurch die Entfernung des Ziels zu bestimmen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Blendervorrichtung nach Anspruch 4, die eine separate Entfernungsmesserquelle (20) zum Aussenden eines Entfernungsstrahls zu dem Ziel hin enthält, und wobei der Entfernungsmesser zum Erkennen und Verarbeiten von Strahlung vom Entfernungsstrahl, der vom Ziel reflektiert ist, betreibbar ist, um dadurch die Entfernung zu erkennen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Blendervorrichtung nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei das Strahlsteuersystem (16, 12) die Stärke des Strahls durch Anpassen der Leistung der Strahlungsquelle und/oder durch Anpassen der Divergenz des Strahls variiert.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Blendervorrichtung nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 6, wobei das Strahlsteuermittel (16, 15) einen Dämpfer zum variablen Dämpfen des Strahls zum Variieren der Stärke der Strahlung am Ziel aufweist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Blendervorrichtung nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei der Streudetektor (26) eine Streudetektorquelle (28) zum Aussenden von mindestens einem Streuerkennungsstrahl (29) zum Beleuchten eines dem Blenderstrahl (11) benachbarten Bereichs und einen Streudetektorempfänger (30) zum Erkennen und Verarbeiten von Strahlung, die von mindestens einem sekundären Objekt reflektiert ist, zum Bestimmen einer Position des sekundären Objekts bezüglich des Blenderstrahls enthält.<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Blendervorrichtung nach Anspruch 9, wobei die Streudetektorquelle (28) einen Strahlformer (34) enthält, wobei der Streuerkennungsstrahl eine abgeflachte Form aufweist, bei der die Strahldivergenz in einer Ebene jener des Blenderstrahls ähnelt und in einer senkrecht stehenden Ebene erheblich größer ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Blendervorrichtung nach Anspruch 9, wobei die Streudetektorquelle (28) mehrere Streudetektorstrahlen (29) aussendet, die jeder zum Beleuchten eines jeweiligen, dem Blenderstrahl (11) benachbarten Bereichs angeordnet sind.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Blendervorrichtung nach Anspruch 9, wobei die Streudetektorquelle (28) zum Abtasten von einem oder mehr Streudetektorstrahlen (29) über einen Bereich hinweg, der dem Blenderstrahl (11) benachbart ist, betreibbar ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Blendervorrichtung nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei der Streudetektor (26) zum Verfolgen der Position eines sekundären Objekts und zum Voraussagen seiner Laufbahn betreibbar ist und das Strahlsteuersystem (16) zum Reduzieren der Stärke des Blenderstrahls oder zum Verhindern desselben betreibbar ist, wenn die vorausgesagte Laufbahn durch eine oder innerhalb einer vorgegebenen Distanz des Blenderstrahls verläuft.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Blendervorrichtung nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei das Strahlsteuersystem (16) außerdem zum Steuern der Winkelposition des Blenderstrahls (11) betreibbar ist, und das ferner einen Zielverfolger enthält, der bei Erfassen oder Zuteilen eines Ziels zum Versehen des Strahlsteuersystems mit Daten betreibbar ist, die es der Steuerung ermöglichen, den Blenderstrahl auf das Ziel zu fixieren.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56978136" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A dazzle apparatus comprising:
<claim-text>a radiation source (10) for emitting a dazzle beam (11) of radiation towards a target to be dazzled, the target being at a variable range, a beam control system (16, 12, 14, 15) to control the strength of the dazzle beam in accordance with the range of said target to deliver to said target radiation of sufficient intensity momentarily to dazzle a user, and a stray detector (26) for detecting approach of a secondary object towards said dazzle beam (11), or vice versa and, in response to such approach, to reduce the strength of or inhibit the beam.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>A dazzle apparatus according to Claim 1, wherein the radiation source (10) emits a beam of laser radiation.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>A dazzle apparatus according to Claim 1 or Claim 2, which includes a range finger (18) operable to determine the range of a target.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>A dazzle apparatus according to Claim 3, wherein the range finder (18) is a laser range finder.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>A dazzle apparatus according to Claim 4, wherein the range finder includes a range finder receiver (22) operable to detect and process radiation from said radiation source reflected by said target thereby to determine the range of the target.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>A dazzle apparatus according to Claim 4, which includes a separate range finder source (20) for emitting a range beam of radiation towards said target and the range finder is operable to detect and process radiation from said range beam of radiation reflected by said target thereby to detect said range.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>A dazzle apparatus according to any of the preceding Claims, wherein the beam control system (16, 12) varies the strength of the beam by adjusting the power of the radiation source, and/or by adjusting the divergence of the beam.<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>A dazzle apparatus according to any of Claims 1 to 6, wherein said beam control means (16, 15) comprises an attenuator for variably attenuating said beam to vary the strength of the radiation at said target.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>A dazzle apparatus according to any preceding Claim, wherein said stray detector (26) includes a stray detector source (28) for emitting at least one stray detection beam (29) to illuminate an area adjacent said dazzle beam (11), and a stray detection receiver (30) for detecting and processing radiation reflected by said at least one secondary object to determine a position of the secondary object relative to the dazzle beam.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>A dazzle apparatus according to Claim 9, wherein said stray detector source (28) includes a beam shaper (34) whereby the stray detection beam has a flattened shape in which the beam divergence in one plane is similar to that of the dazzle beam and is significantly greater in a perpendicular plane.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>A dazzle apparatus according to Claim 9, wherein said stray detector source (28) emits a plurality of stray detection beams (29) each disposed to illuminate a respective area adjacent said dazzle beam (11).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>A dazzle apparatus according to Claim 9, wherein said stray detector source (28) is operable to scan one or more stray detector beams (29) across an area adjacent the dazzle beam (11).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>A dazzle apparatus according to any preceding Claim, wherein said stray detector (26) is operable to track the position of a secondary object and to predict the trajectory thereof, and said beam control system (16) is operable to reduce the strength of, or inhibit, the dazzle beam if the predicted trajectory passes through, or within a preset distance of, the dazzle beam.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>A dazzle apparatus according to any preceding Claim, wherein the beam control system (16) is also operable to control the angular<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> position of the dazzle beam (11), and which further includes a target tracker operable on acquisition or designation of a target to provide to said beam control system data to enable the controller to lock the dazzle beam on the target.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56978137" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Appareil d'éblouissement comprenant :
<claim-text>une source de rayonnement (10) pour émettre un faisceau d'éblouissement (11) de rayonnement vers une cible à éblouir, la cible étant située à une portée variable, un système de commande de faisceau (16, 12, 14, 15) contrôlant l'intensité du faisceau d'éblouissement suivant la portée de ladite cible pour délivrer audit rayonnement cible une intensité suffisante pour éblouir momentanément un utilisateur, et un détecteur de rayonnement parasite (26) pour détecter l'approche d'un second objet vers ledit faisceau d'éblouissement (11), ou vice versa et, en réponse à une telle approche, pour réduire ou inhiber l'intensité du faisceau.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Appareil d'éblouissement selon la revendication 1, dans lequel la source de rayonnement (10) émet un faisceau de rayonnement laser.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Appareil d'éblouissement selon la revendication 1 ou la revendication 2, qui comprend un télémètre (18) utilisable pour déterminer la portée d'une cible.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Appareil d'éblouissement selon la revendication 3, dans lequel le télémètre (18) est un télémètre laser.<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Appareil d'éblouissement selon la revendication 4, dans lequel le télémètre comprend un récepteur de télémètre (22) utilisable pour détecter et traiter un rayonnement provenant de ladite source de rayonnement réfléchi par ladite cible, déterminant par ce moyen la portée de la cible.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Appareil d'éblouissement selon la revendication 4, qui comprend une source de télémètre séparée (20) pour émettre un faisceau de portée de rayonnement vers ladite cible et le télémètre est utilisable pour détecter et traiter un rayonnement à partir dudit faisceau de portée de rayonnement réfléchi par ladite cible, détectant par ce moyen ladite portée.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Appareil d'éblouissement selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans lequel le système de commande de faisceau (16, 12) fait varier l'intensité du faisceau en ajustant la puissance de la source de rayonnement, et/ou en ajustant la divergence du faisceau.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Appareil d'éblouissement selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 6, dans lequel ledit moyen de commande de faisceau (16, 15) comprend un atténuateur pour atténuer de manière variable ledit faisceau pour faire varier l'intensité du rayonnement au niveau de ladite cible.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Appareil d'éblouissement selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans lequel ledit détecteur de rayonnement parasite (26) comprend une source de détecteur de rayonnement parasite (28) pour émettre au moins un faisceau de détection de rayonnement parasite (29) pour éclairer une zone adjacente audit faisceau d'éblouissement (11), et un récepteur de détection<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> de rayonnement parasite (30) pour détecter et traiter un rayonnement réfléchi par ledit au moins un objet secondaire pour déterminer une position de l'objet secondaire par rapport au faisceau d'éblouissement.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Appareil d'éblouissement selon la revendication 9, dans lequel ladite source de détecteur de rayonnement parasite (28) comprend un dispositif de mise en forme de faisceau (34) par lequel le faisceau de détection de rayonnement parasite a une forme aplanie, où la divergence du faisceau dans un plan est similaire à celle du faisceau d'éblouissement et est significativement plus grande dans un plan perpendiculaire.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Appareil d'éblouissement selon la revendication 9, dans lequel ladite source de détecteur de rayonnement parasite (28) émet une pluralité de faisceaux de détection de rayonnement parasite (29) chacun disposé pour éclairer une zone respective adjacente audit faisceau d'éblouissement (11).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Appareil d'éblouissement selon la revendication 9, dans lequel ladite source de détecteur de rayonnement parasite (28) est utilisable pour balayer un ou plusieurs faisceaux de détecteur de rayonnement parasite (29) sur une zone adjacente au faisceau d'éblouissement (11).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Appareil d'éblouissement selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans lequel ledit détecteur de rayonnement parasite (26) est utilisable pour suivre la position d'un objet secondaire et pour prédire la trajectoire de celui-ci, et ladite système de commande de faisceau (16) est utilisable pour réduire, ou inhiber, l'intensité du faisceau d'éblouissement<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> si la trajectoire prédite traverse le faisceau d'éblouissement, ou passe à une distance prédéfinie du faisceau d'éblouissement.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Appareil d'éblouissement selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans lequel le système de commande de faisceau (16) est également utilisable pour contrôler la position angulaire du faisceau d'éblouissement (11), et qui comprend en outre un appareil de poursuite de cible utilisable pour l'acquisition ou la désignation d'une cible pour fournir audit système de commande de faisceau des données pour permettre au contrôleur de verrouiller le faisceau d'éblouissement sur la cible.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16668490" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="165" he="196" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="132" he="214" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3(a),3(b),3(c)"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="165" he="212" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
