<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2960337-A1" country="EP" doc-number="2960337" kind="A1" date="20151230" family-id="51391278" file-reference-id="265330" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="160451884" ucid="EP-2960337-A1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2960337</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20151230</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-14754590-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP193866736" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>14754590</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20140219</date><lang>JA</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP193866737" load-source="patent-office" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>14754590.9</doc-number><date>20140219</date><lang>JA</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC162028428" ucid="JP-2013029701-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>JP</country><doc-number>2013029701</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20130219</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC162026618" ucid="JP-2014053888-W" linkage-type="W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>JP</country><doc-number>2014053888</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20140219</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1915430713" load-source="docdb">C12P   9/00        20060101ALI20160727BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1915435793" load-source="docdb">C12P   7/00        20060101AFI20160727BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1919282935" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">C12P   9/00        20130101 FI20160707BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1919283862" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">C12P   7/20        20130101 LI20160709BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1987779216" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">C12Y 301/03002     20130101 LI20150305BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT165547118" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">HERSTELLUNGSVERFAHREN FÜR GLYCEROLPHOSPHAT</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT165547119" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">PRODUCTION METHOD FOR GLYCEROL PHOSPHATE</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT165547120" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">PROCÉDÉ DE PRODUCTION DE GLYCÉROL PHOSPHATE</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR1103324745" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>THERMOSTABLE ENZYME LAB CO LTD</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR1103324175" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>THERMOSTABLE ENZYME LABORATORY CO. LTD.</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR1101641788" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Thermostable Enzyme Laboratory Co. Ltd.</last-name><iid>101241649</iid><address><street>5-5-2, Minatojima-Minamimachi Chuo-ku Kobe-shi</street><city>Hyogo 650-0047</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1103322288" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>IWATA HIDEYUKI</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1103321288" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>IWATA, HIDEYUKI</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1101651804" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>IWATA, HIDEYUKI</last-name><address><street>c/o THERMOSTABLE ENZYME LABORATORY CO. LTD. 5-5-2 Minatojima-Minamimachi Chuo-ku</street><city>Kobe-shi Hyogo 650-0047</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1103304648" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>TANAKA HISAE</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1103305857" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>TANAKA, HISAE</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1101643193" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>TANAKA, HISAE</last-name><address><street>c/o THERMOSTABLE ENZYME LABORATORY CO. LTD. 5-5-2 Minatojima-Minamimachi Chuo-ku</street><city>Kobe-shi Hyogo 650-0047</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR1101643922" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Webster, Jeremy Mark</last-name><suffix>et al</suffix><iid>100772583</iid><address><street>Mewburn Ellis LLP City Tower 40 Basinghall Street</street><city>London EC2V 5DE</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="JP-2014053888-W"><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>2014053888</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20140219</date><lang>JA</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2014129492-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2014129492</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140828</date><lang>JA</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS660694652" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS660785533" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS660694098" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS660692161" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS660704730" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS660694111" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS660613020" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS660694654" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS660694112" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS660694113" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS660615960" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS660692162" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS660692167" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS660694703" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS660694114" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS660694704" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS660613021" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS660704819" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS660694115" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS660692168" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS660694116" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS660692169" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS660785534" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS660692170" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS660692187" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS660785535" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS660785536" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS660785537" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS660613022" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS660785538" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS660694117" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS660616356" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS660694118" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS660785539" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS660694706" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS660613027" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS660613028" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS660615961" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states><ep-extended-states><ep-extended-state-data><country>BA</country></ep-extended-state-data><ep-extended-state-data><country>ME</country></ep-extended-state-data></ep-extended-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA166480254" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p id="pa01" num="0001">The present invention addresses the problem of providing a method for the efficient phosphorylation of glycerol. The problem is solved by reacting glycerol with either a kinase that includes the active center expressed by sequence (1) and exhibits a catalytic activity with respect to the phosphorylation of glycerol, or a kinase that includes the amino acid sequence represented by SEQ ID NO: 2 and exhibits a catalytic activity with respect to the phosphorylation of glycerol, in the presence of a phosphate group donor. </p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA166760066" lang="EN" source="EPO" load-source="docdb"><p>The present invention addresses the problem of providing a method for the efficient phosphorylation of glycerol. The problem is solved by reacting glycerol with either a kinase that includes the active center expressed by sequence (1) and exhibits a catalytic activity with respect to the phosphorylation of glycerol, or a kinase that includes the amino acid sequence represented by SEQ ID NO: 2 and exhibits a catalytic activity with respect to the phosphorylation of glycerol, in the presence of a phosphate group donor.</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES98404955" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001">TECHNICAL FIELD</heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to a method for the production of a phosphorylated glycerol with high efficiency.</p><heading id="h0002">BACKGROUND ART</heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">Since phosphorylated glycerol is highly useful, for example, as raw materials for cosmetics and as intermediates for producing pharmaceuticals, methods have been investigated in which a phosphorylated glycerol can be obtained with high efficiency. A method for achieving efficient phosphorylation is, for example, one involving the use of a phosphorylating enzyme that catalyzes the phosphorylation of glycerol. Many types of phosphorylating enzymes have been known until now, and there have been found those derived from many different species (Non-Patent Document 1). However, even though any of these many phosphorylating enzymes which exist is employed, the improvement in the efficiency of the phosphorylation reaction is not always accomplished. In addition, it is necessary that in reactions for obtaining a phosphorylated glycerol, a phosphorylating enzyme and glycerol are reacted in the presence of a phosphate group donor. Phosphorylating enzymes that have been used in the past, however, have a problem that expensive ATP (adenosine triphosphate) is required as a phosphate group donor in the reaction, thereby increasing production costs. Polyphosphoric acids, on the other hand, are mentioned as an example of an inexpensive phosphate group donor, but there have not been known any enzymes that<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> use a polyphosphoric acid to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction (see, for example, Non-Patent Document 2). Because of these backgrounds, these is a great need for a method by which a phosphorylated glycerol of great industrial usefulness is produced with high efficiency and at low cost.</p><heading id="h0003">PRIOR ART DOCUMENTS</heading><heading id="h0004">NON-PATENT DOCUMENTS</heading><p id="p0003" num="0003"><ul><li>Non-Patent Document 1: <nplcit id="ncit0001" npl-type="s"><text>Cell Mol Life Sci., 1998 Aug; 54(8): 833-50</text></nplcit></li><li>Non-Patent Document 2: <nplcit id="ncit0002" npl-type="s"><text>Protein Eng., 1998 Dec; 11(12): 1219-27</text></nplcit>.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0005">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading><heading id="h0006">PROBLEMS TO BE SOLVED BY THE INVENTION</heading><p id="p0004" num="0004">The present invention has a main purpose of providing a method for the phosphorylation of glycerol in which a high efficiency of phosphorylation can be achieved.</p><heading id="h0007">MEANS FOR SOLVING THE PROBLEM</heading><p id="p0005" num="0005">The inventors have made intensive studies to solve the above problem, with the result that it has been found that the efficiency of the phosphorylation of glycerol is significantly improved by using a phosphorylating enzyme derived from a particular microorganism. In addition, it has been found that by using this enzyme, a phosphorylated glycerol is efficiently obtained even when the phosphorylation reaction is performed using an inexpensive phosphate group donor like a polyphosphoric acid. Further, the inventors have identified the amino acid sequence responsible for the activity of the phosphorylating enzyme obtained from the particular microorganism.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> The present invention has been completed as a result of further improvements based on these findings.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">Thus, the present invention provides methods for phosphorylation according to the embodiments described below:
<ul><li>Embodiment 1: a method for the production of a phosphorylated glycerol, comprising a step of allowing a phosphorylating enzyme to act on glycerol in the presence of a phosphate group donor,<br/>
wherein the phosphorylating enzyme is a class A acid phosphatase and includes a polypeptide comprising as an active center an amino acid sequence represented by the sequence (1):<br/>
<br/>
        -X<sup>1</sup>-X<sup>2</sup>-X<sup>3</sup>-Pro-Ser-Gly-His-X<sup>4</sup>-     (1)<br/>
<br/>
wherein,
<ul><li>X<sup>1</sup> denotes glycine, alanine, or phenylalanine;</li><li>X<sup>2</sup> denotes any amino acid;</li><li>X<sup>3</sup> denotes tyrosine or tryptophan; and</li><li>X<sup>4</sup> denotes threonine, serine, or alanine;</li><li>with the proviso that when X<sup>1</sup> is phenylalanine, X<sup>4</sup> is threonine or serine.</li></ul></li><li>Embodiment 2: the method for production according to embodiment 1, wherein X<sup>1</sup> and X<sup>4</sup> in the sequence (1) are any of (A1) to (A8) below:
<ul><li>(A1) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</li><li>(A2) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine and X<sup>4</sup> being serine;</li><li>(A3) X<sup>1</sup> being alanine and X<sup>4</sup> being serine;</li><li>(A4) X<sup>1</sup> being alanine and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</li><li>(A5) X<sup>1</sup> being alanine and X<sup>4</sup> being alanine;<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></li><li>(A6) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine and X<sup>4</sup> being alanine;</li><li>(A7) X<sup>1</sup> being phenylalanine and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine; and</li><li>(A8) X<sup>1</sup> being phenylalanine and X<sup>4</sup> being serine.</li></ul></li><li>Embodiment 3: the method for production according to embodiment 1 or 2, wherein in the sequence (1), X<sup>2</sup> is serine, alanine, or aspartic acid.</li><li>Embodiment 4: the method for production according to embodiment 1 or 3, wherein X<sup>1</sup>, X<sup>2</sup>, X<sup>3</sup>, and X<sup>4</sup> in the sequence (1) are any of (B1) to (B11) below:
<ul><li>(B1) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</li><li>(B2) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being alanine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</li><li>(B3) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being serine;</li><li>(B4) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being aspartic acid, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</li><li>(B5) X<sup>1</sup> being alanine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being serine;</li><li>(B6) X<sup>1</sup> being alanine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</li><li>(B7) X<sup>1</sup> being alanine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being alanine;</li><li>(B8) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being alanine;</li><li>(B9) X<sup>1</sup> being phenylalanine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</li><li>(B10) X<sup>1</sup> being phenylalanine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being serine; and</li><li>(B11) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tryptophan, and X<sup>4</sup> being serine.</li></ul></li><li>Embodiment 5: the method for production according to any of embodiments 1 to 4, wherein the histidine (His) residue at the 7-th position in the amino acid sequence represented by the sequence (1) is located between positions 120 and 160 from the N-terminus of the polypeptide employed as the phosphorylating enzyme.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></li><li>Embodiment 6: the method for production according to any of embodiments 1 to 5, wherein the phosphorylating enzyme further includes a polypeptide as defined in (I) or (II) below:
<ul><li>including a polypeptide as defined in (II);
<ol><li>(I) a polypeptide that has the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2, on the N-terminal side of a stretch of the amino acid sequence coding for the active center represented by the sequence (1), or</li><li>(II) a polypeptide that comprises, on the N-terminal side of a stretch of the amino acid sequence coding for the active center represented by the sequence (1), an amino acid sequence having one or a few amino acids substituted, deleted, inserted, or added in the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2 and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction which is comparable or superior to that of the polypeptide as defined in (I).</li></ol></li></ul></li><li>Embodiment 7: the method for production according to embodiment 6, wherein the amino acid residue at the first position in the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2 is located between positions 5 and 40 from the N-terminus of the polypeptide employed as the phosphorylating enzyme.</li><li>Embodiment 8: the method for production according to any of embodiments 1 to 5, wherein the phosphorylating enzyme further includes any of the polypeptides as defined in (III) to (VI) below:
<ul><li>(III) a polypeptide that has the amino acid sequence set forth in any of SEQ ID NOs: 26 to 32 and 106 to 110, on the N-terminal side of the amino acid sequence represented by the sequence (1);</li><li>(IV) a polypeptide that has, on the N-terminal side of the amino acid sequence represented by the sequence (1), an amino acid sequence having one or several amino<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> acids substituted, deleted, inserted, or added in the amino acid sequence set forth in any of SEQ ID NOs: 26 to 32 and 106 to 110 and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction which is comparable or superior to that of its corresponding polypeptide as defined in (III);</li><li>(V) a polypeptide that has the amino acid sequence set forth in any of SEQ ID NOs: 33 to 39 and 111 to 115, on the C-terminal side of the amino acid sequence represented by the sequence (1); and</li><li>(VI) a polypeptide that has, on the C-terminal side of the amino acid sequence represented by the sequence (1), an amino acid sequence having one or several amino acids substituted, deleted, inserted, or added in the amino acid sequence set forth in any of SEQ ID NOs: 33 to 39 and 111 to 115 and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction which is comparable or superior to that of its corresponding polypeptide as defined in (V).</li></ul></li><li>Embodiment 9: the method for production according to any of embodiments 1 to 8, wherein the phosphorylating enzyme includes a polypeptide as defined in (VII) or (VIII) below:
<ul><li>(VII) a polypeptide that has the amino acid sequence set forth in any of SEQ ID NOs: 3 to 9, 13, 104, 105, 116, 117, and 119 to 121, or</li><li>(VIII) a polypeptide that includes an amino acid sequence having, in the amino acid sequence set forth in any of SEQ ID NOs: 3 to 9, 13, 104, 105, 116, 117, and 119 to 121, one or several amino acids substituted, deleted, inserted, or added in a region outside the active center including the amino acid sequence represented by the sequence (1) and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction which is comparable or superior to that of its corresponding polypeptide as defined in (VII).</li></ul></li><li>Embodiment 10: a method for the production of a phosphorylated glycerol, comprising<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> a step of allowing a phosphorylating enzyme to act on glycerol in the presence of a phosphate group donor,<br/>
wherein the phosphorylating enzyme is a class A acid phosphatase and includes a polypeptide as defined in (i) or (ii) below:
<ol><li>(i) a polypeptide that has the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2 and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction, or</li><li>(ii) a polypeptide that has an amino acid sequence having one or several amino acids substituted, deleted, inserted, or added in the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2 and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction which is comparable or superior to that of the polypeptide as defined in (i).</li></ol></li><li>Embodiment 11: the method for production according to embodiment 10, wherein the amino acid residue at the first position in the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2 is located between positions 5 and 40 from the N-terminus of the polypeptide employed as the phosphorylating enzyme.</li><li>Embodiment 12: the method for production according to embodiment 10 or 11, wherein the phosphorylating enzyme includes a polypeptide having, on the C-terminal side of the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2, an amino acid sequence represented by the sequence (1):
<ul><li>-X<sup>1</sup>-X<sup>2</sup>-X<sup>3</sup>-Pro-Ser-Gly-His-X<sup>4</sup>- (1)</li></ul>
wherein,
<ul><li>X<sup>1</sup> denotes glycine, alanine, or phenylalanine;</li><li>X<sup>2</sup> denotes any amino acid;</li><li>X<sup>3</sup> denotes tyrosine or tryptophan; and</li><li>X<sup>4</sup> denotes threonine, serine, or alanine;</li><li>with the proviso that when X<sup>1</sup> is phenylalanine, X<sup>4</sup> is threonine or serine.</li></ul><!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></li><li>Embodiment 13: the method for production according to embodiment 12, wherein X<sup>1</sup> and X<sup>4</sup> in the sequence (1) are any of (A1) to (A8) below:
<ul><li>(A1) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</li><li>(A2) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine and X<sup>4</sup> being serine;</li><li>(A3) X<sup>1</sup> being alanine and X<sup>4</sup> being serine;</li><li>(A4) X<sup>1</sup> being alanine and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</li><li>(A5) X<sup>1</sup> being alanine and X<sup>4</sup> being alanine;</li><li>(A6) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine and X<sup>4</sup> being alanine;</li><li>(A7) X<sup>1</sup> being phenylalanine and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine; and</li><li>(A8) X<sup>1</sup> being phenylalanine and X<sup>4</sup> being serine.</li></ul></li><li>Embodiment 14: the method for production according to embodiment 12 or 13, wherein in the sequence (1), X<sup>2</sup> is serine, alanine, or aspartic acid.</li><li>Embodiment 15: The method for production according to any of embodiments 12 to 14, wherein X<sup>1</sup>, X<sup>2</sup>, X<sup>3</sup>, and X<sup>4</sup> in the sequence (1) are any of (B1) to (B11) below:
<ul><li>(B1) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</li><li>(B2) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being alanine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</li><li>(B3) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being serine;</li><li>(B4) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being aspartic acid, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</li><li>(B5) X<sup>1</sup> being alanine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being serine;</li><li>(B6) X<sup>1</sup> being alanine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</li><li>(B7) X<sup>1</sup> being alanine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being alanine;</li><li>(B8) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being alanine;</li><li>(B9) X<sup>1</sup> being phenylalanine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --></li><li>(B10) X<sup>1</sup> being phenylalanine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being serine; and</li><li>(B11) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tryptophan, and X<sup>4</sup> being serine. Embodiment 16: the method for production according to any of embodiments 12 to 15, wherein the histidine (His) residue at the 7-th position in the amino acid sequence represented by the sequence (1) is located between positions 120 and 160 from the N-terminus of the polypeptide employed as the phosphorylating enzyme.</li></ul></li><li>Embodiment 17: the method for production according to any of embodiments 10 to 16, wherein the phosphorylating enzyme further comprises at least one of the amino acid sequences as defined in (iii) to (vi) below:
<ul><li>(iii) a polypeptide that has, on the N-terminal side of the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2, the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 40 and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction;</li><li>(iv) a polypeptide that has, on the N-terminal side of the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2, an amino acid sequence having one or a few amino acids substituted, deleted, inserted, or added in the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 40 and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction which is comparable or superior to that of the polypeptide as defined in (iii);</li><li>(v) a polypeptide that has, on the C-terminal side of the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2, the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 41 and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction; and</li><li>(vi) a polypeptide that has, on the C-terminal side of the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2, an amino acid sequence having one or a few amino acids substituted, deleted, inserted, or added in the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 41 and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction which is comparable or<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> superior to that of the polypeptide as defined in (v).</li></ul></li><li>Embodiment 18: the method for production according to any of embodiments 10 to 17, wherein the phosphorylating enzyme includes a polypeptide as defined in (vii) or (viii) below:
<ul><li>(vii) a polypeptide that has the amino acid sequence set forth in any of SEQ ID NOs: 9, 15 to 17, 19, 22, and 25; or</li><li>(viii) a polypeptide that includes an amino acid sequence having, in the amino acid sequence set forth in any of SEQ ID NOs: 9, 15 to 17, 19, 22, and 25, one or several amino acids substituted, deleted, inserted, or added in a region outside the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2 and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction which is comparable or superior to that of the polypeptide as defined in (vii).</li></ul></li><li>Embodiment 19: the method for production according to any of embodiments 1 to 18, wherein the phosphate group donor is a polyphosphoric acid.</li><li>Embodiment 20: the method for production according to any of embodiments 1 to 19, wherein the phosphorylated glycerol is α-glycerophosphate.</li><li>Embodiment 21: the method for production according to any of embodiments 1 to 20, wherein the pH of the reaction solution is from 4 to 5 in the step of allowing the phosphorylating enzyme to act on the glycerol in the presence of the phosphate group donor.</li><li>Embodiment 22: the method for production according to any of embodiments 1 to 21, wherein the glycerol is added in an amount of 1000 to 50000 parts by weight per part by weight of the phosphorylating enzyme, in the step of allowing the phosphorylating enzyme to act on the glycerol in the presence of the phosphate group donor.</li><li>Embodiment 23: the method for production according to any of embodiments 1 to 22,<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> wherein the concentration of the phosphate group donor in the reaction solution is from 2% to 10% by weight in the step of allowing the phosphorylating enzyme to act on the glycerol in the presence of the phosphate group donor.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0008">ADVANTAGES OF THE INVENTION</heading><p id="p0007" num="0007">According to the methods for phosphorylation according to the present invention, it is possible to significantly enhance the efficiency of the phosphorylation of glycerol. In addition, it is possible to use an inexpensive polyphosphoric acid as a phosphate group donor, thereby to allow reducing production costs.</p><heading id="h0009">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading><p id="p0008" num="0008"><ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> represents graphs showing the results of the phosphorylation of glycerol in which phosphorylating enzymes derived from various microorganisms were used. In <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, graph (i) shows the results when the reaction was carried out using 4 M of glycerol and at a pH of 5.0, graph (ii) shows the results when using 4 M of glycerol and at a pH of 4.0, and graph (iii) shows the results when using 0.5 M of glycerol and at a pH of 4.5.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> represents graphs showing the results of glycerol phosphorylating reactions in which the type of phosphate group donor was changed.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 3</figref> represents a graph showing the amount of the resulting glycerol-3-phosphate in which the glycerol phosphorylating reaction was performed using Mutant a.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 4</figref> represents a graph showing the amount of the resulting glycerol-3-phosphate in which the glycerol phosphorylating reaction was performed using Mutants b to g.<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">Figs. 5(i)</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0005">(ii)</figref> show the structures of phosphorylating enzyme mutants A to L in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 3</figref>. In <figref idrefs="f0002">Figs. 3(i) and (ii)</figref>, the mutated portion in the amino acid sequences of these mutants is underlined.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 6</figref> represents a graph showing the amount of the resulting glycerol-3-phosphate in which the glycerol phosphorylating reaction was performed using Mutants A to L.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0010">EMBODIMENTS OF THE INVENTION</heading><heading id="h0011"><u>1. Phosphorylating enzymes</u></heading><p id="p0009" num="0009">The present invention provides a method for the production of a phosphorylated glycerol. The method is characterized by allowing a given phosphorylating enzyme to act on glycerol in the presence of a phosphate group donor. present invention is Hereinafter, a method for the production of a phosphorylated glycerol according to the sometimes referred to simply as "a method of the present invention."</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">The glycerol to be phosphorylated in the present invention is represented by C<sub>3</sub>H<sub>8</sub>O<sub>3</sub> and is also referred to as 1,2,3-trihydroxypropane or glycerin.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">The method of the present invention uses as the phosphorylating enzyme a class A acid phosphatase, which catalyzes a glycerol phosphorylating reaction, thereby to obtain a phosphorylated glycerol. Here, an acid phosphatase is a phosphomonoesterase having a function of attaching free phosphate groups from other molecules. In addition, class A is a classification of acid phosphatases and indicates that enzymes of class A belong to a group of enzymes having the property that the<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> enzymatic activity is not inhibited by EDTA and by inorganic phosphates. Further, a class A acid phosphatase is defined as a generic term for enzymes having an amino acid sequence of KX<sub>6</sub>RP-(X<sub>12-54</sub>)-PSGH-(X<sub>31-54</sub>)-SRX<sub>5</sub>HX<sub>3</sub>D wherein each X independently denotes any amino acid (<nplcit id="ncit0003" npl-type="s"><text>The EMBO Journal, Vol 19, No. 11, pp 2412-2423</text></nplcit>).</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">Examples of the phosphorylating enzyme which can be used in the present invention include an enzyme according to embodiment (α), that is, a phosphorylating enzyme comprising the active center represented by the sequence (1) as indicated below, and an enzyme according to embodiment (β), that is, a phosphorylating enzyme comprising the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2. The following will describe each of these phosphorylating enzymes in detail.</p><heading id="h0012"><u>(1-1) Phosphorylating enzymes according to embodiment (α)</u></heading><p id="p0013" num="0013">An embodiment of the phosphorylating enzyme according to embodiment (α) which can be used in the method of the present invention includes a phosphorylating enzyme that comprises the active center including an amino acid sequence represented by the sequence (1) (SEQ ID NO: 1) as indicated below and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction:<br/>
<br/>
        -X<sup>1</sup>-X<sup>2</sup>-X<sup>3</sup>-Pro-Ser-Gly-His-X<sup>4</sup>-     (1)<br/>
<br/>
wherein,
<ul><li>X<sup>1</sup> denotes glycine, alanine, or phenylalanine;</li><li>X<sup>2</sup> denotes any amino acid;</li><li>X<sup>3</sup> denotes tyrosine or tryptophan; and</li><li>X<sup>4</sup> denotes threonine, serine, or alanine;</li><li>with the proviso that when X<sup>1</sup> is phenylalanine, X<sup>4</sup> is threonine or serine.</li></ul><!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></p><p id="p0014" num="0014">X<sup>2</sup> in the sequence (1) may be any amino acid and preferably is an uncharged amino acid, a non-polar amino acid, or an acidic amino acid, further preferably serine, alanine, or aspartic acid, with serine being particularly preferable.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">A specific embodiment of the phosphorylating enzyme which can be used in the method of the present invention is an enzyme in which X<sup>1</sup>, X<sup>2</sup>, and X<sup>4</sup> in the sequence (1) are any of (A1) to (A8) below:
<ul><li>(A1) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine; preferably X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, alanine, or aspartic acid, and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine; further preferably X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being alanine, and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</li><li>(A2) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine and X<sup>4</sup> being serine; preferably X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, and X<sup>4</sup> being serine;</li><li>(A3) X<sup>1</sup> being alanine and X<sup>4</sup> being serine; preferably X<sup>1</sup> being alanine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, and X<sup>4</sup> being serine;</li><li>(A4) X<sup>1</sup> being alanine and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine; preferably X<sup>1</sup> being alanine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</li><li>(A5) X<sup>1</sup> being alanine and X<sup>4</sup> being alanine; preferably X<sup>1</sup> being alanine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, and X<sup>4</sup> being alanine;</li><li>(A6) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine and X<sup>4</sup> being alanine; preferably X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, and X<sup>4</sup> being alanine;</li><li>(A7) X<sup>1</sup> being phenylalanine and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine; preferably X<sup>1</sup> being phenylalanine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine; and</li><li>(A8) X<sup>1</sup> being phenylalanine and X<sup>4</sup> being serine; preferably X<sup>1</sup> being phenylalanine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, and X<sup>4</sup> being serine.</li></ul><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --></p><p id="p0016" num="0016">Among these embodiments (A1) to (A8), the embodiment (A1) is preferable from the viewpoint that the phosphorylation of glycerol is performed with higher efficiency.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">A more specific embodiment of the phosphorylating enzyme which can be used in the method of the present invention is an enzyme in which X<sup>1</sup>, X<sup>2</sup>, and X<sup>4</sup> in the sequence (1) are any of (B1) to (B11) below:
<ul><li>(B1) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</li><li>(B2) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being alanine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</li><li>(B3) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being serine;</li><li>(B4) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being aspartic acid, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</li><li>(B5) X<sup>1</sup> being alanine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being serine;</li><li>(B6) X<sup>1</sup> being alanine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</li><li>(B7) X<sup>1</sup> being alanine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being alanine;</li><li>(B8) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being alanine;</li><li>(B9) X<sup>1</sup> being phenylalanine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</li><li>(B10) X<sup>1</sup> being phenylalanine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being serine; and</li><li>(B11) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tryptophan, and X<sup>4</sup> being serine.</li></ul></p><p id="p0018" num="0018">Among these embodiments (B1) to (B11), the embodiment (B1) is preferable from the viewpoint that the phosphorylation of glycerol is performed with higher<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --> efficiency.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">In the amino acid sequence of a class A acid phosphatase, the position where the active center is positioned is known; thus those skilled in the art would be able to determine where to place the active center represented by the sequence (1), as appropriate in the amino acid sequence of a phosphorylating enzyme to be used in the present invention.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">Additionally, in the amino acid sequence of a class A acid phosphatase, it is known that two active centers are present; the active center represented by the sequence (1) is located on the N-terminal side of these two active centers. The other of these two active centers, which is the active center located on the C-terminal side, usually has an amino acid sequence of RX<sub>5</sub>HX<sub>2</sub>S wherein each X independently denotes any amino acid, and is joined to the active center represented by sequence (1), usually via 20 to 50 amino acids, preferably via 30 to 40 amino acids, from the C-terminal end of the active center represented by the sequence (1).</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">Also in the amino acid sequence of a class A acid phosphatase, the amino acid sequences on both the N-terminal and C-terminal sides of the active center represented by the sequence (1) are known; thus those skilled in the art would be able to determine the amino acid sequence located outside the active center represented by the sequence (1), as appropriate in the amino acid sequence of a phosphorylating enzyme to be used in the present invention.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">The position of the active center represented by the sequence (1) in the entire<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> amino acid sequence of a phosphorylating enzyme according to embodiment (α) is not limited in particular, as long as the enzyme has an activity to catalyze the phosphorylation of glycerol. For example, the active center represented by the sequence (1) is placed at such a position that the histidine (His) residue at the 7-th position in the amino acid sequence represented by the sequence (1) is located between positions 120 and 160, preferably between positions 125 and 155, further preferably between positions 130 and 150, from the N-terminus of the polypeptide employed as the phosphorylating enzyme (class A acid phosphatase). In addition, the phosphorylating enzyme which is used in the method for producing a phosphorylated glycerol according to the present invention may have, besides the active center represented by the sequence (1), a histidine residue as a second active center at such a position that the histidine residue is located between positions 160 and 200, preferably between positions 165 and 195, further preferably between positions 170 and 190, from the N-terminus of the polypeptide employed as the phosphorylating enzyme.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">One embodiment of the phosphorylating enzyme which can be used in the present invention further includes a polypeptide as defined in (I) or (II) below:
<ol><li>(I) a polypeptide that has the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2, on the N-terminal side of a stretch of the amino acid sequence coding for the active center represented by the sequence (1), or</li><li>(II) a polypeptide that comprises, on the N-terminal side of a stretch of the amino acid sequence coding for the active center represented by the sequence (1), an amino acid sequence having one or a few amino acids substituted, deleted, inserted, or added in the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2 and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction which is comparable or superior to that of the<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> polypeptide as defined in (I).</li></ol></p><p id="p0024" num="0024">The amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2 specifically is:</p><heading id="h0013">PDERLVLAPPPAPGSAAQ (SEQ ID NO: 2)</heading><p id="p0025" num="0025">The amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2 may be joined directly to a stretch of the amino acid sequence coding for the active center represented by the sequence (1). Alternatively, the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2 may be joined to a stretch of the amino acid sequence coding for the active center represented by the sequence (1), for example, via 70 to 130 amino acids, preferably via 80 to 120 amino acids, further preferably via 90 to 110 amino acids, as long as the activity of the enzyme to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction is not disturbed. In addition, the phosphorylating enzyme according to embodiment (α) may comprise any amino acid sequence, for example, of 5 to 50 amino acids, preferably of 8 to 40 amino acids, further preferably of 10 to 30 amino acids, on the N-terminal side of the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2, as long as the activity of the enzyme to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction is not disturbed. Further, the phosphorylating enzyme according to embodiment (α) may comprise any amino acid sequence, for example, of 60 to 120 amino acids, preferably of 70 to 110 amino acids, further preferably of 80 to 100 amino acids, on the C-terminal side of a stretch of the amino acid sequence coding for the active center represented by the sequence (1), as long as the activity of the enzyme to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction is not disturbed.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">In the amino acid sequence in which a phosphorylating enzyme according to<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> embodiment (α) is composed, the position of the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2 is not limited in particular, as long as the enzyme has an activity to catalyze the phosphorylation of glycerol. For example, the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2 is placed at such a position that the first amino acid residue in the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2 is located between positions 5 and 40, preferably between positions 8 and 35, further preferably between positions 10 and 30, from the N-terminus of the polypeptide employed as the phosphorylating enzyme according to the embodiment (α).</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">In addition, in a polypeptide as defined in (II) above, the number of amino acids that are substituted, deleted, inserted, or added in the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2 is not limited in particular, with the proviso that the polypeptide has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction which is comparable or superior to that of the corresponding parent polypeptide. For example, the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2 has one or a few amino acids, or, for example, 1 to 10 amino acids, more preferably 1 to 8 amino acids, further preferably 1 to 5 amino acids, particularly preferably 1 to 3 amino acids, or 1 or 2 amino acids substituted, deleted, inserted, or added therein. Methods for obtaining mutants that have an amino acid(s) substituted, deleted, inserted, or added will be described in detail below in the section entitled "2. Preparation of phosphorylating enzymes."</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">In cases of adding an amino acid to a given amino acid sequence, the number of amino acids to be added is, for example, from 1 to 10, more preferably from 1 to 8, further preferably from 1 to 5, particularly preferably from 1 to 3, or 1 or 2. Furthermore, in addition to the added amino acid(s), a sequence for protein purification,<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> such as His tag, may optionally added at the C-terminus of the modified amino acid sequences.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">In cases of deleting an amino acid from a given amino acid sequence, the number of amino acids to be deleted is, for example, from 1 to 10, more preferably from 1 to 8, further preferably from 1 to 5, particularly preferably from 1 to 3, or 1 or 2.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">In cases of inserting an amino acid into a given amino acid sequence, the number of amino acids to be inserted is, for example, from 1 to 10, more preferably from 1 to 8, further preferably from 1 to 5, particularly preferably from 1 to 3, or 1 or 2.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">In cases of substituting an amino acid in a given amino acid, a conservative substitution can be made based on properties of the side-chain functional groups of amino acids. In addition, a non-conservative substitution may be made in which the property of an amino acid residue before the substitution is different from that of an amino acid residue after the substitution, as long as the resulting polypeptide has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction which is comparable or superior to that of the corresponding parent polypeptide. Natural amino acids are classified, based on their side-chain functional groups, into categories of non-polar amino acids, of non-charged amino acids, of acidic amino acids, and of basic amino acids. A conservative substitution refers to a substitution having an amino acid residue that belongs to the same category into which the parent amino acid residue and the substituted amino acid residue are classified. Here, a "non-polar amino acid" specifically includes alanine, valine, leucine, isoleucine, proline, methionine, phenylalanine, and tryptophan; a "non-charged amino acid" specifically includes<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> glycine, serine, threonine, cysteine, tyrosine, asparagine, and glutamine; an "acidic amino acid" specifically includes aspartic acid and glutamic acid; and a "basic amino acid" specifically includes lysine, arginine, and histidine.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">Further, another embodiment of the phosphorylating enzyme which can be used in the present invention includes any of the polypeptides as defined in (III) to (VI) below:
<ul><li>(III) a polypeptide that has the amino acid sequence set forth in any of SEQ ID NOs: 26 to 32 and 106 to 110, on the N-terminal side of the amino acid sequence represented by the sequence (1);</li><li>(IV) a polypeptide that has, on the N-terminal side of the amino acid sequence represented by the sequence (1), an amino acid sequence having one or several amino acids substituted, deleted, inserted, or added in the amino acid sequence set forth in any of SEQ ID NOs: 26 to 32 and 106 to 110 and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction which is comparable or superior to that of its corresponding polypeptide as defined in (III);</li><li>(V) a polypeptide that has the amino acid sequence set forth in any of SEQ ID NOs: 33 to 39 and 111 to 115, on the C-terminal side of the amino acid sequence represented by the sequence (1); and</li><li>(VI) a polypeptide that has, on the C-terminal side of the amino acid sequence represented by the sequence (1), an amino acid sequence having one or several amino acids substituted, deleted, inserted, or added in the amino acid sequence set forth in any of SEQ ID NOs: 33 to 39 and 111 to 115 and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction which is comparable or superior to that of its corresponding polypeptide as defined in (V).</li></ul><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --></p><p id="p0033" num="0033">SEQ ID NOs: 26 to 32, 106, and 107 correspond to the amino acid sequences on the N-terminal side of the active center represented by sequence (1), in SEQ ID NOs: 3 to 9, 104, and 105, respectively. The specific amino acid sequences set forth in SEQ ID NOs: 26 to 32, 106, and 107 are as indicated below.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">SEQ ID NO: 26:
<img id="ib0001" file="imgb0001.tif" wi="151" he="24" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></p><p id="p0035" num="0035">SEQ ID NO: 27:
<img id="ib0002" file="imgb0002.tif" wi="149" he="24" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></p><p id="p0036" num="0036">SEQ ID NO: 28:
<img id="ib0003" file="imgb0003.tif" wi="150" he="23" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></p><p id="p0037" num="0037">SEQ ID NO: 29:
<img id="ib0004" file="imgb0004.tif" wi="151" he="23" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></p><p id="p0038" num="0038">SEQ ID NO: 30:<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> -->
<img id="ib0005" file="imgb0005.tif" wi="152" he="24" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></p><p id="p0039" num="0039">SEQ ID NO: 31:
<img id="ib0006" file="imgb0006.tif" wi="151" he="24" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></p><p id="p0040" num="0040">SEQ ID NO: 32:
<img id="ib0007" file="imgb0007.tif" wi="151" he="23" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></p><p id="p0041" num="0041">SEQ ID NO: 106:
<img id="ib0008" file="imgb0008.tif" wi="151" he="24" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></p><p id="p0042" num="0042">SEQ ID NO: 107:
<img id="ib0009" file="imgb0009.tif" wi="151" he="24" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></p><p id="p0043" num="0043">SEQ ID NOs: 108 to 110 correspond to the amino acid sequences on the N-terminal side of the active center, in SEQ ID NOs: 10 to 12 representing the amino acid sequences of class A acid phosphatases. The specific amino acid sequences set forth in SEQ ID NOs: 108 to 110 are as indicated below.</p><p id="p0044" num="0044"><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --> SEQ ID NO: 108:
<img id="ib0010" file="imgb0010.tif" wi="150" he="23" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></p><p id="p0045" num="0045">SEQ ID NO: 109:
<img id="ib0011" file="imgb0011.tif" wi="151" he="23" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></p><p id="p0046" num="0046">SEQ ID NO: 110:
<img id="ib0012" file="imgb0012.tif" wi="151" he="23" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></p><p id="p0047" num="0047">SEQ ID NOs: 33 to 39, 111, and 112 correspond to the amino acid sequences on the C-terminal side of the active center represented by sequence (1), in SEQ ID NOs: 3 to 9, 104, and 105, respectively. The specific amino acid sequences set forth in SEQ ID NOs: 33 to 39, 111, and 112 are as indicated below.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048">SEQ ID NO: 33:
<img id="ib0013" file="imgb0013.tif" wi="151" he="15" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></p><p id="p0049" num="0049">SEQ ID NO: 34:
<img id="ib0014" file="imgb0014.tif" wi="150" he="23" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --></p><p id="p0050" num="0050">SEQ ID NO: 35:
<img id="ib0015" file="imgb0015.tif" wi="151" he="15" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></p><p id="p0051" num="0051">SEQ ID NO: 36:
<img id="ib0016" file="imgb0016.tif" wi="149" he="15" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></p><p id="p0052" num="0052">SEQ ID NO: 37:
<img id="ib0017" file="imgb0017.tif" wi="150" he="15" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></p><p id="p0053" num="0053">SEQ ID NO: 38:
<img id="ib0018" file="imgb0018.tif" wi="152" he="15" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></p><p id="p0054" num="0054">SEQ ID NO: 39:
<img id="ib0019" file="imgb0019.tif" wi="150" he="15" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></p><p id="p0055" num="0055">SEQ ID NO: 111:
<img id="ib0020" file="imgb0020.tif" wi="151" he="15" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></p><p id="p0056" num="0056">SEQ ID NO: 112:
<img id="ib0021" file="imgb0021.tif" wi="150" he="15" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></p><p id="p0057" num="0057">SEQ ID NOs: 113 to 115 correspond to the amino acid sequences on the C-terminal side of the active center, in SEQ ID NOs: 10 to 12 representing the amino acid sequences of class A acid phosphatases. The specific amino acid sequences set<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> forth in SEQ ID NOs: 113 to 115 are as indicated below.</p><p id="p0058" num="0058">SEQ ID NO: 113:
<img id="ib0022" file="imgb0022.tif" wi="151" he="14" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></p><p id="p0059" num="0059">SEQ ID NO: 114:
<img id="ib0023" file="imgb0023.tif" wi="150" he="15" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></p><p id="p0060" num="0060">SEQ ID NO: 115:
<img id="ib0024" file="imgb0024.tif" wi="151" he="15" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></p><p id="p0061" num="0061">In the present invention, a phosphorylating enzyme according to embodiment (α) may comprise a combination of the sequence (1), one selected from the N-terminal sequences (SEQ ID NOs: 26 to 32 and 106 to 110), and one selected from the C-terminal sequences (SEQ ID NOs: 33 to 39 and 111 to 115), as long as the activity of the enzyme to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction is not disturbed.</p><p id="p0062" num="0062">The same as in the above-described polypeptides as defined in (II) applies to polypeptides as defined in (IV) or (VI), for the number of amino acids to be substituted, deleted, inserted, or added, the type of amino acid to be substituted, and the like.</p><p id="p0063" num="0063">A phosphorylating enzyme according to embodiment (α) which can be used in the method of the present invention includes more specifically one including a polypeptide as defined in (VII) or (VIII) below:<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> -->
<ul><li>(VII) a polypeptide that has the amino acid sequence set forth in any of SEQ ID NOs: 3 to 9, 13, 104, 105, 116, 117, and 119 to 121, or</li><li>(VIII) a polypeptide that includes an amino acid sequence having, in the amino acid sequence set forth in any of SEQ ID NOs: 3 to 9, 13, 104, 105, 116, 117, and 119 to 121, one or several amino acids substituted, deleted, inserted, or added in a region outside the active center including the amino acid sequence represented by the sequence (1) and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction which is comparable or superior to that of its corresponding polypeptide as defined in (VII).</li></ul></p><p id="p0064" num="0064">The same as in the above-described polypeptides as defined in (II) applies to polypeptides as defined in (VIII), for the number of amino acids to be substituted, deleted, inserted, or added, the type of amino acid to be substituted, and the like. In addition, when an amino acid sequence in which one of these polypeptides is composed comprises a sequence corresponding to the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2, it is preferable that a mutation is introduced into a region outside of such a sequence.</p><p id="p0065" num="0065">In a method for producing a phosphorylated glycerol according to the present invention, the phosphorylating enzyme may be used alone by selecting one from among the above-described phosphorylating enzymes, or in combination of two or more of them.</p><heading id="h0014"><u>(1-2) Phosphorylating enzymes according to embodiment (β)</u></heading><p id="p0066" num="0066">An embodiment of the phosphorylating enzyme according to embodiment (β) which can be used in the method of the present invention includes one including a<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --> polypeptide as defined in (i) or (ii) below:
<ol><li>(i) a polypeptide that has the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2 and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction, or</li><li>(ii) a polypeptide that has an amino acid sequence having one or several amino acids substituted, deleted, inserted, or added in the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2 and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction which is comparable or superior to that of the polypeptide as defined in (i).</li></ol></p><p id="p0067" num="0067">The same as in the above-described polypeptides as defined in (II) applies to polypeptides as defined in (ii) above, for the number of amino acids to be substituted, deleted, inserted, or added, the type of amino acid to be substituted, and the like.</p><p id="p0068" num="0068">The amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2, and amino acid sequences having one or several amino acids substituted, deleted, inserted, or added in the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2 are a partial amino acid sequence that is located on the N-terminal side of the active center in the amino acid sequence of the phosphorylating enzyme. In the amino acid sequence of a phosphorylating enzyme according to embodiment (β), it is suitable that the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2 is located on the N-terminal side of the active center, including, in particular, embodiments in which the first amino acid residue in the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2 is located between positions 5 and 40, preferably between positions 8 and 35, further preferably between positions 10 and 30, from the N-terminus of the amino acid sequence of the phosphorylating enzyme.</p><p id="p0069" num="0069">In polypeptides as defined in (i) and (ii) above, the amino acid sequence of the<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --> active center is any amino acid sequence that is not limited in particular, with the proviso that it can serve as the active center of a class A acid phosphatase, and preferably is the amino acid sequence represented by the sequence (1) as described above. The amino acid sequence represented by the sequence (1) is as described above in the section entitled "(1-1) Phosphorylating enzymes according to embodiment (α)."</p><p id="p0070" num="0070">In polypeptides as defined in (i) and (ii) above, wherein the polypeptide comprises as the active center the amino acid sequence represented by the sequence (1), the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2 and a stretch of the amino acid sequence coding for the active center represented by the sequence (1) may be joined directly. Alternatively, they may be joined, for example, via 70 to 130 amino acids, preferably via 80 to 110 amino acids, further preferably via 90 to 110 amino acids, as long as the activity of the polypeptide to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction is not disturbed. In addition, polypeptides as defined in (i) and (ii) above may have any amino acid sequence, for example, of 5 to 50 amino acids, preferably of 8 to 40 amino acids, further preferably of 10 to 30 amino acids, on the N-terminal side of the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2, as long as the activity of the polypeptide to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction is not disturbed.</p><p id="p0071" num="0071">Further, polypeptides as defined in (i) and (ii) above may have any amino acid sequence, for example, of 60 to 120 amino acids, preferably of 70 to 110 amino acids, further preferably of 80 to 100 amino acids, on the C-terminal side of a stretch of the amino acid sequence coding for the active center, as long as the activity of the polypeptide to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction is not disturbed. In polypeptides as defined in (i) and (ii) above, the amino acid sequence on the C-terminal side of the active center may be similar to that on the C-terminal side of the active<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --> center of a class A acid phosphatase.</p><p id="p0072" num="0072">A phosphorylating enzyme according to embodiment (β) may further comprise at least one of the amino acid sequences as defined in (iii) to (vi) below:
<ul><li>(iii) a polypeptide that has, on the N-terminal side of the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2, the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 40 and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction;</li><li>(iv) a polypeptide that has, on the N-terminal side of the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2, an amino acid sequence having one or a few amino acids substituted, deleted, inserted, or added in the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 40 and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction which is comparable or superior to that of the polypeptide as defined in (iii);</li><li>(v) a polypeptide that has, on the C-terminal side of the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2, the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 41 and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction; and</li><li>(vi) a polypeptide that has, on the C-terminal side of the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2, an amino acid sequence having one or several amino acids substituted, deleted, inserted, or added in the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 41 and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction which is comparable or superior to that of the polypeptide as defined in (v).</li></ul></p><p id="p0073" num="0073">SEQ ID NO: 40 corresponds to the amino acid sequence in SEQ ID NO: 9 that is located on the N-terminal side of the amino acid sequence corresponding to SEQ ID NO: 2. SEQ ID NO: 41 corresponds to the amino acid sequence in SEQ ID NO: 9 that is located on the C-terminal side of the amino acid sequence corresponding to SEQ ID<!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --> NO: 2. The specific amino acid sequences of these are as indicated below.</p><p id="p0074" num="0074">SEQ ID NO: 40:<br/>
MDTSATAQGGILPDSAA</p><p id="p0075" num="0075">SEQ ID NO: 41:
<img id="ib0025" file="imgb0025.tif" wi="152" he="33" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></p><p id="p0076" num="0076">The same as in the above-described polypeptides as defined in (II) applies to polypeptides as defined in (iv) or (vi) above, for the number of amino acids to be substituted, deleted, inserted, or added, the type of amino acid to be substituted, and the like.</p><p id="p0077" num="0077">A phosphorylating enzyme according to embodiment (β) which can be used in the method of the present invention includes more specifically one including a polypeptide as defined in (vii) or (viii) below:
<ul><li>(vii) a polypeptide that has the amino acid sequence set forth in any of SEQ ID NOs: 9, 15 to 17, 19, 22, and 25; or</li><li>(viii) a polypeptide that includes an amino acid sequence having, in the amino acid sequence set forth in any of SEQ ID NOs: 9, 15 to 17, 19, 22, and 25, one or several amino acids substituted, deleted, inserted, or added in a region outside the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2 and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction which is comparable or superior to that of the polypeptide as<!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --> defined in (vii).</li></ul></p><p id="p0078" num="0078">The same as in the above-described polypeptides as defined in (II) applies to polypeptides as defined in (iv) or (vi) above, for the number of amino acids to be substituted, deleted, inserted, or added, the type of amino acid to be substituted, and the like.</p><p id="p0079" num="0079">In a method for producing a phosphorylated glycerol according to the present invention, the phosphorylating enzyme may be used alone by selecting one phosphorylating enzyme from among phosphorylating enzymes of one type, or alternatively in combination of two or more phosphorylating enzymes. In addition, a phosphorylating enzyme according to embodiment (α) and a phosphorylating enzyme according to embodiment (β) may be used in combination.</p><heading id="h0015"><u>2. Preparation of phosphorylating enzymes</u></heading><p id="p0080" num="0080">An enzyme as described above having a catalytic activity in a glycerol phosphorylating reaction can be obtained, for example, from a culture of a microorganism that possesses such an enzyme. Alternatively, an enzyme as described above having a catalytic activity in a glycerol phosphorylating reaction can be prepared as a recombinant protein in accordance with conventionally known methods, by obtaining a base sequence encoding such a phosphorylating enzyme of interest from a microorganism possessing the enzyme.</p><p id="p0081" num="0081">A phosphorylating enzyme including one of the amino acid sequences set forth in SEQ ID NOs: 3 to 9, 104, and 105 can be obtained from particular microorganisms as<!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --> described below, respectively.</p><p id="p0082" num="0082">Accordingly, a phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 3 is available from <i>Gluconacetobacter hansenii</i>. A phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 4 is available from <i>Xanthomonas oryzae</i>; a phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 5 is available from <i>Brevundimonas diminuta</i>; a phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 6 is available from <i>Sphingomonas trueperi</i>; a phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 7 is available from <i>Zymomonas mobilis;</i> a phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 8 is available from <i>Desulfovibrio magneticus</i>; a phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 9 is available from <i>Gluconobacter oxydans</i>. A phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 104 is available from <i>Serratia plymartica</i>. A phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 105 is available from <i>Rahnella aqaratilis</i>.</p><p id="p0083" num="0083">A phosphorylating enzyme including one of the amino acid sequences set forth in SEQ ID NOs: 3 to 9, 104, and 105 can be obtained by culturing the corresponding microorganism and treating cultured cells. To this end, more specifically, the methods described below are illustrated.</p><p id="p0084" num="0084">In cases when a phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 3 is obtained from cultured cells of <i>Gluconacetobacter hansenii</i>,<!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --> culture conditions can be set as appropriate from culture methods known for this microorganism, for example, including aerobic conditions at a culture temperature of 30°C in a medium containing 1% polypeptone, 0.2% dry yeast extract, and 0.1 % magnesium sulfate.</p><p id="p0085" num="0085">In cases when a phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 4 is obtained from cultured cells of <i>Xanthomonas oryzae</i>, culture conditions can be set as appropriate from culture methods known for this microorganism, for example, including aerobic conditions at a culture temperature of 30°C in a medium containing 1% polypeptone, 0.2% dry yeast extract, and 0.1% magnesium sulfate.</p><p id="p0086" num="0086">In cases when a phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 5 is obtained from cultured cells of <i>Brevundimonas diminuta</i>, culture conditions can be set as appropriate from culture methods known for this microorganism, for example, including aerobic conditions at a culture temperature of 30°C in a medium containing 1% polypeptone, 0.2% dry yeast extract, and 0.1% magnesium sulfate.</p><p id="p0087" num="0087">In cases when a phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 6 is obtained from cultured cells of <i>Sphingomonas trueperi</i>, culture conditions can be set as appropriate from culture methods known for this microorganism, for example, including aerobic conditions at a culture temperature of 26°C in a medium containing 5% peptone and 3% beef extract.</p><p id="p0088" num="0088"><!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --> In cases when a phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 7 is obtained from cultured cells of <i>Zymomonas mobilis,</i> culture conditions can be set as appropriate from culture methods known for this microorganism, for example, including aerobic conditions at a culture temperature of 30°C in a medium containing 0.5% dry yeast extract and 2% glucose.</p><p id="p0089" num="0089">In cases when a phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 8 is obtained from cultured cells of <i>Desulfovibrio magneticus</i>, culture conditions can be set as appropriate from culture methods known for this microorganism, for example, including anaerobic conditions at a culture temperature of 30°C in a medium containing 0.02% potassium dihydrogenphosphate, 60 ppm ammonium chloride, 50 ppm cysteine, 0.058% sodium fumarate, 0.044% sodium pyruvate, 0.2% iron quinate solution, 0.4% Wolfe's vitamin solution, and 0.2% Wolfe's mineral solution.</p><p id="p0090" num="0090">In cases when a phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 9 is obtained from cultured cells of <i>Gluconobacter oxydans</i>, culture conditions can be set as appropriate from culture methods known for this microorganism, for example, including aerobic conditions at a culture temperature of 30°C in a medium containing 0.5% polypeptone, 0.5% dry yeast extract, 0.5% glucose, and 0.1% magnesium sulfate.</p><p id="p0091" num="0091">In cases when a phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 104 is obtained from cultured cells of <i>Serratia plymutica</i>, culture conditions can be set as appropriate from culture methods known for this<!-- EPO <DP n="36"> --> microorganism, for example, including aerobic conditions at a culture temperature of 37°C in a medium containing 1% polypeptone, 0.2% dry yeast extract, and 0.1% magnesium sulfate.</p><p id="p0092" num="0092">In cases when a phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 105 is obtained from cultured cells of <i>Rahnella aquatilis</i>, culture conditions can be set as appropriate from culture methods known for this microorganism, for example, including aerobic conditions at a culture temperature of 30°C in a medium containing 1% polypeptone, 0.2% dry yeast extract, and 0.1% magnesium sulfate.</p><p id="p0093" num="0093">After the culturing is completed, usual methods for enzyme isolation can be employed to collect the phosphorylating enzyme from the culture. Methods for enzyme isolation include, for example, those in which cultured cells are disrupted by sonication to prepare a cell extract solution, followed by known methods for enzyme purification, such as ammonium sulfate fractionation, ion exchange, chromatofocusing, gel filtration, and the like. In addition, a cultured broth containing an enzyme secreted outside the cells may be used as an enzyme solution.</p><p id="p0094" num="0094">Also, a phosphorylating enzyme including one of the amino acid sequences set forth in SEQ ID NOs: 3 to 9, 104, and 105 can be prepared as a recombinant protein, which then can be used in the method of the present invention. In cases when the phosphorylating enzyme is obtained as a recombinant protein, the preparation of the recombinant protein can be performed based on known genetic engineering procedures. In usual cases, a phosphorylating enzyme can be produced as a recombinant protein by<!-- EPO <DP n="37"> --> inserting a polynucleotide (DNA fragment) encoding the amino acid sequence of a given phosphorylating enzyme into a vector, introducing the vector into a host cell to obtain a transformant, and culturing the transformant. The polynucleotide sequences that encodes phosphorylating enzymes including the amino acid sequences set forth in SEQ ID NOs: 3 to 9, 104, and 105 are represented by SEQ ID NOs: 94 to 100, 122, and 123, respectively. In such cases, a sequence derived from the vector, which is described below, may be incorporated into the polynucleotide, with the proviso that the sequence does not disturb the activity of the phosphorylating enzyme. In addition, the polynucleotide encoding the phosphorylating enzyme may be optimized so that the codon usage is adapted to that of the host cell to be used.</p><p id="p0095" num="0095">As a vector, use can be made of any vector that allows the expression of the gene encoded by the DNA fragment in an appropriate host cell. Such a vector includes, for example, a plasmid vector, a phage vector, a cosmid vector, a shuttle vector, and the like.</p><p id="p0096" num="0096">In the present invention, a vector may comprise a regulatory element(s) that is/are operably linked to a polynucleotide (DNA fragment) encoding an enzyme mutant of the present invention as described above, for example, a promoter, for example, a functional promoter such as a T7 promoter, a <i>lacUV5</i> promoter, a <i>trp</i> promoter, a <i>trc</i> promoter, a <i>tac</i> promoter, an <i>lpp</i> promoter, a <i>tufB</i> promoter, a <i>recA</i> promoter, and a pL promoter; a transcriptional element, for example, an enhancer, a CCAAT box, a TATA box, and an SPI site; a signal sequence, particularly a nuclear localization signal, an endoplasmic reticulum localization signal, PTS1 (Peroxisomal targeting signal 1), and PTS2; and others. Here, by operably linked, it is meant that various regulatory<!-- EPO <DP n="38"> --> elements such as a promoter and an enhancer that regulate the expression of a gene, and a given gene are linked in a state where they are allowed to operate within the host cell.</p><p id="p0097" num="0097">A vector to be used in the present invention can be selected as appropriate from among vectors commonly used in the art and can be used. Examples of such a vector includes, more specifically, pET22b(+), pET39b(+), and others.</p><p id="p0098" num="0098">Host cells are not limited in particular, as long as they can be transformed with an expression vector comprising a polynucleotide (DNA fragment) encoding an above-mentioned phosphorylating enzyme and allow the expression of the phosphorylating enzyme encoded by the polynucleotide.</p><p id="p0099" num="0099">Examples of such host cells include, more specifically, microorganisms, for example, bacteria of the genera <i>Escherichia</i>, <i>Bacillus</i>, <i>Pseudomonas</i>, <i>Serratia</i>, <i>Brevibacterium</i>, <i>Corynebacterium</i>, <i>Streptococcus</i>, <i>Lactobacillus</i> and the like; actinomycetes of the genera <i>Rhodococcus</i>, <i>Streptomyces</i>, and the like; yeasts of the genera <i>Saccharomyces</i>, <i>Kluyveromyces</i>, <i>Schizosaccharomyces</i>, <i>Zygosaccharomyces</i>, <i>Yarrowia</i>, <i>Trichosporon</i>, <i>Rhodosporidium</i>, <i>Pichia</i>, <i>Candida,</i> and the like; fungi of the genera <i>Neurospora</i>, <i>Aspergillus</i>, <i>Cephalosporiarm</i>, <i>Trichoderma</i>, and the like; and the others. Among these, bacteria is preferred from the viewpoint of the efficiency of introduction of genes into host cells and of gene expression. Cells of <i>Escherichia coli,</i> a bacterium of the genus <i>Escherichia</i>, are preferable.</p><p id="p0100" num="0100">Methods for transformation are known and can be selected as appropriate, depending on the type of host cell to be transformed and others. Examples of methods<!-- EPO <DP n="39"> --> for transformation specifically include methods using competent cells, electroporation, heat shock, or the like.</p><p id="p0101" num="0101">Transformants can be cultured, based on conventionally known culture conditions, depending on the type of cell used as host cell. In cases when <i>Escherichia coli</i> cells are used as host cell, for example, culture conditions can be a culture temperature of 20 to 40°C, a culture period of 6 to 24 hours, and a pH of the culture medium of 5 to 8 under aerobic conditions, for example, by shaking culture or aeration culture.</p><p id="p0102" num="0102">A culture medium that is to be used in the present invention is not limited in particular, as long as it allows the host cell to grow and to produce an enzyme mutant of the present invention. Use can be made of media usually employed in the art which contain required amounts of a carbon source, a nitrogen source, inorganic substances, amino acids, nucleic acids, vitamins, and others. In addition, an antibiotic such as ampicillin or tetracycline may be added to the medium as necessary, during the culturing period.</p><p id="p0103" num="0103">Methods for collecting the phosphorylating enzyme of interest after the culturing is completed may follow the procedures for collecting the phosphorylating enzyme from cultured cells as previously described.</p><p id="p0104" num="0104">Introduction of a mutation (substitution, deletion, insertion, and/or addition) into a given amino acid sequence can be carried out according to conventionally known methods. Methods for introducing an amino acid mutation include, for example,<!-- EPO <DP n="40"> --> site-directed mutagenesis, which can be performed by using Inverse PCR-based procedures or commercially available kits, such as QuikChange II Kit (manufactured by Stratagene). These approaches make it possible to obtain a polynucleotide encoding a phosphorylating enzyme having a desired mutation, based on the base sequences set forth in SEQ ID NOs: 94 to 100, 122, and 123. A phosphorylating enzyme mutant can be prepared as a recombinant protein by using the resulting polynucleotide and following known genetic engineering procedures similar to the above.</p><p id="p0105" num="0105">A phosphorylating enzyme that includes a polypeptide having a mutation as described above includes one in which the amino acid sequence identity of such a polypeptide to the corresponding polypeptide before the mutation is introduced is 20% or higher, preferably 30% or higher, further preferably 40% or higher and which is capable of catalyzing the glycerol phosphorylating reaction at a level comparable or superior to that of the phosphorylating enzyme including the corresponding polypeptide before the mutation is introduced.</p><p id="p0106" num="0106">The sequence identity between two polypeptides is expressed as a numerical value obtained by optimally aligning the two polypeptide to be compared, dividing the number of positions at which amino acids are identical in both sequences by the total number of the amino acids compared, and multiplying the quotient by 100. Specifically, the sequence identity between two polypeptide can be determined by using a Maximum matching program, "GENETYX Ver. 10" (GENETYX CORPORATION).</p><heading id="h0016"><u>3. Phosphorylation of glycerol</u></heading><p id="p0107" num="0107">In a method for phosphorylating glycerol according to the present invention,<!-- EPO <DP n="41"> --> the phosphorylation reaction can be carried out by adding glycerol, a phosphate group donor, and an above-described phosphorylating enzyme to a solvent to prepare a reaction composition. Alternatively, the phosphorylation of glycerol may be performed by allowing a culture of an above-described microorganism or transformant that is capable of producing an above-described phosphorylating enzyme to act on glycerol in the presence of a phosphate group donor.</p><p id="p0108" num="0108">In the method of the present invention, a culture means a cultured broth containing cells, a cultured cell mass, or a treated material thereof. Here, a treated material thereof means, for example, a cell-free extract, a freeze-dried cell preparation, an acetone-dried cell preparation, or a disrupted material of these cell preparations. Such cultures can also be used as an immobilized enzyme or cell preparation. Immobilization can be performed using methods well known to those skilled in the art, for example, covalent bonding, physical adsorption, entrapment, and the like.</p><p id="p0109" num="0109">A phosphate group donor is not limited in particular, as long as it functions as a source of the phosphate for an enzyme mutant of the present invention, whereby a phosphorylated glycerol is yielded, and includes, for example, a polyphosphoric acid represented by formula (1): H<sub>n+2</sub>P<sub>n</sub>O<sub>3n+1</sub>, wherein n ≥ 2. The degree of polymerization of the polyphosphoric acid is not limited in particular, and preferably 2 to 10000 structural units described above are polymerized, further preferably 2 to 1000 structural units described above are polymerized. Examples of a polyphosphoric acid specifically include diphosphoric acid (n = 2; pyrophosphoric acid), triphosphoric acid (n = 3), tetraphosphoric acid (n = 4), and the like. It is also possible that in the formula (1), polyphosphoric acids in which 5 or more phosphoric acid groups are polymerized<!-- EPO <DP n="42"> --> (n = 5 or more) are suitably used as a phosphate group donor. A mixture of two or more of these polyphosphoric acids with different degrees of polymerization may be used as a phosphate group donor.</p><p id="p0110" num="0110">Further, as a phosphate group donor which can be used in the present invention, use can also be made of esters, salts with alkali metals such as sodium and potassium, salts with alkaline earth metals such as calcium, and ammonium salts of the polyphosphoric acid described above. Examples of esters of polyphosphoric acids specifically include adenosine diphosphate (ADP), adenosine triphosphate (ATP), and others. Examples of salts of polyphosphoric acids specifically include sodium pyrophosphate (Na<sub>4</sub>P<sub>2</sub>O<sub>7</sub>), sodium tripolyphosphate (Na<sub>5</sub>P<sub>3</sub>O<sub>10</sub>), potassium tripolyphosphate (K<sub>5</sub>P<sub>3</sub>O<sub>10</sub>), sodium tetrapolyphosphate (Na<sub>6</sub>P<sub>4</sub>O<sub>13</sub>), sodium hexametaphosphate, ammonium pyrophosphate salt, ammonium tripolyphosphate salt, and others. Moreover, a phosphate group donor includes para-nitrophenyl phosphate, acetyl phosphate, and the like, in addition to the polyphosphoric acid described above.</p><p id="p0111" num="0111">In the present invention, the phosphate group donor preferably includes polyphosphoric acids, such as diphosphoric acid, triphosphoric acid, and tetraphosphoric acid; esters of polyphosphoric acids, such as adenosine diphosphate (ADP) and adenosine triphosphate (ATP); alkali metal salts of polyphosphoric acids, such as sodium pyrophosphate, sodium tripolyphosphate, potassium tripolyphosphate, sodium tetrapolyphosphate, and sodium hexametaphosphate; para-nitrophenyl phosphate and acetyl phosphate. More preferably, the phosphate group donor includes polyphosphoric acids, and esters and alkali metal salts thereof. Further preferably, the phosphate group donor includes polyphosphoric acids and alkali metal salts thereof,<!-- EPO <DP n="43"> --> with polyphosphoric acids being preferable from the viewpoint that they are available at low cost. These phosphate group donors may be used alone or in combination of two or more.</p><p id="p0112" num="0112">Examples of the concentration at which a phosphorylating enzyme is used in the reaction include 0.0001% to 5% by weight, preferably 0.001% to 1% by weight, further preferably 0.001% to 0.5% by weight, in the reaction composition. Examples of the concentration of a phosphate group donor include 0.5% to 20% by weight, preferably 1% to 15% by weight, further preferably 2% to 10% by weight. Examples of the concentration of glycerol include 0.1% to 80% by weight, preferably 1% to 60% by weight, further preferably 5% to 50% by weight.</p><p id="p0113" num="0113">Examples of the addition ratio of a phosphate group donor per part by weight of a phosphorylating enzyme (polypeptide) include 100 to 30000 parts by weight, preferably 250 to 20000 parts by weight, further preferably 500 to 15000 parts by weight. Examples of the addition ratio of glycerol per part by weight of a phosphorylating enzyme (polypeptide) include 100 to 100000 parts by weight, preferably 500 to 70000 parts by weight, further preferably 1000 to 50000 parts by weight.</p><p id="p0114" num="0114">Examples of the reaction temperature at which the phosphorylation reaction is carried out include 10 to 60°C, preferably 20 to 50°C, further preferably 30 to 40°C.</p><p id="p0115" num="0115">Examples of the optimal pH of the reaction solution when the phosphorylation reaction is carried out include pH 2 to 7, preferably pH 4 to 6, more preferably pH 3 to 5,<!-- EPO <DP n="44"> --> further preferably pH 4 to 5. The pH of the reaction solution can be adjusted using hydrochloric acid, citric acid, gluconic acid, succinic acid, acetic acid, tartaric acid, sorbic acid, lactic acid, maleic acid, sulfuric acid, phosphoric acid, malic acid, arginine, aqueous ammonia, diisopropanolamine, diethanolamine, triisopropanolamine, triethanolamine, monoethanolamine, potassium hydroxide, calcium hydroxide, sodium hydroxide, and buffering agents such as salts thereof, and conventionally known buffering agents.</p><p id="p0116" num="0116">The reaction period when the phosphorylation reaction is carried out is not limited in particular, as long as a phosphorylated glycerol can be produced, and for example, is 1 to 50 hours, preferably 5 to 40 hours, further preferably 10 to 30 hours.</p><p id="p0117" num="0117">As a reaction solvent, an aqueous solvent, such as ion-exchanged water, distilled water, and ultrapure water can be used in usual cases. In addition, an aqueous solvent may contain an organic solvent such as methanol, trimethylamine, triethylamine, and dimethyl sulfoxide (DMSO), or a non-ionic surfactant such as polyoxyethylene lauryl ether, polyoxyethylene dodecyl ether, polyethylene glycol p-octylphenyl ether (whose trade name is Triton X-100), and polyoxyethylene sorbitan monolaurate (whose trade name is Tween 20), in a range in which advantageous effects of the present invention are not inhibited.</p><p id="p0118" num="0118">Examples of amounts of an organic solvent added are usually 0.1% to 50% by weight, preferably 1% to 30% by weight, further preferably 5% to 20% by weight. Examples of amounts of a non-ionic surfactant added are usually 0.0001% to 0.1% by weight, preferably 0.0005% to 0.05% by weight, further preferably 0.001% to 0.01% by<!-- EPO <DP n="45"> --> weight.</p><p id="p0119" num="0119">Methods for collecting a phosphorylated glycerol yielded in the above-described reaction can be, for example, methods using various types of column chromatography, such as ion-exchange chromatography, affinity chromatography, adsorption column chromatography, gel filtration chromatography, and reverse phase chromatography, and methods by which the phosphorylated glycerol is precipitated by the addition of an organic solvent such as ethanol or acetonitrile.</p><p id="p0120" num="0120">In cases when the glycerol phosphorylating reaction is performed under conditions in amounts of 5000 to 50000 parts by weight of glycerol per part by weight of a phosphorylating enzyme (polypeptide) and at a pH of 4 to 6, the phosphorylating enzyme (polypeptide) used includes, for example, a phosphorylating enzyme including one of the amino acid sequences set forth in SEQ ID NOs: 3 to 9, 104, and 105, or a mutant thereof, preferably a phosphorylating enzyme including one of the amino acid sequences set forth in SEQ ID NOs: 4 to 8, or a mutant thereof, further preferably a phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 4, or a mutant thereof.</p><p id="p0121" num="0121">In a method for producing a phosphorylated glycerol according to the present invention, it is possible to achieve a further higher efficiency of the phosphorylation by adjusting conditions for the phosphorylation reaction and selecting an appropriate phosphorylating enzyme. For example, when the glycerol phosphorylating reaction is performed under conditions in amounts of 5000 to 50000 parts by weight of glycerol per part by weight of a phosphorylating enzyme (polypeptide) and at a pH of 3 to 5, the<!-- EPO <DP n="46"> --> phosphorylating enzyme (polypeptide) used includes, for example, a phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 3, 4, 8, or 9, or a mutant thereof, further preferably a phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 4, or a mutant thereof.</p><p id="p0122" num="0122">Further, when the glycerol phosphorylating reaction is performed under conditions in amounts of 2000 to 10000 parts by weight of glycerol per part by weight of a phosphorylating enzyme (polypeptide) and at a pH of 4 to 5, the phosphorylating enzyme (polypeptide) used includes, for example, a phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 3, 5, or 9, or a mutant thereof, further preferably a phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 3, or a mutant thereof.</p><p id="p0123" num="0123">In the method of the present invention, the hydroxyl group position at which the phosphate group is attached is not limited in particular, as long as glycerol is phosphorylated. A specific example of the phosphorylated glycerol yielded in the method of the present invention is glycerol-3-phosphate (also referred to as glycerophosphate). Glycerophosphate occurs in the α and β forms; the glycerophosphate obtained by method of the present invention can include either of these forms. Preferably, the method of the present invention yields glycerophosphate in the α form. In examples described below, it has been found that glycerol-3-phosphate in the α form (also referred to as α-glycerophosphate) is predominantly produced.</p><heading id="h0017">EXAMPLES</heading><p id="p0124" num="0124"><!-- EPO <DP n="47"> --> The present invention will be more specifically described presenting experimental examples below, which are not intended to limit the present invention thereto.</p><heading id="h0018">[Preparation of phosphorylating enzymes]</heading><heading id="h0019"><u>Obtaining of genes for phosphorylating enzymes</u></heading><p id="p0125" num="0125">Genomic DNA was prepared from each strain of the microorganism indicated below in Table 1 and a gene for a phosphorylating enzyme was amplified by PCR method using primers corresponding to the respective strains of the microorganisms.<!-- EPO <DP n="48"> -->
<tables id="tabl0001" num="0001"><table frame="all"><title>[Table 1]</title><tgroup cols="6"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="51mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="64mm"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="34mm"/><colspec colnum="4" colname="col4" colwidth="21mm"/><colspec colnum="5" colname="col5" colwidth="13mm"/><colspec colnum="6" colname="col6" colwidth="61mm"/><thead><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">SEQ ID NO: of the amino acid sequence of the phosphoryl ating enzyme</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">SEQ ID NO: of the base sequence of a gene encoding the phosphorylating enzyme</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">Derived from</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">Primer SEQ ID NO:</entry><entry namest="col5" nameend="col6" align="center" valign="middle">Primer sequence (5' to 3')</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">3</entry><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">94</entry><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">Gluconacetobacter hansenii</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">42</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">FW</entry><entry valign="middle">TGCAC<u>CCATGG</u>ACGCAGGGTATCTAACACCTGCGAC</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">43</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">RV</entry><entry valign="middle">CAAT<u>AAGCTT</u>GAGCGGAGAATGGGCCGCAGCATCATG</entry></row><row><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">4</entry><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">95</entry><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">Xanthomonas oryzae</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">44</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">FW</entry><entry valign="middle">GATC<u>GCCATGG</u>ACGCGCATGGATACCTGGAAAAG</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">45</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">RV</entry><entry valign="middle">TTCC<u>AAGCTT</u>CATCACACCAGGCAACACCGTCTTC</entry></row><row><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">5</entry><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">96</entry><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">Brevundimonas diminuta</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">46</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">FW</entry><entry valign="middle">AGCTT<u>CCATGG</u>ATCATCCGCACGGCTATCTGACCGCC</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">47</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">RV</entry><entry valign="middle">ATCA<u>AAGCTT</u>CTGACGCGCCAGCGAGGCGGGGCAGG</entry></row><row><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">6</entry><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">97</entry><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">Sphingomonas trueperi</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">48</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">FW</entry><entry valign="middle">TCAGG<u>CCATGG</u>CACGGCGCCGTACCTCGCCG</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">49</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">RV</entry><entry valign="middle">AAGA<u>AAGCTT</u>GGGGCGGACGCGAAGGGCCTCCGC</entry></row><row><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">7</entry><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">98</entry><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">Zymomonas mobilis</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">50</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">FW</entry><entry valign="middle">TCTGG<u>CCATGG</u>ATCTTTCTCAAAGCGTTTCAGCT</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">51</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">RV</entry><entry valign="middle">TATG<u>AAGCTT</u>GCGAGCGCTTTGTTCAATCTTGC</entry></row><row><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">8</entry><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">99</entry><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">Desulfovibrio magneticus</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">52</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">FW</entry><entry valign="middle">TAT<u>GGATCC</u>GCAGCTGGCCTGGTCCGAAACGCAGTTC</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">53</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">RV</entry><entry valign="middle">CCTC<u>AAGCTT</u>CTGGGCCAGACCCAGGGCGCTGCGGACTT</entry></row><row><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">9</entry><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">100</entry><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">Gluconobacter oxydans</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">54</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">FW</entry><entry valign="middle">TAACGC<u>CCATGG</u>ATACGTCCGCTACCGCCCAAGGCGGC</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">55</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">RV</entry><entry valign="middle">AACA<u>AAGCTT</u>TTCGCTGAGCAGGGAATGGATCGCGGC</entry></row><row><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">10</entry><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">101</entry><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">Flavobacterium johnsoniae</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">56</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">FW</entry><entry valign="middle">CTTAGA<u>CCATGG</u>ATGCATTGCTGGATGGATATTTG</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">57</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">RV</entry><entry valign="middle">CCAT<u>AAGCTT</u>AGCTCCTGCCATTTCTTTTTTAACCT</entry></row><row><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">11</entry><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">102</entry><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">Methylobacterium ectorquens</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">58</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">FW</entry><entry valign="middle">TACGTT<u>CCATGG</u>ATTCCGCCCCCTCGCTCGAGAAGGA</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">59</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">RV</entry><entry valign="middle">ATCC<u>AAGCTT</u>GAGCAGGGGCTGGCGCGCGGCCGCAT</entry></row><row><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">12</entry><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">103</entry><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">Acetobacter pasteurianus</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">60</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">FW</entry><entry valign="middle">CTTAGA<u>CCATGG</u>ATAGCAGCCTTTTTGGATATACC</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">61</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">RV</entry><entry valign="middle">AAGT<u>AAGCTT</u>AAAAGCGTCTTGCGCAGCCTGCTGTTC</entry></row><row><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">104</entry><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">122</entry><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">Serratia plymutica</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">124</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">FW</entry><entry valign="middle">GCTG<u>CCACCATGG</u>ATACCGGGCCGACGGTAACGGAC</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">125</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">RV</entry><entry valign="middle">GATC<u>AAGCTT</u>GTGCATACTCAAAGAGAGTGCAAC</entry></row><row><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">105</entry><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">123</entry><entry morerows="1" align="center" valign="middle">Rahnella aquatilis</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">126</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">FW</entry><entry valign="middle">GTTCAGG<u>CCATGG</u>AAGAAGCCAAACCCTTTATCACC</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">127</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">RV</entry><entry valign="middle">ACGA<u>AAGCTT</u>TTTCAGGCCAGATTGGGCGCGAAG</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></tables></p><heading id="h0020"><u>Preparation of transformants</u></heading><p id="p0126" num="0126">For SEQ ID NOs: 3 to 7, 9 to 12, 104, and 105, the resultant PCR product was digested with restriction enzymes (<i>Nco</i>I and <i>Hind</i>III), and ligated into a pET22b(+) vector (Novagen) treated with <i>Nco</i>I/<i>Hind</i>III restriction enzymes to obtain a vector for<!-- EPO <DP n="49"> --> expression of the encoded phosphorylating enzyme. For SEQ ID NO: 8, the resultant PCR product was digested with restriction enzymes (<i>Bam</i>HI and <i>Hind</i>III), and ligated into a pET22b(+) vector (Novagen) treated with <i>Bam</i>HI/<i>Hind</i>III restriction enzymes to obtain a vector for expression of the encoded phosphorylating enzyme. These vectors further carry, besides a region encoding the phosphorylating enzyme, a T7 promoter, a <i>pel</i>B signal for transport of the expressed protein into the periplasm, a His-tag gene for protein purification, and an ampicillin resistance gene for selection with a drug. The vector obtained by the above-described procedures was transformed into cells of an <i>Escherichia coli</i> (<i>E. coli</i>) BL21(DE3) strain (Novagen) by heat shock method.</p><heading id="h0021"><u>Preparation of phosphorylating enzymes</u></heading><p id="p0127" num="0127">Culturing of transformant cells of an <i>E. coli</i> BL21(DE3) strain carrying the vector for expression of the encoded phosphorylating enzyme was performed by incubating them at a culture temperature of 27°C in an LB medium (manufactured by Nacalai Tesque, Inc. and having a composition of 1% by weight of tryptone, 0.5% by weight of dry yeast extract, 0.5% by weight of sodium chloride) containing 0.2% by weight of glucose, 0.5% by weight of casamino acid, and 0.1 mg/mL of ampicillin. When the optical density of the culture at 600 nm reached 0.5, isopropyl-β-thiogalactopyranoside was added to a concentration of 0.1 mM and additional culturing was performed at a culture temperature of 27°C for a period of 16 to 24 hours.</p><p id="p0128" num="0128">After the culture was completed, 15 g of wet cells was suspended in 20 mM Tris-HCl buffer (pH 8.0) containing 150 mM sodium chloride, and then subjected to an ultrasonic homogenizer (TOMY UD201) to obtain a cell extract solution. The cell<!-- EPO <DP n="50"> --> extract solution was subjected to centrifugation at 20,000 × g for 20 minutes to collect the supernatant fraction. To the supernatant, ammonium sulfate was added to a saturation of 60%, followed by centrifugation at 20,000 × g for 20 minutes to collect a precipitate. The precipitate after the ammonium sulfate fractionation was suspended in 20 mM Tris-HCl buffer (pH 7.5), and then dialyzed against 20 mM Tris-HCl buffer (pH 7.5) containing 50 mM sodium chloride. After the dialysis was completed, affinity purification was carried out using a His-Trap HP column. Fractions containing the phosphorylating enzyme were collected, and then subjected to dialysis against 20 mM Tris-HCl buffer (pH 7.5) to obtain the phosphorylating enzyme. Conditions for the affinity purification were as follows.</p><heading id="h0022"><u>Purification conditions for phosphorylating enzymes</u></heading><p id="p0129" num="0129"><ul><li>Column: His-Trap HP (manufactured by GE healthcare)</li><li>Equilibration buffer: 20 mM Tris-HCl (pH 7.5), 50 mM sodium chloride</li><li>Elution buffer: 20 mM Tris-HCl (pH 7.5), 50 mM sodium chloride, 1 M imidazole</li><li>(elution in a gradient of the elution buffer from 0 to 50%)</li><li>Flow rate: 5.0 mL/min</li><li>Purification equipment: AKTA prime plus (GE healthcare)</li></ul></p><p id="p0130" num="0130">The amino acid sequence and position of the active center of the phosphorylating enzymes obtained are indicated in Table 2.<!-- EPO <DP n="51"> -->
<tables id="tabl0002" num="0002"><table frame="all"><title>[Table 2]</title><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="67mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="50mm"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="49mm"/><thead><row><entry valign="middle">Amino acid sequence of the phosphorylating enzyme</entry><entry valign="middle">Amino acid sequence of the active center</entry><entry valign="middle">Position of the active center</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry valign="middle">SEQ ID NO: 3</entry><entry valign="middle">Gly Ala Tyr Pro Ser Gly His Thr</entry><entry valign="middle">Positions 130 to 137 in SEQ ID NO: 3</entry></row><row><entry valign="middle">SEQ ID NO: 4</entry><entry valign="middle">Gly Ser Tyr Pro Ser Gly His Thr</entry><entry valign="middle">Positions 131 to 138 in SEQ ID NO: 4</entry></row><row><entry valign="middle">SEQ ID NO: 5</entry><entry valign="middle">Gly Ser Tyr Pro Ser Gly Ilis Ser</entry><entry valign="middle">Positions 131 to 138 in SEQ ID NO: 5</entry></row><row><entry valign="middle">SEQ ID NO: 6</entry><entry valign="middle">Gly Asp Tyr Pro Ser Gly His Thr</entry><entry valign="middle">Positions 125 to 132 in SEQ ID NO: 6</entry></row><row><entry valign="middle">SEQ ID NO: 7</entry><entry valign="middle">Gly Ser Tyr Pro Ser Gly His Thr</entry><entry valign="middle">Positions 142 to 149 in SEQ ID NO: 7</entry></row><row><entry valign="middle">SEQ ID NO: 8</entry><entry valign="middle">Ala Ser Tyr Pro Ser Gly His Ser</entry><entry valign="middle">Positions 134 to 141 in SEQ ID NO: 8</entry></row><row><entry valign="middle">SEQ ID NO: 9</entry><entry valign="middle">Ala Ser Tyr Pro Ser Gly His Thr</entry><entry valign="middle">Positions 134 to 141 in SEQ ID NO: 9</entry></row><row><entry valign="middle">SEQ ID NO: 10</entry><entry valign="middle">Gly Ser Phe Pro Ser Gly His Ala</entry><entry valign="middle">Positions 133 to 140 in SEQ ID NO: 10</entry></row><row><entry valign="middle">SEQ ID NO: 11</entry><entry valign="middle">Phe Ser Tyr Pro Ser Gly His Ala</entry><entry valign="middle">Positions 144 to 151 in SEQ ID NO: 11</entry></row><row><entry valign="middle">SEQ ID NO: 12</entry><entry valign="middle">Tyr Ala Tyr Pro Ser Gly Ilis Thr</entry><entry valign="middle">Positions 135 to 142 in SEQ ID NO: 12</entry></row><row><entry valign="middle">SEQ ID NO: 104</entry><entry valign="middle">Gl y Ser Trp Pro Ser Gl y His Ser</entry><entry valign="middle">Positions 143 to 150 in SEQ ID NO: 104</entry></row><row><entry valign="middle">SEQ ID NO: 105</entry><entry valign="middle">Gly Ser Trp Pro Ser Gly His Ser</entry><entry valign="middle">Positions 123 to 130 in SEQ ID NO: 105</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></tables></p><heading id="h0023">[Experimental Example 1]</heading><p id="p0131" num="0131">The microorganism-derived phosphorylating enzymes obtained as described above (which are represented by SEQ ID NOs: 3 to 12, 104, and 105) were used to phosphorylate glycerol. Conditions for and results of the glycerol phosphorylating reaction are indicated below.</p><heading id="h0024"><u>Phosphorylation of glycerol</u></heading><p id="p0132" num="0132">To ultrapure water were added glycerol (4 M or 0.5 M), a polyphosphoric acid as a phosphate group donor (4% by weight; manufactured by Nacalai Tesque, Inc. under a trade name of polyphosphoric acid), and Triton X-100 (0.1% by weight), to prepare a reaction mixture solution. When glycerol was used at a concentration of 4 M, the pH<!-- EPO <DP n="52"> --> of the solution was adjusted to pH 4.0 or 5.0 with KOH; and when glycerol was used at a concentration of 0.5 M, the pH of the solution was adjusted to pH 4.5 with KOH. Further, the phosphorylating enzyme including one of the amino acid sequences set forth in SEQ ID NOs: 3 to 12, 104, and 105 was added to the reaction mixture solution to make a final concentration of 20 µg/mL. The reaction solution was subjected to reaction in a temperature-controlled air incubator at 37°C overnight. After that, a 0.1-mL sample of the reaction solution was taken and diluted 50 to 500 times in 50 mM PIPES buffer (pH 7.0). The concentration of glycerol-3-phosphate in the sample was detected by an enzymatic method using glycerol-3-phosphate dehydrogenase under the conditions described below.</p><heading id="h0025"><u>Detection method for glycerol-3-phosphate</u></heading><p id="p0133" num="0133">Glycerol-3-phosphate dehydrogenase and potassium ferricyanide were mixed with 50 mM PIPES buffer (pH 7.0) to make final concentrations of 10 U/mL and 2 mM, respectively. To 0.9 mL of this measurement solution was added a 0.1-mL sample of the reaction solution after the phosphorylation reaction, to prepare a reaction mixture, which then was subjected to measurement of the rate of decrease in the absorbance at 420 nm, for 3 minutes at 37°C. A standard curve was prepared from the rates of decrease in the absorbance obtained by using known concentrations of glycerol-3-phosphate, and used to calculate the concentration of glycerol-3-phosphate produced. The results are shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>. In <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, graph (i) shows the results when the reaction was carried out using 4 M glycerol and at a pH of 5.0, graph (ii) shows the results when using 4 M glycerol and at a pH of 4.0, and graph (iii) shows the results when using 0.5 M glycerol and at a pH of 4.5. The absorbance of 50 mM PIPES buffer (pH 7.0) was measured as a control (indicated as "Buffer" in the figure).<!-- EPO <DP n="53"> --></p><heading id="h0026"><u>Results</u></heading><p id="p0134" num="0134">From <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1(i)</figref>, it was found that when the reaction was carried out using 4 M glycerol and at a pH of 5.0, the phosphorylation of glycerol using the phosphorylating enzymes including the respective amino acid sequences set forth in SEQ ID NOs: 3 to 9, 104, and 105 resulted in a significantly high phosphorylation efficiency, relative to the other phosphorylating enzymes. It was also found that among these phosphorylating enzymes, the phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 4 produced a particularly high amount of glycerol-3-phosphate and has an enhanced phosphorylation action on glycerol under these conditions. From these results, it turned out that a class A acid phosphatase having as the active center an amino acid sequence represented by the sequence (1) as described above can be utilized as a glycerol-phosphorylating enzyme.</p><p id="p0135" num="0135">From <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1(ii)</figref>, it was found that when the reaction was carried out using 4 M glycerol and at a pH of 4.0, the phosphorylation of glycerol using the phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 3, 4, 8, or 9, resulted in a significantly high phosphorylation efficiency, relative to the other phosphorylating enzymes. It was also found that among these phosphorylating enzymes, the phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 4 produced a particularly high amount of glycerol-3-phosphate and has an enhanced phosphorylation action on glycerol under these conditions.</p><p id="p0136" num="0136">From <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1(iii)</figref>, it was found that when the reaction was carried out using 0.5 M glycerol and at a pH of 4.5, the phosphorylation of glycerol using the<!-- EPO <DP n="54"> --> phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 3, 5, or 9, resulted in a high phosphorylation efficiency, relative to the other phosphorylating enzymes. It was found that in particular, the phosphorylation of glycerol using the phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 3 resulted in a significantly high phosphorylation efficiency.</p><heading id="h0027">[Experimental Example 2]</heading><heading id="h0028"><u>Examination of phosphate group donors</u></heading><p id="p0137" num="0137">The efficiency of the phosphorylation of glycerol by phosphorylating enzymes (SEQ ID NOs: 3 to 6 and 8) was examined by changing the type of phosphate group donor. As a phosphate group donor, use was made of sodium pyrophosphate, sodium tripolyphosphate, sodium tetrapolyphosphate, potassium tripolyphosphate, sodium hexametaphosphate, or polyphosphoric acid. The polyphosphoric acid used was a polyphosphoric acid manufactured by Nacalai Tesque, Inc. The concentration of a phosphate group donor was set to be 0.2 M, except that the polyphosphoric acid was set to be at 7.5% by weight. A phosphorylating enzyme (phosphorylating enzyme set forth in SEQ ID NO: 3 to 6 or 8; 0.02 mg/mL each), a substrate (glycerol; at a concentration of 1 M), and a phosphate group donor were added to ultrapure water to prepare a reaction solution. The pH of the reaction solution was adjusted to a pH of 5.0 with potassium hydroxide or acetic acid. The reaction was carried out at 37°C for 24 hours. After the reaction was completed, the amount of glycerol-3-phosphate produced was measured by an enzymatic method using glycerol-3-phosphate dehydrogenase as in Experimental Example 1. The results are shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>.</p><p id="p0138" num="0138">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>, it was found that the phosphorylated glycerol was obtained<!-- EPO <DP n="55"> --> when any of the phosphate group donors was used. Particularly, the phosphorylating enzyme set forth in SEQ ID NO: 3 allowed the production of the phosphorylated product with higher efficiency by using sodium tripolyphosphate, sodium tetrapolyphosphate, potassium tripolyphosphate, sodium hexametaphosphate, or polyphosphoric acid as the phosphate group donor.</p><p id="p0139" num="0139">The phosphorylating enzyme set forth in SEQ ID NO: 4 allowed the production of the phosphorylated product with higher efficiency by using sodium hexametaphosphate or polyphosphoric acid as the phosphate group donor.</p><p id="p0140" num="0140">The phosphorylating enzyme set forth in SEQ ID NO: 5 allowed the production of the phosphorylated product with higher efficiency by using sodium tripolyphosphate, potassium tripolyphosphate, or polyphosphoric acid as the phosphate group donor.</p><p id="p0141" num="0141">The phosphorylating enzyme set forth in SEQ ID NO: 6 allowed the production of the phosphorylated product with higher efficiency by using sodium tripolyphosphate, sodium tetrapolyphosphate, potassium tripolyphosphate, sodium hexametaphosphate, or polyphosphoric acid as the phosphate group donor.</p><p id="p0142" num="0142">The phosphorylating enzyme set forth in SEQ ID NO: 8 allowed the production of the phosphorylated product with higher efficiency by using sodium tripolyphosphate, potassium tripolyphosphate, or polyphosphoric acid as the phosphate group donor.</p><heading id="h0029">[Experimental Example 3]</heading><heading id="h0030"><u>Phosphorylation of glycerol by phosphorylating enzyme mutants</u></heading><!-- EPO <DP n="56"> --><heading id="h0031"><u>(3-1) A mutant having mutations introduced in the vicinity of the active center -1</u></heading><heading id="h0032">(Introduction of mutations and generation of transformants)</heading><p id="p0143" num="0143">Mutations were introduced into a phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 11 that did not have any detectable activity to phosphorylate glycerol, to generate an enzyme mutant, Mutant a. The generation procedure is indicated below.</p><p id="p0144" num="0144">To obtain Mutant a, PCR reactions were performed using as a template a base sequence encoding the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 11, and combinations of the primers indicated in Table 3. The resulting PCR product was digested with the restriction enzymes described corresponding to the column of Mutant in Table 3. Ligation was performed between a pET22b(+) vector (Novagen) treated with the same restriction enzymes as those with which the PCR product had been treated and the restriction enzyme-treated PCR product, to obtain a vector for expression of the encoded glycerol-phosphorylating enzyme. The vector further carry, besides the base sequence encoding Mutant a, a T7 promoter, a <i>pel</i>B signal for transport of the expressed protein into the periplasm, a His-tag gene for protein purification, and an ampicillin resistance gene for selection with a drug. The vector obtained by the above-described procedures was transformed into cells of an <i>Escherichia coli</i> (<i>E. coli</i>) BL21(DE3) strain (Novagen) by heat shock method.</p><p id="p0145" num="0145">The primer sets and restriction enzyme sites used for the generation of Mutant a, and the base sequences of the primers are indicated in Tables 3 and 4, respectively. In Table 3, "F144G/A151T" in Mutant a, in the column of Mutant, indicates that the<!-- EPO <DP n="57"> --> phenylalanine residue at position 144 in SEQ ID NO: 11 was replaced with a glycine residue and the alanine residue at position 151 was replaced with a threonine residue.
<tables id="tabl0003" num="0003"><table frame="all"><title>[Table 3]</title><tgroup cols="4"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="57mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="28mm"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="40mm"/><colspec colnum="4" colname="col4" colwidth="42mm"/><thead><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">SEQ ID NO: of (the whole amino acid sequence of) mutant</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">Mutant</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">Primer set</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">Restriction enzyme site</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">13</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">a (F144G/A151T)</entry><entry valign="middle">Primers (1) and (4); Primers (3) and (2)</entry><entry valign="middle"><i>Nco</i>I and <i>Bam</i>HI; <i>Bam</i>HI and <i>Hind</i>III</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></tables>
<tables id="tabl0004" num="0004"><table frame="all"><title>[Table 4]</title><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="31mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="20mm"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="88mm"/><thead><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">Primer SEQ ID NO:</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">Primer No.</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">Sequence (5' to 3')</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">62</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">(1)</entry><entry valign="middle">TACGTT<u>CCATGG</u>ATTCCGCCCCCTCGCTCGAGAAGGA</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">63</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">(2)</entry><entry valign="middle">ATCC<u>AAGCTT</u>GAGCAGGGGCTGGCGCGCGGCCGCAT</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">64</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">(3)</entry><entry valign="middle">AGC<u>GGATCC</u>TATCCCTCCGGTCATACTAGCCAGGGG</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">65</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">(4)</entry><entry valign="middle">ATA<u>GGATCC</u>GCTGTCCGCGAGTTCGGCCGTGCG</entry></row></tbody></tgroup><tgroup cols="3" rowsep="0"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="31mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="20mm"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="88mm"/><tbody><row><entry namest="col1" nameend="col3" align="justify">* In Table 4, the underlined sequences indicate a restriction enzyme cleavage site.</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></tables></p><heading id="h0033">(Culturing of transformants)</heading><p id="p0146" num="0146">Culturing of transformant cells of an <i>E. coli</i> BL21(DE3) strain carrying the vector for expression of the encoded glycerol-phosphorylating enzyme was performed by incubating them at a culture temperature of 27°C in an LB medium (manufactured by Nacalai Tesque, Inc. and having a composition of 1% by weight of tryptone, 0.5% by weight of dry yeast extract, 0.5% by weight of sodium chloride) containing 0.2% by weight of glucose, 0.5% by weight of casamino acid, and 0.1 mg/mL of ampicillin. When the optical density of the culture at 600 nm reached 0.5,<!-- EPO <DP n="58"> --> isopropyl-β-thiogalactopyranoside was added to be 0.1 mM and additional culturing was performed at a culture temperature of 27°C for a period of 16 to 24 hours.</p><heading id="h0034">(Obtaining of a glycerol-phosphorylating enzyme mutant)</heading><p id="p0147" num="0147">After the culture was completed, 15 g of wet cells was suspended in 20 mM Tris-HCl buffer (pH 8.0) containing 150 mM sodium chloride, and then subjected to an ultrasonic homogenizer (TOMY UD201) to obtain a cell extract solution. The cell extract solution was subjected to centrifugation at 20,000 x g for 20 minutes to collect the supernatant fraction. To the supernatant, ammonium sulfate was added to a saturation of 60%, followed by centrifugation at 20,000 x g for 20 minutes to collect a precipitate. The precipitate after the ammonium sulfate fractionation was suspended in 20 mM Tris-HCl buffer (pH 7.5), and then dialyzed against 20 mM Tris-HCl buffer (pH 7.5) containing 50 mM sodium chloride. After the dialysis was completed, affinity purification was carried out using a His-Trap HP column. Fractions containing the glycerol-phosphorylating enzyme were collected, and then subjected to dialysis against 20 mM Tris-HCl buffer (pH 7.5) to obtain the glycerol-phosphorylating enzyme mutant. The amino acid sequences of the active center of the phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 11 and the enzyme mutant, Mutant a, are indicated in Table 5.
<tables id="tabl0005" num="0005"><table frame="all"><title>[Table 5]</title><tgroup cols="2"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="40mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="60mm"/><thead><row><entry valign="middle"/><entry valign="middle">Amino acid sequence of the active center</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry valign="middle">SEQ ID NO: 11</entry><entry valign="middle">Phe Ser Tyr Pro Ser Gly His Ala</entry></row><row><entry valign="middle">Mutant a (F144G/A151T)</entry><entry valign="middle">Gly Ser Tyr Pro Ser Gly His Thr</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></tables><!-- EPO <DP n="59"> --></p><heading id="h0035"><u>Purification conditions</u></heading><p id="p0148" num="0148">Conditions for the affinity purification were as follows.
<ul><li>Column: His-Trap HP (manufactured by GE healthcare)</li><li>Equilibration buffer: 20 mM Tris-HCl (pH 7.5), 50 mM sodium chloride</li><li>Elution buffer: 20 mM Tris-HCl (pH 7.5), 50 mM sodium chloride, 1 M imidazole</li><li>(elution in a gradient of the elution buffer from 0 to 50%)</li><li>Flow rate: 5.0 mL/min</li><li>Purification equipment: AKTA prime plus (GE healthcare)</li></ul></p><heading id="h0036">(Phosphorylation of glycerol using a glycerol-phosphorylating enzyme mutant, Mutant a)</heading><p id="p0149" num="0149">The glycerol phosphorylating reaction was performed using Mutant a, which is the glycerol-phosphorylating enzyme obtained as described above. To ultrapure water were added glycerol (4 M) and a polyphosphoric acid as a phosphate group donor (7.5% by weight; manufactured by Nacalai Tesque, Inc. under a trade name of polyphosphoric acid), to prepare a reaction mixture solution. The pH of the reaction solution was adjusted to a pH of 5.0 with KOH. The phosphorylating enzyme, Mutant a, was added to the reaction mixture solution to make a final concentration of 50 µg/mL. The reaction solution was subjected to reaction in a temperature-controlled air incubator at 37°C for 24 hours. The concentration of glycerol-3-phosphate in the sample was detected by an enzymatic method using glycerol-3-phosphate dehydrogenase. The phosphorylation of glycerol and detection of glycerol-3-phosphate were carried out as in Experimental Example 1. The results are shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 3</figref>.</p><p id="p0150" num="0150">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 3</figref>, it was observed that Mutant a having F144G/A151T<!-- EPO <DP n="60"> --> mutations introduced in the phosphorylating enzyme set forth in SEQ ID NO: 11 that had an extremely low level of phosphorylating enzyme activity resulted in a significant improvement in the enzyme activity.</p><heading id="h0037"><u>(3-2) Mutants having mutations introduced in the vicinity of the active center - 2</u></heading><p id="p0151" num="0151">Mutations were introduced into a phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 11 that did not have any detectable activity to phosphorylate glycerol, to generate enzyme mutants, Mutants b to g. Generation procedures for Mutants b to g were as described above in (3-1), except for using as a template a base sequence (set forth in SEQ ID NO: 128) in which a (wild-type) base sequence encoding the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 11 was codon optimized for expression in <i>E. coli</i> and using the primers indicated in Tables 6 and 7.<!-- EPO <DP n="61"> -->
<tables id="tabl0006" num="0006"><table frame="all"><title>[Table 6]</title><tgroup cols="4"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="56mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="28mm"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="42mm"/><colspec colnum="4" colname="col4" colwidth="40mm"/><thead><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">SEQ ID NO: of (the whole amino acid sequence of) mutant</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">Mutant</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">Primer set</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">Restriction enzyme site</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">116</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">b (F144A)</entry><entry valign="middle">Primers (5) and (7); Primers (8) and (6)</entry><entry valign="middle"><i>Nco</i>I and <i>Nhe</i>I; <i>Nhe</i>I and <i>Hind</i>III</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">117</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">c (F144G)</entry><entry valign="middle">Primers (5) and (9); Primers (10) and (6)</entry><entry valign="middle"><i>Nco</i>I and <i>BamHI</i>; <i>BamHI</i> and <i>Hind</i>III</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">118</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">d (A151D)</entry><entry valign="middle">Primers (5) and (11); Primers (12) and (6)</entry><entry valign="middle"><i>Nco</i>I and <i>Nde</i>I; <i>Nde</i>I and <i>Hind</i>III</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">119</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">e (A151T)</entry><entry valign="middle">Primers (5) and (13); Primers (11) and (6)</entry><entry valign="middle"><i>Nco</i>I and <i>Nde</i>I; <i>Nde</i>I and <i>Hind</i>III</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">120</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">f (A151S)</entry><entry valign="middle">Primers (5) and (14); Primers (15) and (6)</entry><entry valign="middle"><i>Nco</i>I and <i>Nde</i>I; <i>Nde</i>I and <i>Hind</i>III</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">121</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">g (F144G/A151S)</entry><entry valign="middle">Primers (5) and (9); Primers (15) and (6)</entry><entry valign="middle"><i>Nco</i>I and <i>BamHI</i>; <i>BamHI</i> and <i>Hind</i>III</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></tables><!-- EPO <DP n="62"> -->
<tables id="tabl0007" num="0007"><table frame="all"><title>[Table 7]</title><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="31mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="20mm"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="94mm"/><thead><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">Primer SEQ ID NO:</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">Primer No.</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">Sequence (5' to 3')</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">129</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">(5)</entry><entry valign="middle">GGCGATGGCCATGGACAGTGCCCCGAGTCTGGAA</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">130</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">(6)</entry><entry valign="middle">TAAAGAAGCTTCAGCAGCGGTTGACGGGCAGC</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">131</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">(7)</entry><entry valign="middle">ACTCGGATAGCTAGCGCTGTCCGCCAGTTCAGC</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">132</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">(8)</entry><entry valign="middle">GCGGACAGCGCTAGCTATCCGAGTGGTCATGCGTCCCAG</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">133</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">(9)</entry><entry valign="middle">AATAGGATCCGCTGTCCGCCAGTTCAGCGGT</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">134</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">(10)</entry><entry valign="middle">GACAGAGGATCCTATCCGAGTGGTCATGCGTCCCAGGGT</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">135</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">(11)</entry><entry valign="middle">GATCAGACCATATGCCCAACCCTGGGAGTCATGACCACT</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">136</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">(12)</entry><entry valign="middle">CAGGGTTGGGCATATGGTCTGATCATGGCAAAC</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">137</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">(13)</entry><entry valign="middle">GATCAGACCATATGCCCAACCCTGGGACGTATGACCACT</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">138</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">(14)</entry><entry valign="middle">GATCAGACCATATGCCCAACCCTGGGAGCTATGACCACT</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">139</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">(15)</entry><entry valign="middle">GACAGAGGATCCTATCCGAGTGGTCATTCGTCCCAGGGT</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></tables></p><p id="p0152" num="0152">The amino acid sequences of the active center of the phosphorylating enzyme including the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 11 and the enzyme mutants, Mutants b to g, are indicated in Table 8.
<tables id="tabl0008" num="0008"><table frame="all"><title>[Table 8]</title><tgroup cols="2"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="41mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="60mm"/><thead><row><entry valign="middle"/><entry valign="middle">Amino acid sequence of the active center</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry valign="middle">SEQ ID NO: 11</entry><entry valign="middle">Phe Ser Tyr Pro Ser Gly His Ala</entry></row><row><entry valign="middle">Mutant b (F 144A)</entry><entry valign="middle">Ala Ser Tyr Pro Ser Gly His Ala</entry></row><row><entry valign="middle">Mutant c (F 144G)</entry><entry valign="middle">Gly Ser Tyr Pro Ser Gly His Ala</entry></row><row><entry valign="middle">Mutant d (A151D)</entry><entry valign="middle">Phe Ser Tyr Pro Ser Gly His Asp</entry></row><row><entry valign="middle">Mutant e (A151T)</entry><entry valign="middle">Phe Ser Tyr Pro Ser Gly His Thr</entry></row><row><entry valign="middle">Mutant f (A151S)</entry><entry valign="middle">Phe Ser Tyr Pro Ser Gly His Ser</entry></row><row><entry valign="middle">Mutant g (F144G/A151 S)</entry><entry valign="middle">Gly Ser Tyr Pro Ser Gly His Ser</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></tables></p><p id="p0153" num="0153"><!-- EPO <DP n="63"> --> Culturing of transformants, obtaining of glycerol-phosphorylating enzyme mutants, and phosphorylation of glycerol were performed in the same conditions as those described above in (3-1).</p><p id="p0154" num="0154">The results obtained are shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 4</figref>. From these results, it was observed that Mutant d had little detectable activity to phosphorylate glycerol, while Mutants b, c, and e to g exhibited a superior activity to phosphorylate glycerol. Also from these results, it turned out that a class A acid phosphatase having as the active center an amino acid sequence represented by the sequence (1) as described above can be utilized as a glycerol-phosphorylating enzyme.</p><heading id="h0038"><u>(3-2) Mutants having mutations introduced in an N-terminal portion</u></heading><p id="p0155" num="0155">Mutants A to L were generated in which an N-terminal portion of the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 12 was replaced with a partial sequence comprised of the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 9, by means of using as a template a DNA sequence encoding the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 12. Generation procedures were as in Mutants a to d described above in (3-1), and PCR products were obtained using the primer sets and template indicated below in Table 9. The PCR product was treated with restriction enzymes corresponding to the restriction enzyme sites described for the respective mutants in Table 9, and inserted into a vector. The structures of Mutants A to L are shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 5(i)</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0005">(ii)</figref>.</p><p id="p0156" num="0156">Combinations of the primer sets, restriction enzyme sites, and templates used for the generation of Mutants A to L having mutations introduced in an N-terminal portion are shown in Table 9, and the base sequences of the primers are shown in Table<!-- EPO <DP n="64"> --> 10. In Table 9, the description "A143-E244" in Mutant A, for example, in the column of Mutant, indicates that the amino acid sequence corresponding to positions 144 to 242 in SEQ ID NO: 12 was replaced with the corresponding amino acid sequence of from the alanine at position 143 to the glutamic acid at position 244 in SEQ ID NO: 9.
<tables id="tabl0009" num="0009"><table frame="all"><title>[Table 9]</title><tgroup cols="5"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="23mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="24mm"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="33mm"/><colspec colnum="4" colname="col4" colwidth="33mm"/><colspec colnum="5" colname="col5" colwidth="54mm"/><thead><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">SEQ ID NO: of mutant</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">Mutant</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">Primer set</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">Restriction enzyme site</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">Template used</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">14</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">A (A143-E244)</entry><entry valign="middle">Primers (1) and (6); Primers (5) and (4)</entry><entry valign="middle"><i>Nco</i>I and <i>Pst</i>I; <i>Pst</i>I and <i>Hind</i>III</entry><entry valign="middle">a plasmid encoding SEQ ID NO: 12; a plasmid encoding SEQ ID NO: 9</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">15</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">B (M1-A143)</entry><entry valign="middle">Primers (3) and (8); Primers (7) and (2)</entry><entry valign="middle"><i>Nco</i>I and <i>Pst</i>I; <i>Pst</i>I and <i>Hind</i>III</entry><entry valign="middle">a plasmid encoding SEQ ID NO: 9; a plasmid encoding SEQ ID NO: 12</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">16</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">C (M1-P122)</entry><entry valign="middle">Primers (3) and (10); Primers (9) and (2)</entry><entry valign="middle"><i>Nco</i>I and <i>Nhe</i>I; <i>Nhe</i>I and <i>Hind</i>III</entry><entry valign="middle">a plasmid encoding SEQ ID NO: 9; a plasmid encoding SEQ ID NO: 12</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">17</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">D (M1-R70)</entry><entry valign="middle">Primers (3) and (12); Primers (11) and (2)</entry><entry valign="middle"><i>Nco</i>I and <i>Sal</i>I; <i>Xho</i>I and <i>Hind</i>III</entry><entry valign="middle">a plasmid encoding SEQ ID NO: 9; a plasmid encoding SEQ ID NO: 12</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">18</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">E (S126-A143)</entry><entry valign="middle">Primers (1) and (14); Primers (13) and (2)</entry><entry valign="middle"><i>Nco</i>I and <i>Spe</i>I; <i>Spe</i>I and <i>Hind</i>III</entry><entry valign="middle">a plasmid encoding SEQ ID NO: 9; a plasmid encoding SEQ ID NO: 12</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">19</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">F (P18-R70)</entry><entry valign="middle">Primers (1) and (16); Primers (15) and (2)</entry><entry valign="middle"><i>Nco</i>I and <i>Spe</i>I; <i>Spe</i>I and <i>Hind</i>III</entry><entry valign="middle">a plasmid encoding SEQ ID NO: 9; a plasmid encoding Mutant D</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">20</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">G (A29-R70)</entry><entry valign="middle">Primers (1) and (18); Primers (17) and (2)</entry><entry valign="middle"><i>Nco</i>I and <i>Pst</i>I; <i>Pst</i>I and <i>Hind</i>III</entry><entry valign="middle">a plasmid encoding SEQ ID NO: 9; a plasmid encoding Mutant D</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">21</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">H (R53-R70)</entry><entry valign="middle">Primers (1) and (20); Primers (19) and (2)</entry><entry valign="middle"><i>Nco</i>I and <i>Nhe</i>I; <i>Nhe</i>I and <i>Hind</i>III</entry><entry valign="middle">a plasmid encoding SEQ ID NO: 9; a plasmid encoding Mutant D</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">22</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">I (M1-P52)</entry><entry valign="middle">Primers (3) and (22); Primers (21) and (2)</entry><entry valign="middle"><i>Nco</i>I and <i>Nhe</i>I; <i>Nhe</i>I and <i>Hind</i>III</entry><entry valign="middle">a plasmid encoding SEQ ID NO: 9; a plasmid encoding SEQ ID NO: 12</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">23</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">J (M1-A25)</entry><entry valign="middle">Primers (3) and (24); Primers (23) and (2)</entry><entry valign="middle"><i>Nco</i>I and <i>Nhe</i>I; <i>Nhe</i>I and <i>Hind</i>III</entry><entry valign="middle">a plasmid encoding SEQ ID NO: 9; a plasmid encoding SEQ ID NO: 12</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">24</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">K (M1-A17)</entry><entry valign="middle">Primers (3) and (26); Primers (25) and (2)</entry><entry valign="middle"><i>Nco</i>I and <i>Pst</i>I; <i>Pst</i>I and <i>Hind</i>III</entry><entry valign="middle">a plasmid encoding SEQ ID NO: 9; a plasmid encoding SEQ ID NO: 12</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">25</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">L (M1-Q35)</entry><entry valign="middle">Primers (3) and (28); Primers (27) and (2)</entry><entry valign="middle"><i>Nco</i>I and <i>Pst</i>I; <i>Pst</i>I and <i>Hind</i>III</entry><entry valign="middle">a plasmid encoding SEQ ID NO: 9; a plasmid encoding SEQ ID NO: 12</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></tables><!-- EPO <DP n="65"> -->
<tables id="tabl0010" num="0010"><table frame="all"><title>[Table 10]</title><tgroup cols="3"><colspec colnum="1" colname="col1" colwidth="31mm"/><colspec colnum="2" colname="col2" colwidth="20mm"/><colspec colnum="3" colname="col3" colwidth="102mm"/><thead><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">Primer SEQ ID NO:</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">Primer No.</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">Sequence (5' to 3')</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">66</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">1</entry><entry valign="middle">CTTAGA<u>CCATGG</u>ATAGCAGCCTTTTTGGATATACC</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">67</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">2</entry><entry valign="middle">AAGT<u>AAGCTT</u>AAAAGCGTCTTGCGCAGCCTGCTGTTC</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">68</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">3</entry><entry valign="middle">TAACGC<u>CCATGG</u>ATACGTCCGCTACCGCCCAAGGCGGC</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">67</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">4</entry><entry valign="middle">AACA<u>AAGCTT</u>TTCGCTGAGCAGGGAATGGATCGCGGC</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">70</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">5</entry><entry valign="middle">GA<u>CTGCAG</u>GCTACGGGATGGCGCTGCTCCTG</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">71</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">6</entry><entry valign="middle">ATC<u>CTGCAG</u>TTGTATGGCCAGAGGGATA</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">72</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">7</entry><entry valign="middle">CAA<u>CTGCAG</u>GATGGCTCACGGCATCCATT</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">73</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">8</entry><entry valign="middle">TC<u>CTGCAG</u>TCGTATGACCCGACGGATAGGACGC</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">74</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">9</entry><entry valign="middle">AATAAACA<u>CATATG</u>CACAGCACATTCAGATGGGCTT</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">75</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">10</entry><entry valign="middle">GAGAGCTG<u>CATATG</u>GGCAGGTTCGTACCCACGAACG</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">76</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">11</entry><entry valign="middle">TTTAAT<u>GTCGAC</u>CCAGAAAAACTTCCCGCAATG</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">77</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">12</entry><entry valign="middle">GCCAG<u>CTCGAG</u>4TTGAACCCGCCGCACAGGAGAA</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">78</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">13</entry><entry valign="middle">AC<u>ACTAGT</u>CCGGAAGGTCTTGGTCTCAACGCTTCCTATCCCTCT</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">79</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">14</entry><entry valign="middle">GG<u>ACTAGT</u>GCAGATGTCTTTATTTGTGCCGAC</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">80</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">15</entry><entry valign="middle">CG<u>ACTAGT</u>TCTGGCTCCGCCGCCGGCG</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">81</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">16</entry><entry valign="middle">AA<u>ACTAGT</u>CGTTCATCAGGTAGGGTAAACTG</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">82</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">17</entry><entry valign="middle">GGAA<u>CTGCAG</u>CGCAGAGTGATGACGACCGGGTG</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">83</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">18</entry><entry valign="middle">AGTG<u>CTGCAG</u>ATCCGGGCGCTGGTGGCGGGGGCAAAA</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">84</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">19</entry><entry valign="middle">CGCTGGAA<u>GCTAG</u>CGCAGAGCGATGCGGATCTG</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">85</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">20</entry><entry valign="middle">ATTCTGTA<u>GCTAGC</u>TTCCAGCGCGCCTTATCTTTTAA</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">86</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">21</entry><entry valign="middle">CGCTGGAA<u>GCTAGC</u>CCAGAATGACGCCAACCTT</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">87</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">22</entry><entry valign="middle">GCTCTGA<u>GCTAGC</u>TTCCAGCGCGGCGTGTCCTTCAG</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">88</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">23</entry><entry valign="middle">GACTTCA<u>GCTAGC</u>ACCGCCACCACAGGCAGAAGAACCC</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">89</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">24</entry><entry valign="middle">CGGCGGA<u>GCTAGC</u>ACGAGACGCTCGTCCGGAGCCGC</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">90</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">25</entry><entry valign="middle">CAGT<u>CTGCAG</u>CACCTGATGGACGTGCATTTTTG</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">91</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">26</entry><entry valign="middle">GGAG<u>CTGCAG</u>AGTCCGGCAGGATGCCGCCTTG</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">92</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">27</entry><entry valign="middle">AAC<u>CTGCAG</u>CACAACAGGCAGACTTGCGGGCT</entry></row><row><entry align="center" valign="middle">93</entry><entry align="center" valign="middle">28</entry><entry valign="middle">CTG<u>CTGCAG</u>ATCCGGGCGCCGGCGGCGGAGC</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></tables><!-- EPO <DP n="66"> --></p><heading id="h0039">(Phosphorylation of glycerol using glycerol-phosphorylating enzyme mutants, Mutants A to L)</heading><p id="p0157" num="0157">The glycerol phosphorylating reaction was performed using the resulting Mutants A to L. The phosphorylation of glycerol was carried out as described above for Mutants a to g, and the detection of glycerol-3-phosphate was carried out as in Experimental Example 1. The results are shown in <figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 6</figref>.</p><p id="p0158" num="0158">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0004 f0005">Fig. 5</figref>, the glycerol phosphorylating reactions in which Mutants A to L were used resulted in an increased amount of produced glycerol-3-phosphate for Mutants B, C, and D. Based on these results, it was revealed that the amino acid sequence of the amino acids at positions 1 to 70 from the N terminus of the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 9 is responsible for the activity of the glycerol-phosphorylating enzyme. In addition, it was found that the glycerol phosphorylating reactions in which Mutants F to L were used resulted in an improvement in the activity of the phosphorylating enzyme for Mutants F, I, and L. The other Mutants G, H, J, and K, on the other hand, did not result in a great improvement in the activity of the phosphorylating enzyme, as compared to Mutants F and I. Based on these results, it was revealed that the amino acid sequence of from the proline residue at position 18 to the glutamine residue at position 35 from the N terminus of the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 9 is responsible for the activity of the glycerol-phosphorylating enzyme.</p><p id="p0159" num="0159">Therefore, it was revealed that the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2, PDERLVLAPPPAPGSAAQ, is important for the expression of the enzyme<!-- EPO <DP n="67"> --> activity of the above-described enzymes catalyzing the glycerol phosphorylating reaction.</p><heading id="h0040">SEQUENCE LISTING FREE TEXT</heading><p id="p0160" num="0160"><ul><li>SEQ ID NO: 1 represents the amino acid sequence represented by sequence (1).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 2 represents the amino acid sequence of the N-terminal essential region of the phosphorylating enzyme.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 13 represents the amino acid sequence of Mutant a (F144G/A151T).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 14 represents the amino acid sequence of Mutant A (A143-E244).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 15 represents the amino acid sequence of Mutant B (M1-A143).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 16 represents the amino acid sequence of Mutant C (M1-P122).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 17 represents the amino acid sequence of Mutant D (M1-R70).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 18 represents the amino acid sequence of Mutant E (S126-A143).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 19 represents the amino acid sequence of Mutant F (P18-R70).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 20 represents the amino acid sequence of Mutant G (A29-R70).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 21 represents the amino acid sequence of Mutant H (R53-R70).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 22 represents the amino acid sequence of Mutant I (M1-P52).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 23 represents the amino acid sequence of Mutant J (M1-A25).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 24 represents the amino acid sequence of Mutant K (M1-A17).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 25 represents the amino acid sequence of Mutant L (M1-Q35).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 42 represents a forward primer for the phosphorylating enzyme set forth in amino acid sequence 3.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 43 represents a reverse primer for the phosphorylating enzyme set<!-- EPO <DP n="68"> --> forth in amino acid sequence 3.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 44 represents a forward primer for the phosphorylating enzyme set forth in amino acid sequence 4.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 45 represents a reverse primer for the phosphorylating enzyme set forth in amino acid sequence 4.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 46 represents a forward primer for the phosphorylating enzyme set forth in amino acid sequence 5.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 47 represents a reverse primer for the phosphorylating enzyme set forth in amino acid sequence 5.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 48 represents a forward primer for the phosphorylating enzyme set forth in amino acid sequence 6.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 49 represents a reverse primer for the phosphorylating enzyme set forth in amino acid sequence 6.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 50 represents a forward primer for the phosphorylating enzyme set forth in amino acid sequence 7.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 51 represents a reverse primer for the phosphorylating enzyme set forth in amino acid sequence 7.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 52 represents a forward primer for the phosphorylating enzyme set forth in amino acid sequence 8.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 53 represents a reverse primer for the phosphorylating enzyme set forth in amino acid sequence 8.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 54 represents a forward primer for the phosphorylating enzyme set forth in amino acid sequence 9.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 55 represents a reverse primer for the phosphorylating enzyme set forth in amino acid sequence 9.<!-- EPO <DP n="69"> --></li><li>SEQ ID NO: 56 represents a forward primer for the phosphorylating enzyme set forth in amino acid sequence 10.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 57 represents a reverse primer for the phosphorylating enzyme set forth in amino acid sequence 10.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 58 represents a forward primer for the phosphorylating enzyme set forth in amino acid sequence 11.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 59 represents a reverse primer for the phosphorylating enzyme set forth in amino acid sequence 11.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 60 represents a forward primer for the phosphorylating enzyme set forth in amino acid sequence 12.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 61 represents a reverse primer for the phosphorylating enzyme set forth in amino acid sequence 12.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 62 represents the base sequence of primer number (1).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 63 represents the base sequence of primer number (2).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 64 represents the base sequence of primer number (3).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 65 represents the base sequence of primer number (4).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 66 represents the base sequence of primer number 1.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 67 represents the base sequence of primer number 2.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 68 represents the base sequence of primer number 3.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 69 represents the base sequence of primer number 4.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 70 represents the base sequence of primer number 5.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 71 represents the base sequence of primer number 6.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 72 represents the base sequence of primer number 7.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 73 represents the base sequence of primer number 8.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 74 represents the base sequence of primer number 9.<!-- EPO <DP n="70"> --></li><li>SEQ ID NO: 75 represents the base sequence of primer number 10.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 76 represents the base sequence of primer number 11.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 77 represents the base sequence of primer number 12.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 78 represents the base sequence of primer number 13.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 79 represents the base sequence of primer number 14.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 80 represents the base sequence of primer number 15.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 81 represents the base sequence of primer number 16.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 82 represents the base sequence of primer number 17.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 83 represents the base sequence of primer number 18.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 84 represents the base sequence of primer number 19.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 85 represents the base sequence of primer number 20.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 86 represents the base sequence of primer number 21.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 87 represents the base sequence of primer number 22.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 88 represents the base sequence of primer number 23.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 89 represents the base sequence of primer number 24.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 90 represents the base sequence of primer number 25.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 91 represents the base sequence of primer number 26.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 92 represents the base sequence of primer number 27.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 93 represents the base sequence of primer number 28.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 116 represents the amino acid sequence of Mutant b (F144A).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 117 represents the amino acid sequence of Mutant c (F144G).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 118 represents the amino acid sequence of Mutant d (A151D).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 119 represents the amino acid sequence of Mutant e (A151T).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 120 represents the amino acid sequence of Mutant f (A151S).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 121 represents the amino acid sequence of Mutant g<!-- EPO <DP n="71"> --> (F144G/A151S).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 124 represents a forward primer for the phosphorylating enzyme set forth in amino acid sequence 104.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 125 represents a reverse primer for the phosphorylating enzyme set forth in amino acid sequence 104.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 126 represents a forward primer for the phosphorylating enzyme set forth in amino acid sequence 105.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 127 represents a reverse primer for the phosphorylating enzyme set forth in amino acid sequence 105.</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 128 represents a base sequence in which a gene encoding the phosphorylating enzyme set forth in SEQ ID NO: 11 was codon optimized for expression in <i>Escherichia coli.</i></li><li>SEQ ID NO: 129 represents the base sequence of primer number (5).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 130 represents the base sequence of primer number (6).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 131 represents the base sequence of primer number (7).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 132 represents the base sequence of primer number (8).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 133 represents the base sequence of primer number (9).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 134 represents the base sequence of primer number (10).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 135 represents the base sequence of primer number (11).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 136 represents the base sequence of primer number (12).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 137 represents the base sequence of primer number (13).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 138 represents the base sequence of primer number (14).</li><li>SEQ ID NO: 139 represents the base sequence of primer number (15).</li></ul><!-- EPO <DP n="72"> --><img id="ib0026" file="imgb0026.tif" wi="129" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="73"> --><img id="ib0027" file="imgb0027.tif" wi="129" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="74"> --><img id="ib0028" file="imgb0028.tif" wi="129" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="75"> --><img id="ib0029" file="imgb0029.tif" wi="129" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="76"> --><img id="ib0030" file="imgb0030.tif" wi="129" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="77"> --><img id="ib0031" file="imgb0031.tif" wi="129" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="78"> --><img id="ib0032" file="imgb0032.tif" wi="129" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="79"> --><img id="ib0033" file="imgb0033.tif" wi="129" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="80"> --><img id="ib0034" file="imgb0034.tif" wi="129" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="81"> --><img id="ib0035" file="imgb0035.tif" wi="129" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="82"> --><img id="ib0036" file="imgb0036.tif" wi="129" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="83"> --><img id="ib0037" file="imgb0037.tif" wi="129" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="84"> --><img id="ib0038" file="imgb0038.tif" wi="131" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="85"> --><img id="ib0039" file="imgb0039.tif" wi="130" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="86"> --><img id="ib0040" file="imgb0040.tif" wi="136" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="87"> --><img id="ib0041" file="imgb0041.tif" wi="136" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="88"> --><img id="ib0042" file="imgb0042.tif" wi="129" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="89"> --><img id="ib0043" file="imgb0043.tif" wi="130" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="90"> --><img id="ib0044" file="imgb0044.tif" wi="134" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="91"> --><img id="ib0045" file="imgb0045.tif" wi="130" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="92"> --><img id="ib0046" file="imgb0046.tif" wi="136" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="93"> --><img id="ib0047" file="imgb0047.tif" wi="136" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="94"> --><img id="ib0048" file="imgb0048.tif" wi="129" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="95"> --><img id="ib0049" file="imgb0049.tif" wi="130" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="96"> --><img id="ib0050" file="imgb0050.tif" wi="134" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="97"> --><img id="ib0051" file="imgb0051.tif" wi="134" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="98"> --><img id="ib0052" file="imgb0052.tif" wi="136" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="99"> --><img id="ib0053" file="imgb0053.tif" wi="134" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="100"> --><img id="ib0054" file="imgb0054.tif" wi="134" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="101"> --><img id="ib0055" file="imgb0055.tif" wi="129" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="102"> --><img id="ib0056" file="imgb0056.tif" wi="129" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="103"> --><img id="ib0057" file="imgb0057.tif" wi="132" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="104"> --><img id="ib0058" file="imgb0058.tif" wi="130" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="105"> --><img id="ib0059" file="imgb0059.tif" wi="136" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="106"> --><img id="ib0060" file="imgb0060.tif" wi="136" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="107"> --><img id="ib0061" file="imgb0061.tif" wi="130" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="108"> --><img id="ib0062" file="imgb0062.tif" wi="134" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="109"> --><img id="ib0063" file="imgb0063.tif" wi="156" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="110"> --><img id="ib0064" file="imgb0064.tif" wi="152" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="111"> --><img id="ib0065" file="imgb0065.tif" wi="152" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="112"> --><img id="ib0066" file="imgb0066.tif" wi="152" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="113"> --><img id="ib0067" file="imgb0067.tif" wi="156" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="114"> --><img id="ib0068" file="imgb0068.tif" wi="152" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="115"> --><img id="ib0069" file="imgb0069.tif" wi="152" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="116"> --><img id="ib0070" file="imgb0070.tif" wi="152" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="117"> --><img id="ib0071" file="imgb0071.tif" wi="156" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="118"> --><img id="ib0072" file="imgb0072.tif" wi="151" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="119"> --><img id="ib0073" file="imgb0073.tif" wi="156" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="120"> --><img id="ib0074" file="imgb0074.tif" wi="151" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="121"> --><img id="ib0075" file="imgb0075.tif" wi="156" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="122"> --><img id="ib0076" file="imgb0076.tif" wi="151" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="123"> --><img id="ib0077" file="imgb0077.tif" wi="157" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="124"> --><img id="ib0078" file="imgb0078.tif" wi="132" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="125"> --><img id="ib0079" file="imgb0079.tif" wi="132" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="126"> --><img id="ib0080" file="imgb0080.tif" wi="134" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="127"> --><img id="ib0081" file="imgb0081.tif" wi="134" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="128"> --><img id="ib0082" file="imgb0082.tif" wi="134" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="129"> --><img id="ib0083" file="imgb0083.tif" wi="129" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="130"> --><img id="ib0084" file="imgb0084.tif" wi="130" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="131"> --><img id="ib0085" file="imgb0085.tif" wi="136" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="132"> --><img id="ib0086" file="imgb0086.tif" wi="132" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="133"> --><img id="ib0087" file="imgb0087.tif" wi="136" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="134"> --><img id="ib0088" file="imgb0088.tif" wi="129" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="135"> --><img id="ib0089" file="imgb0089.tif" wi="130" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="136"> --><img id="ib0090" file="imgb0090.tif" wi="136" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="137"> --><img id="ib0091" file="imgb0091.tif" wi="136" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="138"> --><img id="ib0092" file="imgb0092.tif" wi="151" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="139"> --><img id="ib0093" file="imgb0093.tif" wi="156" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="140"> --><img id="ib0094" file="imgb0094.tif" wi="154" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="141"> --><img id="ib0095" file="imgb0095.tif" wi="152" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="142"> --><img id="ib0096" file="imgb0096.tif" wi="154" he="233" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/><!-- EPO <DP n="143"> --><img id="ib0097" file="imgb0097.tif" wi="159" he="66" img-content="dna" img-format="tif"/></p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM90459908" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="144"> --><claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A method for production of a phosphorylated glycerol, comprising a step of allowing a phosphorylating enzyme to act on glycerol in the presence of a phosphate group donor,<br/>
wherein the phosphorylating enzyme is a class A acid phosphatase and comprises a polypeptide comprising as an active center an amino acid sequence represented by the sequence (1):<br/>
<br/>
        -X<sup>1</sup>-X<sup>2</sup>-X<sup>3</sup>-Pro-Ser-Gly-His-X<sup>4</sup>-     (1)<br/>
<br/>
wherein,
<claim-text>X<sup>1</sup> denotes glycine, alanine, or phenylalanine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>X<sup>2</sup> denotes any amino acid;</claim-text>
<claim-text>X<sup>3</sup> denotes tyrosine or tryptophan; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>X<sup>4</sup> denotes threonine, serine, or alanine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>with the proviso that when X<sup>1</sup> is phenylalanine, X<sup>4</sup> is threonine or serine.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The method for production according to claim 1, wherein X<sup>1</sup> and X<sup>4</sup> in the sequence (1) are any of (A1) to (A8) below:
<claim-text>(A1) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(A2) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine and X<sup>4</sup> being serine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(A3) X<sup>1</sup> being alanine and X<sup>4</sup> being serine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(A4) X<sup>1</sup> being alanine and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(A5) X<sup>1</sup> being alanine and X<sup>4</sup> being alanine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(A6) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine and X<sup>4</sup> being alanine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(A7) X<sup>1</sup> being phenylalanine and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(A8) X<sup>1</sup> being phenylalanine and X<sup>4</sup> being serine.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="145"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The method for production according to claim 1 or 2, wherein in the sequence (1), X<sup>2</sup> is serine, alanine, or aspartic acid.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The method for production according to any of claims 1 to 3, wherein X<sup>1</sup>, X<sup>2</sup>, X<sup>3</sup>, and X<sup>4</sup> in the sequence (1) are any of (B1) to (B11) below:
<claim-text>(B1) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(B2) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being alanine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(B3) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being serine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(B4) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being aspartic acid, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(B5) X<sup>1</sup> being alanine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being serine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(B6) X<sup>1</sup> being alanine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(B7) X<sup>1</sup> being alanine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being alanine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(B8) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being alanine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(B9) X<sup>1</sup> being phenylalanine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(B10) X<sup>1</sup> being phenylalanine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being serine; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(B11) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tryptophan, and X<sup>4</sup> being serine.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="146"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The method for production according to any of claims 1 to 4, wherein the histidine (His) residue at the 7-th position in the amino acid sequence represented by the sequence (1) is located between positions 120 and 160 from the N-terminus of the polypeptide employed as the phosphorylating enzyme.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The method for production according to any of claims 1 to 5, wherein the phosphorylating enzyme further comprises a polypeptide as defined in (I) or (II) below: including a polypeptide as defined in (II);
<claim-text>(I) a polypeptide that has the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2, on the N-terminal side of a stretch of the amino acid sequence coding for the active center represented by the sequence (1), or</claim-text>
<claim-text>(II) a polypeptide that comprises, on the N-terminal side of a stretch of the amino acid sequence coding for the active center represented by the sequence (1), an amino acid sequence having one or a few amino acids substituted, deleted, inserted, or added in the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2 and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction which is comparable or superior to that of the polypeptide as defined in (I).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The method for production according to claim 6, wherein the amino acid residue at the first position in the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2 is located between positions 5 and 40 from the N-terminus of the polypeptide employed as the phosphorylating enzyme.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The method for production according to any of claims 1 to 5, wherein the phosphorylating enzyme further comprises any of the polypeptides as defined in (III) to<!-- EPO <DP n="147"> --> (VI) below:
<claim-text>(III) a polypeptide that has the amino acid sequence set forth in any of SEQ ID NOs: 26 to 32 and 106 to 110, on the N-terminal side of the amino acid sequence represented by the sequence (1);</claim-text>
<claim-text>(IV) a polypeptide that has, on the N-terminal side of the amino acid sequence represented by the sequence (1), an amino acid sequence having one or several amino acids substituted, deleted, inserted, or added in the amino acid sequence set forth in any of SEQ ID NOs: 26 to 32 and 106 to 110 and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction which is comparable or superior to that of its corresponding polypeptide as defined in (III);</claim-text>
<claim-text>(V) a polypeptide that has the amino acid sequence set forth in any of SEQ ID NOs: 33 to 39 and 111 to 115, on the C-terminal side of the amino acid sequence represented by the sequence (1); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(VI) a polypeptide that has, on the C-terminal side of the amino acid sequence represented by the sequence (1), an amino acid sequence having one or several amino acids substituted, deleted, inserted, or added in the amino acid sequence set forth in any of SEQ ID NOs: 33 to 39 and 111 to 115 and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction which is comparable or superior to that of its corresponding polypeptide as defined in (V).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The method for production according to any of claims 1 to 8, wherein the phosphorylating enzyme comprises a polypeptide as defined in (VII) or (VIII) below:
<claim-text>(VII) a polypeptide that has the amino acid sequence set forth in any of SEQ ID NOs: 3 to 9, 13, 104, 105, 116, 117, and 119 to 121, or</claim-text>
<claim-text>(VIII) a polypeptide that comprises an amino acid sequence having, in the<!-- EPO <DP n="148"> --> amino acid sequence set forth in any of SEQ ID NOs: 3 to 9, 13, 104, 105, 116, 117, and 119 to 121, one or several amino acids substituted, deleted, inserted, or added in a region outside the active center comprising the amino acid sequence represented by the sequence (1) and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction which is comparable or superior to that of its corresponding polypeptide as defined in (VII).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>A method for production of a phosphorylated glycerol, comprising a step of allowing a phosphorylating enzyme to act on glycerol in the presence of a phosphate group donor,<br/>
wherein the phosphorylating enzyme is a class A acid phosphatase and comprises a polypeptide as defined in (i) or (ii) below:
<claim-text>(i) a polypeptide that has the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2 and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction, or</claim-text>
<claim-text>(ii) a polypeptide that has an amino acid sequence having one or several amino acids substituted, deleted, inserted, or added in the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2 and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction which is comparable or superior to that of the polypeptide as defined in (i).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>The method for production according to claim 10, wherein the amino acid residue at the first position in the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2 is located between positions 5 and 40 from the N-terminus of the polypeptide employed as the phosphorylating enzyme.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>The method for production according to claim 10 or 11, wherein the phosphorylating enzyme comprises a polypeptide having, on the C-terminal side of the<!-- EPO <DP n="149"> --> amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2, an amino acid sequence represented by the sequence (1):<br/>
<br/>
        -X<sup>1</sup>-X<sup>2</sup>-X<sup>3</sup>-Pro-Ser-Gly-His-X<sup>4</sup>-     (1)<br/>
<br/>
wherein,
<claim-text>X<sup>1</sup> denotes glycine, alanine, or phenylalanine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>X<sup>2</sup> denotes any amino acid;</claim-text>
<claim-text>X<sup>3</sup> denotes tyrosine or tryptophan; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>X<sup>4</sup> denotes threonine, serine, or alanine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>with the proviso that when X<sup>1</sup> is phenylalanine, X<sup>4</sup> is threonine or serine.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>The method for production according to claim 12, wherein X<sup>1</sup> and X<sup>4</sup> in the sequence (1) are any of (A1) to (A8) below:
<claim-text>(A1) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(A2) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine and X<sup>4</sup> being serine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(A3) X<sup>1</sup> being alanine and X<sup>4</sup> being serine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(A4) X<sup>1</sup> being alanine and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(A5) X<sup>1</sup> being alanine and X<sup>4</sup> being alanine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(A6) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine and X<sup>4</sup> being alanine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(A7) X<sup>1</sup> being phenylalanine and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(A8) X<sup>1</sup> being phenylalanine and X<sup>4</sup> being serine.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>The method for production according to claim 12 or 13, wherein in the sequence (1), X<sup>2</sup> is serine, alanine, or aspartic acid.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>The method for production according to any of claims 12 to 14, wherein X<sup>1</sup>, X<sup>2</sup>,<!-- EPO <DP n="150"> --> X<sup>3</sup>, and X<sup>4</sup> in the sequence (1) are any of (B1) to (B11) below:
<claim-text>(B1) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(B2) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being alanine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(B3) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being serine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(B4) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being aspartic acid, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(B5) X<sup>1</sup> being alanine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being serine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(B6) X<sup>1</sup> being alanine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(B7) X<sup>1</sup> being alanine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being alanine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(B8) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being alanine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(B9) X<sup>1</sup> being phenylalanine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being threonine;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(B10) X<sup>1</sup> being phenylalanine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tyrosine, and X<sup>4</sup> being serine; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(B11) X<sup>1</sup> being glycine, X<sup>2</sup> being serine, X<sup>3</sup> being tryptophan, and X<sup>4</sup> being serine.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0016" num="0016"><claim-text>The method for production according to any of claims 12 to 15, wherein the histidine (His) residue at the 7-th position in the amino acid sequence represented by the sequence (1) is located between positions 120 and 160 from the N-terminus of the<!-- EPO <DP n="151"> --> polypeptide employed as the phosphorylating enzyme.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0017" num="0017"><claim-text>The method for production according to any of claims 10 to 16, wherein the phosphorylating enzyme further comprises at least one of the amino acid sequences as defined in (iii) to (vi) below:
<claim-text>(iii) a polypeptide that has, on the N-terminal side of the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2, the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 40 and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction;</claim-text>
<claim-text>(iv) a polypeptide that has, on the N-terminal side of the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2, an amino acid sequence having one or a few amino acids substituted, deleted, inserted, or added in the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 40 and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction which is comparable or superior to that of the polypeptide as defined in (iii);</claim-text>
<claim-text>(v) a polypeptide that has, on the C-terminal side of the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2, the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 41 and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>(vi) a polypeptide that has, on the C-terminal side of the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2, an amino acid sequence having one or a few amino acids substituted, deleted, inserted, or added in the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 41 and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction which is comparable or superior to that of the polypeptide as defined in (v).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0018" num="0018"><claim-text>The method for production according to any of claims 10 to 17, wherein the phosphorylating enzyme comprises a polypeptide as defined in (vii) or (viii) below:
<claim-text>(vii) a polypeptide that has the amino acid sequence set forth in any of SEQ ID<!-- EPO <DP n="152"> --> NOs: 9, 15 to 17, 19, 22, and 25; or</claim-text>
<claim-text>(viii) a polypeptide that comprises an amino acid sequence having, in the amino acid sequence set forth in any of SEQ ID NOs: 9, 15 to 17, 19, 22, and 25, one or several amino acids substituted, deleted, inserted, or added in a region outside the amino acid sequence set forth in SEQ ID NO: 2 and has an activity to catalyze the glycerol phosphorylating reaction which is comparable or superior to that of the polypeptide as defined in (vii).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0019" num="0019"><claim-text>The method for production according to any of claims 1 to 18, wherein the phosphate group donor is a polyphosphoric acid.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0020" num="0020"><claim-text>The method for production according to any of claims 1 to 19, wherein the phosphorylated glycerol is α-glycerophosphate.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0021" num="0021"><claim-text>The method for production according to any of claims 1 to 20, wherein the pH of the reaction solution is from 4 to 5 in the step of allowing the phosphorylating enzyme to act on the glycerol in the presence of the phosphate group donor.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0022" num="0022"><claim-text>The method for production according to any of claims 1 to 21, wherein the glycerol is added in an amount of 1000 to 50000 parts by weight per part by weight of the phosphorylating enzyme, in the step of allowing the phosphorylating enzyme to act on the glycerol in the presence of the phosphate group donor.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0023" num="0023"><claim-text>The method for production according to any of claims 1 to 22, wherein the concentration of the phosphate group donor in the reaction solution is from 2% to 10%<!-- EPO <DP n="153"> --> by weight in the step of allowing the phosphorylating enzyme to act on the glycerol in the presence of the phosphate group donor.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW20422615" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="154"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1(i),1(ii),1(iii)"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="148" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="155"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2,3"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="164" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="156"> --><figure id="f0003" num="4"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="165" he="121" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="157"> --><figure id="f0004" num="5-1(i)"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="160" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="158"> --><figure id="f0005" num="5-2(ii)"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="160" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="159"> --><figure id="f0006" num="6"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="165" he="164" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><search-report-data><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="165" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="165" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0003" file="srep0003.tif" wi="165" he="233" type="tif"/></search-report-data><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
