<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-1976110-B1" country="EP" doc-number="1976110" kind="B1" date="20140101" family-id="38657225" file-reference-id="239497" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146553519" ucid="EP-1976110-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>1976110</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-07006798-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154827442" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>07006798</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20070331</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140448223" ucid="EP-07006798-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>07006798</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20070331</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130722</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988127326" load-source="docdb">H03D   3/24        20060101AFI20071113BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2122433928" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H03D   3/241       20130101 FI20150106BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132193041" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Schaltung und Verfahren zum Verarbeiten eines Eingabesignals</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132193042" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Circuit and method for processing an input signal</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132193043" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Circuit et procédé pour le traitement d'un signal d'entrée</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918155742" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>SONY DEUTSCHLAND GMBH</last-name><address><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918156045" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>SONY DEUTSCHLAND GMBH</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918170330" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>SPALINK GERD</last-name><address><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918151960" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>SPALINK, GERD</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918997079" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Spalink, Gerd, c/o Sony Deutschland GmbH</last-name><address><street>Stuttgart Technology Center, Hedelfinger Strasse 61</street><city>70327 Stuttgart</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918172616" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>EITEL BEN</last-name><address><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918153951" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>EITEL, BEN</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918997078" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Eitel, Ben, c/o Sony Deutschland GmbH</last-name><address><street>Stuttgart Technology Center, Hedelfinger Strasse 61</street><city>70327 Stuttgart</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918997081" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>SONY DEUTSCHLAND GMBH</last-name><iid>100734616</iid><address><street>Kemperplatz 1</street><city>10785 Berlin</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918997080" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Müller - Hoffmann &amp; Partner</last-name><iid>100061044</iid><address><street>Patentanwälte Innere Wiener Strasse 17</street><city>81667 München</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548863045" load-source="docdb">GB</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63957247" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><p id="p0001" num="0001">An embodiment of the invention relates to a circuit and method for processing an input signal. A further embodiment of the invention relates to a receiver and a still further embodiment to a television set.</p><heading id="h0001">BACKGROUND</heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">There exist a large number of signal processing devices, where a phase locked loop is applied among other signal processing parts. For example, there exist OFDM-signals, analogue television signals or other signals that need to be demodulated, wherein a phase locked loop is used. The resulting signal of the phase locked loop is then used for further processing.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">It is an object of the invention to provide a circuit for processing an input signal, wherein the processed signal is improved.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US5533059A"><text>US 5,533,059</text></patcit> describes a phase-locked loop (PLL) circuit including a voltage-controlled oscillator (VCO) and a sweep control circuit that stops the sweep operation of the VCO after detecting a phase locked detection. <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="US3909735A"><text>US 3,909,735</text></patcit> describes a PLL circuit with a pair of loop filters one of which has a narrow filter range and the other has a wide filter range. <patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="US4479091A"><text>US 4,479,091</text></patcit> describes a PLL with a variable filter and <patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="US20030143950A1"><text>US 2003/0143950 A1</text></patcit> describes a PLL with a switched filter.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">This object is achieved by a circuit, method and receiver according to claims 1, 14, and 18, respectively.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">Further details of the invention will become apparent from a consideration of the drawings and ensuing description.</p><heading id="h0002">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE SEVERAL VIEWS OF THE DRAWINGS</heading><p id="p0007" num="0007"><dl id="dl0001"><dt>Fig. 1</dt><dd>shows a block diagram according to an embodiment of the invention;<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></dd><dt>Fig. 2</dt><dd>shows a further block diagram according to a further embodiment of the invention;</dd><dt>Fig. 3</dt><dd>shows an analogue television signal comprising echoes;</dd><dt>Fig. 4</dt><dd>shows a diagram with ghost canceling reference signals;<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></dd><dt>Fig. 5</dt><dd>shows a demodulating circuit for demodeling an analogue television signal;</dd><dt>Fig. 6</dt><dd>shows a phase locked loop according to an embodiment of the invention;</dd><dt>Fig. 7</dt><dd>shows diagrams with reference signals and corresponding speed of a PLL demodulator; and</dd><dt>Fig. 8</dt><dd>shows steps of a method according to an embodiment of the invention.</dd></dl></p><heading id="h0003">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</heading><p id="p0008" num="0008">In the following, embodiments of the invention are described. It is important to note that all described embodiments in the following may be combined in any way, i.e. there is no limitation that certain described embodiments may not be combined with others.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009"><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> shows a circuit 100 comprising a phase locked loop (PLL) circuit 102, reference signal detector 104 and further processing block 106. PLL circuit receives an input signal 103. The input signal 103 may be of various types and/or sources. For example, input signal 103 could be an OFDM signal, or any kind of analog signal, e.g. a television or radio signal. Input signal 103 may correspond to a received signal r(t) = s(t)*h(t,τ). s(t) may denote a signal that has been sent out from a sending device, e.g. broadcast station or the like. h(t,τ) may describe the characteristics of the channel over which signal s(t) has been transmitted.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">PLL circuit 102 tries to detect frequency and/or phase of input signal 103 and outputs a demodulated signal 108. Demodulated signal 108 is fed to reference signal detector 104 that is configured to detect a reference signal within demodulated signal 108. If reference signal detector 104 detects a reference signal, reference signal detector 104 outputs a speed control signal 110 to PLL circuit 102. The speed control signal 110 sets a speed of PLL circuit 102. "Speed" in the context of this specification may e.g. describe the following speed or correction speed or the PLL, i.e. the speed with which the phase locked loop demodulator follows the frequency and/or phase of the input signal 103.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p><p id="p0011" num="0011">The speed control signal 110 may also be set such that PLL circuit 102 is completely stopped, i.e. PLL circuit 102 does not follow the frequency and/or phase of input signal 103.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">Thus, the circuit 100 shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> allows for controlling the speed of the PLL circuit 102 during or based on a reference signal detected by reference signal detector 104 and speed control signal 110.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">Further processing block 106 may accommodate further processing parts such as e.g. various filters e.g. adaptive filters for filtering various distortions of input signal 103 and/or demodulated signal 108. Further processing block 106 may also process the reference signal, and, in certain applications it may be desirable that the distorted signal 103 is not or to a lesser extent modified by PLL circuit 102. Thus, according to the embodiment of <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, it is possible to eliminate processing of input signal 103 by PLL circuit 102 or at least to weaken the influence of the PLL depending on reference signals. Since the reference signals are also received in further processing block 106, processing in further processing block 106 may not be influenced by a certain behavior of the PLL circuit 102.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">The output signal 112 in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> corresponds to a signal ŝ(t), i.e. an estimation of signal s(t).</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">It should be noted that there is no limitation that the reference signal is detected within demodulated signal 108. It may also be possible to detect the reference signal within input signal 103. It may also be possible that a reference signal be transmitted independently of input signal 103, i.e. via a different channel or the like. In this case, reference signal detector 104 may not need as input demodulated signal 108 and/or input signal 103.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">According to the embodiment of <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, it may be possible that the reference signal detector decreases the speed to a predetermined level, wherein the predetermined level is lower than a normal level before a reference signal has been detected. The speed may be decreased for a predetermined period of time or for a period of time which depends on the duration of a reference signal. Further, the period of time may start before an (expected) occurrence of the reference signal and may last until after the occurrence of the reference signal. For example, if the reference signal is an analogue television signal, then it is a priori known in which lines a reference signal occurs, e.g. in line 18 and 281. In this case, the speed of the PLL<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> may already be lowered half a line before line 18 and maintained at the low level until half a line after the 18<sup>th</sup> line.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017"><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> shows a further example of a circuit 200 comprising a PLL demodulator 201, equalizer 202, reference signal detector 203 and data processor 204.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">PLL demodulator 201 receives an input signal 205 corresponding to a received signal r(t) = s(t)*h(t,τ). PLL demodulator 201 outputs a demodulated signal 206 that may comprise a reference signal. The reference signal is detected by a reference signal detector 203 that outputs a speed control signal 207. Speed control signal 207 controls the speed of PLL demodulator 201, i.e. reference signal detector 203 may set the speed of PLL demodulator 201 according to which speed PLL demodulator 201 follows the frequency and/or phase of input signal 205.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">The input signal 205 may be distorted, i.e. input signal 205 may comprise complex echoes or the like. Thus, the input signal 205 may comprise a main path signal part and an echo signal part. The main path signal corresponds to a received signal part that has not or only very little been reflected on the way from a sender to the receiver. PLL demodulator 201 may try to follow the input signal including such echoes. However, the PLL should in fact only follow the main path signal part and not the echo signal part. Therefore, the PLL may cause distortions that may be avoided as explained.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">In certain embodiments, although, PLL demodulator 201 does not follow the frequency and/or phase of input signal 205 at a high speed, it may cause less problems in data processor 204. For example, it may be desirable that data processor 204 receives a signal without distortions caused by PLL demodulator 201. This may allow determining filter coefficients 209 that are better suited for equalizing signal 205/206.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">Therefore, equalizer 202 may be based on filter coefficients 209 that are determined by data processor 204 e.g. based on a signal 208 generated by a reference signal detector 203. Signal 208 may comprise demodulated signal 206 and/or a detected reference signal.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">The output of equalizer 202 is an equalized signal 210.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">The phase locked loop demodulator in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> may comprise a speed control mechanism configured to control the speed. The speed control mechanism may be<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> a multiplier arranged in a feedback path of the phase locked loop demodulator. The speed control signal may also indicate a zero speed if a reference signal is detected.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024"><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> shows a broadcast station 40 which may be e.g. a television broadcast station, broadcasting a television signal 50.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">Television signal 50 may be received by an antenna 58 of a television set 59 of a user. However, antenna 58 may receive several parts of television signal 50, i.e. a first echo signal 50-1 of said television signal 50, a second echo signal 50-2 of said television signal 50 and a main path signal 50-3 of said television signal 50. The first echo signal 50-1 may have been caused by a first obstacle 54, e.g. a mountain. The second echo signal 50-2 may have been caused by a second obstacle 55, e.g. a building. The main path signal 50-3 is received by antenna 58 without having been reflected by any obstacle.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">When demodulating the received signal 50-1, 50-2 and 50-3 in television set 59, the demodulated video picture may have picture distortions.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">It is important to note that although <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> and the further description shows a television signal, all of the described embodiments of the invention may also be applied in other fields of radio communication, e.g. in satellite communication, when broadcasting/receiving a radio signal and various other fields where signals need to be demodulated that may comprise echoes. For example, the explained principles may also be applied to an orthogonal frequency division multiplex (OFDM) signal. Also, it is not necessary that input signal have been transmitted wireless. All explained principles are likewise applicable if the signals were transmitted e.g. via cable.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028"><figref idrefs="f0004">Fig. 4</figref> shows a first ghost canceling reference signal 500 GCR_A, a second ghost canceling reference signal 502 GCR_B and a ghost canceling reference difference signal 504 GCR_F = GCR_A - GCR_B.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">Such ghost canceling reference signals may e.g. be included in an analogue television signal in order to cancel ghosts. Therefore, the exact form of either one of the ghost canceling reference signals or the ghost canceling reference difference signal is known at the receiver side. For example, ghost canceling reference difference signal GCR_F may be known at the receiver, wherein the broadcaster sends out<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> first reference signal 500 and second reference signal 502. The receiver then may receive a distorted first and second ghost canceling reference signal and determines a (distorted) ghost canceling reference difference signal GCR_F'.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">Then, the receiver may compare the predetermined (known) ghost canceling reference difference signal GCR_F with the calculated ghost canceling reference signal GCR_F' corresponding to the difference of the received ghost canceling reference signal.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031"><figref idrefs="f0005">Fig. 5</figref> shows a further circuit 600 according to a further embodiment of the invention. Circuit 600 may be used e.g. for demodulating an analogue television signal 599 and output a ghost-free video signal 598.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">Circuit 600 comprises a PLL demodulator 601, vestigial sideband filter 602, ghost canceling (GC) equalizer 603, ghost canceling reference signal (GCR) detector 604, GCR line extractor 605, four-field-difference calculator 606, and data processor 607.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">The input signal 599 may have been received by e.g. an antenna or via cable. Input signal 599 may comprise complex distortions, e.g. resulting from echoes. PLL demodulator 601 tries to follow the phase and/or frequency of input signal 599. The output of PLL demodulator is a demodulated signal 597 that is further processed by the vestigial sideband filter 602 and GC equalizer 603.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">The filter coefficients 612 of GC equalizer 603 are determined based on signal 608 and GCR detector 604, GCR line extractor 605 and four-field difference calculator 606.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">If GCR detector 604 detects a ghost canceling reference signal, GCR detector 604 may control the speed of PLL demodulator 601 via speed control signal 613. Thus, the influence of PLL demodulator 601 on vestigial sideband filter 602 and/or GC equalizer 603 as well as on the determination of filter coefficients 612 may be controlled by GCR detector 604. If GCR detector 604 detects a reference signal, then the speed may be set to a lower level. Thus, e.g. for the duration of a reference signal, the speed of the PLL demodulator 601 may be decreased in comparison to when no reference signal is received. It may also be possible that the speed of the PLL demodulator 601 is decreased a certain period of time before a reference signal is expected until a certain period of time after the reference signal. By such control of the speed of PLL demodulator 601, it may be possible to make sure that<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> the PLL speed is at a low level when a reference signal is received. Also, if the ghost canceling reference signal is distorted by echoes, then in order to capture such echoes, it may be good to lower the speed of the PLL demodulator 601 before a reference signal occurs until after an occurrence of a reference signal.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">It should be noted that this is possible, because in analogue television, ghost canceling reference signals occur in predetermined lines e.g. in the 18<sup>th</sup> and 281<sup>st</sup> line in a repeated manner. In other words, two different reference signals GCR_A and GCR_B may be transmitted in line 18 and 281, respectively, of a television signal. However, for the reasons mentioned above, the ghost canceling reference detector 604 may decrease the speed of PLL demodulator 601 already half a line before the 18<sup>th</sup> and 281<sup>st</sup> line, respectively, and may maintain the lower speed until half a line after the 18<sup>th</sup> and 281<sup>st</sup> line, respectively.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">Four-field difference calculator 606 subtracts GCR_A from GCR_B according to the four-field difference operation. The difference signal GCR_F' is then compared with GCR_F which is completely known by the receiver and can therefore be used in data processor 607 to determine filter coefficients to equalize signal 608 in order to output a ghost-free video signal 598.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">It should be noted that the reference signal GCR_F only allows for a good equalization under static or very slowly time-varying channel conditions. However, in case of complex valued echoes, the phase/frequency estimation of the PLL demodulator 601 may be influenced by the wave form of the received signal. By controlling the speed of the PLL, such influences may be reduced. Therefore, the PLL video carrier phase/frequency correction may behave the same for GCR_A and GCR_B signals. Thus, the difference signal OCR_F' may be improved in that there are no influences of PLL demodulator 601. Therefore, a data processor 607 may only see signal distortions originating from the transmission channel and not distortions caused by the PLL. Therefore, data processor 607 may be able to determine filter coefficients 612 that are better suited to equalize the video signal. Finally, this may lead to a better equalization of the output signal 598.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039"><figref idrefs="f0006">Fig. 6</figref> shows a possible embodiment of a PLL circuit 700 with speed control. PLL circuit 700 comprises a phase shifter 701, integrator 702, loop filter 703, multiplier 704 and phase detector 705. The input signal 706 may be a modulated input signal and the output signal 707 may be a demodulated signal. Based on output signal 707 phase detector 705 determines a phase error signal 708. Phase error signal 708 is multiplied with a speed control signal 709 by multiplier 704.<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --></p><p id="p0040" num="0040">By multiplying phase error signal 708 with speed control signal 709, signal 710 may be increased or decreased in comparison to phase error signal 708. Thus, by setting the multiplication factor, i.e. the magnitude of the speed control signal 709, it is possible to control the speed according to which PLL circuit 700 follows the frequency and/or phase of modulated input signal 706.</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">It should be noted that input signal 706 may correspond to a complex base band signal, e.g. a down converted video signal.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">It should also be noted that multiplier 704 allows for a continuous loop speed control without switching artifacts. For example, speed control signal 709 may be increased or decreased continuously such that no switching artifacts may occur.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043"><figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 7</figref> shows a first diagram 800 depicting an example of a sequence of reference signals 801. In the diagram 800, as an example, reference signals 801 may occur with a certain repeating rate (period) T.</p><p id="p0044" num="0044">Diagram 802 of <figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 7</figref> shows how the speed of a PLL circuit may be controlled. Diagram 802 shows periods 803 where the speed of the PLL is controlled at a normal level v<sub>N</sub>. During periods 803, no reference signal 801 occurs. As seen, a certain period of time 805 before the occurrence of a reference signal 801, the PLL speed is decreased to a lower level v<sub>L</sub>. The lower level v<sub>L</sub> is maintained during a period 806 following the duration of reference signal 801 corresponding to period 804 in diagram 802. Because the speed is already lowered a period of time 805 before the occurrence of a reference signal 801 and maintained until a certain period 806 after the occurrence of a reference signal 801, it may be possible to eliminate any distortions resulting from echoes of the reference signal itself.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045"><figref idrefs="f0008">Fig. 8</figref> shows a diagram according to an embodiment of a method for processing an input signal. In step 900, a phase locked loop is used for following a frequency and/or phase of an input signal at speed V.</p><p id="p0046" num="0046">In step S902, a reference signal is detected. In step S904, it is determined if a reference signal has been detected. If a reference signal has been detected, in step S905, speed V of the phase locked loop is set to a low level V<sub>L</sub>. If in step S904, no reference signal is detected, then in step S906, the speed V of the phase locked loop is set to V<sub>N</sub>, i.e. to a normal speed.<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --></p><p id="p0047" num="0047">It should be noted that as explained in connection with <figref idrefs="f0007">Fig. 7</figref>, it is possible that the speed is decreased to a predetermined level (low level) for a period of time starting before an occurrence of the reference signal and lasting until after the occurrence of a reference signal.</p><p id="p0048" num="0048">In a further embodiment of the invention, a circuit for ghost cancelling of a television signal, may comprise a ghost cancelling reference signal detector configured to detect a ghost cancelling reference signal; a PLL demodulator configured to follow a video carrier frequency and/or phase of said television signal at a speed, wherein said speed is controlled depending on said ghost cancelling reference signal.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">In a further embodiment of the invention, a circuit for equalizing an input signal based on a reference signal, may comprise a phase locked loop demodulator configured to receive a speed control signal and said input signal and further configured to follow a frequency and/or a phase of said input signal, wherein said phase locked loop demodulator includes a speed control mechanism configured to control a following speed of said phase locked loop demodulator, wherein said following speed depends on said speed control signal, and wherein said following speed determines at what speed said phase locked loop demodulator follows said frequency and/or said phase; and a reference signal detector configured to determine said reference signal and to output said speed control signal to said phase locked loop demodulator, wherein, if said reference signal is detected, said speed control signal indicates a lower speed than if no reference signal is detected.</p><p id="p0050" num="0050">In a further embodiment of the invention, a television set configured to receive a television signal, may comprise a ghost cancelling reference signal detector configured to detect a ghost cancelling reference signal; a PLL demodulator configured to follow a video carrier frequency and/or phase of said television signal at a speed, wherein said speed is controlled depending on said ghost cancelling reference signal; and a ghost cancelling equalizer configured to cancel ghosts of said television signal based on said ghost cancelling reference signal.</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">In a further embodiment of the invention, a circuit for equalizing an input signal based on at least one reference signal, may comprise a phase locked loop demodulator configured to receive a speed control signal and said input signal and further configured to follow a frequency and/or a phase of said input signal at a speed, wherein said speed depends on said speed control signal; a reference signal detector configured to determine said at least one reference signal and to set said<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> speed by outputting said speed control signal to said phase locked loop demodulator, wherein, if said reference signal detector detects said at least one reference signal, said reference signal detector sets said speed to a lower speed than if said reference signal detector does not detect said at least one reference signal.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56979230" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Signalverarbeitungsschaltkreis, umfassend:
<claim-text>einen Demodulator mit Phasenregelschleife (201), der konfiguriert ist, ein Geschwindigkeitssteuersignal (207) und ein Eingangssignal (205) zu empfangen und ein demoduliertes Signal (206) auszugeben, und der außerdem konfiguriert ist, einer Frequenz und/oder einer Phase des Eingangssignals (205) mit einer Geschwindigkeit zu folgen, wobei die Geschwindigkeit von dem Geschwindigkeitssteuersignal (207) abhängig ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Bezugssignaldetektor (203), der mit dem Ausgang des Demodulators mit Phasenregelschleife (201) verbunden ist und der konfiguriert ist, ein Bezugssignal innerhalb des demodulierten Signals (206) zu erkennen und die Geschwindigkeit einzustellen, indem er das Geschwindigkeitssteuersignal (207) an den Demodulator mit Phasenregelschleife (201) ausgibt, wobei, wenn der Bezugssignaldetektor (203) das Bezugssignal erkennt, das Geschwindigkeitssteuersignal (207) eine andere Geschwindigkeit anzeigt, als im Fall, wenn kein Bezugssignal erkannt wird, und wobei das Bezugssignal ein Signal ist, das unabhängig vom Eingangssignal oder innerhalb des Eingangssignals (205) übertragen wird.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Signalverarbeitungsschaltkreis nach Anspruch 1,<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> wobei der Bezugssignaldetektor (203) die Geschwindigkeit auf eine vorbestimmte Stufe verringert, wobei die vorbestimmte Stufe niedriger ist als eine normale Stufe, bevor das Bezugssignal erkannt wurde.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Signalverarbeitungsschaltkreis nach Anspruch 1 oder 2, wobei die Geschwindigkeit während eines vorbestimmten Zeitraums verringert wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Signalverarbeitungsschaltkreis nach Anspruch 1 oder 2, wobei die Geschwindigkeit während eines Zeitraums verringert wird, der von der Dauer des Bezugssignals abhängig ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Signalverarbeitungsschaltkreis nach Anspruch 4, wobei der Zeitraum vor einem Auftreten des Bezugssignals beginnt und bis nach dem Auftreten des Bezugssignals dauert.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Signalverarbeitungsschaltkreis nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 5, wobei das Bezugssignal regelmäßig auftritt und eine vorbestimmte Dauer hat.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Signalverarbeitungsschaltkreis nach einem der vorangehenden Ansprüche, wobei der Demodulator mit Phasenregelschleife (201) einen Geschwindigkeitssteuermechanismus umfasst, der konfiguriert ist, die Geschwindigkeit zu steuern.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Signalverarbeitungsschaltkreis nach Anspruch 7, wobei der Geschwindigkeitssteuermechanismus eine Multipliziereinheit ist, die in einem Rückkopplungspfad des Demodulators mit Phasenregelschleife (201) angeordnet ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Signalverarbeitungsschaltkreis nach Anspruch 8, wobei die Multipliziereinheit konfiguriert ist, einen Phasenfehler mit dem Geschwindigkeitssteuersignal (207) oder einer Ableitung davon zu multiplizieren.<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Signalverarbeitungsschaltkreis nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei das Geschwindigkeitssteuersignal (207) eine Nullgeschwindigkeit anzeigt, wenn der Bezugssignaldetektor (203) das Bezugssignal erkennt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Signalverarbeitungsschaltkreis nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei der Bezugssignaldetektor (203) außerdem konfiguriert ist, die Geschwindigkeit während eines ersten vorbestimmten Zeitraums vor einem Auftreten des Bezugssignals auf Null zu setzen und die Nullgeschwindigkeit bis zu einem zweiten vorbestimmten Zeitraum nach dem Auftreten des Bezugssignals beizubehalten.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Signalverarbeitungsschaltkreis nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, umfassend<br/>
einen Entzerrer, der konfiguriert ist, das Eingangssignal (205) zu entzerren;<br/>
einen Datenprozessor, der konfiguriert ist, Filterkoeffizienten für den Entzerrer auf der Grundlage des Bezugssignals zu bestimmen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Signalverarbeitungsschaltkreis nach einem der vorhergehenden Ansprüche, wobei das Eingangssignal (205) ein analoges Fernsehsignal ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Empfänger, der einen Signalverarbeitungsschaltkreis nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 13 umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Entzerrerschaltkreis, der einen Signalverarbeitungsschaltkreis nach einem der Ansprüche 1 bis 13 umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0016" num="0016"><claim-text>Geisterbildlöschschaltkreis für Fernsehsignale, umfassend:
<claim-text>den Signalverarbeitungsschaltkreis nach einem<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> der Ansprüche 1 bis 13, wobei</claim-text>
<claim-text>der Bezugssignaldetektor (203) ein Bezugssignaldetektor (203) für ein Geisterbildlöschen ist, der konfiguriert ist, ein Bezugssignal für ein Geisterbildlöschen als das Bezugssignal zu erkennen; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>das Eingangssignal (205) ein Fernsehsignal ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0017" num="0017"><claim-text>Fernsehgerät, das konfiguriert ist, ein Fernsehsignal zu empfangen, umfassend:
<claim-text>den Geisterbildlöschschaltkreis nach Anspruch 16; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Entzerrer für ein Geisterbildlöschen, der konfiguriert ist, Geisterbilder auf der Grundlage des Bezugssignals für ein Geisterbildlöschen aus dem Fernsehsignal zu löschen.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0018" num="0018"><claim-text>Signalverarbeitungsverfahren, umfassend:
<claim-text>Folgen einer Frequenz und/oder einer Phase eines Eingangssignals (205) mit einer Geschwindigkeit, wobei eine Phasenregelschleife verwendet wird;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Ausgeben eines demodulierten Signals (206) von der Phasenregelschleife;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Erkennen eines Bezugssignals innerhalb des demodulierten Signals (206), wobei das Bezugssignal ein Signal ist, das unabhängig vom Eingangssignal oder innerhalb des Eingangssignals (205) übertragen wird;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Einstellen der Geschwindigkeit, wobei, wenn das Bezugssignal erkannt wird, eine andere Geschwindigkeit eingestellt wird, als im Fall, wenn kein Bezugssignal erkannt wird.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0019" num="0019"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 18, wobei die Geschwindigkeit auf eine vorbestimmte Stufe verringert wird, wobei die vorbestimmte Stufe niedriger ist als eine normale Stufe, bevor das mindestens ein Bezugssignal erkannt wurde.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0020" num="0020"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 18 oder 19, wobei die<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> Geschwindigkeit während eines vorbestimmten Zeitraums verringert wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0021" num="0021"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 18 oder 19, wobei die Geschwindigkeit während eines Zeitraums verringert wird, der von der Dauer des mindestens einen Bezugssignals abhängig ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0022" num="0022"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 21, wobei der Zeitraum vor einem Auftreten des Bezugssignals beginnt und bis nach dem Auftreten des Bezugssignals dauert.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0023" num="0023"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 18 bis 22, wobei das Bezugssignal regelmäßig auftritt und eine vorbestimmte Dauer hat.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0024" num="0024"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 18 bis 23, wobei die Geschwindigkeit gesteuert wird, indem ein Phasenfehler in dem Rückkopplungspfad der Phasenregelschleife mit einem Geschwindigkeitssteuerfaktor multipliziert wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0025" num="0025"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 18 bis 24, wobei die Geschwindigkeit auf Null gesetzt wird, wenn das Bezugssignal erkannt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0026" num="0026"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 18 bis 25, das ein Entzerren des Eingangssignals (205) auf der Grundlage von Filterkoeffizienten umfasst, wobei die Filterkoeffizienten auf der Grundlage des Bezugssignals bestimmt werden.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0027" num="0027"><claim-text>Verfahren nach einem der Ansprüche 18 bis 26, wobei das Eingangssignal (205) ein analoges Fernsehsignal ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0028" num="0028"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 27, wobei das Bezugssignal ein Bezugssignal für ein Geisterbildlöschen in dem analogen Fernsehsignal ist.<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0029" num="0029"><claim-text>Computerprogrammprodukt, das Computerprogrammbefehle enthält, die einen Computer veranlassen ein Signalverarbeitungsverfahren nach Anspruch 18 auszuführen, das umfasst:
<claim-text>Folgen einer Frequenz und/oder einer Phase eines Eingangssignals (205) mit einer Geschwindigkeit, wobei eine Phasenregelschleife verwendet wird;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Ausgeben eines demodulierten Signals (206) von der Phasenregelschleife;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Erkennen eines Bezugssignals innerhalb des demodulierten Signals (206), wobei das Bezugssignal ein Signal ist, das unabhängig vom Eingangssignal oder innerhalb des Eingangssignals (205) übertragen wird;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Einstellen der Geschwindigkeit, wobei, wenn das Bezugssignal erkannt wird, eine andere Geschwindigkeit eingestellt wird, als im Fall, wenn kein Bezugssignal erkannt wird.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56979231" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A signal processing circuit comprising:
<claim-text>a phase locked loop demodulator (201) configured to receive a speed control signal (207) and an input signal (205) and to output a demodulated signal (206) and further configured to follow a frequency and/or a phase of said input signal (205) at a speed, wherein said speed depends on said speed control signal (207); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a reference signal detector (203) coupled to the output of the phase locked loop demodulator (201) configured to detect a reference signal within the demodulated signal (206) and to set said speed by outputting said speed control signal (207) to said phase locked loop demodulator (201), wherein, if said reference signal detector (203) detects said reference signal, said speed control signal (207) indicates a different speed than if no reference signal is detected and wherein the reference signal is a signal that is transmitted independently of or within the input signal (205).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The signal processing circuit according to claim 1, wherein said reference signal detector (203) decreases said speed to a predetermined level, said predetermined level being lower than a normal level before said reference signal was detected.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The signal processing circuit according to claim 1 or 2, wherein said speed is decreased for a predetermined period of time.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The signal processing circuit according to claim 1 or 2, wherein said speed is decreased for a period of time which depends on the duration of said reference signal.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The signal processing circuit according to claim 4, wherein said period of time starts before an occurrence of said reference signal and lasts until after said occurrence of said reference signal.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The signal processing circuit according to any of claims 1 to 5, wherein said reference signal occurs periodically and has a predetermined duration.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The signal processing circuit according to any of the preceding claims, wherein said phase locked loop demodulator (201) comprises a speed control mechanism configured to control said speed.<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The signal processing circuit according to claim 7, wherein said speed control mechanism is a multiplier arranged in a feedback path of said phase locked loop demodulator (201).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The signal processing circuit according to claim 8, wherein said multiplier is configured to multiply a phase error with said speed control signal (207) or a derivative thereof.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The signal processing circuit according to any of the preceding claims, wherein said speed control signal (207) indicates zero speed, if said reference signal detector (203) detects said reference signal.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>The signal processing circuit according to any of the preceding claims, wherein said reference signal detector (203) is further configured to set said speed to zero a first predetermined period of time before an occurrence of said reference signal and to maintain zero speed until a second predetermined period of time after said occurrence of said reference signal.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>The signal processing circuit according to any of the preceding claims, comprising<br/>
an equalizer configured to equalize said input signal (205);<br/>
a data processor configured to determine filter coefficients for said equalizer based on said reference signal.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>The signal processing circuit according to any of the preceding claims, wherein said input signal (205) is an analogue television signal.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>A receiver comprising a signal processing circuit according to any of claims 1 to 13.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>An equalizer circuit comprising a signal processing circuit according to any of claims 1 to 13.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0016" num="0016"><claim-text>A ghost cancelling circuit for television signals, comprising:
<claim-text>the signal processing circuit according to any of claims 1 to 13, wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>the reference signal detector (203) is a ghost cancelling reference signal detector (203) configured to detect a ghost cancelling reference signal as said reference signal; and<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>the input signal (205) is a television signal.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0017" num="0017"><claim-text>Television set configured to receive a television signal, comprising:
<claim-text>the ghost cancelling circuit of claim 16; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a ghost cancelling equalizer configured to cancel ghosts of said television signal based on said ghost cancelling reference signal.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0018" num="0018"><claim-text>A signal processing method comprising:
<claim-text>following a frequency and/or a phase of an input signal (205) at a speed using a phase locked loop;</claim-text>
<claim-text>outputting a demodulated signal (206) from the phase locked loop;</claim-text>
<claim-text>detecting a reference signal within the demodulated signal (206), wherein the reference signal is a signal that is transmitted independently of or within the input signal (205);</claim-text>
<claim-text>setting said speed, wherein, if said reference signal is detected, a different speed is set than if no reference signal is detected.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0019" num="0019"><claim-text>Method according to claim 18, wherein said speed is decreased to a predetermined level, said predetermined level being lower than a normal level before said at least one reference signal was detected.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0020" num="0020"><claim-text>Method according to claim 18 or 19, wherein said speed is decreased for a predetermined period of time.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0021" num="0021"><claim-text>Method according to claim 18 or 19, wherein said speed is decreased for a period of time which depends on the duration of said at least one reference signal.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0022" num="0022"><claim-text>Method according to claim 21, wherein said period of time starts before an occurrence of said reference signal and lasts until after said occurrence of said reference signal.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0023" num="0023"><claim-text>Method according to any of claims 18 to 22, wherein said reference signal occurs periodically and has a predetermined duration.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0024" num="0024"><claim-text>Method according to any of claims 18 to 23, wherein said speed is controlled by multiplying a phase error in the feedback path of said phase locked loop with a speed control factor.<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0025" num="0025"><claim-text>Method according to any of claims 18 to 24, wherein said speed is set to zero, if said reference signal is detected.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0026" num="0026"><claim-text>Method according to any of claims 18 to 25, comprising equalizing said input signal (205) based on filter coefficients, wherein said filter coefficients are determined based on said reference signal.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0027" num="0027"><claim-text>Method according to any of claims 18 to 26, wherein said input signal (205) is an analogue television signal.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0028" num="0028"><claim-text>Method according to claim 27, wherein said reference signal is a ghost canceling reference signal of said analogue television signal.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0029" num="0029"><claim-text>A computer program product including computer program instructions that cause a computer to execute a signal processing method of claim 18 comprising:
<claim-text>following a frequency and/or a phase of an input signal (205) at a speed using a phase locked loop;</claim-text>
<claim-text>outputting a demodulated signal (206) from the phase locked loop;</claim-text>
<claim-text>detecting a reference signal within the demodulated signal (206), wherein the reference signal is a signal that is transmitted independently of or within the input signal (205);</claim-text>
<claim-text>setting said speed, wherein, if said reference signal is detected, a different speed is set than if no reference signal is detected.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56979232" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Circuit de traitement de signal comprenant :
<claim-text>un démodulateur à boucle de verrouillage de phase (201) configuré pour recevoir un signal de contrôle de vitesse (207) et un signal d'entrée (205) et pour délivrer en sortie un signal démodulé (206) et en outre configuré pour suivre une fréquence et/ou une phase dudit signal d'entrée (205) à une certaine vitesse, où ladite vitesse dépend dudit signal de contrôle de vitesse (207) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un détecteur de signal de référence (203) couplé à la sortie du démodulateur à boucle de verrouillage de phase (201) configuré pour détecter un signal de référence dans le signal démodulé (206) et pour définir ladite vitesse en délivrant en sortie ledit signal de contrôle de vitesse (207) audit démodulateur à boucle de verrouillage de phase (201), où, si ledit détecteur de signal de référence (203) détecte ledit signal de référence, ledit signal de contrôle de vitesse (207) indique une vitesse différente par rapport au cas où aucun signal de référence n'est détecté et où le signal de référence est un signal qui est transmis indépendamment de ou dans le signal d'entrée (205).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Circuit de traitement de signal selon la revendication 1, dans lequel ledit détecteur de signal de référence (203) diminue ladite vitesse à un niveau<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> prédéterminé, ledit niveau prédéterminé étant plus bas qu'un niveau normal avant que ledit signal de référence ne soit détecté.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Circuit de traitement de signal selon la revendication 1 ou la revendication 2, dans lequel ladite vitesse est diminuée pour une période de temps prédéterminée.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Circuit de traitement de signal selon la revendication 1 ou la revendication 2, dans lequel ladite vitesse est diminuée pour une période de temps qui dépend de la durée dudit signal de référence.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Circuit de traitement de signal selon la revendication 4, dans lequel ladite période de temps commence avant une occurrence dudit signal de référence et dure jusqu'après ladite occurrence dudit signal de référence.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Circuit de traitement de signal selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 5, dans lequel ledit signal de référence se produit périodiquement et a une durée prédéterminée.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Circuit de traitement de signal selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans lequel ledit démodulateur à boucle de verrouillage de phase (201) comprend un mécanisme de contrôle de vitesse configuré pour contrôler ladite vitesse.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Circuit de traitement de signal selon la revendication 7, dans lequel ledit mécanisme de contrôle de vitesse est un multiplicateur disposé dans un chemin de rétroaction dudit démodulateur à boucle de verrouillage de phase (201).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Circuit de traitement de signal selon la revendication 8, dans lequel ledit multiplicateur est<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --> configuré pour multiplier une erreur de phase par ledit signal de contrôle de vitesse (207) ou un dérivé de celui-ci.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Circuit de traitement de signal selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans lequel ledit signal de contrôle de vitesse (207) indique une vitesse nulle, si ledit détecteur de signal de référence (203) détecte ledit signal de référence.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Circuit de traitement de signal selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans lequel ledit détecteur de signal de référence (203) est en outre configuré pour définir ladite vitesse à zéro pendant une première période de temps prédéterminée avant une occurrence dudit signal de référence et pour maintenir une vitesse nulle jusqu'à une seconde période de temps prédéterminée après ladite occurrence dudit signal de référence.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Circuit de traitement de signal selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, comprenant :
<claim-text>un égaliseur configuré pour égaliser ledit signal d'entrée (205) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un processeur de données configuré pour déterminer des coefficients de filtrage pour ledit égaliseur sur la base dudit signal de référence.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Circuit de traitement de signal selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans lequel ledit signal d'entrée (205) est un signal de télévision analogique.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Récepteur comprenant un circuit de traitement de signal selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 13.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Circuit d'égalisation comprenant un circuit de traitement de signal selon l'une quelconque des<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --> revendications 1 à 13.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0016" num="0016"><claim-text>Circuit de suppression d'image fantôme pour des signaux de télévision, comprenant :
<claim-text>le circuit de traitement de signal selon l'une quelconque des revendications 1 à 13, dans lequel</claim-text>
<claim-text>le détecteur de signal de référence (203) est un détecteur de signal de référence de suppression d'image fantôme (203) configuré pour détecter un signal de référence de suppression d'image fantôme comme ledit signal de référence ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>le signal d'entrée (205) est un signal de télévision.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0017" num="0017"><claim-text>Poste de télévision configuré pour recevoir un signal de télévision, comprenant :
<claim-text>le circuit de suppression d'image fantôme de la revendication 16 ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un égaliseur de suppression d'image fantôme configuré pour supprimer des images fantôme dudit signal de télévision sur la base dudit signal de référence de suppression d'image fantôme.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0018" num="0018"><claim-text>Procédé de traitement de signal comprenant les étapes suivantes :
<claim-text>suivre une fréquence et/ou une phase d'un signal d'entrée (205) à une certaine vitesse au moyen d'une boucle de verrouillage de phase ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>délivrer en sortie un signal démodulé (206) à partir de la boucle de verrouillage de phase ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>détecter un signal de référence dans le signal démodulé (206), où le signal de référence est un signal qui est transmis indépendamment de ou dans le signal d'entrée (205) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>définir ladite vitesse, où, si ledit signal de référence est détecté, une vitesse différente est définie par rapport au cas où aucun signal de référence n'est détecté.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0019" num="0019"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 18, dans lequel ladite vitesse est diminuée à un niveau prédéterminé, ledit niveau prédéterminé étant plus bas qu'un niveau normal avant que ledit au moins un signal de référence n'ait été détecté.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0020" num="0020"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 18 ou la revendication 19, dans lequel ladite vitesse est diminuée pour une période de temps prédéterminée.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0021" num="0021"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 18 ou la revendication 19, dans lequel ladite vitesse est diminuée pour une période de temps qui dépend de la durée dudit au moins un signal de référence.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0022" num="0022"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 21, dans lequel ladite période de temps commence avant une occurrence dudit signal de référence et dure jusqu'après ladite occurrence dudit signal de référence.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0023" num="0023"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications 18 à 22, dans lequel ledit signal de référence se produit périodiquement et a une durée prédéterminée.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0024" num="0024"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications 18 à 23, dans lequel ladite vitesse est contrôlée en multipliant une erreur de phase dans le chemin de rétroaction de ladite boucle de verrouillage de phase par un facteur de contrôle de vitesse.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0025" num="0025"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications 18 à 24, dans lequel ladite vitesse est définie à zéro, si ledit signal de référence est détecté.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0026" num="0026"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications 18 à 25, comprenant d'égaliser ledit signal d'entrée (205) sur la base de coefficients de filtrage, où lesdits coefficients de filtrage sont déterminés sur la base dudit signal de référence.<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0027" num="0027"><claim-text>Procédé selon l'une quelconque des revendications 18 à 26, dans lequel ledit signal d'entrée (205) est un signal de télévision analogique.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0028" num="0028"><claim-text>Procédé selon la revendication 27, dans lequel ledit signal de référence est un signal de référence de suppression d'image fantôme dudit signal de télévision analogique.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0029" num="0029"><claim-text>Produit programme informatique comprenant des instructions de programme informatique qui amènent un ordinateur à exécuter un procédé de traitement de signal de la revendication 18 comprenant les étapes suivantes :
<claim-text>suivre une fréquence et/ou une phase d'un signal d'entrée (205) à une certaine vitesse au moyen d'une boucle de verrouillage de phase ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>délivrer en sortie un signal démodulé (206) à partir de la boucle de verrouillage de phase ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>détecter un signal de référence dans le signal démodulé (206), où le signal de référence est un signal qui est transmis indépendamment de ou dans le signal d'entrée (205) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>définir ladite vitesse, où, si ledit signal de référence est détecté, une vitesse différente est définie par rapport au cas où aucun signal de référence n'est détecté.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16668807" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="107" he="169" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="99" he="184" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="131" he="141" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --><figure id="f0004" num="4"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="146" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --><figure id="f0005" num="5"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="123" he="219" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --><figure id="f0006" num="6"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="124" he="177" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --><figure id="f0007" num="7"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="105" he="230" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --><figure id="f0008" num="8"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="116" he="139" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
