<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2012376-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2012376" kind="B1" date="20140101" family-id="26633505" file-reference-id="311080" date-produced="20180822" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146554284" ucid="EP-2012376-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2012376</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-08166285-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154828207" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>08166285</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>19990310</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP204139974" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>08166285.0</doc-number><date>19990310</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140446560" ucid="EP-99301808-A" linkage-type="3" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>99301808</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>19990310</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140445873" ucid="KR-19980007901-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>KR</country><doc-number>19980007901</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>19980310</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140445594" ucid="KR-19980019608-U" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>KR</country><doc-number>19980019608</doc-number><kind>U</kind><date>19981014</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130809</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988095689" load-source="docdb">H01M  10/05        20100101ALI20130710BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988116108" load-source="docdb">H01M   2/02        20060101AFI20051220RMJP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988132522" load-source="docdb">H01M   2/06        20060101AFI20130710BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988138706" load-source="docdb">H01M   2/08        20060101ALI20130710BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2102339713" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01M  10/05        20130101 LA20140728BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2102341336" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01M   2/08        20130101 LI20140728BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL2102344340" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01M   2/06        20130101 FI20140728BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132195336" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Sekundärbatterie</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132195337" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Sealing structure in a secondary battery</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132195338" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Batterie secondaire</invention-title></technical-data><related-documents><relation type="division"><child-doc ucid="EP-08166285-A"><document-id load-source="patent-office" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>08166285</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>19990310</date></document-id></child-doc><parent-doc ucid="EP-99301808.4"><document-id load-source="patent-office" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>99301808.4</doc-number><date>19990310</date></document-id></parent-doc></relation></related-documents><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918135831" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>SAMSUNG DISPLAY DEVICES CO LTD</last-name><address><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918166428" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>SAMSUNG DISPLAY DEVICES CO., LTD.</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918143742" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>KIM HAN-SUNG</last-name><address><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918140428" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>KIM, HAN-SUNG</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918999296" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>KIM, HAN-SUNG</last-name><address><street>1-203 Ssangyong Moran Apt. Ssangyong-dong</street><city>Cheonan-city Chungcheongnam-do</city><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918162173" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>ROH WHAN-JIN</last-name><address><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918141399" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>ROH, WHAN-JIN</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918999295" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>ROH, WHAN-JIN</last-name><address><street>Na-803 Samho Garden Mansion Banpo-dong</street><city>Seocho-gu Seoul</city><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918152277" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>NOH HYUNG-GON</last-name><address><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918135565" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>NOH, HYUNG-GON</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918999297" load-source="patent-office" sequence="3" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>NOH, HYUNG-GON</last-name><address><street>29 Hwa-Dong, Jongno-gu</street><city>Seoul</city><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918999299" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Samsung Display Devices Co., Ltd.</last-name><iid>101396338</iid><address><street>575, Shin-dong, Paldal-gu</street><city>Suwon-si Kyungki-do 445-970</city><country>KR</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918999298" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Greene, Simon Kenneth</last-name><iid>100044086</iid><address><street>Elkington and Fife LLP Prospect House 8 Pembroke Road</street><city>Sevenoaks Kent TN13 1XR</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548888105" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548993052" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548832722" load-source="docdb">GB</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63957703" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to a secondary battery, and more particularly, to a secondary battery having an improved seal structure between electrode tabs acting as terminals of the battery and a case, thereby preventing leakage of electrolyte.</p><p id="p0002" num="0002">As portable wireless electronic apparatuses such as a camcorder, cellular phone or laptop computer becomes lighter and requires high functionality, a high performance secondary battery is regarded as a driving power source. Such secondary battery includes nickel-cadmium battery, nickel-hydrogen battery, nickel-zinc battery, lithium secondary battery and the like. In particular, the lithium secondary battery has a long life span and large capacity.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">The lithium secondary battery is classified into a Li metal battery and a Li ion battery both using a liquid electrolyte, and a Li polymer battery using a polymer solid electrolyte, according to the type of electrolyte.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">The Li polymer battery is classified into a complete solid type Li polymer battery which does not contain an organic liquid electrolyte at all, and a Li ion polymer battery using a gel type polymer electrolyte containing small amounts of organic liquid electrolytes, according to the type of polymer solid electrolyte.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">Thus, leakage of the organic liquid electrolyte is serious in the case of the secondary battery containing a organic liquid electrolyte, e.g. Li ion polymer battery, while the<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> complete solid type Li polymer battery has nothing to do with the leakage problem of organic liquid electrolyte.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006"><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is an exploded perspective view showing an example of a conventional secondary battery.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>, the secondary battery includes a battery body 14 in which a positive electrode (not shown), a negative electrode (not shown) and a separator(not shown) are stacked, and a dielectric package 15 for sealing around the battery body 14. The, the battery body 14 and electrode tabs 17 and 17' acting as electrical paths for inducing current formed in the battery body 14 to the outside are connected by connection tabs 16 and 16' respectively provided on the positive and negative electrodes, and the electrode tabs 17 and 17' are installed to be exposed outward by a predetermined length.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">The dielectric package 15 is in the form of a dielectric film obtained by forming a heat sealable material layer on a metal base such as aluminum thin film. The dielectric package 15 seals the battery body 14 as follows. That is, while the positive electrode tabs 17 and 17' are partially exposed to the outside of the dielectric package 15, the battery body 14 is put on the dielectric package 15. Then, the dielectric package 15 is folded in half, and the pressure and heat are applied thereto such that the heat sealable material layers formed along the edges of an upper dielectric package 15a and a lower dielectric package 15b adhere to each other, thereby sealing the battery body 14.<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --></p><p id="p0009" num="0009"><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> is a section view showing the sealing state between the dielectric package 15 and the electrode tabs 17 and 17' of the conventional secondary battery shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>, upper and lower surfaces of the electrode tabs 17 and 17' are surrounded by the upper and lower dielectric packages 15a and 15b. However, spaces 19 through which the leakage of the organic liquid electrolyte can be made are uaually formed at both sides of the electrode tabs 17 and 17'. Such spaces at both sides of the electrode tabs disrupt complete sealing, the detailed reason of which are as follows.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">First, adhesive force between metals forming the electrode tabs 17 and 17' and the heat sealable material layer of the dielectric package 15 is weak. Second, the fluidity of the heat sealable material layer of the dielectric package 15 is poor. That is, for complete sealing, the heat sealable material layer of the dielectric package 15 should show good fluidity when melted by the pressure and heat applied for sealing so as to be flowed into the sides of the electrode tabs 17 and 17' to fill the spaces. However, due to the poor fluidity of the heat sealable material layer, the spaces formed at the sides of the electrode tabs 17 and 17' are not well filled.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">Thus, in the conventional secondary battery, the incomplete sealing near the electrode tabs 17 and 17', between the upper and lower dielectric packages 15a and 15b, leaks the organic liquid electrolyte, thereby deteriorating charging and discharging property and reducing the life span of the battery.<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p><p id="p0013" num="0013"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="WO9708762A"><text>WO 97/08762</text></patcit> teaches a sealed battery tab in which heat sealable material is provided on the outside of a battery tab to seal to a protective package.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">A sealed electrolyte cell is described in <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="WO9740540A"><text>WO 97/40540</text></patcit> - wires are sealed by heat sealing.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015"><patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="EP862227A"><text>EP 862 227</text></patcit>, which was not published at the priority date of the present case, teaches a cell having a moisture-proofing film which seals to electrode terminals formed of a netted or porous material.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016"><patcit id="pcit0004" dnum="EP938145A"><text>EP 938 145</text></patcit>, which was not published at the filing date of the present invention, teaches a lead for a lithium ion secondary cell with a variety of materials used for a fusion-bonding seal mateiral sounding a lead and a sealant layer as part of the packaging.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">According to the present invention, there is provided a secondary battery according to claim 1.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">Preferably, in the secondary battery of the present invention, the sealing materials each have side arms extended towards both sides by a predetermined length.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">Preferably, in the secondary battery of the present invention, the dielectric package material is formed of ionomer.<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></p><p id="p0020" num="0020">In the secondary battery of present invention, the sealing materials are formed of polypropylene resin.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">Preferably, in the secondary battery of present invention, the ionomer is obtained by adding one of sodium (Na), potassium (K), magnesium (Mg) and zinc (Zn) to a copolymer of ethylene and acrylic acid to neutralize carboxylic acid of its side chain.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">Preferably, in the secondary battery of present invention, the separator is solid type separator, gel type separator, or hybrid type separator.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">Examples of the present invention will now be described in detail with reference to the accompanying drawings, in which:
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is an exploded perspective view of an example of a conventional secondary battery;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> is a section view showing the sealing state between a dielectric package and electrode tabs in the conventional secondary battery shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref>;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> is an exploded perspective view of a secondary battery according to a preferred embodiment of the present invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 4</figref> is a section view showing in detail a sealing portion between electrode tabs and upper and lower dielectric packages in the secondary battery shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3</figref>;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 5</figref> is an exploded perspective view of a secondary battery according to another embodiment of the present invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 6</figref> is a section view showing in detail a sealing portion between electrode tabs and upper and lower dielectric packages in the secondary battery shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 5</figref>; and,</li><li><figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 7</figref> is a view illustrating a method for coating sealing materials having side arms on the electrode tabs of the secondary battery shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 5</figref>.</li></ul><!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --></p><p id="p0024" num="0024">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3</figref>, a secondary battery according to the present invention includes a battery body 20 in which a positive electrode (not shown), a negative electrode (not shown) and a separator (not shown) are stacked, and a dielectric package 30 for sealing around the battery body 20. Also, electrode tabs 23 and 23' acting as electrical paths for inducing current generated in the battery body 20 to the outside are connected to the battery body 20 by connection tabs 21 and 21' respectively provided on the positive and negative electrodes. Predetermined surface portions of the electrode tabs 23 and 23' are pre-coated with sealing materials 25 and 25'.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">The dielectric package 30 is in the form of a film obtained by forming a heat sealable material layer on a metal base such as aluminum thin film.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">The dielectric package 30 seals the battery body 20 as follows. That is, while the electrode tabs 23 and 23' are partially exposed to the outside of the dielectric package 30, the battery body 20 is put on the dielectric package 30, and then the dielectric<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> package 30 is folded in half. The folded dielectric package 30 is heated under pressure such that the heat sealable material layers of the upper and lower dielectric packages 30a and 30b adhere to each other at the edge portions. The sealing materials 25 and 25' pre-coated on the predetermined surface portions of the electrode tabs 23 and 23' are interposed between the edge portions of the upper and lower dielectric packages 30a and 30b, so that sealing materials 25 and 25' are fused together with the heat sealable material layers of the upper and lower dielectric packages 30a and 30b to completely fill spaces(19, 19' of <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig 2</figref>) formed at both sides of the sealing portions between the electrode tabs 23 and 23' and the the upper and lower dielectric packages 30a and 30b, thereby preventing the organic liquid electrolyte from leaking through the spaces.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">For strong adhesiveness, the sealing materials 25 and 25' coated on the electrode tabs 23 and 23' are formed of the same material as that for the heat sealable material layer formed on the inner surface of the metal base. In addition, the sealing materials 25 and 25' are formed of polypropylene resin.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">The sealing materials 25 and 25' are coated on the electrode tabs 23 and 23' in several ways, one of which is as follows. The surfaces of the electrode tabs 23 or 23' are etched using acid for several seconds and cleaned using hydrogen peroxide to remove impurities. Then, a suitable adhesive is applied on the surfaces of the electrode tabs 23 and 23'. Then, the upper and lower surfaces of the electrode tabs 23 and 23' are<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> respectively covered with a sheet of film formed of heat sealable material, and then pressed while supplying heat thereto, thereby completing coating of predetermined portions of the electrode tabs 23 and 23' with the sealing materials 25 and 25'. Alternatively, the sealing materials 25 and 25' may be coated by injection molding. Preferably, the electrode tabs 23 and 23' are as thick as 10∼100µm and the sealing materials 25 and 25' are coated on the electrode tabs 23 and 23' to a thickness of 5∼50µm. If the thickness of the sealing materials 25 and 25' each coated on the electrode tabs 23 and 23' is less than 5µm, the sealing materials 25 and 25' are pushed out while being pressed under heat and pressure, thereby resulting in incomplete sealing. If the thickness of the sealing materials 25 and 25' exceeds 50µm, spaces may be formed at both sides of the electrode tabs 23 and 23'.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029"><figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 4</figref> is a section view showing in detail the sealing portions between the electrode tabs 23 and 23' and upper and lower dielectric packages 30a and 30b.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 4</figref>, the upper and lower surfaces of the electrode tabs 23 and 23' are enclosed by the upper and lower dielectric packages 30a and 30b while the electrode tabs 23 and 23' are partially exposed to the outside of the dielectric package 30. Here, the sealing materials 25 and 25' pre-coated on the electrode tabs 23 and 23' are interposed between the edges of the upper and lower dielectric packages 30a and 30b, thereby completely sealing the electrode tabs 23 and 23' with the dielectric package 30. This is because the sealing materials 25 and 25' are fused by the heat and pressure applied for the sealing to completely fill the spaces between electrode tabs 23 and 23' and the dielectric package 30.<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --></p><p id="p0031" num="0031">Also, in the leakage preventing effect of the organic liquid electrolyte, when the conventional Li ion polymer battery having the structure of <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>, containing 3g of organic liquid electrolyte, is left at 90°C under a pressure of 0.2atm, the organic liquid electrolyte leaks after 20 minutes. However, the Li ion polymer battery having the structure of <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 4</figref> according to the present invention leaks organic liquid electrolyte after 16 hours under the same conditions.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032"><figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 5</figref> is an exploded perspective view of a secondary battery according to another embodiment of the present invention.<br/>
Referring to <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 5</figref>, the secondary battery comprises a battery body 50 in which a positive electrode (not shown), a negative electrode (not shown) and a separator (not shown) are stacked, and a dielectric package 70 for sealing around the battery body 50. Also, electrode tabs 53 and 53' acting as electrical paths for inducing current generated in the battery body 50 to the outside are connected to the battery body 50 by connection tabs 51 and 51' respectively provided on the positive and negative electrodes. Predetermined surface portions of the electrode tabs 53 and 53' are pre-coated with<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> sealing materials 25 and 25' each having side arms extended laterally by a predetermined length.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">The method for sealing the secondary battery with the dielectric package 70 is the same as that illustrated with reference to <figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3</figref>. That is, while the electrode tabs 53 and 53' are partially exposed to the outside of the dielectric package 70, the battery body 50 is put on the dielectric package 70, and then the dielectric package 70 is folded in half. The folded dielectric package 70 is heated under pressure such that the heat sealable material layers of the upper and lower dielectric packages 70a and 70b adhere to each other at the edge portions. The sealing materials 55 and 55' having side arms, pre-coated on the predetermined surface portions of the electrode tabs 53 and 53' are interposed between the edge portions of the upper and lower dielectric packages 70a and 70b, so that the sealing materials 55 and 55' having side arms are fused together with the heat sealable material layers of the upper and lower dielectric packages 70a and 70b to completely fill spaces(19, 19' of <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>) formed at both sides of the sealing portions between the electrode tabs 53 and 53' and the the upper and lower dielectric packages 70a and 70b" thereby preventing the organic liquid electrolyte from leaking through the spaces.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">For strong adhesiveness, the sealing materials 55 and 55' having side arms coated on the electrode tabs 53 and 53' are formed of the same material as that for the heat sealable material layer formed on the inner surface of the metal base. In addition, the sealing materials 55 and 55' having side arms capable of adhering to the heat sealable material layer formed on the inner surface of the metal base by heat under pressure are formed of polypropylene resin.<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --></p><p id="p0035" num="0035"><figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 6</figref> is a section view showing in detail the sealing portions between the electrode tabs 53, 53' and upper and lower dielectric packages 70a and 70b of the secondary battery shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 5</figref>.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 6</figref>, the upper and lower surfaces of the electrode tabs 53 and 53' are enclosed by the upper and lower dielectric packages 70a and 70b while the electrode tabs 53 and 53' are partially exposed to the outside of the dielectric package 70. Here, the sealing materials 55 and 55' each having side arms, pre-coated on the electrode tabs 53 and 53' are interposed between the edges of the upper and lower dielectric packages 70a and 70b, thereby completely sealing the electrode tabs 53 and 53' with the dielectric package 70. This is because the sealing materials 55 and 55' each having side arms are fused by the heat and pressure applied for the sealing to completely seal the spaces between electrode tabs 53 and 53' and the dielectric package 70.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037"><figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 7</figref> illustrates a method for coating the sealing material 55 having side arms on the electrode tab 53 of the secondary battery shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 5</figref>.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">That is, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 7</figref>, the electrode tap 53 is put on a frame 81 having a depression 80 having the same size as that of the side arms of the sealing material 55, and a solution obtained by dissolving ionomer in isopropyl alcohol is pour into the depression 80. Then, the resulting product is aged at 70°C for 6 hours, thereby completing the coating of the electrode tab 53 with the sealing material 55 having side arms.<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> completing the coating of the electrode tab 53 with the sealing material 55 having side arms.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">As described above, the secondary battery according to the present invention has an enhanced sealing property between the electrode tabs and the dielectric package, thereby effectively preventing leakage of organic liquid electrolyte. As a result, the charging and discharging property and the life span of the secondary battery are improved.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980598" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Akkumulator, umfassend:
<claim-text>einen Batteriekörper (20, 50) mit einer positiven Elektrode, einer negativen Elektrode und einer Trennvorrichtung, welche gestapelt sind, und Elektrodenfahnen (23, 23', 53, 53') zum Induzieren von Strom, welcher darin erzeugt wird, nach außen;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine dielektrische Packung (30, 70) mit einer oberen (30a, 70a) und einer unteren (30b, 70b) dielektrischen Packung, wobei die Packungen eine Metallbasis und eine heiß versiegelbare Metallschicht umfassen, die auf der inneren Oberfläche der Metallbasis zum Einschließen des Batteriekörpers (20, 50) durch Versiegeln von Kantenabschnitten der oberen (30a, 70a) und der unteren (30b, 70b) dielektrischen Packung ausgeformt ist, während die Elektrodenfahnen (23, 23', 53, 53') teilweise außen freiliegen; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Versiegelungsmaterialien (25, 25', 55, 55'), welche auf Abschnitten der Elektrodenfahnen (23, 23', 53, 53') mit Kantenabschnitten der oberen und der unteren dielektrischen Packung als Schicht aufgebracht sind, wobei die Versiegelungsmaterialien Seitenarme aufweisen, welche parallel mit den Kantenabschnitten der oberen und der unteren dielektrischen Packung erstreckt sind, um Leckschlagen eines organischen flüssigen Elektrolyts zu verhindern, während sie zwischen den Kantenabschnitten der oberen (30a, 70a) und der unteren (30b, 70b) dielektrischen Packung zwischengelegt und verschmolzen sind;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>die Versiegelungsmaterialien (25, 25', 55, 55') aus dem gleichen Material wie die heiß versiegelbare Materialschicht ausgebildet sind und</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei sowohl die Versiegelungsmaterialien (25, 25', 55, 55') als auch die heiß versiegelbare Schicht aus Polypropylenkunstharz ausgebildet sind.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Akkumulator nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Materialschicht der dielektrischen Packung aus Ionomer ausgebildet ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Akkumulator nach einem beliebigen der vorangehenden Ansprüche, wobei die Versiegelungsmaterialien (55, 55') aus Polypropylenkunstharz ausgebildet sind.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Akkumulator nach einem beliebigen der vorangehenden Ansprüche, wobei das Ionomer durch Hinzufügen von entweder Natrium (Na), Kalium (K), Magnesium (Mg) oder Zink (Zn) zu einem Copolymer aus Ethylen und Acrylsäure erzielt wird, um die Carbonsäure seiner Seitenkette zu neutralisieren.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Akkumulator nach einem beliebigen der vorangehenden Ansprüche, des Weiteren umfassend:
<claim-text>ein Elektrolyt, welches ein organisches, flüssiges Elektrolyt umfasst, das in der dielektrischen Packung angeordnet ist; wobei</claim-text>
<claim-text>jedes der Versiegelungsmaterialien (25, 25', 55, 55') Seitenarme aufweist, welche zu den entsprechenden Verbindungspunkten zwischen den oberen und unteren Kantenabschnitten erstreckt sind und an diesen enden, um die entsprechenden Spalten zwischen der entsprechenden Fahne und den Verbindungspunkten vollständig auszufüllen, um das organische, flüssige Elektrolyt daran<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> zu hindern, durch die Spalten während des Betriebs des Akkumulators leckzuschlagen, wobei die oberen und die unteren Kantenabschnitte sich an den Verbindungspunkten verbinden und jedes der Versiegelungsmaterialien eine Gestalt aufweist, in welcher vor dem Versiegeln eine Dicke der Seitenarme, welche sich von der entsprechenden Fahne erstrecken, größer ist als die Summe der Dicken von Abschnitten der Versiegelungsmaterialien auf der entsprechenden Elektrodenfahne, welche zwischen den Kanten der oberen und</claim-text>
<claim-text>der unteren dielektrischen Packung und der Elektrodenfahne angeordnet werden sollen.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Akkumulator nach einem beliebigen der vorangehenden Ansprüche, wobei die dielektrische Packung des Weiteren ein organisches, flüssiges Elektrolyt aufnimmt und die Versiegelungsmaterialien mit den Seitenarmen das Leckschlagen des organischen, flüssigen Elektrolyts aus der dielektrischen Packung an den Elektrodenfahnen und den Versiegelungsmaterialien mit den Seitenarmen vorbei verhindern.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Akkumulator nach einem beliebigen der vorangehenden Ansprüche, wobei die Seitenarme der Versiegelungsmaterialien eine Gestalt aufweisen, welche einen Spalt zwischen den Kantenabschnitten der oberen und der unteren dielektrischen Packung und der entsprechenden Elektrodenfahnen auffüllen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Akkumulator nach einem beliebigen der vorangehenden Ansprüche, wobei eine äußerste Kante jedes der Seitenarme der Versiegelungsmaterialien an einem Verbindungspunkt endet, an welchem sich die Kantenabschnitte der oberen und der unteren dielektrischen Packung treffen, um Leckschlagen des organischen, flüssigen Elektrolyts zwischen der entsprechenden<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> Elektrodenfahne und dem Verbindungspunkt zu verhindern.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Akkumulator nach einem beliebigen der vorangehenden Ansprüche, wobei vor dem Versiegeln die Dicke des Abschnitts von Versiegelungsmaterial, welches auf einer Oberfläche jeder entsprechenden Fahne aufgebracht ist, zwischen 5 µm und 50 µm beträgt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Akkumulator nach einem beliebigen der vorangehenden Ansprüche, wobei die Dicke der Elektrodenfahne bei oder zwischen 10 um und 100 µm liegt.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980599" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A secondary battery comprising:
<claim-text>a battery body (20, 50) having a positive electrode, a negative electrode and a separator which are stacked, and electrode tabs (23, 23', 53, 53') for inducing current generated therein to the outside;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a dielectric package (30, 70) having upper (30a, 70a) and lower (30b, 70b) dielectric packages, the packages comprising a metal base and a heat sealable material layer formed on the inner surface of the metal base for enclosing the battery body (20, 50) by sealing edge portions of the upper (30a, 70a) and lower (30b, 70b) dielectric packages while the electrode tabs (23, 23', 53, 53') are partially exposed to the outside; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>sealing materials (25, 25', 55 55') coated on portions of the electrode tabs (23, 23', 53, 53') with edge portions of the upper and lower dielectric packages, wherein said sealing materials have side arms extended in parallel with the edge portions of the upper and lower dielectric packages for preventing leakage of an organic liquid electrolyte while being interposed and fused between the edge portions of the upper (30a, 70a) and lower (30b, 70b) dielectric packages;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>the sealing materials (25, 25', 55, 55') are formed of the same material as the heat sealable material layer, and.</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein both of the sealing materials (25, 25', 55, 55') and the heat sealable layer are formed of polypropylene resin.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The secondary battery of claim 1, wherein the dielectric package material layer is formed of ionomer.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The secondary battery according to any preceding claim, wherein the sealing materials (55, 55') are formed of<br/>
polypropylene resin.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The secondary battery according to any preceding claim, wherein the ionomer is obtained by adding one of sodium (Na), potassium (K), magnesium (Mg) and zinc (Zn) to a copolymer of ethylene and acrylic acid to neutralize carboxylic acid of its side chain.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The secondary battery according to any preceding claim further comprising:
<claim-text>an electrolyte comprising an organic liquid electrolyte disposed in the dielectric<br/>
package; wherein</claim-text>
<claim-text>each of the sealing materials (25, 25', 55, 55') has side arms extended to and terminating at corresponding connection points between the upper and lower edge portions to completely fill corresponding gaps between the corresponding tab and the connection points so as to prevent the organic liquid electrolyte from leaking through gaps during operation of the battery, the upper and lower edges portions connect at the connection points, and each of the sealing materials has a shape in which, prior to sealing, a thickness of the side arms extending from the corresponding tab is greater than a sum of thicknesses of portions of the sealing materials on the corresponding electrode tab to be disposed between the edges of the upper and lower dielectric packages and the electrode tab.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The secondary battery according to any preceding claim, wherein the dielectric package further houses the organic liquid electrolyte and the sealing materials with the side arms preventing leakage of the organic liquid electrolyte from within the dielectric package past the electrode tabs and the sealing materials with the side arms.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The secondary battery according to any preceding claim, wherein the side arms of the sealing materials have a shape which completely fills in a gap between the edge portions of the upper and lower dielectric packages and the corresponding electrode tabs.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The secondary battery according to any preceding claim, wherein an outermost edge of each of the side arms of the sealing materials terminates at a connection point at which the edge portions of the upper and lower dielectric packages meet to prevent leakage of the organic liquid electrolyte between the corresponding electrode tab and the connection point.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The secondary battery according to any preceding claim, wherein, prior to sealing, the thickness of the portion of the sealing material coated on a surface of each corresponding tab is between 5 µm and 50 µm.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The secondary battery according to any preceding claim, wherein the thickness of the electrode tab is at or between 10 µm and 100 µm.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980600" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Pile secondaire comprenant :
<claim-text>un corps de pile (20, 50) ayant une électrode positive, une électrode négative et un séparateur qui sont empilés, et des pattes d'électrode (23, 23', 53, 53') pour induire un courant généré à l'intérieur de celui-ci vers l'extérieur ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un conditionnement diélectrique (30, 70) comportant des conditionnements diélectriques supérieur (30a, 70a) et inférieur (30b, 70b), les conditionnements comprenant une base métallique et une couche de matériau thermoscellable constituée sur la surface intérieure de la base métallique pour renfermer le corps de pile (20, 50) en scellant des portions de bord des conditionnements diélectriques supérieur (30a, 70a) et inférieur (30b, 70b) pendant que les pattes d'électrode (23, 23', 53, 53') sont partiellement exposées vers l'extérieur ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>des matériaux de scellage (25, 25', 55, 55') enduits sur des portions des pattes d'électrode (23, 23', 53, 53') avec des portions de bord des conditionnements diélectriques supérieur et inférieur, dans laquelle lesdits matériaux de scellage ont des bras latéraux s'étendant parallèlement aux portions de bord des conditionnements diélectriques supérieur et inférieur afin d'empêcher toute fuite d'un électrolyte liquide organique en étant interposés et fondus entre les portions de bord des conditionnements diélectriques supérieur (30a, 70a) et inférieur (30b, 70b) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans laquelle<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>les matériaux de scellage (25, 25', 55, 55') sont constitués du même matériau que la couche de matériau thermoscellable, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans laquelle les matériaux de scellage (25, 25', 55, 55') et la couche thermoscellable sont constitués de résine de polypropylène.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Pile secondaire selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle la couche de matériau de conditionnement diélectrique est constituée d'un ionomère.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Pile secondaire selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans laquelle les matériaux de scellage (55, 55') sont constitués de résine de polypropylène.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Pile secondaire selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans laquelle l'ionomère est obtenu en ajoutant l'un du sodium (Na), du potassium (K), du magnésium (Mg) et du zinc (Zn) à un copolymère d'éthylène et d'acide acrylique pour neutraliser l'acide carboxylique de sa chaîne latérale.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Pile secondaire selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, comprenant en outre :
<claim-text>un électrolyte comprenant un électrolyte liquide organique disposé dans le conditionnement diélectrique ; dans laquelle</claim-text>
<claim-text>chacun des matériaux de scellage (25, 25', 55, 55') comporte des bras latéraux s'étendant et se terminant à des points de liaison correspondants entre les portions de bord supérieure et inférieure pour remplir complètement des espacements correspondants entre la<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> patte correspondante et les points de liaison afin d'empêcher toute fuite d'électrolyte liquide organique à travers des espacements pendant le fonctionnement de la pile, les portions de bord supérieure et inférieure se relient aux points de liaison, et chacun des matériaux de scellage a une forme telle que, avant le scellage, une épaisseur des bras latéraux s'étendant à partir de la patte correspondante soit supérieure à une somme d'épaisseurs de portions des matériaux de scellage sur la patte d'électrode correspondante à disposer entre les bords des conditionnements diélectriques supérieur et inférieur et la patte d'électrode.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Pile secondaire selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans laquelle le conditionnement diélectrique héberge en outre l'électrolyte liquide organique et les matériaux de scellage avec les bras latéraux empêchant toute fuite de l'électrolyte liquide organique de l'intérieur du conditionnement diélectrique au-delà des pattes d'électrode et des matériaux de scellage avec les bras latéraux.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Pile secondaire selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans laquelle les bras latéraux des matériaux de scellage ont une forme qui remplit complètement un espacement entre les portions de bord des conditionnements diélectriques supérieur et inférieur et les pattes d'électrodes correspondantes.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Pile secondaire selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans laquelle un bord le plus extérieur de chacun des bras latéraux des matériaux de scellage se termine à un point de liaison auquel les portions de bord des conditionnements<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> diélectriques supérieur et inférieur se rejoignent pour empêcher toute fuite de l'électrolyte liquide organique entre la patte d'électrode correspondante et le point de liaison.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Pile secondaire selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans laquelle, avant le scellage, l'épaisseur de la portion du matériau de scellage enduit sur une surface de chaque patte correspondante est entre 5 µm et 50 µm.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Pile secondaire selon l'une quelconque des revendications précédentes, dans laquelle l'épaisseur de la patte d'électrode est à ou entre 10 µm et 100 µm.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16669209" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="156" he="197" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="136" he="184" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="150" he="185" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --><figure id="f0004" num="4"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="145" he="187" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --><figure id="f0005" num="5"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="148" he="190" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --><figure id="f0006" num="6"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="155" he="189" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --><figure id="f0007" num="7"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="146" he="142" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
