<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2679016-A1" country="EP" doc-number="2679016" kind="A1" date="20140101" family-id="45757230" file-reference-id="314269" date-produced="20180823" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146550481" ucid="EP-2679016-A1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2679016</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-12705768-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154824404" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12705768</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120216</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP207030631" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12705768.5</doc-number><date>20120216</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140453625" ucid="US-201113034482-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>201113034482</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20110224</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140448676" ucid="US-2012025502-W" linkage-type="W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>2012025502</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20120216</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988099971" load-source="docdb">H04N  21/41        20110101ALI20120914BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988105101" load-source="docdb">H04N  21/435       20110101ALI20120914BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988112204" load-source="docdb">H04N  21/81        20110101AFI20120914BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988112753" load-source="docdb">H04N  21/236       20110101ALI20120914BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988121219" load-source="docdb">H04N  21/434       20110101ALI20120914BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2122371787" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04N  21/8106      20130101 LI20150107BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2122374854" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04N  21/4348      20130101 LI20150107BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2122376030" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04N  21/23614     20130101 LI20150107BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2122381622" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04N  21/4355      20130101 LI20150107BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2122382866" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04N  21/4126      20130101 FI20150107BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-2122382963" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H04N  21/8133      20130101 LI20150107BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132183927" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">BEREITSTELLUNG VON ZUGÄNGLICHEM INHALT MIT MATRIX-CODES</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132183928" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">PROVISION OF ACCESSIBILITY CONTENT USING MATRIX CODES</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132183929" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">FOURNITURE DE CONTENU D'ACCESSIBILITÉ AU MOYEN DE CODES MATRICIELS</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918144097" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>ECHOSTAR TECHNOLOGIES LLC</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918159866" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>ECHOSTAR TECHNOLOGIES L.L.C.</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918979268" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Echostar Technologies L.L.C.</last-name><iid>101303512</iid><address><street>100 Inverness Circle East</street><city>Englewood, Colorado 80112</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918161277" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>SCHAEFER GERMAR</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918170506" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>SCHAEFER, GERMAR</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918989594" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>SCHAEFER, GERMAR</last-name><address><street>620 Portland Road</street><city>Monument, Colorado 80132</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918990162" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Bebbington, Nicholas Paul</last-name><iid>100834219</iid><address><street>Beck Greener Fulwood House 12 Fulwood Place</street><city>London WC1V 6HR</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="US-2012025502-W"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2012025502</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20120216</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2012115859-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2012115859</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20120830</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548907220" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS548909570" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS548907221" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS548811639" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS548894281" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS548830571" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS548909571" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS548907222" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548830572" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS548830573" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS548911046" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS548811640" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS548811641" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548907223" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548830574" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS548907224" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS548909572" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS548894282" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS548830575" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS548811642" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS548830576" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS548916871" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS548909573" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS548916872" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS548916873" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS548858430" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS548858431" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS548911047" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS548811643" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS548858432" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS548894283" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS548911048" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS548894284" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS548858433" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS548894285" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS548811644" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS548858434" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS548830577" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA99619646" ref-ucid="WO-2012115859-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p num="0000">A method of presenting a matrix code for providing accessibility content includes receiving, at a content receiver, a signal carrying accessibility content, generating, at the content receiver, a matrix code from the accessibility content, and transmitting the matrix code as part of a content presentation to a presentation device for display, wherein the content presentation includes at least one of audio and visual content and the accessibility content includes an alternative form of at least one of the audio and the visual content for allowing a user to more fully comprehend the content presentation. Systems for implementing the method are also provided.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA99819325" ref-ucid="WO-2012115859-A1" lang="EN" source="national office" load-source="docdb"><p>A method of presenting a matrix code for providing accessibility content includes receiving, at a content receiver, a signal carrying accessibility content, generating, at the content receiver, a matrix code from the accessibility content, and transmitting the matrix code as part of a content presentation to a presentation device for display, wherein the content presentation includes at least one of audio and visual content and the accessibility content includes an alternative form of at least one of the audio and the visual content for allowing a user to more fully comprehend the content presentation. Systems for implementing the method are also provided.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA99619647" ref-ucid="WO-2012115859-A1" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><p num="0000">Un procédé de présentation d'un code matriciel selon l'invention destiné à fournir un contenu d'accessibilité comprend la réception, sur un récepteur de contenu, d'un signal transportant un contenu d'accessibilité, la génération, sur le récepteur de contenu, d'un code matriciel à partir du contenu d'accessibilité, et la transmission du code matriciel dans le cadre d'une présentation de contenu à un dispositif de présentation pour affichage, la présentation de contenu comprenant au moins l'un d'un contenu sonore et visuel et le contenu d'accessibilité comprenant une forme alternative d'au moins l'un du contenu sonore et visuel pour permettre à un utilisateur d'appréhender de manière plus complète la présentation du contenu. L'invention concerne également des systèmes de mise en œuvre du procédé.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA99819326" ref-ucid="WO-2012115859-A1" lang="FR" source="national office" load-source="docdb"><p>Un procédé de présentation d'un code matriciel selon l'invention destiné à fournir un contenu d'accessibilité comprend la réception, sur un récepteur de contenu, d'un signal transportant un contenu d'accessibilité, la génération, sur le récepteur de contenu, d'un code matriciel à partir du contenu d'accessibilité, et la transmission du code matriciel dans le cadre d'une présentation de contenu à un dispositif de présentation pour affichage, la présentation de contenu comprenant au moins l'un d'un contenu sonore et visuel et le contenu d'accessibilité comprenant une forme alternative d'au moins l'un du contenu sonore et visuel pour permettre à un utilisateur d'appréhender de manière plus complète la présentation du contenu. L'invention concerne également des systèmes de mise en oeuvre du procédé.</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES50930367" ref-ucid="WO-2012115859-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="3"/>--><p id="p0001" num="0001"> PROVISION OF ACCESSIBILITY CONTENT USING MATRIX CODES </p><p id="p0002" num="0002">CROSS REFERENCE TO RELATED APPLICATIONS </p><p id="p0003" num="0003">This Patent Cooperation Treaty patent application claims priority to United States application No. 13/034,482, which was filed on February 24, 2011 , and entitled "Matrix Code-Based Accessibility", the contents of which are incorporated herein by reference in their entirety. </p><p id="p0004" num="0004">FIELD OF THE INVENTION </p><p id="p0005" num="0005">The present disclosure relates generally to an interface for television programming. More particularly, the present disclosure relates to QR codes presented on a display for scanning, where the codes have accessibility content stored therein. </p><p id="p0006" num="0006">SUMMARY </p><p id="p0007" num="0007">In one embodiment, a method of presenting a matrix code for providing accessibility content may include receiving, at a content receiver, a signal carrying accessibility content, generating, at the content receiver, a matrix code from the accessibility content, and transmitting the matrix code as part of a content presentation to a presentation device for display, wherein the content presentation includes at least one of audio and visual content and the accessibility content includes an alternative form of at least one of the audio and the visual content for allowing a user to more fully comprehend the content presentation. </p><p id="p0008" num="0008">In variations of this embodiment, the signal carrying the accessibility content may include the content presentation. The content receiver may transmit the matrix code in response to a user indication. Furthermore, the content receiver may transmit the matrix code in a user-indicated configuration. The user-indicated configuration may include a size of the matrix code on the presentation device and/or a position of the matrix code on the presentation device. In further variations of this embodiment, the matrix code may be displayed on the presentation device continuously throughout the content presentation, or intermittently throughout the content presentation. More than one matrix code may be displayed on the presentation device throughout the content presentation. The accessibility content may include visual information regarding the content presentation. In this manner, the visual information may be provided in a format for use with a Braille writer. Alternatively or additionally, the accessibility content may include audio information regarding the content presentation. Furthermore, the matrix code may define a two dimensional pattern that embodies data. Thus, the matrix code may be a QR code. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="4"/>-->
 In another embodiment, a method of generating a matrix code representing accessibility content may include receiving, at a content receiver, a signal carrying data relating to a content presentation and to the accessibility content; and generating, at the content receiver, a matrix code from the data relating to the accessibility content, wherein the content presentation includes at least one of audio and visual content and the </p><p id="p0009" num="0009">accessibility content includes an alternative form of at least one of the audio and the visual content for allowing a user to more fully comprehend the content presentation. </p><p id="p0010" num="0010">In variations of this embodiment, the matrix code and the content presentation may be displayed simultaneously on a presentation device. The presentation device may be a television. Furthermore, the content receiver may be a connected and integral part of the presentation device. </p><p id="p0011" num="0011">In further embodiments, a method of generating a matrix code having accessibility content for allowing a user to more fully comprehend a content presentation having at least one of audio and visual content may include receiving, at a content receiver, a signal carrying data relating to the accessibility content and generating, at the content receiver, a matrix code from the data relating to the accessibility content and configured in a format for use with a Braille writer, wherein the accessibility content includes an alternative form of at least one of the audio and the visual content of the content presentation. </p><p id="p0012" num="0012">In still further embodiments, a system may include an input that receives a broadcast signal carrying accessibility content, a processor that receives the broadcast signal and that generates a matrix code that includes the accessibility content, and an output that transmits the matrix code to a presentation device for display. </p><p id="p0013" num="0013">In still other embodiments, a system may include an optical device configured to capture a matrix code presented with an audiovisual presentation, a processor in </p><p id="p0014" num="0014">communication with the optical device configured to receive the matrix code from the optical device and transform the matrix code into accessibility data readable by the accessibility device, and an accessibility device interface component in communication with an accessibility device and the processor configured to output the accessibility data to the accessibility device. The accessibility device may provide accessibility information to a user based on the received accessibility data. </p><p id="p0015" num="0015">It is to be understood that both the foregoing general description and the following detailed description are for purposes of example and explanation and do not necessarily limit the present disclosure. The accompanying drawings, which are incorporated in and constitute a part of the specification, illustrate subject matter of the disclosure. Together, the descriptions and the drawings serve to explain the principles of the disclosure. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="5"/>-->
 BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS </p><p id="p0016" num="0016">Figure 1 is a diagram illustrating a system for transmitting audiovisual and </p><p id="p0017" num="0017">accessibility content to a user, according to certain embodiments. </p><p id="p0018" num="0018">Figure 2 is a diagram illustrating a method for transmitting audiovisual and accessibility content to a user, according to certain embodiments. </p><p id="p0019" num="0019">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE EMBODIMENTS </p><p id="p0020" num="0020">The description that follows includes sample systems and methods that embody various elements of the present disclosure. However, it should be understood that the described disclosure may be practiced in a variety of forms in addition to those described herein. </p><p id="p0021" num="0021">Audiovisual programming generally involves transmitting signals carrying audiovisual content to a receiver. Generally, the audiovisual content includes one or more streams of data supporting several viewable programs at any given time. As such, the signals may be processed and the audiovisual content may be selectively displayed on a presentation device by, for example, selecting a particular channel. It should be appreciated that selecting a channel does not necessarily require tuning to a particular frequency but instead selecting a different group of data streams (typically identified by packet identifiers, or PIDS) for processing and/or display. </p><p id="p0022" num="0022">In addition to audiovisual content, the streams of data may include accessibility content relating to one or more of the audiovisual signals. In one embodiment, accessibility content may refer to any information, whether presented in an audio, visual, or tactile form, that allows persons having one or more impairments, disabilities, infirmities, language barriers, or any other condition to more fully comprehend the audiovisual content provided through the presentation device. That is, the accessibility content may include an alternative form of the visual aspect of the audiovisual content or it may include an alternative form of the audio aspect of the audiovisual content or it may include some combination of alternative forms of the both the visual and audio aspects of the content. Existing accessibility content, which is currently supported on many presentation devices, includes closed captioning, wherein the audio aspect of a content presentation is provided in an alternative textual form displayed on a portion of the presentation device corresponding to the audiovisual stream in order to allow hearing-impaired persons to read content that is otherwise presented as audio. Furthermore, bilingual content may be available in some systems, such that the audio is provided in two languages, e.g., English and Spanish, to allow the user to select a desired language. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="6"/>-->
 The present disclosure relates to systems and methods for receiving accessibility content from a television provider as well as methods associated with presenting and/or receiving the accessibility content. In some embodiments, the system includes a satellite configured to receive transmissions and instructions from a satellite provider. The methods, in some embodiments, involve producing a matrix code, such as a QR code, and associating the matrix code with audiovisual content. Specifically, the matrix code may contain data relating to accessibility content for association with the audiovisual content. A user may scan the code using any device capable of reading (scanning) the matrix code and converting the code into transmittable accessibility content. The transmittable accessibility content may be transmitted to an accessibility device, for receipt by the user. In this manner, a QR code may be produced and associated with a television program. The QR code may be viewable on the presentation device while the television program is being displayed. Thus, the accessibility content may be presented concurrently with the television program to which such information relates, and it may be concurrently received by the reading device (reader), and thereafter transmitted to the accessibility device wherein the user may receive the accessibility content. </p><p id="p0023" num="0023">In one embodiment, the accessibility content may be visual information related to the television program (for example, descriptions of scenes, descriptions of characters, descriptions of actions, and other description of the visual content of the television program) translated into Braille, the reading device may be an optical scanner, and the accessibility device may be a Braille writer. In this embodiment, the matrix code may contain accessibility content relating to the visual content of a television program which would not be viewable by persons having visual impairments. For example, the accessibility content may include a narration of a television program allowing a person with visual impairments to "hear" the television program, or the narration may be translated into Braille such that the person may use their sense of touch with a Braille writer to read the visual aspects of the program. </p><p id="p0024" num="0024">In this or another embodiment, the receiving device and the transmitting device may be, or may be a part of, the same device. Thus, a single device may be provided to read the accessibility content from the displayed matrix code on the presentation device, and transmit such accessibility content to the user. Other embodiments and variations of those mentioned will be described below. </p><p id="p0025" num="0025">Referring now to Figure 1 , a sample system 100 for performing the methods described herein is shown. As shown, the system 100 may include a receiver 102 for receiving audiovisual programs and matrix code information. The system 100 may also include a presentation device 104 for displaying the audiovisual programs and matrix code. The system 100 may also include a reader 106 for reading information displayed on the presentation device 104, which may be in the form of a matrix code 140. The reader 106 
<!-- EPO <DP n="7"/>-->
 may be in communication with an accessibility device 108 for providing the accessibility content captured from presentation device 104 to a user. </p><p id="p0026" num="0026">The receiver 102 may be configured to receive a signal carrying a broadcast television program, a program guide, a menu, a movie or other audiovisual content. The receiver 102 may also be configured to receive associated metadata or other data information carried by the signal. The receiver 102 may further be configured for </p><p id="p0027" num="0027">transmitting the content to the presentation device 104 for viewing, listening, or both. As such, the receiver 102 may be in the form of a set top box 116, other television receiver box (such as a cable box, network-enabled box, and the like) or a satellite system as shown including a dish 112, cabling 114 leading to the set top box 116, and cabling 118 leading to the presentation device 104, for example. Other examples of a receiver 102 may include an antenna system employing an analog or digital antenna connected by cabling leading either to a television receiver or directly to the presentation device 104. Still other examples may include a cable system including an incoming cable leading directly to a presentation device 104 or to a presentation device via a set top box. </p><p id="p0028" num="0028">In some embodiments, the receiver 102 may be configured to convert, configure, or otherwise modify the display prior to transmitting it to the presentation device for viewing. The receiver may further be configured for storing and displaying audiovisual content. The receiver may thus be in the form of a computer-type device having one or more processing units 120, one or more inputs 122, one or more outputs 124, and one or more computer readable storage media 126 (which may take the form of, but is not limited to: a magnetic storage medium; optical storage medium; magneto-optical storage medium; read only memory; random access memory; erasable programmable memory; flash memory; non- transitory storage media; and so on). In some embodiments, these computer-type elements may be incorporated into a set top box 116 for receiving a broadcast, program guide information, audio and video streams, other audiovisual content, data, or other information. The set top box 116 may receive the information through the one or more inputs 122, process or store the incoming information, and selectively output information to the presentation device 104 for viewing and interaction by a viewer. For example, the viewer may select which television channel he would like to watch, select from time-shifted television programs stored in the storage medium, or select movies from a video-on-demand menu, for example. In another example, the viewer may navigate an electronic program guide or other series of menus, which may be output to the presentation device 104. Instructions executed by the processor 120 may be stored in the storage medium 126 or received through the one or more inputs 122 or both. The set top box 120 may include a remote control 128 for remote interaction with the viewer. In still other embodiments, some or all of these aspects of the receiver 102 may be connected and 
<!-- EPO <DP n="8"/>-->
 integral with the presentation device 104 described below. For example, a presentation device 104 in the form of a television may include some or all of these elements. </p><p id="p0029" num="0029">The presentation device 104 may include one or more inputs 130 for receiving information from the receiver and an electronic device 132 for receiving information from the one or more inputs 130 and transmitting the information to a display screen, speaker, or other output 134. The presentation device 104 may be a television, computer monitor, or other device for presenting a viewer with visual and/or audio stimuli. </p><p id="p0030" num="0030">The reader 106 may be a remote device configured for optically scanning information from the presentation device 104. The reader 106, like the receiver 102 described above, may also be a computer-type device having one or more inputs, a processor, a computer readable storage medium, and one or more outputs. One of the inputs of the reader 106 may include an optical receiver configured for receiving and recording light patterns. The optical receiver may be a digital optical receiver similar to that found in digital cameras and some mobile phones. In some embodiments, the reader 106 may be in the form of a dedicated optical scanner, a personal digital assistant (PDA), a portable computing device, a tablet computer, a smartphone and the like. The reader 106 may receive image input, for example, from the optical receiver and the processor may access processing instructions for the image from the computer readable storage medium. That is, in some embodiments, the reader 106 may have decoding software stored in the storage medium for decoding matrix codes. In some embodiments, the software may include an "auto run" feature so that decoding software automatically executes when a matrix code is scanned and recognized. The processor may process the image produced by the optical receiver and may follow additional instructions produced by the processing of the image. In at least one </p><p id="p0031" num="0031">embodiment, the processor receives an image captured by the optical receiver, such as an image including a matrix code, and transforms the matrix code into accessibility data readable by an accessibility device, such as a Braille writer. </p><p id="p0032" num="0032">The reader 106 may have data transmitting capabilities, such as, for example, by hardwired connection, a wireless network, or another electronic data connection. Thus, the reader 106 may be capable of transmitting the decoded information from the matrix code, which may be accessibility content, to an accessibility device 108. In at least one embodiment, the reader 106 includes an accessibility device interface component configured to output data to the accessibility device 108. For example, the accessibility device interface component may output Braille data for presentation by the accessibility device 108. The accessibility device 108 may be configured to receive accessibility content transmitted from the reader 106, and thereafter provide a user with the accessibility content. In one embodiment, the reader 106 and the accessibility device 108 may be the same device, or a may be a part of the same device, such that the procedure of transmitting the data 
<!-- EPO <DP n="9"/>-->
 representing the accessibility content is not necessary. For example, the accessibility device 108 may be provided with a camera or other image-capture device, as well as appropriate software to recognize, decode and/or process a captured matrix code. Thus, in this embodiment, the same device may read the matrix-based code, and directly provide the accessibility content encoded therein to the user. </p><p id="p0033" num="0033">Having described a system 100 upon which the current methods may be performed, reference is now made to Figure 2, which illustrates a process for using matrix codes displayed in programming content to provide accessibility content to a user. For example, accessibility content in the form of a textual description of the visual programming content may be embedded in a television program. This textual description may describe various elements of the programming content instead of, or in addition to, providing a transcript of the audio portion of the content. For example, the textual description may set out the actions of persons, animals, and the like as they occur, locations shown in the content, actions taking place, and so on. In some embodiments, the textual description may also include (or take the form solely of) a transcript of some or all of the audio portion of content. </p><p id="p0034" num="0034">A viewer of the television program may scan the matrix code in the display with a reader, for example, and the reader may decode the accessibility content and transmit it to an accessibility device, such as a Braille writer. In this fashion, a user with a visual impairment may be able to read the output of the Braille writer as the program is shown, thereby allowing the user to enjoy the program to a greater degree than if he were just listening to the audio portion of the program. </p><p id="p0035" num="0035">Before discussing the operations performed in the method, additional information is provided with regard to the programming content, the matrix codes included therein, and the information in the matrix codes. The programming content may be in the form of live television, pre-recorded television, movies, on-demand programming, or any other form of audiovisual content which may be provided from a content provider. In general, such content is produced by third parties, such as a television or movie production studio, and is then transmitted to the television signal provider for simultaneous or eventual broadcast or transmission to the user, via the transmission media described above, to the display device. The programming content may include a matrix code, such as a QR code, that is presented to the user for viewing and/or capturing, such as scanning with a reader 106. The matrix code may be visible throughout the programming or it may appear for a portion thereof. The matrix code may be provided on the entire display device (i.e., in place of the visual portion of the programming), or it may be provided on only a portion thereof. In this manner, a person with visual impairment may choose to have the matrix code displayed on the entire display device if there is no one else watching the programming; however, if the 
<!-- EPO <DP n="10"/>-->
 visually impaired person is watching the programming with normal sighted persons, then the matrix-code may be displayed in only a portion of the display device to allow the sighted persons to view the visual portion of the programming content. Moreover, the user may choose not to have the matrix code displayed on the display device at all. As the accessibility content may be provided in the transmission signal along with the audiovisual content, the user may use the set-top box 116 or other like device to select the configuration (size, positioning, etc.) of the matrix code on the display device, including selecting whether or not the code will be present at all. The set-top box may execute the user's instructions by providing the display device with both the user's selected programming and the user's selected accessibility content. The receiver may thus have a menu stored in the computer readable storage medium that is accessible by a key pad on the set top box or a via a remote control. The user may interact with the set top box using the menu and the set top box may filter or otherwise reconfigure the incoming signal to display the audiovisual content and data as selected by the user. </p><p id="p0036" num="0036">An exemplary matrix code 140, as depicted in Figure 1 , is a two-dimensional display (such as a QR code) defining patterns and regions that embody data, similar to a bar code. The matrix code 1 0 may take the form of alternating black and white elements, such as squares or other geometric shapes. The two-dimensional nature of the display may generally allow for more data to be stored than a typical bar code. While the present disclosure is related to the use of two-dimensional matrix codes 140, other data </p><p id="p0037" num="0037">storing/displaying images or systems may also be used. For example, holographic images allowing for three-dimensional storage of data may be used, as may changing images that allow for recording and/or display of information over time. Each of these and other methods for storing information in a display may be used and are considered to be included in the term "matrix code" 140. The matrix code 140 may be embedded in the visual portion of the content as transmitted by the content or signal provider, or may be constructed by the set- top box 116 from data provided as part of the transmission and then overlaid, as appropiate, on the visual portion for display. In the latter embodiment, the set-top box may store and execute an application to construct a matrix code from data provided to the set-top box, thus rendering a QR code that may be captured by the reader and processed by the appropriate device (e.g., the reader 106, the accessibility device 108, and the like). </p><p id="p0038" num="0038">The matrix codes 140 in the present embodiment may store accessibility data representing accessibility content. Accessibility data, in one embodiment, may relate to any type of information or content that would allow a person with an impairment to more fully sense, or otherwise receive, and enjoy the programming. As previously discussed, accessibility data may include a textual description of the visual programming content. In this manner, a person having a visual impairment may be able to receive such visual 
<!-- EPO <DP n="11"/>-->
 information via a Braille writer or other medium, in lieu of actually seeing the content. </p><p id="p0039" num="0039">Greater or lesser levels of accessibility content are possible. For example, the content may simply describe the general scene of the programming, for example, every time the scene changes. In other examples, the content may fully describe certain or all scenes, backgrounds, actions, and other information occurring in the program. In some </p><p id="p0040" num="0040">embodiments, the described accessibility content may be in the form of a narration of greater or lesser detail that allows a person with visual impairments to understand what the visual content of the audiovisual content is showing. As such, the user may hear the audio content and associate the audio content with the visual content. Other types of accessibility content are possible. For example, the matrix code may be configured to provide textual information to a person with a hearing impairment. In this manner, the textual information could be displayed to the user on a device that is connected to (or is a part of) the reader 106 to allow the user to read the audio content. In a further example, the matrix code may be configured to provide textual or audio information in a language other than the broadcast language. In this manner, the textual or audio </p><p id="p0041" num="0041">information could be provided to the user on a device that is connected to (or is a part of) the reader 106 to allow the user to read or listen to the audio content in another language. </p><p id="p0042" num="0042">Matrix codes having accessibility content stored therein may be provided at any interval and in any number throughout the course of the selected audiovisual content. For example, a single matrix code may be displayed at the beginning of the program. </p><p id="p0043" num="0043"> Alternatively, numerous codes may be displayed at regular intervals throughout the program, e.g., every minute, 30 seconds, 15 seconds, etc. In still other embodiments, the matrix codes may be spaced throughout the program at the beginning, or end, or each scene of the program. It is generally anticipated that a greater frequency of code presentation will correspond with a higher level of accessibility content being provided, though this may not be the case. In all cases, the set-top box 116 or other like device may be responsible for receiving the accessibility content from the signal, and presenting the content in the form of a matrix code on the display device. </p><p id="p0044" num="0044">The accessibility content may be supplied by the content provider. For example, a producer of a movie may develop, or have developed, accessibility content for its movie. At the time of developing the accessibility content, a matrix code 140 and any associated features may be included in the movie. The matrix code 140 may be included in a data stream associated with the program or it may be included in a secondary visual stream. When a network or other program providing entity assembles programming they may include the accessibility content in their programming. Accordingly, the receiver in the system above may receive the accessibility content together with the program or other audiovisual content 
<!-- EPO <DP n="12"/>-->
 being provided by the television signal provider and may selectively display portions of the signal. </p><p id="p0045" num="0045">In another embodiment, the accessibility content may be supplied by the television signal provider. At the time of receiving the content from the content provider, the television signal provider may develop and embed the accessibility content along with the regular content signal and, as above, may embed the content as a data stream or a secondary visual stream. Thus, as above, the receiver in the system above may receive the </p><p id="p0046" num="0046">accessibility content together with the program or other audiovisual content being provided by the television signal provider and may selectively display portions of the signal. With this background regarding programming content, matrix codes, and the data stored therein, the method 250 (Figure 2) may be described in more detail. The method 250 may be performed by all or a portion of the system 100 of Figure 1. The method may also be performed by other systems. </p><p id="p0047" num="0047">Turning now to the embodiment shown in Figure 2, the receiver 102 may receive a signal carrying audiovisual programming content (252), such as a television program, a movie, or an on-demand program, for example. In addition to audiovisual content, the signal may include accessibility content stored therein or provided in an additional data stream, visual stream, or other stream associated with the audiovisual content. The accessibility content may be in the form of one or more matrix codes or data that may be compiled into a matrix code or series of codes. The received signal, of course, may be any programming content signal. For example, the signal may be a television broadcast signal carrying a live program or it may be a signal carrying a program guide or other menu. As such, the signal received by the receiver 102 may include several forms and may be carrying at least one of several types of audiovisual content and associated accessibility content. Having received a signal carrying programming content with possibly additional accessibility content (252), the receiver 102 may search the signal for any matrix codes or otherwise available accessibility content which may be present (254). In other </p><p id="p0048" num="0048">embodiments, the receiver 102 may be pre-configured or selectively configured via a menu to receive accessibility content from a particular stream of the transmitted signal. As such, the search step (254) may be omitted, as shown in Figure 2. </p><p id="p0049" num="0049">Depending on the nature of the accessibility content, the receiver 102 may generate a matrix code 140 in a format for graphical display. Generating a matrix code 140 may be done in several manners, depending on how the matrix code data is received into the receiver 102. In some embodiments, the matrix codes 140 may be received in a visual stream apart from the audiovisual content and the receiver 102 may display the visual stream together with the audiovisual content. The relationship of the matrix code visual 
<!-- EPO <DP n="13"/>-->
 stream to the audiovisual content may be selected via menu by the user and the receiver 102 may compile the audiovisual content and matrix code visual stream to suitably display the matrix visual stream together with the audiovisual content (256a). This may include replacing the visual aspect of the audiovisual content with the matrix code visual stream or it may include coordination between the two. In some other embodiments, matrix codes may be present in a data stream and may be received and read or decoded by the receiver 102 (256b). The receiver 102 may then generate matrix codes 140 for visual display and embed them in the audiovisual content or display them along with or in place of the visual aspect of the audiovisual content. In still other embodiments, the receiver 102 may receive a data stream including accessibility content and may develop matrix codes 140 by grouping portions of the accessibility content and generating a matrix code or codes 140 and associating the code or codes 140 with the audiovisual content (256c). Any of the above embodiments or combinations thereof may be included in procedures (256a, 256b, 256c) of generating a matrix code 140 in format for display. It will be appreciated that, in certain embodiments, two or more procedures (256a, 256b, 256c) may be performed, depending on how the matrix code data is received. </p><p id="p0050" num="0050">Having received a signal (252), possibly searched for accessibility content (254), and generated a matrix code for display (256), the receiver may then transmit the matrix code 140 (258) to the display device to be displayed (260). The transmission may correspond to the generated matrix code 140. That is, for example, where the accessibility content is replacing a portion of the audiovisual content, the transmission may include the accessibility content in the form of one or matrix codes 140 and the portion of the audiovisual content not replaced. </p><p id="p0051" num="0051">Once a program including matrix codes 140 has been output to a presentation device 104, a viewer may scan a matrix code when it is presented on the presentation device 104 (262). The matrix code 140 may have accessibility data, representing accessibility content, stored therein. The viewer may direct the optical receiver portion of a reader 106 toward the presentation device 104 when the presentation device 104 is displaying a matrix code 140. The viewer may then actuate the optical receiver by, for example, depressing a shutter button. In other embodiments, the optical receiving is in an "always on" configuration, i.e., it may capture the matrix code without input from the user. The reader 106 may thus capture an image of the matrix code 140. In some embodiments, the viewer may zoom, focus, or otherwise direct the reader toward the portion of the presentation device displaying the matrix code. In some embodiments, the reader 106 may be in a stationary position relative to the presentation device 104 and may be focused on all or a respective portion of the presentation device 104 such that it may capture matrix codes 140 as they are available and without the need for focusing, directing, or otherwise positioning the reader 106. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="14"/>-->
 As mentioned above, the reader 106 may include an auto run feature causing the reader 106 to begin the decoding process when a matrix code 140 has been captured. In other cases, the viewer may deliberately select software resident on the reader 106 and direct the software to decode the captured image of the matrix code 140. The software may decode the image thus producing the accessibility content. The accessibility content may be transmitted to an accessibility device, such as a Braille writer, or the reader 106 may be a part of the accessibility device, in which case the accessibility device 108 may have the accessibility content directly available to it. The accessibility device 108 may then provide the accessibility content to the user, in a manner depending on the type of device, as is known in the art (264). </p><p id="p0052" num="0052">The overall process of the method for generating a matrix code 250 may be advantageous for several reasons. For example, the process may allow a television service provider to make accessibility content available to a user to enhance the user's ability to experience the program, particularly when the user has a visual, audio, or other impairment. At the same time, the user may enjoy the programming with other persons who do not have impairments, because the matrix-code may be displayed on only a portion of the display device, and the accessibility content may be provided directly to the individual user (as opposed to completely altering the audio or visual presentation from the display device). The user may have the option to turn on or off the matrix code display at any time, and to configure the code size and display positioning to suit the user's needs. </p><p id="p0053" num="0053">In the present disclosure, the methods disclosed may be implemented as sets of instructions or software readable by a device. Further, it is understood that the specific order or hierarchy of operations in the methods disclosed are examples of sample approaches. In other embodiments, the specific order or hierarchy of operations in the method can be rearranged while remaining within the disclosed subject matter. The accompanying method claims present elements of the various operations in a sample order, and are not necessarily meant to be limited to the specific order or hierarchy presented. </p><p id="p0054" num="0054">The described disclosure may be provided as a computer program product, or software, that may include a non-transitory machine-readable medium having stored thereon instructions, which may be used to program a computer system (or other electronic devices) to perform a process according to the present disclosure. A non-transitory machine- readable medium includes any mechanism for storing information in a form (e.g., software, processing application) readable by a machine (e.g., a computer). The non-transitory machine-readable medium may take the form of, but is not limited to, a magnetic storage medium (e.g., floppy diskette, video cassette, and so on); optical storage medium (e.g., CD- ROM); magneto-optical storage medium; read only memory (ROM); random access memory 
<!-- EPO <DP n="15"/>-->
 (RAM); erasable programmable memory (e.g., EPROM and EEPROM); flash memory; and so on. </p><p id="p0055" num="0055">It is believed that the present disclosure and many of its attendant advantages will be understood by the foregoing description, and it will be apparent that various changes may be made in the form, construction and arrangement of the components without departing from the disclosed subject matter or without sacrificing all of its material advantages. The form described is merely explanatory, and it is the intention of the following claims to encompass and include such changes. </p><p id="p0056" num="0056">While the present disclosure has been described with reference to various embodiments, it will be understood that these embodiments are illustrative and that the scope of the disclosure is not limited to them. Many variations, modifications, additions, and improvements are possible. More generally, embodiments in accordance with the present disclosure have been described in the context or particular embodiments. Functionality may be separated or combined in blocks differently in various embodiments of the disclosure or described with different terminology. These and other variations, modifications, additions, and improvements may fall within the scope of the disclosure as defined in the claims that follow. 
</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM44726288" ref-ucid="WO-2012115859-A1" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><claim-statement><!-- EPO <DP n="16"/>-->CLAIMS: </claim-statement><claim id="clm-0001" num="1"><claim-text> 1. A method of presenting a matrix code for providing accessibility content, comprising: </claim-text><claim-text> receiving, at a content receiver, a signal carrying the accessibility content; generating, at the content receiver, a matrix code from the accessibility content; and </claim-text><claim-text> transmitting the matrix code as part of a content presentation to a presentation device for display, </claim-text><claim-text>wherein: </claim-text><claim-text> the content presentation includes at least one of audio and visual content; and the accessibility content includes an alternative form of at least one of the audio and the visual content for allowing a user to more fully comprehend the content presentation.</claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0002" num="2"><claim-text>2. The method of claim 1 , wherein the signal carrying accessibility content includes the content presentation. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0003" num="3"><claim-text> 3. The method of claim 1 , wherein the operation of transmitting the matrix code is responsive to a user indication. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0004" num="4"><claim-text> 4. The method of claim 3, wherein the user indication includes a user-indicated configuration. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0005" num="5"><claim-text> 5. The method of claim 4, wherein the user-indicated configuration includes at least one of a size of the matrix code on the presentation device and a position of the matrix code on the presentation device. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0006" num="6"><claim-text> 6. The method of claim 1 , wherein the accessibility content provides visual information regarding the content presentation. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0007" num="7"><claim-text> 7. The method of claim 6, wherein the visual information includes a narration of the visual aspects of the content presentation. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0008" num="8"><claim-text> 8. The method of claim 6, wherein the visual information is provided in a format for use with a Braille writer. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0009" num="9"><claim-text> 9. The method of claim 1 , wherein the accessibility content provides audio information regarding the content presentation. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0010" num="10"><claim-text> 10. A system, comprising: </claim-text><claim-text> an input that receives a broadcast signal carrying accessibility content; a processor that receives the broadcast signal and that generates a matrix code that includes the accessibility content; and </claim-text><claim-text> an output that transmits the matrix code to a presentation device for display. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0011" num="11"><claim-text> 11. The system of claim 10, wherein the content receiver is a connected and integral part of the presentation device. <!-- EPO <DP n="17"/>--> </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0012" num="12"><claim-text>12. The system of claim 10, wherein the processor compiles the audiovisual content and matrix code visual stream to suitably display the matrix code visual stream together with the audiovisual content. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0013" num="13"><claim-text> 13. The system of claim 10, wherein the processor is configured to read or decode the matrix codes from the broadcast signal and arrange the matrix codes relative to the audiovisual content. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0014" num="14"><claim-text> 14. The system of claim 13, wherein the processor is configured to output the matrix codes in place of the visual aspect of the audiovisual content. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0015" num="15"><claim-text> 15. The system of claim 10, wherein the processor is configured to develop matrix codes from a data stream including accessibility content and group portions of the accessibility content for the matrix codes. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0016" num="16"><claim-text> 16. A system, comprising: </claim-text><claim-text> an optical device configured to capture a matrix code presented with an audiovisual presentation; </claim-text><claim-text> a processor in communication with the optical device configured to receive the matrix code from the optical device and transform the matrix code into accessibility data readable by the accessibility device; and </claim-text><claim-text> an accessibility device interface component in communication with an accessibility device and the processor configured to output the accessibility data to the accessibility device, the accessibility device providing accessibility information to a user based on the received accessibility data. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0017" num="17"><claim-text> 17. The system of claim 16, wherein the accessibility device comprises a Braille writer and the accessibility information includes a narration relating to the audiovisual content.</claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0018" num="18"><claim-text>18. The system of claim 16, wherein the optical device captures the matrix code responsive to a user input. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0019" num="19"><claim-text> 19. The system of claim 17, wherein the optical device captures a plurality of matrix codes, responsive to the user input, each of the matrix codes associated with a portion of the accessibility information related to the audiovisual content. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0020" num="20"><claim-text> 20. The system of claim 16, wherein the accessibility device, the optical device and the accessibility device interface component are integrated into a single device. </claim-text></claim></claims><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
