<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2405137-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2405137" kind="B1" date="20140108" family-id="44801960" file-reference-id="318294" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146588491" ucid="EP-2405137-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2405137</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-11171162-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154850683" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>11171162</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20110623</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140557400" ucid="US-83045410-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>83045410</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20100706</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130820</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989325798" load-source="ipcr">F04B   1/04        20060101AFI20130628BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989325799" load-source="ipcr">F04B  19/00        20060101ALI20130628BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989325800" load-source="ipcr">F04B  53/16        20060101ALI20130628BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1989325801" load-source="ipcr">F04B  53/22        20060101ALI20130628BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989621478" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F04B   1/0426      20130101 LI20121116BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989623132" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F04B  53/16        20130101 LI20121116BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989624924" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F04B   1/0452      20130101 FI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989625025" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F04B  19/006       20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989625866" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F04B  53/22        20130101 LI20121116BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989631733" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">F04B   1/0456      20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370106" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Pumpe</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370107" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Pump</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132370108" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Pompe</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919518564" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>JONGHERYA CO LTD</last-name><address><country>CN</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919546485" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>JONGHERYA CO., LTD.</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919523376" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>HSIEH HUANG CHIN</last-name><address><country>TW</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919537926" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>Hsieh, Huang Chin</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919023363" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Hsieh, Huang Chin</last-name><address><street>No.42, Ln. 82, Guangyang Rd., Tanzi Dist.</street><city>427 Taichung City</city><country>TW</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR919023364" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Jongherya Co., Ltd.</last-name><iid>101253465</iid><address><street>No. 5-8, Lioujia Lane, Yunghe Rd., Daya Dist.</street><city>Taichung</city><country>CN</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919023362" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Viering, Jentschura &amp; Partner</last-name><iid>101239391</iid><address><street>Kennedydamm 55 / Roßstrasse</street><city>40476 Düsseldorf</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549924260" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS549893566" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549924261" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549786063" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549875867" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549803260" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549803261" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549786305" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549924262" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549924263" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549870767" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549786064" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549786069" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549786306" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549924264" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549786307" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549803262" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549875868" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549924265" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549786070" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549924266" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549786308" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549893567" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549786071" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549786321" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549893568" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS549893573" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549893574" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549875869" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549893575" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549870768" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549893576" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549870769" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS549893581" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549786322" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549875886" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549875887" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS549924267" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63960912" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001">BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</heading><heading id="h0002">1. Field of Invention</heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The invention relates to pumps and more particularly to such a pump with improved characteristics.</p><heading id="h0003">2. Description of Related Art</heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">Positive-displacement pumps for transporting fluids are known in the art, see for example <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="WO9942725A"><text>WO 9942725</text></patcit>. The pump comprises a periodic displacer, a piston or diaphragm, and two passive check valves. Due to the periodic movement of the piston or diaphragm, liquid is drawn into a pump chamber through an inlet valve and displaced from the pump chamber through an outlet valve. Due to the use of these valves, the conventional pumps are complicated and expensive. Moreover, the direction of transport is predetermined by the arrangement of the valves. When the pumping direction of such an arrangement is to be reversed, such pumps require a change of the operating direction of the valves from outside which entails a high expenditure.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">Further, a type of pump having a small constructional size and delivering small pumped streams is referred to as micro-pumps. The invention described later is directed to a miniaturized pump with improved characteristics.</p><heading id="h0004">SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</heading><p id="p0004" num="0004">It is therefore one object of the invention to provide a pump comprising an electric motor having a driving shaft; a substantially cylindrical main body comprising a central channel, four spaced radial partially threaded holes, each hole having one end communicating with the channel and the other end open, four valve assemblies each threadedly fastened in the hole, first and second cavities, disposed to each hole and communicating therewith, a spring activated first check valve disposed in each of the first cavities, a spring activated second check valve disposed in each of the second<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> cavities, an outlet disposed in the main body and having one end open, a partially threaded outlet orifice disposed in the main body to communicate with the outlet, the outlet orifice having one end open, an inlet disposed in the main body and having one end open, a partially threaded inlet orifice disposed in the main body to communicate with the inlet, the inlet orifice having one end open, four plungers each disposed in a plunger chamber communicating between the hole and the channel, opposite outlet and inlet tunnels, disposed in the main body, the outlet tunnel having one end communicating with the plunger chamber and the other end communicating with the first check valve via the hole, the inlet tunnel having one end communicating with the plunger chamber and the other end communicating with the second check valve via the hole, two snapping members each having a central hole and a snapping bifurcation at either bent end, the snapping bifurcation being slidably put on an inner end of the plunger, a plurality of first passages each communicating between the first cavity and the hole, and a plurality of second passages each communicating between the second cavity and the hole wherein one of the holes is disposed between the inlet orifice and the outlet orifice; a top cover disposed on the main body and comprising a central stepped diameter passageway, a first bearing disposed in the passageway, and an annular first groove spaced around the passageway on one surface facing and communicating with the outlet; a bottom cover disposed on the main body and comprising a bossed central hole, an annular second groove spaced around the hole on one surface facing and communicating with the inlet; and an eccentric shaft having one end secured to the driving shaft and disposed in the passageway to be supported by the bearing, the eccentric shaft further disposed in the channel and comprising an eccentric portion at the other end and passing the hole, a central protrusion projecting out of the other end to fit in a second bearing in the bottom cover, and a third bearing put on the eccentric portion to abut the eccentric shaft, wherein in response to<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> activating the motor, the eccentric shaft rotates to move the plungers back and forth in the plunger chambers; wherein the second check valve is open when the plunger moves to increase a volume of the plunger chamber in an inward stroke, and fluid from the inlet orifice is drawn into the plunger chamber via the second groove, the open second check valve, and the inlet tunnel; wherein the first check valve is open when the plunger moves to decrease the volume of the plunger chamber in an outward stroke to pressurize the fluid, and the pressurized fluid is supplied from the plunger chamber to the outlet orifice via the outlet tunnel, the open first check valve, and the first groove; wherein vacuum is created in the plunger chamber in the inward stroke to close the first check valve so that the fluid is directed into the plunger chamber via the open second check valve; wherein the fluid flows into the plunger chamber from the inlet orifice via the second groove, the open second check valve, and the inlet tunnel in the inward stroke; and wherein pressure is built in the plunger chamber in the outward stroke to close the second check valve so that the pressurized fluid is directed to flow out of the open first check valve.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">The above and other objects, features and advantages of the invention will become apparent from the following detailed description taken with the accompanying drawings.</p><heading id="h0005">BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</heading><p id="p0006" num="0006"><ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">FIG. 1</figref> is a perspective view of a pump according to the invention;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref> is an exploded perspective view of the pump;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">FIG. 3</figref> is an exploded view of the components in the lower portion of the pump in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 4</figref> is a longitudinal sectional view of the lower portion of the pump in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 5</figref> is a simplified view of <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 4</figref> showing details of the inlet arrangement;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0005">FIG. 6</figref> is a simplified view of <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 4</figref> showing details of the outlet arrangement;<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></li><li><figref idrefs="f0006">FIG. 7</figref> is a cross-sectional view of the lower portion of the pump in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIG. 2</figref>;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 8</figref> is a reduced view of <figref idrefs="f0004">FIG. 4</figref> with the motor mounted thereon, the motor activated and the eccentric portion of the eccentric shaft disposed to the right of a central axis;</li><li><figref idrefs="f0008">FIG. 9</figref> is a view similar to <figref idrefs="f0007">FIG. 8</figref> with the eccentric portion of the eccentric shaft disposed to the left of the central axis; and</li><li><figref idrefs="f0009">FIGS. 10, 11, and 12</figref> are exploded view of the valve assembly, the upper check valve, and the lower check valve respectively.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0006">DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</heading><p id="p0007" num="0007">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0001 f0002 f0003 f0004 f0005 f0006 f0007 f0008 f0009">FIGS. 1 to 12</figref>, a pump in accordance with the invention comprises the following components as discussed in detail below.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">A substantially eight-sided housing 10 comprises a main body 11, a top cover 12 provided on the main body 11, and a bottom cover 13 provided on the main body 11. The main body 11 comprises a central channel 110 and a plurality of (four) equally spaced radial partially threaded holes 111 arranged annually, each hole 111 having one end in communication with the channel 110 and the other end open to the periphery. A plurality of valve assemblies 14 each is fastened in the hole 111. An upper cavity 112 and a lower cavity 113 are provided to each hole 111 and in communication therewith. An upper check valve 15 is provided in the upper cavity 112 and a lower check valve 16 is provided in the lower cavity 113. An outlet 114 is provided in the main body 11 and has one end communicating with a partially threaded outlet orifice 116 and the other end open to the top of the main body 11. An inlet 115 is provided in the main body 11 and has one end communicating with a partially threaded inlet orifice 117 and the other end open to the bottom of the main body 11. The inlet orifice 117 is provided between two adjacent holes 111. A plunger 17 is provided in a plunger chamber 140 of each valve assembly 14. An outlet tunnel 141 and an opposite inlet<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> tunnel 142 are provided in the main body 11. The outlet tunnel 141 has one end communicating with the plunger chamber 140 and the other end communicating with the upper check valve 15 via the hole 111. The inlet tunnel 142 has one end communicating with the plunger chamber 140 and the other end communicating with the lower check valve 16 via the hole 111. The plunger 17 has on end extending into the channel 110 to be fastened by one of two snapping members 18. In detail, the bent snapping member 18 has a central hole 180 and a snapping bifurcation 181 at either end. The snapping bifurcations 181 are retained and put on the ends of the opposite plungers 17.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">The disc shaped top cover 12 comprises a central stepped diameter passageway 120, a bearing 121 provided in the passageway 120, and an annular groove 122 around the passageway 120 on one surface facing the main body 11. An eccentric shaft 19 is provided in both the passageway 120 and the bearing 121. The outlet 114 communicates with both the groove 122 and the upper cavity 112. The shaft 19 has one end 190 matingly secured to an open end of a driving shaft 21 of an electric motor 20, an eccentric portion 191 at the other end and passing the hole 180 , and a central protrusion 192 projecting out of the other end to fit in a bearing 131. A bearing 193 is put on the eccentric portion 191 to abut the shaft 19. The bottom cover 13 further comprises a bossed central hole 130 and an annular groove 132 around the hole 130 on one surface facing the main body 11. The inlet 115 communicates with both the groove 132 and the lower cavity 113.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">A ring shaped bushing member 22 has a plurality of holes 220 along edge, and a plurality of screws 221 driven through the holes 220 into a plurality of threaded holes 123 of the top cover 12. As a result, the bushing member 22 is mounted between the motor 20 and the top cover 12. An outlet line (not shown) is threaded connected to the outlet orifice 116 and an inlet line (not shown) is threaded connected to the inlet<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> orifice 117.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">An activation of the motor 20 will rotate the eccentric shaft 19 via the driving shaft 21. Thus, the eccentric portion 191 of the eccentric shaft 19 cyclically pushes the plungers 17. As such, each plunger 17 moves back and forth in the plunger chamber 140 (i.e., reciprocally). Further, the lower check valve 16 is open when the plunger 17 moves out of the plunger chamber 140 (i.e., in inward stroke). Fluid from the inlet orifice 117 is drawn into the plunger chamber 140 via the open lower check valve 16 and the groove 132. To the contrary, the upper check valve 15 is open when the plunger 17 moves into the plunger chamber 140 (i.e., in outward stroke). The pressurized fluid is thus supplied from the plunger chamber 140 to the outlet orifice 116 via the open upper check valve 15 and the groove 122.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIGS. 3</figref>, <figref idrefs="f0004">4</figref>, and <figref idrefs="f0009">10</figref>, the plunger 17 has an inner end 170 retained by the snapping bifurcation 181 of the snapping member 18. The cylindrical valve assembly 14 comprises, from inner end to outer end, a cylindrical receptacle 143 having bottom engaged with the outer end of the plunger 17 and internal threads 147, a plug 144 having first outer threads 149 secured to the threads 147 and second outer threads 148 secured to the hole 111, opposite outlet tunnel 141 and inlet tunnel 142 on the surface of the plunger chamber 140 in which the outlet tunnel 141 communicates with the upper check valve 15 and the inlet tunnel 142 communicates with the lower check valve 16, two spaced support rings 145 in the stepped diameter bore of the receptacle 143 for anchoring the plunger 17, and a sealing ring 146 put on the plunger 17 and clamped between the support rings 145.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">In operations, the lower check valve 16 is open when the plunger 17 moves out of the plunger chamber 140 in inward stroke. Fluid from the inlet orifice 117 is drawn into the plunger chamber 140 via the groove 132, the open lower check valve 16, and the inlet tunnel 142. To the contrary, the upper check valve 15 is open when the plunger<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> 17 moves into the plunger chamber 140 in outward stroke. The pressurized fluid is thus supplied from the plunger chamber 140 to the outlet orifice 116 via the outlet tunnel 141, the open upper check valve 15, and the groove 122.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">An upper passage 150 communicates with the upper cavity 112 and the hole 111 at both ends. The upper check valve 15 comprises a cylindrical receptacle 151, an anchoring member 152 on the shoulder bottom, a helical spring 153 seated on the anchoring member 152, a three-legged fastening member 154 put on the spring 153, a sealing ring 155 provided in the upper cavity 112 for fastening the receptacle 151, and an opening 156 in the bottom of the receptacle 151 to be in communication with the upper passage 150. In an inoperative position, the opening 156 is closed by the anchoring member 152 due to the expansion of the spring 153. Moreover, the expansion of the spring 153 urges the fastening member 154 to sealingly engage with the groove 122.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">In operations, the pressurized fluid is supplied from the plunger chamber 140 to the outlet orifice 116 via the outlet tunnel 141, the open upper check valve 15 (i.e., the upper passage 150, the opening 156, the anchoring member 152, and the receptacle 151), and the groove 122 in the outward stroke (i.e., volume of the plunger chamber 140 being decreased). To the contrary, a vacuum is created in the plunger chamber 140 in the inward stroke of the plunger 17. And in turn, the spring 153 pushes the anchoring member 152 to block the opening 156. Hence, the upper check valve 15 is closed. This ensures that fluid is prevented from flowing back to the plunger chamber 140 via the upper check valve 15. To the contrary, fluid flows into the plunger chamber 140 via the open lower check valve 16.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">A lower passage 160 communicates with the lower cavity 113 and the hole 111 at both ends. The upper check valve 16 comprises a cylindrical receptacle 161, an anchoring member 162 on the shoulder bottom, a helical spring 163 seated on the<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> anchoring member 162, a three-legged fastening member 164 put on the spring 163, a sealing ring 165 provided in the lower cavity 113 for fastening the receptacle 161, and an opening 166 in the bottom of the receptacle 161 to be in communication with the lower passage 160. In an inoperative position, the opening 166 is closed by the anchoring member 162 due to the expansion of the spring 163. The closure of the opening 166 also blocks the fluid communication with the groove 132.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">In operations, fluid flows into the plunger chamber 140 from the inlet orifice 117 via the groove 132, the open lower check valve 16 (i.e., the lower passage 160, the opening 166, the anchoring member 162, and the receptacle 161), and the inlet tunnel 142 in the inward stroke (i.e., volume of the plunger chamber 140 being increased). To the contrary, a pressure is built in the plunger chamber 140 in the outward stroke of the plunger 17 (i.e., fluid is pressurized). And in turn, the spring 163 is pushed by the pressurized fluid in the plunger chamber 140 to urge the anchoring member 162 to block the opening 166. Hence, the lower check valve 16 is closed. This ensures that fluid is prevented from flowing back from the groove 132 to the plunger chamber 140 via the lower check valve 16. To the contrary, the pressurized fluid flows out of the open upper check valve 15.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">While the invention has been described in terms of preferred embodiments, those skilled in the art will recognize that the invention can be practiced with modifications within the scope of the appended claims.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56985476" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Eine Pumpe umfassend:
<claim-text>einen elektrischen Motor (20) mit einer Antriebswelle (21);</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen im Wesentlichen zylindrischen Hauptkörper (11) umfassend einen zentralen Kanal (110), vier radial verteilt angeordnete Teilgewindebohrungen (111), jede Bohrung (111) hat ein mit dem Kanal (110) in Verbindung stehendes Ende und das andere Ende ist offen, vier Ventilanordnungen (14), die jeweils mit einem Gewinde in der Bohrung (111) befestigt sind, erste und zweite Hohlräume (112, 113), die in jeder Bohrung (111) angeordnet sind und damit in Verbindung stehen, ein federrückgestelltes erstes Kontrollventil (15), das in jedem der ersten Hohlräume (112) angeordnet ist, ein federrückgestelltes zweites Kontrollventil (16), das in jedem der zweiten Hohlräume (113) angeordnet ist, ein in dem Hauptkörper (11) angeordneter Auslass (114) mit einem offenen Ende, eine in dem Hauptkörper (11) angeordnete Teilgewindeauslassmündung (116), um mit dem Auslass (114) in Verbindung zu stehen, die Auslassmündung (116) hat ein offenes Ende, ein in dem Hauptkörper (11) angeordneter Einlass (115), der ein offenes Ende hat, eine in dem Hauptkörper (11) angeordnete Teilgewindeeinlassmündung (117), um mit dem Einlass (115) in Verbindung zu stehen, die Einlassmündung (117) hat ein offenes Ende, vier Kolben (17), die jeweils in einer Kolbenkammer (140) angeordnet sind, die eine Verbindung zwischen der Bohrung (111) und dem Kanal (110) herstellt, gegenüberliegende Auslass- und Einlasstunnel (141, 142), die in dem Hauptkörper (11) angeordnet sind, der Auslasstunnel (141) hat ein Ende, das mit der Kolbenkammer (140) in Verbindung steht, und das andere Ende steht mit dem ersten Kontrollventil (14) durch die Bohrung (111) in Verbindung, der Einlasstunnel (142) hat ein Ende, das in Verbindung mit der Kolbenkammer (140) steht, und das andere Ende steht in Verbindung mit dem zweiten Kontrollventil (16) durch die Bohrung (111), zwei Einrastelemente (18), jeweils versehen mit einer zentralen Bohrung (180) und einer Einrastverzweigung (181) an einem gebogenen Ende, die Einrastverzweigung (181) ist verschiebbar aufgesetzt am inneren Ende des Kolbens (17), eine Mehrzahl von ersten Durchgängen (150), die jeder eine Verbindung zwischen dem ersten Hohlraum (112) und der Bohrung (111) herstellt, und eine Mehrzahl von zweiten Durchgängen (118), die jeder zwischen dem<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> zweiten Hohlraum (113) und der Bohrung (111) eine Verbindung herstellt, wobei eine der Bohrungen (111) zwischen der Einlassmündung (117) und der Auslassmündung (116) angeordnet ist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine auf dem Hauptkörper (11) angeordnete obere Abdeckung (12), die einen zentralen, im Durchmesser stufenförmigen Durchgangsweg (120) umfasst, ein in dem Durchgangsweg (120) angeordnetes Lager (121), und eine ringförmige erste Nut (122), die um den Durchgangsweg (120) herum räumlich auf einer Oberfläche angeordnet ist, die dem Auslass (114) zugewandt ist und mit ihm in Verbindung steht;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine auf dem Hauptkörper (11) angeordnete Bodenabdeckung (13), die eine bossierte zentrale Bohrung (130) aufweist, eine ringförmige zweite Nut (132), die um die Bohrung (130) herum auf einer Oberfläche angeordnet ist, die dem Einlass (115) zugeordnet ist und mit ihm in Verbindung steht;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine exzentrische Welle (19) mit einem Ende (190), der an der Antriebswelle (21) befestigt ist und im Durchgangsweg (120) angeordnet ist, um von dem Lager (122) abgestützt zu werden, die exzentrische Welle (19) ist weiter in dem Kanal (110) angeordnet und umfasst einen exzentrischen Bereich (191) an dem anderen Ende und durchsetzt die Bohrung (180), einen zentralen Vorsprung (192), der aus dem anderen Ende herausragt, um in ein zweites Lager (131) in der Bodenabdeckung (13) zu passen, und ein drittes Lager (193), das an dem exzentrischen Bereich (191) angebracht ist, um an der exzentrischen Welle (19) anzuliegen, wobei durch Betätigen des Motors (20) sich die exzentrische Welle (19) dreht, um die Kolben (17) hin und her in den Kolbenkammern (140) zu bewegen;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei das zweite Kontrollventil (16) geöffnet ist, wenn sich der Kolben (17) bewegt, um ein Volumen der Kolbenkammer (140) beim nach innen gerichteten Takt zu erhöhen, und Flüssigkeit wird von der Eingangsmündung (117) in die Kolbenkammer (140) durch die zweite Nut (132), das offene Kontrollventil (16) und den Einlasstunnel (142) eingezogen;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei das erste Kontrollventil (15) geöffnet ist, wenn sich der Kolben (70) bewegt, um das Volumen der Kolbenkammer (140) bei einem nach außen gerichteten Takt zu verringern, um die Flüssigkeit mit Druck zu beaufschlagen, und die unter Druck stehende Flüssigkeit wird von der Kolbenkammer (140) in die<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --> Auslassmündung (116) eingespeist durch den Auslasstunnel (141), das offene erste Kontrollventil (15) und die erste Nut (122);</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei bei dem nach innen gerichteten Takt ein Vakuum in der Kolbenkammer (140) erzeugt wird, um das erste Kontrollventil (15) zu schließen, so dass die Flüssigkeit in die Kolbenkammer (140) durch das offene zweite Kontrollventil (16) gelenkt wird;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei die Flüssigkeit in die Kolbenkammer (140) von der Einlassmündung (117) durch die zweite Nut (132), das offene zweite Kontrollventil (16) und den Einlasstunnel (142) während des nach innen gerichteten Taktes fließt; und</claim-text>
wobei ein Druck in der Kolbenkammer (140) aufgebaut wird bei dem nach außen gerichteten Takt, um das zweite Kontrollventil (16) zu schließen, so dass die unter Druck gesetzte Flüssigkeit so geleitet wird, dass sie aus dem ersten offenen Kontrollventil (16) ausfließt.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Die Pumpe nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Ventilanordnung (16) weiter umfasst, von einem inneren Ende zu einem äußeren Ende, eine zylindrische Steckerbuchse (143) mit einem Boden, der mit dem Kolben (17) zusammenwirkt, und interne Gewinde (147), einen Stecker (144) mit ersten äußeren Gewinden (149) zum Einsetzen in die Gewinde (147), und zweiten äußeren Gewinden (148) zum Einsetzen in die Bohrung (111), zwei aneinander liegende Stützringe (145) in der Steckerbuchse (143) zum Verankern des Kolbens (17), und einen Dichtungsring (146), der auf den Kolben (17) aufgesetzt ist und zwischen den Stützringen (145) eingespannt ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Die Pumpe nach Anspruch 1, wobei das erste Kontrollventil (15) umfasst eine zylindrische Steckbuchse (151), ein Bodenverankerungselement (152), ein Vorspannungselement (153), das auf dem Verankerungselement (152) sitzt, ein dreibeiniges Befestigungselement (154), das in das Vorspannungselement (153) eingesetzt ist, ein Dichtungsringelement (155), das in dem ersten Hohlraum (112) angeordnet ist zur Befestigung der Steckbuchse (151), und eine Öffnung (156) im Boden der Steckbuchse (151), um mit dem ersten Durchgang (150) in Verbindung zu stehen, und wobei in einer Ruhestellung die Öffnung (156) durch das Verankerungselement (152) aufgrund der Ausdehnung des Vorspannungselementes (153) geschlossen ist.<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Die Pumpe nach Anspruch 1, wobei das zweite Kontrollventil (16) umfasst eine zylindrische Steckbuchse (161), ein Bodenverankerungselement (162), ein Vorspannungselement (163), das auf dem Verankerungselement (162) sitzt, ein dreibeiniges Befestigungselement (164), das auf das Vorspannungselement (163) aufgesetzt ist, ein in dem zweiten Hohlraum (113) angeordnetes Dichtungsringelement (165) zur Befestigung der Steckbuchse (161), und eine Bodenöffnung (166) in der Steckbuchse (161), um mit dem zweiten Durchgang (160) in Verbindung zu stehen, wobei in der Ruhestellung die Öffnung (166) durch das Verankerungselement (162) aufgrund der Ausdehnung des Vorspannungselementes (163) geschlossen ist.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56985477" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A pump comprising:
<claim-text>an electric motor (20) having a driving shaft (21);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a substantially cylindrical main body (11) comprising a central channel (110), four spaced radial partially threaded holes (111), each hole (111) having one end communicating with the channel (110) and the other end open, four valve assemblies (14) each threadedly fastened in the hole (111), first and second cavities (112, 113) disposed to each hole (111) and communicating therewith, a spring activated first check valve (15) disposed in each of the first cavities (112), a spring activated second check valve (16) disposed in each of the second cavities (113), an outlet (114) disposed in the main body (11) and having one end open, a partially threaded outlet orifice (116) disposed in the main body (11) to communicate with the outlet (114), the outlet orifice (116) having one end open, an inlet (115) disposed in the main body (11) and having one end open, a partially threaded inlet orifice (117) disposed in the main body (11) to communicate with the inlet (115), the inlet orifice (117) having one end open, four plungers (17) each disposed in a plunger chamber (140) communicating between the hole (111) and the channel (110), opposite outlet and inlet tunnels (141, 142) disposed in the main body (11), the outlet tunnel (141) having one end communicating with the plunger chamber (140) and the other end communicating with the first check valve (15) via the hole (111), the inlet tunnel (142) having one end communicating with the plunger chamber (140) and the other end communicating with the second check valve (16) via the hole (111), two snapping members (18) each having a central hole (180) and a snapping bifurcation (181) at either bent end, the snapping bifurcation (181) being slidably put on an inner end of the plunger (17), a plurality of first passages (150) each communicating between the first cavity (112) and the hole (111), and a plurality of second passages (160) each communicating between<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> the second cavity (113) and the hole (111) wherein one of the holes (111) is disposed between the inlet orifice (117) and the outlet orifice (116);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a top cover (12) disposed on the main body (11) and comprising a central stepped diameter passageway (120), a first bearing (121) disposed in the passageway (120), and an annular first groove (122) spaced around the passageway (120) on one surface facing and communicating with the outlet (114);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a bottom cover (13) disposed on the main body (11) and comprising a bossed central hole (130), an annular second groove (132) spaced around the hole (130) on one surface facing and communicating with the inlet (115); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an eccentric shaft (19) having one end (190) secured to the driving shaft (21) and disposed in the passageway (120) to be supported by the bearing (121), the eccentric shaft (19) further disposed in the channel (110) and comprising an eccentric portion (191) at the other end and passing the hole (180), a central protrusion (192) projecting out of the other end to fit in a second bearing (131) in the bottom cover (13), and a third bearing (193) put on the eccentric portion (191) to abut the eccentric shaft (19),</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein in response to activating the motor (20), the eccentric shaft (19) rotates to move the plungers (17) back and forth in the plunger chambers (140);</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the second check valve (16) is open when the plunger (17) moves to increase a volume of the plunger chamber (140) in an inward stroke, and fluid from the inlet orifice (117) is drawn into the plunger chamber (140) via the second groove (132), the open second check valve (16), and the inlet tunnel (142);</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the first check valve (15) is open when the plunger (17) moves to decrease the volume of the plunger chamber (140) in an outward stroke to pressurize the fluid, and the pressurized fluid is supplied from the plunger chamber (140) to the outlet orifice (116) via the outlet tunnel (141), the open first check valve (15), and the first groove (122);<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein vacuum is created in the plunger chamber (140) in the inward stroke to close the first check valve (15) so that the fluid is directed into the plunger chamber (140) via the open second check valve (16);</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein the fluid flows into the plunger chamber (140) from the inlet orifice (117) via the second groove (132), the open second check valve (16), and the inlet tunnel (142) in the inward stroke; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>wherein pressure is built in the plunger chamber (140) in the outward stroke to close the second check valve (16) so that the pressurized fluid is directed to flow out of the open first check valve (15).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The pump of claim 1, wherein the valve assembly (14) further comprises, from an inner end to an outer end, a cylindrical receptacle (143) having bottom engaged with the plunger (17) and internal threads (147), a plug (144) having first outer threads (149) secured to the threads (147) and second outer threads (148) secured to the hole (111), two spaced support rings (145) in the receptacle (143) for anchoring the plunger (17), and a sealing ring (146) put on the plunger (17) and clamped between the support rings (145).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The pump of claim 1, wherein the first check valve (15) comprises a cylindrical receptacle (151), a bottom anchoring member (152), a biasing member (153) seated on the anchoring member (152), a three-legged fastening member (154) put on the biasing member (153), a sealing ring member (155) disposed in the first cavity (112) for fastening the receptacle (151), and an opening (156) in bottom of the receptacle (151) to communicate with the first passage (150), and wherein in an inoperative position, the opening (156) is closed by the anchoring member (152) due to expansion of the biasing member (153).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The pump of claim 1, wherein the second check valve (16) comprises a cylindrical receptacle (161), a bottom anchoring member (162), a biasing member<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> (163) seated on the anchoring member (162), a three-legged fastening member (164) put on the biasing member (163), a sealing ring member (165) disposed in the second cavity (113) for fastening the receptacle (161), and a bottom opening (166) in the receptacle (161) to communicate with the second passage (160), and wherein in the inoperative position, the opening (166) is closed by the anchoring member (162) due to expansion of the biasing member (163).</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56985478" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Pompe comprenant :
<claim-text>un moteur électrique (20) qui présente un arbre d'entraînement (21) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un corps principal essentiellement cylindrique (11) qui comprend un canal central (110), quatre trous en partie filetés radiaux espacés (111), chaque trou (111) présentant une extrémité qui communique avec le canal (110) et l'autre extrémité étant ouverte, quatre ensembles de soupapes (14), chacune d'elles étant fixée par vissage dans le trou (111), des premières et secondes cavités, (112, 113) disposées au niveau de chaque trou (111) et qui communique avec celui-ci, un premier clapet anti-retour activé par ressort (15) disposé dans chacune des premières cavités (112), un second clapet anti-retour activé par ressort (16) disposé dans chacune des secondes cavités (113), une sortie (114) disposée dans le corps principal (11) et qui présente une extrémité ouverte, un orifice de sortie en partie fileté (116) disposé dans le corps principal (11) pour communiquer avec la sortie (114), l'orifice de sortie (116) présentant une extrémité ouverte, une entrée (115) disposée dans le corps principal (11) et qui présente une extrémité ouverte, un orifice d'entrée en partie fileté (117) disposé dans le corps principal (11) pour communiquer avec l'entrée (115), l'orifice d'entrée (117) présentant une extrémité ouverte, quatre pistons (17), chacun d'eux étant disposé dans une chambre de pistons (140) qui communique entre le trou (111) et le canal (110), une sortie opposée et des canaux d'entrée (141, 142) disposés dans le corps principal (11), le canal de sortie (141) présentant une extrémité qui communique avec la chambre de pitons (140) et l'autre extrémité qui communique avec le premier clapet anti-retour (15) par l'intermédiaire du trou (111), le canal d'entrée (142) présentant une extrémité qui communique avec la chambre de pistons (140) et l'autre extrémité qui communique avec le second clapet anti-retour (16) par l'intermédiaire du trou (111), deux éléments de clip (18) chacun d'eux présentant un trou central (180) et une bifurcation de clips (181) au niveau de l'une ou l'autre extrémité coudée, la bifurcation de clips (181) étant placée de façon coulissante sur une extrémité intérieure du<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> piston (17), une pluralité de premiers passages (150) chacun d'eux communiquant entre la première cavité (112) et le trou (111), et une pluralité de seconds passages (160) chacun d'eux communiquant entre la seconde cavité (113) et le trou (111), dans lequel l'un des trous (111) est disposé entre l'orifice d'entrée (117) et l'orifice de sortie (116) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un couvercle supérieur (12) disposé sur le corps principal (11) et qui comprend une dérivation (120) de diamètre étagé central, un premier roulement (121) disposé dans la dérivation (120), et une première rainure annulaire (122) espacée autour de la dérivation (120) sur une surface qui fait face à la sortie (114) et qui communique avec celle-ci ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un couvercle inférieur (13) disposé sur le corps principal (11) et qui comprend un trou central à bossage (130), une seconde rainure annulaire (132) espacée autour du trou (130) sur une surface qui fait face à l'entrée (115) et qui communique avec celle-ci ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un arbre excentrique (19) qui présente une extrémité (190) fixée sur l'arbre d'entraînement (21) et disposé dans la dérivation (120) pour être soutenu par le roulement (121), l'arbre excentrique (19) étant disposé en outre dans le canal (110) et comprenant une partie excentrique (191) au niveau de l'autre extrémité et passant à travers le trou (180), une saillie centrale (192) qui fait saillie à partir de l'autre extrémité pour s'ajuster dans un deuxième roulement (131) dans le couvercle inférieur (13), et un troisième roulement (193) placé sur la partie excentrique (191) pour venir en butée contre l'arbre excentrique (19);</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans laquelle, en réponse à l'activation du moteur (20), l'arbre excentrique (19) tourne pour déplacer les pistons (17) dans un mouvement de va-et-vient dans les chambres de pistons (140) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans laquelle le second clapet anti-retour (16) est ouvert lorsque le piston (17) se déplace pour augmenter un volume de la chambre de pistons (140) dans une trajectoire vers l'intérieur, et le fluide en provenance de l'orifice d'entrée (117) est entraîné dans la chambre de pistons (140) par l'intermédiaire de la seconde rainure (132), du second clapet anti-retour ouvert (16), et du canal d'entrée (142) ;<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>dans laquelle le premier clapet anti-retour (15) est ouvert lorsque le piston (17) se déplace pour réduire le volume de la chambre de pistons (140) dans une trajectoire vers l'extérieur pour mettre sous pression le fluide, et le fluide sous pression est fourni à partir de la chambre de pistons (140) à l'orifice de sortie (116) par l'intermédiaire du canal de sortie (141), du premier clapet anti-retour ouvert (15) et de la première rainure (122) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans laquelle un vide est créé dans la chambre de pistons (140) dans la trajectoire vers l'intérieur pour fermer le premier clapet anti-retour (15) de telle sorte que le fluide soit dirigé dans la chambre de pistons (140) par l'intermédiaire du second clapet anti-retour ouvert (16) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans laquelle le fluide circule dans la chambre de pistons (140) à partir de l'orifice d'entrée (117) par l'intermédiaire de la seconde rainure (132), du second clapet anti-retour ouvert (16) et du canal d'entrée (142) dans la trajectoire vers l'intérieur ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>dans laquelle une pression monte dans la chambre de pistons (140) dans la trajectoire vers l'extérieur pour fermer le second clapet anti-retour (16) de telle sorte que le fluide sous pression soit dirigé de manière à s'écouler hors du premier clapet anti-retour ouvert (15).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Pompe selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle l'ensemble de soupape (14) comprend en outre, à partir d'une extrémité inférieure vers une extrémité extérieure, un réceptacle cylindrique (143) qui présente un fond mis en prise avec le piston (17) et des filets intérieurs (147), un bouchon (144) qui présente des premiers filets extérieurs (149) fixés sur les filets (147) et des seconds filets extérieurs (148) fixés sur le trou (111), deux anneaux de soutien espacés (145) dans le réceptacle (143) pour un ancrage du piston (17), et un anneau d'étanchéité (146) placé sur le piston (17) et serré entre les anneaux de soutien (145).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Pompe selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle le premier clapet anti-retour (15) comprend un réceptacle cylindrique (151), un élément d'ancrage<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> inférieur (152), un élément de sollicitation (153) placé sur l'élément d'ancrage (152), un élément de fixation à trois jambes (154) placé sur l'élément de sollicitation (153), un élément d'anneau d'étanchéité (155) disposé dans la première cavité (112) pour la fixation du réceptacle (151), et une ouverture (156) située dans le fond du réceptacle (151) pour communiquer avec le premier passage (150), et dans laquelle, dans un état non fonctionnelle, l'ouverture (156) est fermée par l'élément d'ancrage (152) en raison d'une expansion de l'élément de sollicitation (153),</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Pompe selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle le second clapet anti-retour (16) comprend un réceptacle cylindrique (161), un élément d'ancrage inférieur (162), un élément de sollicitation (163) placé sur l'élément d'ancrage (162), un élément de fixation à trois jambes (164) placé sur l'élément de sollicitation (163), un élément d'anneau d'étanchéité (165) disposé dans la seconde cavité (113) pour la fixation du réceptacle (161), et une ouverture inférieure (166) située dans le réceptacle (161) pour communiquer avec le second passage (160), et dans laquelle, dans l'état non fonctionnelle, l'ouverture (166) est fermée par l'élément d'ancrage (162) en raison d'une expansion de l'élément de sollicitation (163).</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16672172" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="162" he="227" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="117" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="165" he="226" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --><figure id="f0004" num="4"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="149" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --><figure id="f0005" num="5,6"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="150" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --><figure id="f0006" num="7"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="165" he="191" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --><figure id="f0007" num="8"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="163" he="225" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --><figure id="f0008" num="9"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="158" he="219" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --><figure id="f0009" num="10,11,12"><img id="if0009" file="imgf0009.tif" wi="165" he="217" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
