<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2402217-B1" country="EP" doc-number="2402217" kind="B1" date="20140101" family-id="42665399" file-reference-id="315045" date-produced="20180826" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146552746" ucid="EP-2402217-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2402217</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-10746070-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154826669" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>10746070</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20100204</date><lang>JA</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140453059" ucid="JP-2009042307-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>JP</country><doc-number>2009042307</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20090225</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140453149" ucid="JP-2010051641-W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>JP</country><doc-number>2010051641</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20100204</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20130807</date></intention-to-grant-date><search-report-dispatch-date><date>20120703</date></search-report-dispatch-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988104524" load-source="ipcr">B60R  16/02        20060101AFI20120627BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988130445" load-source="ipcr">H02G  11/00        20060101ALI20120627BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988095822" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">B60R  16/0207      20130101 FI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988120164" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H02G   3/26        20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988125775" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H02G  11/003       20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132190722" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">KABELBAUMKORDELSTRUKTUR</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132190723" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">WIRE HARNESS LANYARD STRUCTURE</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132190724" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">STRUCTURE DE CORDONS DE FAISCEAU DE FILS</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918161520" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>YAZAKI CORP</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918135146" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>YAZAKI CORPORATION</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918137804" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>SATOU KUNIHIKO</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918148428" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>SATOU, KUNIHIKO</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918995473" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>SATOU, KUNIHIKO</last-name><address><street>c/o Yazaki Parts Co., Ltd. 2464-48, washizu Kosai-shi</street><city>Shizuoka</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918159082" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>YAMAGUCHI ATSUYOSHI</last-name><address><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918157113" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>YAMAGUCHI, ATSUYOSHI</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918995470" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>YAMAGUCHI, ATSUYOSHI</last-name><address><street>c/o Yazaki Parts Co., Ltd. 2464-48, washizu Kosai-shi</street><city>Shizuoka</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918995472" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Yazaki Corporation</last-name><iid>101122192</iid><address><street>4-28, Mita 1-chome</street><city>Minato-ku Tokyo 108-8333</city><country>JP</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918995471" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Grünecker, Kinkeldey, Stockmair &amp; Schwanhäusser Anwaltssozietät</last-name><iid>100060488</iid><address><street>Leopoldstrasse 4</street><city>80802 München</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="JP-2010051641-W"><document-id><country>JP</country><doc-number>2010051641</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20100204</date><lang>JA</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2010098189-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2010098189</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20100902</date><lang>JA</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548966159" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS548824948" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS548956503" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS548850708" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS548956534" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS548966160" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS548824949" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548956535" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS548956536" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS548968695" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS548956504" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS548956505" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548824958" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS548956537" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS548824959" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS548966161" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS548850709" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS548824960" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS548956586" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS548956542" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS548960998" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS548966166" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS548960999" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS548961000" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS548879057" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS548879058" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS548968696" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS548966167" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS548879059" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS548956543" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS548968697" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS548968702" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS548956544" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS548966168" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS548879060" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS548850710" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63956923" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001">Technical Field</heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to a wire harness installation structure in which a wire harness is installed so as to bridge over a stationary structural body and a movable structural body so as to supply electric power to an electric component or the like provided on the movable structural body such as, for example, a slidable door, a hatchback door or the like of a vehicle, the movable structural body being movably provided at the stationary structural body. Such a structure is known from <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="EP0855312A2"><text>EP 0 855 312 A2</text></patcit>.</p><heading id="h0002">Background Art</heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">In a wire harnesses installed in a vehicle, for example, a wire harness for supplying electric power to an electric component or the like provided on a movable structural body such as a slidable door, a hatchback door or the like is installed so as to bridge over a stationary structural body such as a vehicle body frame or the like and a movable structural body, the movable structural body being movably provided on the stationary structural body.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">As such a wire harness installation structure, the patent document 1 described below discloses a configuration wherein one end and the other end of a wire harness are respectively fixed to a movable structural body and a stationary structural body and a plate spring is provided along the wire harness so that the wire harness is supported by the plate spring.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">In the above configuration, the plate spring and the wire harness are fixed by using a binding member such as an adhesive vinyl tape, a band, a<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> clamp or the like.</p><heading id="h0003">Related Art Documents</heading><heading id="h0004">Patent Documents</heading><p id="p0005" num="0005">Patent Document 1: <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="JP2001359232A"><text>JP-A-2001-359232</text></patcit></p><heading id="h0005">Summary of Invention</heading><heading id="h0006">Problems that the Invention is to Solve</heading><p id="p0006" num="0006">However, the wire harness installation structure has problems as described below. While the wire harness is so constituted that electric wires are bound to the plate spring by the binding member such as a vinyl tape, a binding band, or the like and are supported and fixed to the plate spring, water or oil may be undesirably splashed to the installed wire harness. At that time, in a case where the wire harness is fixed to the plate spring by the binding member such as a vinyl tape, a binding band or the like, adhering water or oil may possibly stay in a small space between the binding member and the plate spring so that the plate spring can be corroded. Particularly, in a binding member which always exists at the lowermost portion of a wire harness, water or oil is liable to stay so that the binding member can be easily corroded.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">When corrosion occurs at a portion on the plate spring to which a load is particularly concentrated, the plate spring may be possibly broken by a synergetic effects of both the corrosion and the load. If the plate spring is broken, the wire harness is not stably supported. As a result, the problems may arise that the wire harness is not adequately moved so that it may be damaged by contact to a peripheral member and an electric power supplying<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> function is disabled.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">In addition, when a binding member such as a vinyl tape, a binding band or the like is wound around a portion on electric wires to which a large load is to be applied, the problems may arise that a bending way of the electric wires becomes instable and an extra load is applied to the electric wires so that a conductor in the electric wires is possibly broken.</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">A purpose of the invention that relates to solution of the above problems, is to improve bending durability of a slip-like plate spring which is arranged along a wire harness by preventing the slip-like plate spring from being corroded, and to provide a wire harness installation structure in which a conductor in electric wires is not liable to be broken.</p><heading id="h0007">Means for solving the Problems</heading><p id="p0010" num="0010">The purpose of the invention can be achieved by the following configurations.
<ol><li>(1) A wire harness installation structure according to claim 1.</li></ol><!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p><p id="p0011" num="0011">(2) The wire harness installation structure according to the above item (1), further comprising:
<ul><li>a stationary-side protector to which one ends of the bound slip-like plate spring and the electric wire bound to each other are fixed, and the stationary-side protector being fixed to the stationary-side structural body; and</li><li>a movable-side protector to which the other ends of the slip-like plate spring and the electric wire bound to each other are fixed, and the movable-side protector being fixed to the movable-side structural body.</li></ul></p><p id="p0012" num="0012">(3) The wire harness installation structure according to the above item (1) or the above item (2), wherein the slip-like plate spring and the electric wire bound to each other are covered with a protective member.</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">In accordance with the above configuration (1), water or oil adhering to the electric wire or the slip-like plate spring falls down to a lowermost end position along the slip-like plate spring or the electric wire. However, since the slip-like plate spring and the electric wire are not bound at a portion to which an extremely large load is applied, the portion being to be a curved lowermost portion of the slip-like plate spring, water or oil does not adhere to a binding member nor stay thereon so that the water or oil can be discharged from the wire harness installation structure.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">In addition, an extremely large load is also applied to a portion of the electric wires which is placed along the portion of the slip-like plate spring to<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> which the extremely large load is applied. However, since the slip-like plate spring and the electric wire are not bound at the portion of the electric wires to which the extremely large load is applied, a surplus load is not applied to the electric wires so that a conductor in the electric wires is not liable to be broken.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">In accordance with the above configuration (2), while a position of the movable-side protector is moved together with the movable-side structural body and the slip-like plate spring is deformed to be curved corresponding to the position, water or oil is discharged from the lowermost end of a curved position.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">In accordance with the above configuration (3), since the electric wire is covered with the protection member, the electric wire does not contact a peripheral member so that the electric wire is not liable to be broken.</p><heading id="h0008">Brief Description of the Drawings</heading><p id="p0017" num="0017"><ul><li>[<figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1] Fig. 1</figref> is a side elevational view of a main part showing a configuration of a wire harness installation structure according to an embodiment of the invention.</li><li>[<figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2] Fig. 2</figref> is a plan view showing the configuration of the wire harness installation structure.</li><li>[<figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3] Fig. 3</figref> is a plan view showing a binding form of a wire harness assembly.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0009">Mode for Carrying Out the Invention</heading><p id="p0018" num="0018">A preferable embodiment of a wire harness installation structure is described below with reference to the drawings.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">A wire harness structure 1 of the embodiment is used in a case where electric power is supplied to a heating wire provided on a window glass 3 at a<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> back door 5 of a vehicle as shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, the wire harness installation structure 1 is so configured that a wire harness assembly 7 is installed so as to bridge over a door panel 5a of the back door 5 corresponding to a stationary-side structural body and the window glass 3 corresponding to a movable structural body which is movably attached to the door panel 5a.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Figs. 2</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0003">3</figref>, the wire harness assembly 7 is formed such that electric wires 19 are provided along a slip-like plate spring 17 made of metal, the electric wires 19 and the plate spring 17 are bound by vinyl tapes as binding members 21 at predetermined intervals so as to be united and the whole outer periphery thereof is covered with a mesh shaped protective member 23. Therefore, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>, in a state where the wire harness assembly 7 is fastened and fixed to a stationary-side protector 11 and a movable-side protector 9, the protective member 23 of the wire harness assembly 7 is exposed at the outermost portion. Since the electric wires 19 are covered with the protective member 23, the electric wires 19 do not contact a peripheral member so that the damage can be prevented.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>, the both ends of the wire harness assembly 7 are respectively provided with the stationary-side protector 11 and the movable-side protector 9. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, the stationary-side protector 11 is fixed to the door panel 5a of the back door 5 as the stationary-side structural body and the movable-side protector 9 is fixed to the window glass 3 as the movable-side structural body.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">Meanwhile, for example, retaining projections (not shown) are respectively provided on the stationary-side protector 11 and the movable-side<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> protector 9 at respective predetermined positions. On the other hand, for example, retaining holes (not shown) are respectively provided at both ends of the slip-like plate spring 17. In the wire harness assembly 7 has the stationary-side protector 11 and the movable-side protector 9 as shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>, both ends of the slip-like plate spring 17 are respectively retained to the stationary-side protector 5 and the movable-side protector 9 and the both ends of the wire harness assembly 7 are further fastened to the stationary-side protector 11 and the movable-side protector 9, respectively.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>, a stationary-side coupling section 7a of the wire harness assembly 7 is fastened and fixed to the stationary-side protector 11 by a binding band 13 so as not to be pulled out, and a movable-side coupling section 7b of the wire harness assembly 7 is fastened and fixed to the movable-side protector 9 by a binding band 15 so as not to be pulled out.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">Each of the stationary-side protector 11 and the movable-side protector 9 is formed of a compound resin in an integral molding manner. The slip-like plate spring 17 is formed of a stainless thin plate.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">The wire harness assembly 7 has a surplus length portion that allows the window glass 3 to be vertically moved and is provided at a prolongation portion 7c placed between the stationary-side coupling section 7a fixed on the stationary-side protector 11 of the door panel 5a as the stationary structural body and the movable-side coupling section 7b fixed on the window glass 3 as the movable structural body.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">The window glass 3 is attached to the door panel 5a so as to be vertically moved by a lifting/lowering device (not shown) in directions indicated by arrows A and B shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>. In <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, a symbol Pa indicates the<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> window glass 3 in a state that it is moved to an upper limit position, a symbol Pb indicates the window glass 3 in a half-open state that it is moved to an intermediate position, and a symbol Pc indicates the window glass 3 in a full-open state that it is moved to a lower limit position.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">In association with the vertical movement of the window glass 3, a curved portion of the wire harness assembly 7 installed so as to bridge over the door panel 5a and the window glass 3 is moved as shown by symbols P1, P2 and P3.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">The curved portion P1 indicates a curved state of the wire harness assembly 7 at a time when the window glass 3 is moved to the upper limit position. At that position, a curvature radius of the wire harness assembly 7 in the vicinity of the stationary-side protector 11 is the smallest and the portion having the smallest curvature radius is arranged at the lowermost end position of the wire harness assembly 7.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">The curved portion P2 indicates a curved state of the wire harness assembly 7 at a time when the window glass 3 is moved to the intermediate position. At that position, a curvature radius of the wire harness assembly 7 in the vicinity of the stationary-side protector 11 is the smallest and the portion having the smallest curvature radius is arranged at the lowermost end position of the wire harness assembly 7.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">The curved portion P3 indicates a curved state of the wire harness assembly 7 at a time when the window glass 3 is moved to the lower limit position. At that position, a curvature radius of the wire harness assembly 7 in the vicinity of the movable-side protector 9 is the smallest and the portion having the smallest curvature radius is arranged at the lowermost end position<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> of the wire harness assembly 7.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">Each of the curved portions P1, P2 and P3 is a portion where the curvature radius becomes the smallest when the wire harness assembly 7 is deformed and an extremely large load is applied. Each of the curved portions P1, P2 and P3 is placed at the lowermost position of the wire harness assembly 7 and is a portion which allows water or oil to be liable to stay when the water or oil is splashed thereto. Particularly, each of areas indicated by dotted lines at the curved portions P1 and P3 is a portion to which a load is mostly applied in the wire harness assembly 7.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">Each of parts corresponding to the curved portions P1 and P3 in the wire harness assembly 7, is not bound by the binding member 21 as in areas shown by dotted lines in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>. That is, in the wire harness assembly 7, the electric wires 19 are bound to the slip-like plate spring 17 at portions other than a portion in the vicinity of the stationary-side protector 11 and a portion in the vicinity of the movable-side protector 9 as the portions corresponding to the curved portions P1 and P3.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, in a case where the window glass 3 is controlled to be vertically moved from the position Pc indicated by a solid line to the position Pb or Pa indicated by a virtual line, or from the position Pa to the position Pb or Pc, the wire harness installation structure 1 having the above configuration is adopted and electric power is supplied to the heating wire of the window glass 3 via the wire harness installation structure 1 from a power supply circuit (not shown) provided in the door panel 5a.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">At that time, while the wire harness assembly 7 is bent and deformed in accordance with the position of the window glass 3 as shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, a<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> large peripheral space is attained so that the wire harness assembly 7 does not interfere the peripheral portion even when the wire harness assembly 7 is sagged. In addition, since the wire harness assembly 7 has the slip-like plate spring 17 built therein as described above, a rigidity with respect to a width direction of the wire harness assembly 7 is applied to the wire harness assembly 7 over the whole length of the wire harness assembly 7 and positional restriction of the wire harness assembly 7 can be taken by the application of the rigidity. Consequently, it is possible to eliminate troubles such as generation of an abnormal noise, a damage or the like due to contact to the door panel 5a.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">During controlling of the lifting or lowering movement of the window glass 3, the curvature radius of the wire harness assembly 7 becomes small at portions in the vicinity of the stationary-side protector 11 and the movable-side connector 9 as shown by the curved portions P1 and P3 in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>. The load to the slip-like plate spring 17 becomes large as the curvature radius becomes small.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">The position where the curvature radius of the wire harness assembly 7 is small and the load is large, is the lowermost end position of the wire harness assembly 7 including the slip-like plate spring 17.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">Here, when assuming that water or oil is splashed to the wire harness assembly 7 in a state indicated by a virtual line in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, the water or oil flows down to a portion in the vicinity of the stationary-side protector 11 along the slip-like plate spring 17 or the electric wires 19. However, since the curved portion P1 in the vicinity of the stationary-side protector 11 is not bound by the binding member 21 as shown in the area indicated by the dotted line in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>, the water or oil does not stay at the curved portions P1 and P3 so as to be<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> discharged out of the wire harness assembly 7 as it is by the dropping.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">On the other hand, when assuming that water or oil is splashed to the wire harness assembly 7 in a state shown by the solid line in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, the water or oil flows down to a portion in the vicinity of the movable-side protector 9 along the slip-like plate spring 17 or the electric wires 19. However, since the curved portion P3 of the movable-side protector 9 is not bound by the binding member 21, the water or oil does not stay at the curved portions P3 so as to be discharged out of the wire harness assembly 7 as it is by the dropping.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">As described above, since water or oil is smoothly discharged out of the wire harness assembly 7 even when the water or oil is splashed to the wire harness assembly 7, the water or oil does not stay at the slip-like plate spring 17 so that the wire harness assembly 7 is not liable to be corroded. Consequently, bending durability of the slip-like plate spring 17 is improved and the wire harness assembly 7 can be permanently deformed at a constant elasticity.</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">In addition, the areas of the curved portions P1 and P3 indicated by dotted lines are the portions to which a load is mostly applied to the electric wires 19. However, since the portions are not bound by the binding members 21, a surplus load is not applied to the electric wires 19 so that the conductor in the electric wires 19 is not liable to be broken. Consequently, the reliability of the wire harness assembly 7 is improved.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">The invention is not limited to the above mentioned embodiment, but can be varied or modified if needed. The material, shape, dimension, value, style, number, installation position and the like of each of the structural components in the above embodiment can be arbitrarily determined and is not<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> limited thereto as long as the invention can be achieved.</p><p id="p0043" num="0043">For example, while the vinyl tape is used as the binding member 21 in the embodiment, a binding band made of a soft resin can be used instead of that.</p><heading id="h0010">Industrial Applicability</heading><p id="p0044" num="0044">In accordance with the wire harness installation structure according to the invention, since the electric wires are bound to the plate spring by the binding members at the portions other than a portion of the plate spring to which a load is mostly applied, water or oil does not stay at a portion such as the curved lowermost portion to which an extremely large load is applied, even when the water or oil is splashed to the wire harness. Consequently, it is possible to prevent the portion applied with the extremely large load from being corroded. With this, the slip-like plate spring can stably support the electric wires for a long time period. The bending durability of the slip-like plate spring can be improved.</p><p id="p0045" num="0045">In addition, an extremely large load is applied to a portion of the electric wires existing along a portion of the slip-like plate spring to which an<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> extremely large load is applied. However, since the slip-like plate spring and the electric wires are not bound to each other at a portion to which an extremely large load is not applied, a surplus load is not applied to the electric wires so that the conductor in the electric wires is not liable to be broken.</p><p id="p0046" num="0046">Further, since the bending durability of the slip-like plate spring can be improved, breaking of the electric wires can be prevented so that the reliability of the wire harness can be improved.</p><heading id="h0011">Description of Reference Numerals and Signs</heading><p id="p0047" num="0047"><dl id="dl0001" compact="compact"><dt>1</dt><dd>wire harness installation structure</dd><dt>3</dt><dd>window glass</dd><dt>5</dt><dd>back door</dd><dt>7</dt><dd>wire harness assembly</dd><dt>9</dt><dd>movable-side protector</dd><dt>11</dt><dd>stationary-side protector</dd><dt>13, 15</dt><dd>binding member</dd><dt>17</dt><dd>slip-like plate spring</dd><dt>19</dt><dd>electric wires</dd><dt>21</dt><dd>binding member (vinyl tape)</dd><dt>23</dt><dd>protective member</dd></dl></p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56978258" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Eine Kabelbauminstallation (1), umfassend:
<claim-text>einen elektrischen Draht, (19), der ein Ende hat, das elektrisch mit einer elektrischen Komponente verbunden ist, die an einem unbeweglichen Bauteil (5) vorgesehen ist, und dessen anderes Ende elektrisch mit einer elektrischen Komponente verbunden ist, die an einem beweglichen Bauteil (3) vorgesehen ist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei das bewegliche Bauteil Positionen (Pa, Pb, Pc) hat;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine streifenförmige Blattfeder (17), die aus Metall hergestellt ist und mit einem Ende an dem unbeweglichen Bauteil (5) und mit dem anderen Ende an dem beweglichen Bauteil (3) befestigt ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Halteelement (21), das dazu ausgelegt ist, den elektrischen Draht (19) an der streifenförmigen Blattfeder (17) zu halten,</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>dadurch gekennzeichnet, dass</b> der elektrische Draht (19) an der streifenförmigen Blattfeder (17) durch das Halteelement (21) an einem Abschnitt (P1, P3) gehalten wird, der nicht ein Abschnitt ist, der den kleinsten Biegeradius der streifenförmigen Blattfeder (17) hat, an dem eine überaus große Last anliegt, wenn die streifenförmige Blattfeder (17) verformbar in den Endpositionen (Pa, Pc) des beweglichen Bauteils gebogen ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Die Kabelbauminstallation (1) gemäß Anspruch 1, ferner umfassend:
<claim-text>einen auf der unbeweglichen Seite angebrachten Schutz (11) an dem ein Ende der gehaltenen streifenförmigen Blattfeder (17) und des elektrischen Drahts (19), die aneinander gehalten sind, fixiert sind, wobei der auf der unbeweglichen Seite angebrachte Schutz (11) an dem auf der unbeweglichen Seite angebrachten Bauteil (5) angeordnet ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen auf der beweglichen Seite angebrachten Schutz (9), an dem die anderen Enden der streifenförmigen Blattfeder (17) und des elektrischen Drahts (19), die aneinander gehalten sind, fixiert sind, wobei der auf der beweglichen Seite angebrachte Schutz (9) an dem auf der beweglichen Seite angebrachten Bauteil (3) angeordnet ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Die Kabelbauminstallation (1) gemäß Anspruch 1, wobei die streifenförmige Blattfeder (17) und der elektrischen Draht (19), die aneinander gehalten sind, mit einem Schutzelement (23) bedeckt sind.<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Die Kabelbauminstallation (1) gemäß Anspruch 2, wobei die streifenförmige Blattfeder (17) und der elektrischen Draht (19), die aneinander gehalten sind, mit einem Schutzelement (23) bedeckt sind.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56978259" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>A wire harness installation structure (1) comprising:
<claim-text>an electric wire (19) that has one end electrically connected to an electric component provided on a stationary structural body (5) and the other end electrically connected to an electric component provided on a movable structural body (3);</claim-text>
<claim-text>the movable structural body (3) having positions (Pa, Pb, Pc);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a slip-like plate spring (17) that is made of metal and has one end fixed to the stationary structural body (5) and the other end fixed to the movable structural body (3); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a binding member (21) that is adapted to bind the electric wire (19) to the slip-like plate spring (17),</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>characterized in that</b> the electric wire (19) is bound to the slip-like plate spring (17) by the binding member (21) at a portion other than a portion (P1, P3) which has the smallest curvature radius of the slip-like plate spring (17) to which an extremely large load is applied when the slip-like plate spring (17) is deformably bent in the end positions (Pa, Pc) of the movable structural body.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The wire harness installation structure (1) according to claim 1, further comprising:
<claim-text>a stationary-side protector (11) to which one ends of the bound slip-like plate spring (17) and the electric wire (17) bound to each other are fixed, and the stationary-side protector (11) being fixed to the stationary-side structural body (5); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a movable-side protector (9) to which the other ends of the slip-like plate spring (17) and the electric wire (19) bound to each other are fixed, and the movable-side protector (9) being fixed to the movable-side structural body (3).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The wire harness installation structure (1) according to claim 1, wherein the slip-like plate spring (17) and the electric wire (19) bound to each other are covered with a protective member (23).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The wire harness installation structure (1) according to claim 2, wherein the slip-like plate spring (17) and the electric wire (19) bound to each other are covered with a protective member (23).</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56978260" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Structure d'installation de faisceau de câble (1) comportant :
<claim-text>un câble électrique (19) qui a une extrémité reliée électriquement à un composant électrique prévu sur un corps structurel fixe (5) et l'autre extrémité électriquement reliée à un composant électrique prévu sur un corps structurel mobile (3) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>le corps structurel mobile (3) ayant des positions (Pa, Pb, Pc) ;</claim-text>
<claim-text>un ressort à lame en forme de gaine (17) qui est fabriqué en métal et a une extrémité fixée sur le corps structurel fixe (5) et l'autre extrémité fixée sur le corps structurel mobile (3) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un élément de liaison (21) qui est prévu pour lier le câble électrique (19) au ressort à lame en forme de gaine (17),</claim-text>
<claim-text><b>caractérisée en ce que</b> le câble électrique (19) est lié au ressort à lame en forme de gaine (17) par l'élément de liaison (21) au niveau d'une partie autre qu'une partie (P1, P3) qui a le plus petit rayon de courbure du ressort à lame en forme de gaine (17) sur laquelle une charge extrêmement grande est appliquée quand le ressort à lame en forme de gaine (17) est plié de manière déformable dans les positions d'extrémité (Pa, Pc) du corps structurel mobile.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Structure d'installation de faisceau de câble (1) selon la revendication 1, comportant en outre :
<claim-text>un protecteur du côté fixe (11) sur lequel des premières extrémités du ressort à lame en forme de gaine lié (17) et du câble électrique (17) liés l'un à l'autre sont fixées,<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> et le protecteur du côté fixe (11) étant fixé sur le corps structurel du côté fixe (5) ; et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un protecteur du côté mobile (9) sur lequel les autres extrémités du ressort à lame en forme de gaine (17) et du câble électrique (19) liés l'un à l'autre sont fixées, et le protecteur du côté mobile (9) étant fixé sur le corps structurel du côté mobile (3).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Structure d'installation de faisceau de câble (1) selon la revendication 1, dans laquelle le ressort à lame en forme de gaine (17) et le câble électrique (19) liés l'un à l'autre sont recouverts avec un élément de protection (23).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Structure d'installation de faisceau de câble (1) selon la revendication 2, dans laquelle le ressort à lame en forme de gaine (17) et le câble électrique (19) liés l'un à l'autre sont recouverts avec un élément de protection (23).</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16668527" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="157" he="206" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="118" he="225" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="114" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
