<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2959919-A1" country="EP" doc-number="2959919" kind="A1" date="20151230" family-id="51062762" file-reference-id="310470" date-produced="20180825" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="160452759" ucid="EP-2959919-A1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2959919</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20151230</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-14306004-A" is-representative="YES"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP193868486" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>14306004</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20140625</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP193868487" load-source="patent-office" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>14306004.4</doc-number><date>20140625</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC162033022" ucid="EP-14306004-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>14306004</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20140625</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL-1988522705" load-source="docdb">A61L   2/07        20060101AFI20141030BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL-1984696472" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">A61L   2/07        20130101 FI20160106BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT165549743" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">Vorrichtung und Verfahren zur Herstellung und Sterilisation dickflüssiger Produkte mit temperaturempfindlichen Verbindungen</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT165549744" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">Apparatus and method for the preparation and sterilization of viscous products containing temperature sensitive compounds</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT165549745" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">Appareil et procédé pour la préparation et la stérilisation de produits visqueux contenant des composés sensibles à la température</invention-title><citations><patent-citations><patcit mxw-id="PCIT335964260" load-source="docdb" ucid="EP-1734073-A2"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>1734073</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20061220</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="A" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT377490035" load-source="docdb" ucid="JP-H09175985-A"><document-id format="epo"><country>JP</country><doc-number>H09175985</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>19970708</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="XYI" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT335964264" load-source="docdb" ucid="US-20090148343-A1"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>20090148343</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20090611</date></document-id><sources><source name="APP" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT377496953" load-source="docdb" ucid="US-201213713760-A" dnum-type="application"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>201213713760</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20121213</date></document-id><sources><source name="APP" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT335964265" load-source="docdb" ucid="US-20140165634-A1"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>20140165634</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20140619</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="Y" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT335964262" load-source="docdb" ucid="WO-2002072156-A2"><document-id format="epo"><country>WO</country><doc-number>2002072156</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20020919</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="A" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit><patcit mxw-id="PCIT335964263" load-source="docdb" ucid="WO-2007148022-A2"><document-id format="epo"><country>WO</country><doc-number>2007148022</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20071227</date></document-id><sources><source name="SEA" category="A" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit></patent-citations></citations></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR1103315266" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>SPX APV DANMARK AS</last-name><address><country>DK</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR1103319407" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>SPX APV DANMARK A/S</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR1101644693" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>SPX APV Danmark A/S</last-name><iid>101189245</iid><address><street>Pasteursvej 1</street><city>8600 Silkeborg</city><country>DK</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1103303418" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>COELHO GIL</last-name><address><country>FR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1103341566" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>COELHO, Gil</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1101652662" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>COELHO, Gil</last-name><address><street>10, rue de la Garenne</street><city>27110 EPREVILLE PRES LE NEUBOURG</city><country>FR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1103303751" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>MARES PHILIPPE</last-name><address><country>FR</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1103317466" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>Mares, Philippe</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR1101644688" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Mares, Philippe</last-name><address><street>SPX Flow Technology SAS Zone Industrielle n°2 6 Rue Jacquard - BP 684</street><city>27006 EVREUX</city><country>FR</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR1101652433" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Collet, Alain</last-name><iid>100049796</iid><address><street>Marks &amp; Clerk France Conseils en Propriété Industrielle Immeuble Visium 22, avenue Aristide Briand</street><city>94117 Arcueil Cedex</city><country>FR</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS660627775" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS660789879" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS660627777" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS660707074" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS660713187" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS660628829" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS660789880" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS660627778" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS660628830" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS660628839" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS660706276" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS660707079" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS660707080" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS660627783" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS660628840" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS660627784" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS660789881" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS660713188" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS660628841" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS660707081" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS660628842" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS660730308" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS660789882" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS660730309" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS660730310" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS660628328" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS660628329" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS660789883" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS660706277" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS660713189" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS660730320" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS660789884" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS660730321" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS660713190" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS660707082" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS660706278" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS660713207" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS660628330" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states><ep-extended-states><ep-extended-state-data><country>BA</country></ep-extended-state-data><ep-extended-state-data><country>ME</country></ep-extended-state-data></ep-extended-states></designated-states></international-convention-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA166480857" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p id="pa01" num="0001">The invention relates to an apparatus for the preparation and sterilization of a viscous fluid (10) containing a temperature sensitive compound (11) diluted into a viscous matrix (12), characterized in that it comprises:<br/>
- a heat treatment unit (15), fed with the viscous matrix (12), wherein the viscous matrix (12) is sterilized,<br/>
- a mixing unit (17), fed with the sterilized viscous matrix (12) and the sterile temperature sensitive compound (11), wherein the temperature sensitive compound (11) is incorporated into the sterilized viscous matrix (12) to form the viscous fluid (10).
<img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="141" he="95" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA166760669" lang="EN" source="EPO" load-source="docdb"><p>The invention relates to an apparatus for the preparation and sterilization of a viscous fluid (10) containing a temperature sensitive compound (11) diluted into a viscous matrix (12), characterized in that it comprises: 
- a heat treatment unit (15), fed with the viscous matrix (12), wherein the viscous matrix (12) is sterilized, 
- a mixing unit (17), fed with the sterilized viscous matrix (12) and the sterile temperature sensitive compound (11), wherein the temperature sensitive compound (11) is incorporated into the sterilized viscous matrix (12) to form the viscous fluid (10).</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES98405558" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001"><b>TECHNICAL FIELD</b></heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates to apparatuses and methods for preparing and sterilizing a viscous fluid containing a temperature sensitive compound diluted in a viscous matrix. Such viscous fluid includes, without limitation, cosmetic products, drugs, vegetal and animal extracts, and/or food products into which is diluted a temperature sensitive compound such as for example a perfume or a pharmaceutical active compound. The present invention is particularly suited to the preparation and sterilization of cosmetic cream containing temperature-sensitive perfumes. The invention relates more generally to devices, systems, and methods for processing viscous fluids.</p><heading id="h0002"><b>BACKGROUND ART</b></heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">The industrial production of food has faced for years the issue of aseptic production and packaging. The aim of such production and packaging is to extend shelf life of products, to preserve nutritional qualities for an extended period of time and to kill germs potentially harmful to health. Government regulations have rapidly constrained the range of options available to extend product shelf life and specifically banned inclusion of many preservatives in foodstuffs destined for human ingestion.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">Heat treatment of liquid food products for the purpose of sterilization is a commonly used industrial process. To achieve rapid heating up to high temperatures, typically exceeding 100°C, steam is employed. The heating may take place either directly or indirectly. In indirect heating, use is made of different types of heat exchangers. In direct heating, steam is directly incorporated into the product. A sterilization process, well known for dairy products, is commonly referred to as the UHT process, which stands for <i>Ultra Heat Treatment</i> or <i>Ultra High Temperature;</i> an appropriate control of both temperature level and exposure duration of the heat treatment allowing the extermination of those microorganisms which are found in dairy products.<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --></p><p id="p0004" num="0004">There are two types of steam incorporation processes: injection and infusion. With injection, steam is injected into the product in a closed system, whereas infusion implies that the product is finely sprayed and caused to pass through a space filled with steam. In both cases, the supplied steam rapidly and efficiently heats the product to the desired temperature and the product is then kept at this temperature during a given predetermined exposure duration. The supplied steam must thereafter be removed from the product in order to avoid diluting it.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">This normally takes place by evaporative cooling, commonly referred as flash-cooling, in a vacuum chamber. During the process, the steam is released and condensed at the same time as the product is cooled down to a similar temperature it had before the heat treatment. The evaporative cooling usually takes place by feeding the steamed product, under pressure, into a vacuum chamber. When the product enters the vacuum chamber, the liquid boils, the steam is released and rises upwards in the chamber while the product accumulates in the lower region of the chamber. Thus cooled, the product may be tapped off from the lower region of the chamber. The steam which leaves the product together with incondensable gases is to be condensed in order for it to be able to be run off to an outlet.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">The cosmetic industry is facing a similar issue. As one example, skincare and cosmetic creams are meant to be used multiple times, for a use life extended to months. To address that issue, the cosmetic industry includes various preservatives, such as parabens, which prevent the growth of fungi and bacteria. A number of studies highlighted the potential harmfulness of such preservatives to human health. Other compounds have been investigated as paraben substitutes, but show lower efficiency and/or still carry the risk of long term impact on human health. Consequently, regulations are being more and more restrictive about preservatives integration into cosmetic products.</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">As an alternative route to incorporating preservatives, it was thought to sterilize cosmetic products. The high viscosity of the products prohibits the use of filters. Several methods and devices based upon heating were investigated. In particular, United States Patent Application <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US20090148343A"><text>US 2009/0148343</text></patcit> discloses the<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> sterilization of a cosmetic product based upon indirect heating, by means of circulating the product through a circuit traversing heating and cooling baths.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">To improve the efficiency of the sterilization process, apparatus and method to sterilize viscous products based upon the alternative direct heating have been developed. However, it remains to be found a sterilizing method that allows keeping the expected properties of a temperature sensitive active compound diluted into a viscous matrix.</p><heading id="h0003"><b>SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</b></heading><p id="p0009" num="0009">The sterilization of cosmetic products is a good solution to extend shelf life and preserve properties of the product for an extended period of time while avoiding the inclusion of various additives potentially harmful to health. One challenge is to eliminate or at least minimize the denaturization - caused by heat treatment - of temperature sensitive compound contained in such cosmetic products.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">It is one object of the present invention to cope with the disadvantages of the state of the art by providing an apparatus and method for the preparation and sterilization of a viscous fluid containing at least one temperature sensitive compound diluted in a viscous matrix.</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">To this end, certain embodiments of the present invention relate to an apparatus for the preparation and sterilization of a viscous fluid containing a sterile temperature sensitive compound diluted into a viscous matrix, characterized in that it comprises:
<ul><li>a heat treatment unit, fed with the viscous matrix, wherein the viscous matrix is sterilized,</li><li>a mixing unit, fed with the sterilized viscous matrix and the sterile temperature sensitive compound, wherein the temperature sensitive compound is incorporated into the sterilized viscous matrix to form the viscous fluid.</li></ul><!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --></p><p id="p0012" num="0012">Certain embodiments of the present invention also relate to an apparatus wherein the heat treatment unit comprises:
<ul><li>a direct heating device wherein the viscous matrix is heated up by incorporating steam into the viscous matrix,</li><li>a high temperature circuitry, fed with the heated viscous matrix, wherein the heated viscous matrix is maintained in a temperature range of approximately 120°C to 155°C for a predetermined residence time to allow sterilization of the viscous matrix, and</li><li>an evaporative cooling device, fed with the sterilized viscous matrix, wherein the sterilized viscous matrix is cooled to a temperature of between approximately 20 °C to 90 °C by steam evaporation.</li></ul></p><p id="p0013" num="0013">In certain embodiments of the present invention, the direct heating unit comprises a steam infusion device. In certain embodiments, the direct heating unit comprises a steam injection device. Additionally, the apparatus may further comprise an indirect heating device located upstream the direct heating device, configured to feed the direct heating device with the viscous matrix at a temperature of between approximately 20 °C to 90 °C.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">In certain embodiments of the present invention, the heat treatment unit comprises:
<ul><li>a first heat exchanger device wherein the viscous matrix is heated up,</li><li>a high temperature circuitry, fed with the heated viscous matrix, wherein the heated viscous matrix is maintained in a temperature range of approximately 120°C to 155°C for a predetermined residence time to allow sterilization of the viscous matrix, and<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --></li><li>a second heat exchanger, fed with the sterilized viscous matrix, wherein the sterilized viscous matrix is cooled to a temperature of between approximately 20°C to 90°C.</li></ul></p><p id="p0015" num="0015">In certain embodiments of the invention, the apparatus further comprises a sterilizing device located upstream the mixing unit, fed with the temperature sensitive compound.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">In certain embodiments of the invention, the sterilizing device fed with the temperature sensitive compound comprises a filtration device or a heat treatment device. A device ensuring sterilization of the temperature sensitive compound by radiation exposure, irradiation exposure or ultra violet radiation is also considered by the present invention.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">In certain embodiments of the invention, the apparatus further comprises a dosing pump located upstream the mixing unit, fed with the temperature sensitive compound and configured to dose the flow rate or quantity of temperature sensitive compound injected into the mixing unit. Additionally, the dosing pump may be located upstream the sterilizing device. The dosing pump may be a positive displacement pump.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018">It is another object of the present invention to propose a method for the preparation and sterilization of a viscous fluid using certain embodiments of the apparatus, and which comprises the steps of sterilizing the viscous matrix in the heat treatment device and incorporating the temperature sensitive compound into the sterilized matrix. In certain embodiments of the invention, the method further comprises a step of filling the viscous fluid in a sterile container. In certain embodiments of the invention, the method further comprises the steps of filling the viscous fluid in a non sterile container, and storing the container in a cold environment</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">There has thus been outlined, rather broadly, certain embodiments of the invention in order that the detailed description thereof herein may be better understood, and in order that the present contribution to the art may be better appreciated. There are, of course, additional embodiments of the invention that will be<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> described below and which will form the subject matter of the claims appended hereto.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">In this respect, before explaining at least one embodiment of the invention in detail, it is to be understood that the invention is not limited in its application to the details of construction and to the arrangements of the components set forth in the following description or illustrated in the drawings. The invention is capable of embodiments in addition to those described and of being practiced and carried out in various ways. Also, it is to be understood that the phraseology and terminology employed herein, as well as the abstract, are for the purpose of description and should not be regarded as limiting.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">As such, those skilled in the art will appreciate that the conception upon which this disclosure is based may readily be utilized as a basis for the designing of other structures, methods and systems for carrying out the several purposes of the present invention. It is important, therefore, that the claims be regarded as including such equivalent constructions insofar as they do not depart from the spirit and scope of the present invention.</p><heading id="h0004"><b>BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE ACCOMPANYING DRAWINGS</b></heading><p id="p0022" num="0022">Other features and advantages of the present invention will become clear from the following detailed description of the non limitative embodiments of the invention, referring to the accompanying Drawings representing schematically the apparatus of the invention. In the accompanying Drawings:
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> is a flow diagram according to a first embodiment of an apparatus for the preparation and sterilization of a viscous fluid; and</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> is a flow diagram according to a second embodiment of an apparatus for the preparation and sterilization of a viscous fluid; and</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> is a flow diagram according to a third embodiment of an apparatus for the preparation and sterilization of a viscous fluid.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0005"><b>DESCRIPTION OF PREFERRED EMBODIMENTS</b></heading><!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --><p id="p0023" num="0023">A flow diagram of a first embodiment of an apparatus for the preparation and sterilization of a viscous fluid is shown in detail in <figref idrefs="f0001"><b>Fig. 1</b></figref><b>.</b> The apparatus is designed for cosmetic products, such as skincare creams or lotions, including emulsion products. However, the present invention is not limited to cosmetic products, but more generally covers, among other things, fluids of high viscosity containing a temperature sensitive active compound diluted in a viscous matrix. Other viscous fluids for which the present invention is adapted include, for example, drugs, vegetal and animal extracts, and food products. Examples of temperature sensitive active compounds include perfumes, essential oil, dyes, vitamins, proteins, pharmaceutical active compound or more generally active principals. A sterile temperature-sensitive compound is incorporated into a viscous matrix to form the viscous fluid. In the present application, a compound is considered sterile when it went through a sterilization process. Such compounds may be diluted in one or more types of viscous matrices, which may include for example an emulsion of oil into water or water into oil, a lipophilic medium, an aqueous or alcoholic medium or more generally any type of dilution substrate. Certain embodiments of the present invention aim at preparing and sterilizing any type of viscous fluids, preferably having a static viscosity exceeding 1500 cP at a temperature between approximately 20°C and 90°C. It has been shown that certain embodiments of the present invention are especially adapted to fluid for which a static viscosity exceeding 1500 cP is measured in this temperature range and after an evaporative cooling step, e.g. after sterilization based upon direct heating.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">The flow diagram shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig 1</figref> describes the first embodiment of an apparatus for the preparation and sterilization of a viscous fluid 10, which contains at least one temperature sensitive active compound 11 diluted into a viscous matrix 12.</p><p id="p0025" num="0025">The apparatus comprises :
<ul><li>a heat treatment unit 15, fed with the viscous matrix 12, wherein the viscous matrix is sterilized,</li><li>a feeding unit 16 for the sterile temperature sensitive compound 11, and<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --></li><li>a mixing unit 17, fed with the sterilized viscous matrix 12 and the sterile temperature sensitive device 11, wherein the temperature sensitive compound is incorporated into the sterilized viscous matrix 12 to form the viscous fluid 10.</li></ul></p><p id="p0026" num="0026">In the first embodiment, the heat treatment unit 15 includes a direct heating device 18 wherein the viscous matrix 12 is heated up by incorporating steam into the viscous matrix. The direct heating device 18 is a steam infusion device. It includes a chamber fed with steam, having an upper cylindrical part and a lower conical part. The inlet viscous matrix 12 is introduced in the upper cylindrical part and finely divided, for example by means of a dedicated perforated plate. Steam is incorporated into the matrix which is sprayed in the chamber. The lower conical part collects the heated matrix before transferring it to a high temperature circuitry 19. An efficient distribution of the steam flow, together with an efficient distribution of matrix inside the chamber, lead to an efficient heating of the viscous matrix. A temperature in the range of between approximately 120°C and 155 °C may be reach in less than 1 second.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">Subsequently, the heated viscous matrix circulates through a high temperature circuitry 19, wherein the heated viscous matrix is maintained in a temperature range of approximately 120°C to 155°C for a predetermined residence time to allow sterilization of the viscous matrix 12. As is known to the person of the art, the high temperature circuitry may include a holding tube and a combination of different kind of pumps or valves.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">The heat treatment unit 15 also includes an evaporative cooling device 20 fed with the sterilized viscous matrix, wherein the viscous matrix is cooled to a temperature in the range of 20°C to 90°C by steam evaporation. In a possible embodiment, the evaporative cooling device 20 includes a vacuum chamber, having an upper cylindrical part and a lower conical part extending downwardly from the upper part. In the upper part is injected the heated viscous matrix 12. The matrix is then cooled down by evaporating, at least partially, the steam added to the fluid during the direct heating step. The lower part collects the cooled down matrix by gravitational force. Depending on the vacuum level and the matrix inlet and outlet temperatures, the amount of evaporated water can be adjusted. The pressure of vacuum chamber may be between approximately 0.05 and 1 bars (absolute<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> pressure). A flash cooling duration of less than one second is achieved to cool down the fluid to a temperature of between approximately 20°C and 90°C. The temperature of the viscous matrix 12 at the outlet of the heat treatment unit 15 is set sufficiently low to ensure it does not denaturize the temperature sensitive compound 11 in the mixing unit 17. The cooled down matrix may be transported to the mixing unit 17 by direct pumping. But the high viscosity of the cooled down matrix at bottom of the lower part of vacuum chamber may make it difficult to extract the matrix out of the evaporative cooling device 20. For that matter, the evaporative cooling device may also include an extraction device, to extract the matrix from the lower part and ensure its transportation to the downstream circuit. As an example, the <patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="US13713760B"><text>US patent application 13/713760</text></patcit> discloses an efficient design of an evaporative cooling device including such extraction device.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">The heat treatment unit 15 may further include an indirect heating device 21 located upstream the direct heating device 18. The indirect heating device 21 aims at increasing the viscous matrix temperature up to an intermediate level to facilitate the introduction of the viscous matrix into the direct heating device 18 and the incorporation of steam. In a possible scenario, the indirect heating device 21, for example a heat exchanger, is configured to feed the direct heating device 18 with the viscous matrix at a temperature range of between approximately 20°C and 90°C.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, the feeding unit 16 of the temperature sensitive compound 11 may include a storage tank 25 and a dosing pump 26. The dosing pump 26 allows controlling the flow rate of temperature sensitive compound entering the mixing unit 17. In other words, the dosing pump 26 is configured to control the ratio of temperature sensitive compound to the viscous matrix. Many types of dosing pump may be used, depending on the properties of the temperature sensitive compound, the expected performance, etc... In a possible scenario, the dosing pump 26 is a positive displacement pump.</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">The feeding unit 16 may further include a sterilizing device 27 located upstream the mixing unit 17, fed with the temperature sensitive compound. The sterilizing device 27 may include a sterilizing filtration device, configured to filter largest undesired organic compounds. A device ensuring sterilization of the<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> temperature sensitive compound by, for example, radiation exposure, irradiation exposure or ultra violet radiation is also considered by the present invention. The use of high pressure sterilizing device may also be used. The sterilizing device 27 may also include a heat treatment device such as a heat exchanger. In this case, the sterilizing device is configured to ensure some degree of sterilization of the temperature sensitive compound 11, while it prevents the compound from a significant denaturization that would occur at higher temperature. The temperature of the compound or its residence time throughout the sterilizing device 27 are kept at sufficiently low values, i.e. lower than the temperature or residence time values faced by the viscous matrix in the heat treatment unit 15.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032">In the embodiment as shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, the sterilizing device 27 is located downstream the dosing pump 26. This arrangement allows the dosing pump to push the temperature sensitive compound through the sterilizing device 27, up to the mixing unit 17. This arrangement is also typically preferred to its alternative, wherein the pump is located downstream the sterilizing device, usually to avoid potential cavitation and/or to avoid the sterilized compound potentially passing through the pump.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033">The viscous fluid is prepared in the mixing unit 17 which combines the sterilized viscous matrix 12 and the temperature sensitive compound 11. In a possible embodiment, the mixing unit includes a dynamic mixer 30, for example comprising successive perforated plates and rotating blades inserted between the perforated plates. The viscous matrix and the temperature sensitive compound may be introduced separately into an agitated storage tank. Alternately, they may be combined before being introduced into the dynamic mixer. A possible solution is to configure the piping so that the temperature sensitive compound is introduced counter-current of the flow of viscous matrix. The resulting mixing is then introduced into the dynamic mixer to improve the homogenization of the mixing.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034">As shown on <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, the mixing unit 17 may further include a heat exchanger 31 to manage the temperature of the viscous fluid 10 at the outlet of the mixing unit 17. Optionally, the mixing unit may also include a heat exchanger at the inlet of the<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> dynamic mixer 30 to manage the temperature of the viscous fluid in the mixer. To further improve the homogenization of the viscous fluid 10, the mixing unit 17 may include several successive dynamic mixers 30 and several heat exchangers 31 in between the mixers.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035">A flow diagram of a second embodiment of an apparatus for the preparation and sterilization of a viscous fluid is shown in detail in <figref idrefs="f0002"><b>Fig. 2</b></figref><b>.</b> This second embodiment involves a number of components which have been described above in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>. The same numbers on the figures refer to the same components; these components are not detailed again systematically below.</p><p id="p0036" num="0036">The second embodiment includes a heat treatment unit 45 wherein the viscous matrix 12 is sterilized, a temperature sensitive compound feeding unit 16 and a mixing unit 17 wherein the viscous matrix 12 and the temperature sensitive compound 11 are mixed to form the viscous fluid 10. The designs of the feeding unit 16 and the mixing unit 17 are identical to the first embodiment. The second embodiment differs from the first one by the heat treatment unit. The heat treatment unit 45 of the second embodiment includes a direct heating device 46, wherein the viscous matrix 12 is heated up by incorporating steam into the viscous matrix, a high temperature circuitry 19, in which the viscous matrix circulates for a predetermined residence time to allow sterilizing the viscous matrix, and an evaporative cooling device 20, wherein the viscous matrix is cooled down by steam evaporation.</p><p id="p0037" num="0037">In this second embodiment, the direct heating device 46 is a steam injector device, though other direct heating devices are also within the scope of the present invention. The inlet viscous matrix 12, having a temperature in the range of between approximately 20°C and 90°C, for example thanks to an indirect preheating step (not represented on the figure), is brought to pass through a steam injection nozzle in which the viscous matrix is mixed with steam. The incorporation of steam heats up the fluid to a temperature in the range of between approximately 120°C and 155°C in less than 1 second. At the outlet of the direct heating device 46, the heated viscous matrix feeds the high temperature circuitry 19.<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></p><p id="p0038" num="0038">A flow diagram of a third embodiment of an apparatus for the preparation and sterilization of a viscous fluid is shown in detail in <figref idrefs="f0003">Fig. 3</figref>. This third embodiment involves a number of components which have been described above in <figref idrefs="f0001">Fig. 1</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>. The same numbers on the figures refer to the same components; these components are not detailed again systematically below.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">The third embodiment includes a heat treatment unit 55 wherein the viscous matrix 12 is sterilized, a temperature sensitive compound feeding unit 16 and a mixing unit 17 wherein the viscous matrix 12 and the temperature sensitive compound 11 are mixed to form the viscous fluid 10. The designs of the feeding unit 16 and the mixing unit 17 are identical to the first and second embodiment. The third embodiment differs from the previous ones by the heat treatment unit. The heat treatment unit 55 of the third embodiment is an indirect heating device. It includes a first heat exchanger 56 (or a first unit comprising several successive heat exchangers) to heat up the viscous matrix 12, a high temperature circuitry 19 to allow sterilizing the viscous matrix, and a second heat exchanger 57 (or a second unit comprising several successive heat exchangers) to cool down the sterilized viscous matrix 12.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">Certain embodiment of the present invention also relates to a method for the preparation and sterilization of a viscous fluid containing a sterile temperature sensitive active compound diluted in a viscous matrix, which method comprises the successive steps of:
<ul><li>sterilizing the viscous matrix in the heat treatment device, and</li><li>incorporating the sterile temperature sensitive compound into the sterilized matrix.</li></ul></p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM90460523" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --><claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>An apparatus for the preparation and sterilization of a viscous fluid (10) containing a sterile temperature sensitive compound (11) diluted into a viscous matrix (12), <b>characterized in that</b> it comprises :
<claim-text>- a heat treatment unit (15, 45, 55), fed with the viscous matrix (12), wherein the viscous matrix (12) is sterilized,</claim-text>
<claim-text>- a mixing unit (17), fed with the sterilized viscous matrix (12) and the sterile temperature sensitive compound (11), wherein the temperature sensitive compound (11) is incorporated into the sterilized viscous matrix (12) to form the viscous fluid (10).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The apparatus according to claim 1, wherein the heat treatment unit (15, 45) comprises:
<claim-text>- a direct heating device (18, 46) wherein the viscous matrix (12) is heated up by incorporating steam into the viscous matrix (12),</claim-text>
<claim-text>- a high temperature circuitry (19), fed with the heated viscous matrix (12), wherein the heated viscous matrix (12) is maintained in a temperature range of approximately 120°C to 155°C for a predetermined residence time to allow sterilization of the viscous matrix (12), and</claim-text>
<claim-text>- an evaporative cooling device (20), fed with the sterilized viscous matrix (12), wherein the sterilized viscous matrix (12) is cooled to a temperature of between approximately 20 °C to 90 °C by steam evaporation.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The apparatus according to claim 2, wherein the direct heating unit (15) comprises a steam infusion device (18).<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The apparatus according to claim 2, wherein the direct heating unit (45) comprises a steam injection device (46).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The apparatus according to any of the claims 2 to 4, further comprising an indirect heating device (21) located upstream the direct heating device (18, 46), configured to feed the direct heating device (18, 46) with the viscous matrix (12) at a temperature of between approximately 20 °C to 90 °C</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The apparatus according to claim 1, wherein the heat treatment unit (55) comprises:
<claim-text>- a first heat exchanger device (56) wherein the viscous matrix (12) is heated up,</claim-text>
<claim-text>- a high temperature circuitry (19), fed with the heated viscous matrix (12), wherein the heated viscous matrix (12) is maintained in a temperature range of approximately 120°C to 155°C for a predetermined residence time to allow sterilization of the viscous matrix (12), and</claim-text>
<claim-text>- a second heat exchanger (57), fed with the sterilized viscous matrix (12), wherein the sterilized viscous matrix (12) is cooled to a temperature of between approximately 20 °C to 90 °C.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The apparatus according to any of the claims 1 to 6, further comprising a sterilizing device (27) located upstream the mixing unit (17), fed with the temperature sensitive compound (11).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The apparatus according to claim 7, wherein the sterilizing device (27) fed with the temperature sensitive compound (11) comprises a filtration device or a heat treatment device, or a device ensuring sterilization by radiation exposure, irradiation exposure, or UV exposure, or a high pressure sterilizing device.<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The apparatus according to any of the claims 1 to 8, further comprising a dosing pump (26) located upstream the mixing unit (17), fed with the temperature sensitive compound (11) and configured to dose the flow rate or quantity of temperature sensitive compound (11) injected into the mixing unit (17).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>The apparatus according to claims 7 and 9, wherein the dosing pump (26) is located upstream the sterilizing device (27), to dose the flow rate of temperature sensitive compound (11) feeding the sterilizing device (27).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>The apparatus according to any of the claims 9 or 10, wherein the dosing pump (26) is a positive displacement pump.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>The apparatus according to any of the claims 1 to 11, wherein the mixing unit (17) comprises a dynamic mixer (30) or an agitated storage tank.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>A method for the preparation and sterilization of a viscous fluid (10) containing a sterile temperature sensitive compound (11) diluted into a viscous matrix (12), wherein the viscous fluid (10) circulates throughout an apparatus according to any of the claims 1 to 12, which method comprises the successive steps of:
<claim-text>- sterilizing the viscous matrix (12) in the heat treatment unit (15, 45, 55), and</claim-text>
<claim-text>- incorporating the sterile temperature sensitive compound (11) into the sterilized viscous matrix (12).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>The method according to claim 13, further comprising a step of filling the viscous fluid in a sterile container.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>The method according to claim 13, further comprising the steps of :
<claim-text>- filling the viscous fluid in a non sterile container,<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>- storing the container in a cold environment.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></claims><amended-claims mxw-id="PCLM90460522" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office" amended-claim-type="EPC"><heading id="h0006">Amended claims in accordance with Rule 137(2) EPC.</heading><claim id="ac-en-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>An apparatus for the preparation and sterilization of a viscous fluid (10) containing a sterile temperature sensitive compound (11) diluted into a viscous matrix (12), <b>characterized in that</b> it comprises :
<claim-text>- a heat treatment unit (15, 45, 55), fed with the viscous matrix (12), wherein the viscous matrix (12) is sterilized,</claim-text>
<claim-text>- a sterilizing device (27), fed with a temperature sensitive compound (11), ensuring the sterilization of the temperature sensitive compound (11),</claim-text>
<claim-text>- a mixing unit (17), fed with the sterilized viscous matrix (12) and the sterile temperature sensitive compound (11), wherein the temperature sensitive compound (11) is incorporated into the sterilized viscous matrix (12) to form the viscous fluid (10), the sterilizing device (27) being located upstream the mixing unit (17),</claim-text>
<claim-text>- a dosing pump (26) located upstream the mixing unit (17), fed with the temperature sensitive compound (11) and configured to dose the flow rate or quantity of temperature sensitive compound (11) injected into the mixing unit (17).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="ac-en-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>The apparatus according to claim 1, wherein the heat treatment unit (15, 45) comprises:
<claim-text>- a direct heating device (18, 46) wherein the viscous matrix (12) is heated up by incorporating steam into the viscous matrix (12),</claim-text>
<claim-text>- a high temperature circuitry (19), fed with the heated viscous matrix (12), wherein the heated viscous matrix (12) is maintained in a temperature range of approximately 120°C to 155°C for a predetermined residence time to allow sterilization of the viscous matrix (12), and</claim-text>
<claim-text>- an evaporative cooling device (20), fed with the sterilized viscous matrix (12), wherein the sterilized viscous matrix (12) is cooled to a temperature of between approximately 20°C to 90°C by steam evaporation.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="ac-en-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>The apparatus according to claim 2, wherein the direct heating unit (15) comprises a steam infusion device (18).</claim-text></claim><claim id="ac-en-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>The apparatus according to claim 2, wherein the direct heating unit (45) comprises a steam injection device (46).</claim-text></claim><claim id="ac-en-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>The apparatus according to any of the claims 2 to 4, further comprising an indirect heating device (21) located upstream the direct heating device (18, 46), configured to feed the direct heating device (18, 46) with the viscous matrix (12) at a temperature of between approximately 20°C to 90°C</claim-text></claim><claim id="ac-en-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>The apparatus according to claim 1, wherein the heat treatment unit (55) comprises:
<claim-text>- a first heat exchanger device (56) wherein the viscous matrix (12) is heated up,</claim-text>
<claim-text>- a high temperature circuitry (19), fed with the heated viscous matrix (12), wherein the heated viscous matrix (12) is maintained in a temperature range of approximately 120°C to 155°C for a predetermined residence time to allow sterilization of the viscous matrix (12), and</claim-text>
<claim-text>- a second heat exchanger (57), fed with the sterilized viscous matrix (12), wherein the sterilized viscous matrix (12) is cooled to a temperature of between approximately 20°C to 90°C.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="ac-en-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>The apparatus according to claim 6, wherein the sterilizing device (27) fed with the temperature sensitive compound (11) comprises a filtration device or a heat treatment device, or a device ensuring sterilization by radiation exposure, irradiation exposure, or UV exposure, or a high pressure sterilizing device.</claim-text></claim><claim id="ac-en-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>The apparatus according to any of the preceding claims, wherein the dosing pump (26) is a positive displacement pump.</claim-text></claim><claim id="ac-en-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>The apparatus according to any of the claims 1 to 8, wherein the mixing unit (17) comprises a dynamic mixer (30) or an agitated storage tank.</claim-text></claim><claim id="ac-en-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>A method for the preparation and sterilization of a viscous fluid (10) containing a sterile temperature sensitive compound (11) diluted into a viscous matrix (12), wherein the viscous fluid (10) circulates throughout an apparatus according to any of the claims 1 to 9, which method comprises the successive steps of:
<claim-text>- sterilizing the viscous matrix (12) in the heat treatment unit (15, 45, 55), and</claim-text>
<claim-text>- incorporating the sterile temperature sensitive compound (11) into the sterilized viscous matrix (12).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="ac-en-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>The method according to claim 10, further comprising a step of filling the viscous fluid in a sterile container.</claim-text></claim><claim id="ac-en-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>The method according to claim 10, further comprising the steps of :
<claim-text>- filling the viscous fluid in a non sterile container,</claim-text>
<claim-text>- storing the container in a cold environment.</claim-text></claim-text></claim></amended-claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW20423153" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="152" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="148" he="219" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="144" he="226" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><search-report-data><doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="159" he="233" type="tif"/><doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="159" he="233" type="tif"/></search-report-data><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
