<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-1131681-B1" country="EP" doc-number="1131681" kind="B1" date="20140101" family-id="22720187" file-reference-id="270022" date-produced="20180822" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146554349" ucid="EP-1131681-B1"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>1131681</doc-number><kind>B1</kind><date>20140101</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-99931843-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154828272" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>99931843</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>19990621</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP219616569" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>99931843.9</doc-number><date>19990621</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140450637" ucid="US-19513798-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>19513798</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>19981118</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140452937" ucid="US-9913919-W" linkage-type="W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>9913919</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>19990621</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><dates-of-public-availability><intention-to-grant-date><date>20131022</date></intention-to-grant-date></dates-of-public-availability><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988101157" load-source="docdb">G03H   1/20        20060101A I20051008RMEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988101353" load-source="docdb">G03H   1/04        20060101ALI20130402BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988118183" load-source="docdb">G03H   1/26        20060101AFI20130402BHEP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988127482" load-source="docdb">G02B   5/32        20060101ALI20051220RMJP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988135720" load-source="docdb">G02B  26/08        20060101AFI20051220RMJP        </classification-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL1988138086" load-source="docdb">G03H   1/24        20060101A I20051008RMEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988098902" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G03H2227/05        20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988103101" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G02B   5/0252      20130101 FI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988105670" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G03H   1/202       20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988106358" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G03H2001/0232      20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988107439" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G03H2001/0473      20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988111247" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G03H2222/18        20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988115067" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G03H   1/26        20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988116005" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G02B   5/32        20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988119611" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G03H2001/0415      20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988119747" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G03H2001/2695      20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988120013" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G03H   1/24        20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988123176" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G03H2001/2685      20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988125779" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G03H2001/205       20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988128594" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G02B   5/1876      20130101 LI20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988129622" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G03H   1/0486      20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988131622" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G03H2225/61        20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988134102" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G03H2227/03        20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1988139079" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">G03H2210/22        20130101 LA20130101BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132195531" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">VERFAHREN UND VORRICHTUNG ZUR AUFNAHME VON HOLOGRAPHISCHEN VOLLFARB- UND VOLLPARALLAX-STEREOGRAMMEN IN EINEM SCHRITT</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132195532" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">METHOD AND APPARATUS FOR RECORDING ONE-STEP, FULL-COLOR, FULL-PARALLAX, HOLOGRAPHIC STEREOGRAMS</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132195533" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">PROCEDE ET APPAREIL D'ENREGISTREMENT EN UNE SEULE ETAPE DE STEREOGRAMMES HOLOGRAPHIQUES A COULEUR PURE ET EN PARALLAXE COMPLET</invention-title><citations><patent-citations><patcit mxw-id="PCIT369529490" load-source="docdb" ucid="EP-1059574-A1"><document-id format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>1059574</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20001213</date></document-id><sources><source name="EXA" created-by-npl="N"/></sources></patcit></patent-citations></citations></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918153158" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>ZEBRA IMAGING INC</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR918161418" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>ZEBRA IMAGING, INC.</last-name></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918143032" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>KLUG MICHAEL ANTHONY</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918140718" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>KLUG, MICHAEL, ANTHONY</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918999532" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>KLUG, MICHAEL, ANTHONY</last-name><address><street>4200 Farhills Drive</street><city>Austin, TX 78731</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918138917" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>HOLZBACH MARK EVAN</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918155150" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>HOLZBACH, MARK, EVAN</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918999531" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>HOLZBACH, MARK, EVAN</last-name><address><street>706-D West Avenue</street><city>Austin, TX 78701</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918151802" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>FERDMAN ALEJANDRO JOSE</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918149309" load-source="docdb" sequence="3" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>FERDMAN, ALEJANDRO, JOSE</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR918999530" load-source="patent-office" sequence="3" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>FERDMAN, ALEJANDRO, JOSE</last-name><address><street>6107 Sierra Arbor Court</street><city>Austin, TX 78759</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><assignees><assignee mxw-id="PPAR918999534" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Zebra Imaging, Inc.</last-name><iid>100259056</iid><address><street>1406 Three Points Road</street><city>Pflugerville, TX 78660</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></assignee></assignees><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR918999533" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Gill, David Alan</last-name><iid>100032981</iid><address><street>WP Thompson 55 Drury Lane</street><city>London WC2B 5SQ</city><country>GB</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="US-9913919-W"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>9913919</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>19990621</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2000029909-A1"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2000029909</doc-number><kind>A1</kind><date>20000525</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS548986603" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS548989419" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS548986604" load-source="docdb">GB</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><description mxw-id="PDES63957754" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="1"> --><heading id="h0001"><u>TECHNICAL FIELD OF THE INVENTION</u></heading><p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention relates generally to the field of holography. More particularly, it concerns methods and devices for creating and printing variable size and variable resolution holographic stereograms and holographic optical elements using computer rendered images of three-dimensional computer models or using computer processed images.</p><heading id="h0002"><u>BACKGROUND OF THE INVENTION</u></heading><p id="p0002" num="0002">A holographic stereogram is a type of hologram synthesized or composed from a set of two-dimensional views of a subject. A holographic stereogram is capable of creating the convincing illusion of a solid three-dimensional subject from closely spaced, discrete-perspective, two-dimensional component views. In addition, if the two-dimensional component views are properly generated, a holographic stereogram can also create the illusion of an animated image. Although holographic stereograms can project such special effects, due to limitations in the methods and techniques for printing holographic stereograms, holographic stereograms have generally been expensive, difficult and time consuming to produce.</p><p id="p0003" num="0003">Techniques have been developed for reducing the number of steps involved in producing holographic stereograms to one optical printing step. One-step technology usually involves using computer processed images of objects or<!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> computer models of objects to build a hologram from a number of contiguous, small, elemental pieces, known as elemental holograms or hogels. This one-step technology eliminates the need to create a preliminary hologram.</p><p id="p0004" num="0004">To produce a full-parallax, holographic stereogram using traditional one-step technology, a three-dimensional computer model of an object or a scene is created. There are numerous computer graphic modeling programs, rendering programs, animation programs, three dimensional digitalization systems, or combinations of the programs or systems that can be used to generate and manipulate a three-dimensional computer model of an object or a scene. Examples of such programs or systems include, but are not limited to, computer-aided-design (CAD) programs, scientific visualization programs, and virtual reality programs.</p><p id="p0005" num="0005">In addition, to produce a holographic stereogram using one-step technology requires that the position of the hologram surface and individual elemental holograms relative to an object or a scene be determined. Furthermore, a proper computer graphic camera(s)'s description for an elemental hologram and the size and location of a spatial light modulator (SLM), a device that can display a two-dimensional image, need to be determined.</p><p id="p0006" num="0006">Once all the aforementioned initial parameters are determined, a two-dimensional projection on the SLM for each elemental hologram is computed based on the computer graphic model of the object or scene that was created, the positions of the elemental holograms, and the computer graphic camera's description for the elemental holograms. The two-dimensional projection on the SLM for each elemental hologram may be rendered using various computer graphic techniques. The process of creating two-dimensional views from a three-dimensional object and<!-- EPO <DP n="3"> --> adding qualities such as variations in color and shade to a computer graphic model is often referred to as rendering. There are numerous methods for rendering. One method is ray-tracing, which computes images by accurately simulating sampled light rays in a computer model. Another method is scan-line conversion, which computes images one raster or line at a time. Typically scan-line rendering does not produce as realistic results as ray tracing. However, scan-line rendering is frequently used in animation packages because it is faster. Another method for using computer graphics to render images for one-step, full-parallax holographic stereograms is described in an article by Halle and Kropp.<nplcit id="ncit0001" npl-type="s"><text> Halle, M. and Kropp, A., "Fast Computer Graphics Rendering for Full Parallax Spatial Displays," Proc. Soc, Photo-Opt. Instrum. Eng. (SPIE), 3011:105-112 (February 10-11, 1997</text></nplcit>)</p><p id="p0007" num="0007">When holographic stereograms are produced by either the multi-step or one-step techniques, the reconstructed images may have geometric image distortions. These geometric image distortions may be very apparent, especially in large, billboard size holographic displays or holographic displays in other geometries, such as an alcove or a partial cylinder.</p><p id="p0008" num="0008">One solution that has been incorporated into multi-step techniques to correct for geometric image distortions for multiplex holograms is discussed in an article by Okada.<nplcit id="ncit0002" npl-type="s"><text> Okada, K., et. al., "A Method of Distortion Compensation of Multiplex Holograms," Optics Communications, vol. 48, no. 3, pp. 167-170 (December 1, 1983</text></nplcit>)</p><p id="p0009" num="0009">The technique discussed in Okada's article to correct distortion is a method to correct geometrical and time distortion of a single or monocular viewpoint of a<!-- EPO <DP n="4"> --> finished hologram. Because it is a post-processing method that takes place after image acquisition, Okada's technique would be inefficient if adopted to generate animated computer graphics one-step, holographic stereograms. Moreover, Okada's method only produces horizontal-parallax-only transmission type holograms.</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">Others have developed techniques for pre-distorting one-step, holographic stereograms to reduce distortion in the final holographic display. One such pre-distortion technique is described in a paper by Halle and others. <nplcit id="ncit0003" npl-type="s"><text>Halle, M. et al, "The Ultragram: A Generalized Holographic Stereogram," Proc. Soc. Photo-Opt. Instrum. Eng. (SPIE), vol. 1461 Practical Holography V, p. 142 (February 1991</text></nplcit>)</p><p id="p0011" num="0011">Although widely used, typical pre-distortion techniques for one-step methods for producing full-parallax, holographic stereograms are significantly limited by available computer processing speeds and the resolution of images produced by traditional one-step methods. In addition, techniques for pre-distorting one-step, full parallax, holographic stereograms have not been able to produce comprehensible, animated, one step, full parallax, holographic stereograms.</p><p id="p0012" num="0012">Apparatus for printing one-step, monochromatic, holographic-stereograms have been developed. Typically, such prior art printers, as depicted in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURE 1</figref> include: a monochrome coherent light source 1, lenses 42, mirrors 40, an optical system 89, a shutter 10, a mechanism for translating film 69, holographic recording material 70, usually in the form of film, a personal computer 85 to control the timing for the exposure sequence, and a separate high-speed computer 87 for image calculations. The prior art printer depicted in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURE 1</figref>, was discussed in two articles by <nplcit id="ncit0004" npl-type="s"><text>Yamaguchi. Yamaguchi, M., et al.,<!-- EPO <DP n="5"> --> "Development of a Prototype Full-Parallax Holoprinter," Proc. Soc. Photo-Opt Instrum. Eng. (SPIE) vol. 2406, Practical Holography IX. pp. 50-56 (February 1995</text></nplcit>); and <nplcit id="ncit0005" npl-type="s"><text>Yamaguchi, M., et al., "High-Quality Recording of a Full-Parallax Holographic Stereogram with a Digital Diffuser," Optical Letters, vol. 19, no. 2, pp. 135-137 (January 20, 1994</text></nplcit>)</p><p id="p0013" num="0013">The prior art printer depicted in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURE 1</figref> is capable of producing monochromatic holographic stereograms, but not full-color holographic stereograms.</p><p id="p0014" num="0014">A typical prior art hologram printer, like the one depicted in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURE 1</figref>, usually is supported by a vibration isolation table 80. In addition the prior art printer depicted by <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURE 1</figref> uses a HeNe laser for a light source 1 that produces a coherent light beam 5 that may be collimated. A shutter 10 is placed at the output of light source 1. A beam-splitter 15 splits the light 5 from the light source 1 into an object beam 20 and a reference beam 25. The polarization of the object and reference beams 20, 25 are adjusted by a pair of half-wave plates 30 and a pair of polarizers 35. The half-wave plates 30 and polarizers 35 also control the ratio of the beams. The prior art printer also uses a number of mirrors 40. In addition, the prior art printer uses a system of enlarging lenses 42 to distribute the object beam 20 from the light source 1 into the optical system 89 depicted in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURE 1</figref>.</p><p id="p0015" num="0015">The optical system 89 of the prior art printer of <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURE 1</figref> includes a band-limited diffuser 45, a liquid crystal display panel (LCD panel) 50, and a converging lens 55. A band-limited diffuse is a diffuser with a deterministic phase pattern designed to diffuse light in a specific pattern or direction. The band-limited diffuser 45 depicted in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURE 1</figref> is specifically designed for the monochromatic light source being used -- a HeNe laser. The<!-- EPO <DP n="6"> --> LCD panel 50 used in the prior art printer of <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURE 1</figref> is a gray scale, electrically addressed panel with twisted-nematic liquid crystals. The LCD panel 50 receives image data calculated by a high-speed computer 87 by an analog video signal. The converging lens 55 shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURE 1</figref> focuses the images from the LCD panel 50 to the holographic recording material 70. The converging lens 55 generally has a low f-number in order to produce a wide angle of view. Due to the need to correct for spherical aberrations along the optical axis, Yamaguchi utilized a converging lens 55 composed of three lenses to reduce spherical aberration and realize a f-number of around 0.8.</p><p id="p0016" num="0016">To prevent the exposure of parts of the holographic recording material 70 that are not part of the elemental hologram 110 meant to be exposed, the prior art printer of <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURE 1</figref>, uses, in close proximity to the holographic recording material 70, an object beam masking plate 60 with an aperture the size of the elemental hologram 110 to prevent the object beam 20 from exposing other parts of the holographic recording material 70.</p><p id="p0017" num="0017">The band-limited diffuser 45 shown in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURE 1</figref> improves the uniformity of the distribution of the object beam 20 over an elemental hologram on the holographic recording material 70. If the band-limited diffuser 45 is designed such that an object beam 20 is focused only over the area of an elemental hologram, then an object beam masking plate 60 is not needed to prevent exposure of areas outside the elemental hologram. However, if used with such a band-limited diffuse, the object beam masking plate 60 may have an aperture larger than the size of the elemental hologram 110. An object beam 20 and a band-limited diffuser 45 that allow even illumination of an elemental hologram 110 by an object beam 20 need to be matched by a reference beam masking plate 65 with an aperture the size<!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> of the elemental hologram 110. Because the required matching of a object beam 20, a band-limited diffuse 45, and reference beam masking plate 65 to the size of a desired elemental hologram, it has been difficult to change the sizes of elemental holograms exposed by a hologram printer. Because of this lack of flexibility, prior art printers cannot easily print holograms having different sizes of elemental holograms, and are restricted to printing holograms with single, fixed-sized elemental holograms.</p><p id="p0018" num="0018"><figref idrefs="f0002 f0003">FIGUREs 2-4</figref> illustrate alternative prior art examples of optical systems that function in the same way as the optical system 89 depicted in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURE 1</figref>.</p><p id="p0019" num="0019">In <figref idrefs="f0002 f0003">FIGUREs 2-4</figref>, an object beam 20 is directed through a SLM 90 that has a sample image point 100 on its surface. The object beam 20 may be normal to the SLM surface or off-axis from the normal. SLM 90 may also have an array of pixels 95. LCD panels, cinematography film, and transparencies have been used as SLMs 90.</p><p id="p0020" num="0020">In <figref idrefs="f0002">FIGURE 2</figref>, the object beam is directed through a simple diffuser 105, such as a section of ground glass, that scatters light. When a simple diffuser 105 is used, then an object beam masking plate 60 must be used to prevent exposing areas of the holographic recording material 70 outside the elemental hologram 110 that are not meant to be exposed.</p><p id="p0021" num="0021">In <figref idrefs="f0003">FIGURE 3</figref>, an object beam 20 is directed through a holographic optical element (HOE) 115. A HOE is a hologram that is specially designed to redirect light emanating from a source in a certain way. For instance, a HOE may be designed to act as a lens to converge light to a single point. As another example, a HOE may be designed to act as a band-limited diffuser that is paired with a lens to converge light over an area rather than a single point.<!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> The HOE 115 depicted in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIGURE 3</figref> is one that is designed to evenly expose an area the size and shape of an elemental hologram 110. When such a HOE is used, an object beam masking plate 60 (shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIGURE 2</figref>) need not be used at all or, if used, may have an aperture larger than the size of the elemental hologram 110 to be exposed.</p><p id="p0022" num="0022">In <figref idrefs="f0003">FIGURE 4</figref>, an object beam 20 is directed through a band-limited diffuser, which may be a band-limited digital diffuser, 45 and a converging lens 55. The band-limited diffuser 45 depicted in <figref idrefs="f0003">FIGURE 4</figref> is designed to converge the object beam 20 over the area of elemental hologram 110. Thus, an object beam masking plate 60 (shown in <figref idrefs="f0002">FIGURE 2</figref>) need not be used at all or, if used may have an aperture larger than the size of the elemental hologram 110 to be exposed.</p><p id="p0023" num="0023">In <figref idrefs="f0002 f0003">FIGUREs 2-4</figref>, the sample image point 100 is an image point of the SLM 90 that is recorded in an elemental hologram 110 on a holographic recording material 70. Reference beam 25 is directed at the elemental hologram 110 such that the interference pattern formed by the interaction of the object beam 20 and the reference beam 25 may be recorded on the elemental hologram 110 on the holographic 110 on the holographic recording material 70.</p><p id="p0024" num="0024">To expose a two-dimensional array of elemental holograms, the prior art printer of <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURE 1</figref> uses a mechanism for translating holographic film 69 that includes pulse controlled motors 71. Typically, the holographic recording material 70 in a prior art printer is photographic film. The film is held between the object beam masking plate 60 and the reference beam masking plate 65. Both masking plates 60 and 65 have apertures that are the size of the elemental holograms 110 being exposed. The masking plates 60 and 65 are moved by a solenoid 72. Pulse controlled motors 71 translate the film in two directions.<!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --></p><p id="p0025" num="0025">In the prior art system depicted in <figref idrefs="f0001">FIGURE 1</figref>, the timing of the exposure sequence is controlled by a personal computer. Thus, the solenoid 72, as well as the pulse controlled motors 71 and the shutter 10, are controlled by the personal computer 85. In contrast, the images for the exposures are calculated off-line by a high-speed computer 87. The image calculations are transferred by an analog video signal to the LCD panel 50.</p><p id="p0026" num="0026">For a holographic stereogram to be reconstructed, an illumination source must be placed at an appropriate angle. If the illumination source is not placed correctly, a holographic stereogram will not be reconstructed or will appear with distortions, such as magnification distortions. Despite advances in holographic techniques and equipment, the display illumination geometry of a one-step, holographic stereogram remains a problem. The display illumination geometry, i.e., the placement of an illumination source with respect to a holographic stereogram, depends on the cumulative effect of the angles at which a reference beam exposed each of a holographic stereogram's elemental holograms. For example, if the angle at which all of the elemental holograms on a holographic stereogram are exposed to a collimated reference beam is constant, and if the surface of the holographic stereogram is flat, then the holographic stereogram needs a collimated illumination source to illuminate each of the elemental holograms from the appropriate angle if the hologram is to be properly reconstructed without defects such as magnification distortion.</p><p id="p0027" num="0027">Furthermore, in practice, it has been common to create reflection holographic stereograms which are meant to be illuminated with a diverging light source such as a point source. However, the prior art has not overcome the<!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> difficulty in designing a printer in which the angle of a reference beam is automatically and flexibly changeable to allow reconstruction by a point source and with minimal distortion.</p><p id="p0028" num="0028">In addition, it remains difficult to control the resolution or elemental hologram density of a holographic image. The sharpness of a holographic image depends on the image resolution and the extent of any blurring. Blurring can be caused by having a large illumination source, such as that of a long florescent light, illuminate a hologram. In addition, blurring can be caused by the large spectral spread of an illumination source. If an illumination source that is small and monochromatic, such as a laser source expanded through a microscope objective lens (i.e. a small, inexpensive, achromatic, high-power lens), is used, blurring may be minimized, and the sharpness of the holographic image will mainly depend on the image resolution of the hologram.</p><p id="p0029" num="0029">The image resolution of a three-dimensional image is defined as the volumetric density of individually distinguishable image points in an image volume. For one-step, holographic stereograms, including full-parallax and horizontal-parallax holograms, this resolution is usually not constant throughout an image volume. For small images of little depth, the variation of image resolution with depth is hardly noticeable. However, for holographic stereograms with significant depth, the variation in image resolution with depth can be very apparent.</p><p id="p0030" num="0030">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">FIGURE 5</figref>, if the light from an illumination source 130 that is the same type of light source as that which generated the reference beam 25 that exposed an elemental hologram 110 illuminates the elemental hologram 110 from the appropriate conjugate angle, the reconstruction 125 of the sample image point 100, (shown in<!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --></p><p id="p0031" num="0031"><figref idrefs="f0002 f0003">FIGUREs 2-4</figref>), on the reconstruction 120 of the image of the SLM is formed at the same apparent distance and position relative to the elemental hologram 110 as it appeared to the elemental hologram 110 at the time of recording.</p><p id="p0032" num="0032"><figref idrefs="f0004">FIGURE 6</figref> shows lines drawn from the boundaries between neighboring elemental holograms 110 on a holographic recording material 70 through the boundaries between neighboring reconstructed pixels 135 of the reconstructed image 120 of a SLM. The areas bounded between the lines drawn from the boundaries of at least two elemental holograms represent independently addressable volume elements, or voxels 140. A voxel 140 is a component unit which represents an arbitrary three-dimensional object or scene. Assuming that the elemental holograms 110 are larger than the SLM pixels, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0004">FIGURE 6</figref>, the sizes of the voxels 140 increase with increasing distance from the surface of a reconstructed image of a SLM 120. If the sizes of the voxels 140 are too coarse relative to the desired detail size of a three-dimensional object or scene, the reproduced image will be poor or indiscernible. If the three-dimensional image of an object or scene extends over a wide range of depth, a variation in the sizes of the voxels will also be very undesirable because such a variation would lead to poor image quality.</p><p id="p0033" num="0033"><patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US5138471A"><text>US 5,138,471</text></patcit> discloses a method for making holographic images by recording an array of pixels which together form a two or three dimensional composite image.</p><p id="p0034" num="0034"><patcit id="pcit0002" dnum="US4067638A"><text>US 4,067,638</text></patcit> discloses multi-color holographic stereograms.</p><p id="p0035" num="0035"><patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="EP1059574A"><text>EP 1 059 574</text></patcit> discloses a device for forming a hologram for reproducing a three-dimensional image. A controller calculates a three-dimensional interference pattern for generating reproduction light associated with a desired three-dimensional image when a recording medium is illuminated with reference light for reproduction, divides the three-dimensional interference pattern into partial interference patterns and calculates reference light and information light for recording for each of the partial interference patterns. A final hologram is formed by illuminating the recording mediumwith reference light and information light for recording using a head while changing the relative positional relationship between the recording medium and the head by moving the head with a voice coil motor while transporting the recording medium.<!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --></p><p id="p0036" num="0036">Thus, hologram printers of the prior art have limitations that make them impractical for commercial purposes. In particular, these prior art printers suffer from: lack of ability to print full-color holographic stereograms; lack of ability to simultaneously expose multiple elemental holograms; lack of flexibility to quickly and easily adjust a hologram printer to print at different elemental hologram sizes; lack of flexibility to easily change the angle of a reference beam to a holographic recording material; lack of ability to control the resolution of a hologram; and lack of ability to create computer generated images which display animation or different images with a change of viewing position.</p><heading id="h0003"><u>SUMMARY OF THE INVENTION</u></heading><p id="p0037" num="0037">The present invention overcomes many of the above noted limitations and problems of prior art hologram printers and methods used to print holographic stereograms with the following structures and methods.</p><p id="p0038" num="0038">The present invention is an apparatus and method for printing one-step, full-color, full parallax holographic stereograms utilizing a reference beam-steering system that allows a reference beam to expose a holographic recording material from different angles. More particularly, a coherent beam is split into object and reference beams. The object beam passes through an object beam unit in which a rendered image is displayed, while the reference beam passes through the reference beam-steering system. The object and reference beams interfere with each other at an elemental hologram on a holographic recording material. A computer controls the exposure time and the movement of the recording material and may also render the images displayed in the object beam unit. In addition, the computer may also store the images before they are displayed in the object beam unit.</p><p id="p0039" num="0039">According to an aspect of the present invention, there is provided an apparatus for printing one-step, multi-wavelength holographic stereograms, comprising: a first light source configured to produce a first coherent beam; a beam splitter configured to split the first coherent beam into a first object beam and a first reference beam; a material holder configured to hold a holographic recording material having elemental holograms; an object beam unit including at least one spatial light modulator, wherein the spatial light modulator is configured for displaying a rendered image and for conditioning the first object beam with the rendered image to interfere with the first reference beam at a chosen elemental hologram; a second light source configured to produce a second object beam and a second reference beam, wherein the second object beam<!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> has a wavelength different from a wavelength of the first object beam, and is directed at the spatial light modulator; a third light source configured to produce a third object beam and a third reference beam, wherein the third object beam has a wavelength different from the wavelengths of the first and second object beams, and is directed at the spatial light modulator; a reference beam steering system configured to direct the first reference beam to interfere with the first object beam at the chosen elemental hologram to expose the area of the selected elemental hologram, and configured to direct the second reference beam to interfere with the second object beam at the chosen elemental hologram to expose the area of the selected elemental hologram, and configured to direct the third reference beam to interfere with the third object beam at the chosen elemental hologram to expose the area of the selected elemental hologram; and a computer programmed to control at least one of the interference of each of the object beams with a corresponding reference beam of the reference beams at the selected elemental hologram, and the delivery of the rendered image to the object beam unit.</p><p id="p0040" num="0040">According to another aspect of the present invention, there is provided a method of printing a one-step, multi-wavelength holographic stereogram with elemental holograms, comprising the steps of: selecting an elemental hologram; splitting a first coherent light beam into a first object beam and a first reference beam; splitting a second coherent light beam into a second object beam and a second reference beam, wherein the second coherent light beam has a wavelength different from a wavelength of the first coherent light beam; splitting a third coherent light beam into a third object beam and a third reference beam, wherein the third coherent light beam has a wavelength different from the wavelengths of the first and second coherent light beams; rendering an image; conditioning each of the object beams with the rendered image displayed on at least one spatial light modulator; selectively steering the first, second, and third reference beams at the selected elemental hologram; directing the second object beam at the spatial light modulator; directing the third object beam at the spatial light modulator; and interfering each of the conditioned object beams with a corresponding reference beam of the reference beams at the selected elemental hologram to expose the area of the selected elemental hologram.</p><p id="p0041" num="0041">In addition, the present invention may also utilize a voxel-control lens placed in the path of the object beam and in close proximity to the holographic recording material to control the resolution of a holographic stereogram.</p><p id="p0042" num="0042">In addition, the present invention may also utilize interchangeable band-limited diffusers and reference-beam masking plates.<!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --></p><p id="p0043" num="0043">Furthermore, the present invention incorporates viewing zone techniques to the rendering process for one-step, holographic stereograms to produce animated, one-step holographic stereograms.</p><p id="p0044" num="0044">In accordance with long-standing patent law convention, the words "a" and "an" when used in this application, including the claims, denotes "at least one".</p><heading id="h0004"><u>BRIER DESCRIPTION OF</u><u>THE DRAWINGS</u></heading><p id="p0045" num="0045">The following drawings form part of the specification and are included to further demonstrate certain aspects of the present invention. The invention may be better understood by reference to one or more of these drawings in combination with the detailed description of specific embodiments presented herein.
<ul><li><figref idrefs="f0001">FIGUREs 1(a) and (b)</figref> are schematic, top-view drawings of a prior art hologram printer.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0002">FIGUREs 2(a) and (b)</figref> are simplified, top-view illustrations of a one-step, reflection, elemental hologram recording using an optical system including a simple diffuser.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">FIGURE 3</figref> is a simplified, top-view illustration of a one-step, reflection, elemental hologram recording using an optical system including a holographic optical element.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0003">FIGURE 4</figref> is a simplified, top-view illustration of a one-step, reflection, elemental hologram recording using an optical system including a band-limited diffuser and a converging lens.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">FIGURE 5</figref> is a simplified, top-view illustration of the reconstruction of an elemental hologram of a holographic stereogram.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0004">FIGURE 6</figref> is a illustration of the changes in sizes of voxels with distance from a reconstructed image of a SLM.<!-- EPO <DP n="15"> --></li><li><figref idrefs="f0005">FIGURE 7</figref> is a top-view, schematic drawing of one embodiment of the present invention for a one-step, full-color, full-parallax printer for holographic stereograms.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0006">FIGURE 8</figref> is a top-view, schematic drawing of another embodiment of the present invention for a one-step, full-color, full-parallax printer for holographic stereograms.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0007">FIGURE 9</figref> is an illustration of a particular embodiment of the present invention to control the variation in sizes of voxels.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0008">FIGUREs 10(a) and (b)</figref> illustrate how the apparent distance of a SLM, as seen by an elemental hologram, may change when a voxel-control lens is utilized.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0007">FIGURE 11</figref> is an illustration of voxel boundary lines that are approximately parallel to each other.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0009">FIGURE 12</figref> is a schematic illustration of an embodiment of the reference beam-steering system of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0010">FIGURE 13</figref> is a schematic illustration of another embodiment of the reference beam-steering system of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0011">FIGURE 14</figref> is a schematic illustration of an embodiment of the reference beam-steering system of the present invention that utilizes a beam-steering aperture.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0012">FIGURE 15</figref> is a orthogonal-view illustration of an embodiment of the beam-steering mirror system of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0013">FIGURE 16</figref> is a front-view illustration of another embodiment of the beam-steering mirror system of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0014">FIGURE 17</figref> is a schematic illustration of an embodiment of the reference beam-steering system of the present invention that utilizes fiber optics and a translation system.<!-- EPO <DP n="16"> --></li><li><figref idrefs="f0015">FIGURE 18</figref> is a simplified, orthogonal-view illustration of an embodiment of the reference beam-steering system of the present invention that utilizes fiber optics and a translation system.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0016">FIGURE 19</figref> is a simplified, orthogonal-view illustration of an embodiment of a reference beam-steering system of the present invention that utilizes fiber optics, a translation system, and a optical combiner unit.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0017">FIGURE 20</figref> is a schematic illustration of an object beam unit of the present invention that utilizes the fiber optics.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0018">FIGURE 21</figref> is a top-view, schematic drawing of one embodiment, which utilizes fiber optics, of the present invention for a one-step, full-color, full-parallax printer for holographic stereograms.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0019">FIGURE 22</figref> is a simplified, orthogonal-view illustration of an embodiment of a material holder of the present invention.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0020">FIGURE 23</figref> is a schematic illustration of an embodiment of the present invention with fixed object beam units and fixed reference beam-steering systems.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0021">FIGURE 24</figref> is a schematic illustration of an embodiment of the present invention with mobile object beam units and mobile reference beam-steering systems.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0022">FIGURE 25</figref> is a schematic illustration of another embodiment of the present invention with mobile object beam units and mobile reference beam-steering systems.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0023">FIGURE 26</figref> is a schematic illustration of yet another embodiment of the present invention with mobile object beam units and mobile reference beam-steering systems.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0024">FIGUREs 27(a), (b), and (c)</figref> are orthogonal-view illustrations of removable band-limited diffusers and removable reference beam masking plates.<!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --></li><li><figref idrefs="f0025">Figure 28</figref> is a flow chart illustrating the steps for creating an animated, one-step, full-parallax holographic stereogram.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0026">FIGURE 29</figref> is an illustration of viewing zones for a holographic stereogram that displays different images when viewed from different viewing zones.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0026">FIGURE 30</figref> is an illustration of rays projecting from the perimeter of viewing zones.</li><li><figref idrefs="f0027">FIGURE 31</figref> is an illustration of viewing zone mask volumes.</li></ul></p><heading id="h0005"><u>DETAILED DESCRIPTION OF THE INVENTION</u></heading><p id="p0046" num="0046">The following examples are included to demonstrate illustrative embodiments of the present invention. It should be appreciated by those with skill in the art that the techniques disclosed in the following examples represent techniques discovered by the inventors to function well in practice, and thus can be considered to constitute exemplary modes for its practice.</p><p id="p0047" num="0047">Alternative arrangements include a HOE or other appropriate optics which replace the combination of a lens and a band-limited diffuser. In addition, a HOE may also replace a lens or a combination of lenses. Furthermore, SLMs may include, but are not limited to LCD panels, digital micro-mirror arrays, film, or transparencies. In addition, computer storage devices may include, but are not limited to hard disks, static or dynamic RAM, flash memory, DVD drives, or tape drives. Moreover, motors may include, but are not limited to DC servo motors, stepper motors, or actuators.<!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --></p><p id="p0048" num="0048">The present invention provides a system and method for printing one-step, full-color, full-parallax holographic stereograms. Some presently illustrated embodiments are depicted in <figref idrefs="f0005 f0006 f0007 f0008 f0009 f0010 f0011 f0012 f0013 f0014 f0015 f0016 f0017 f0018 f0019 f0020 f0021 f0022 f0023 f0024 f0025 f0026 f0027">FIGUREs 7-31</figref>.</p><p id="p0049" num="0049">One embodiment of the present invention for a printer is illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIGURE 7</figref>. As depicted in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIGURE 7</figref>, most of the parts of the printer, except for a computer 230 and controllers 305 and 455, are isolated from vibrations by, for example, being supported on vibration isolation table 80. The table 80 may be composed of steel with a honeycomb interior. The legs of the table 80 may be air pistons which can absorb vibrations. Other types of vibration isolation may also be acceptable. In some embodiments, the computer 230 and controllers 305 and 455 may be supported on table 80. The computer 230 may have multiple ports and serial or parallel cables through which the computer 230 can control devices, like motor controllers, or through which the computer 230 can send output, such as images. In addition, computer 230 may have computational power and speed sufficient for three-dimensional computer graphics. Furthermore, computer 230 may include one or more central processing unit and may include one or more storage devices, for example, hard disks, a redundant array of independent disks, FLASH memory, or static or dynamic RAM, in which rendered images are stored. If more than one central processing unit is used, they may operate independently or in parallel. If more than one storage device is used, they may also operate independently or in parallel. In some embodiments, lasers 200 are not supported by table 80. The lasers 200 may be lasers of three different colors. For example, one laser 200 may be a krypton ion or a HeNe laser to produce a red beam of light, another laser 200 may be an argon ion or a YAG laser to produce a green beam of light, and a third laser 200 may<!-- EPO <DP n="19"> --> be an argon ion or a HeCd laser to produce a blue beam of light. Other light wavelengths are also acceptable. In addition, lasers 200 may be solid state diodes or other types of lasers. The beams of light from the lasers 200 may go through open air. In addition, the beams of light from the lasers 200 may go through pipes so that instabilities due to air currents will be reduced. Also, the beams may be transmitted through polarization-preserving optical fibers.</p><p id="p0050" num="0050">In <figref idrefs="f0005">FIGURE 7</figref>, the coherent light beams 5 produced by the lasers 200 are directed at variable beam splitters 205. Variable beam splitters are half-mirrors that split a beam by reflecting part of the beam and transmitting most of the rest of the beam. If fiber optics are used to transmit beams, then fiber optic beam splitters that work by contacting two parallel fibers together and letting the light from the fibers couple may be used. The coherent light beam 5 from each of the lasers 200 is split into two beams, an object beam 20 and a reference beam 25. In some embodiments, each object beam 20 and each reference beam 25 may be directed through half-wave plates 30 and polarizers 35. In other embodiments, if polarization-retaining fiber optic cables are used to transmit a beam and if the cables are rotatable about their center axes, half-wave plates 30 need not be used. If needed, each object beam may be reflected off one or more mirror 40. The mirrors 40 used in the present invention may be, for example, first surface or front surface mirrors. Each object beam 20 may be directed through a low pass spatial filter 220 to remove unwanted noise. A low pass spatial filter 220 may include a microscope objective lens and a pinhole. Each object beam 20 may then pass through a beam shutter 225. In one embodiment, the beam shutters 225 may be high-speed, mechanical iris shutters, for example, those used in made<!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> the photography industry. In other embodiments, the beam shutters 225 may be electro-optical systems such as liquid crystal cells or acousto-optical modulator crystals. In another embodiment, instead of using separate beam shutters 225, the SLM 90 in the object beam unit, generally 700, can function as a shutter for all three object beams. The shutters 225 are controlled by the computer 230. The object beams 20 may be then directed through an object beam unit 700. In the object beam unit 700, the object beams 20 may be directed such that the object beams 20 converge at the plane of a SLM 90. SLM 90 may include, but is not limited to, a transmissive LCD panel, a reflective LCD panel, an optically addressed LCD panel, a digital micro-mirror array, film, a projection or a transparency. The SLM 90 may receive image input by a video cable from the computer 230. In addition, multiple SLMs may receive images generated in parallel by multiple central processing units. Moreover, multiple SLMs may receive images from the storage device or devices of computer 230. After passing through the SLM 90, the object beam 20 may pass through a HOE 115, or another system, like those illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0002 f0003">FIGUREs 2-4</figref>, that is designed to converge the object beam and evenly expose an area the size of an elemental hologram. In one implementation, the HOE 115 may be a transmission-type hologram that can converge three different monochromatic object beams at slightly different angles onto the elemental holograms to be exposed without allowing zeroth-ordered light from any of the object beams to intersect the elemental holograms to be exposed. After passing through the object beam unit 700, the object beam 20 may then be transmitted through a voxel control lens 500 and may then expose an elemental hologram 110 on a holographic recording material 70 in a material holder 300. The holographic recording material 70 may be, but is not<!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> limited to, a pan-chromatic photopolymer, a pan-chromatic or monochromatic silver halide photographic emulsion dichromated gelatin, or other suitable photopolymers. The holographic recording material 70 may be held securely by a material holder 300 that may be able to translate the holographic recording material in two directions. The movement of the material holder 300 may be controlled by film holder motor controller 305 which may be controlled by computer 230.</p><p id="p0051" num="0051">As further depicted in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIGURE 7</figref>, after the beams are split into object beams 20 and reference beams 25 by the variable beam splitters 205, each of the reference beams 25 passes through a variable attenuator 210 which allows the intensity of each reference beam 25 to be independently adjusted. The reference beams may be reflected off of a mirror 40 before passing through dichroic combiners 215 or other suitable optical combiners. A dichroic combiner is a wavelength selective mirror which reflects some wavelengths, but is transparent to other wavelengths. The dichroic combiners 215 in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIGURE 7</figref> combine the three reference beams 25 into one beam which may the pass through a beam shutter 225 before passing through a low pass spatial filter 220. The reference beam 25 then passes through a reference beam-steering system 400 which controls the angle which the reference beam 25 intersects with the holographic recording material 70. A beam-steering mirror system of the reference beam-steering system is controlled by a mirror system motor controller 455 that is controlled by computer 230.</p><p id="p0052" num="0052">Furthermore, the present invention allows separate elemental holograms to be printed in different colors. For instance, by placing a beam shutter in the path of each object beam and reference beam and then selectively closing the beam shutters, one elemental hologram may be exposed to<!-- EPO <DP n="22"> --> only red object and reference beams, another may be exposed to only green object and reference beams, and another may be exposed to only blue object and reference beams.</p><p id="p0053" num="0053">An embodiment of the present invention in which multiple elemental holograms are simultaneously exposed is depicted in <figref idrefs="f0006">FIGURE 8</figref>. The beams from lasers 200 are split by variable beam splitters 205 and then after being reflected by mirrors 40 are split again by additional variable beam splitters 205, thereby forming two or more object beams 20 and two or more reference beams 25 from each laser 200. In other embodiments, the beams from laser 200 may be split even more times to form more object beams 20 and more reference beams 25. Each object beam 20 passes through a low pass filter 220 and a beam shutter 225. Each set of three object beams 20 may be reflected by mirrors 40 and pass through a SLM 90, a HOE 115, and a voxel control lens 500 to expose an elemental hologram 110 on a holographic recording material 70 held by a material holder 300. The movement of the material holder 300 is controlled by film holder motor controllers that are controlled by computer 230. Each set of three reference beams 25 passes through variable attenuators 210 and are combined into a beam by a dichroic combiner 215 or other suitable optical combiners. Each of the resulting two reference beams 25 passes through a beam shutter 225 and a low pass spatial filter 220. Each reference beam 25 then passes through a beam-steering system 400 before hitting an elemental hologram 110. Thus, as depicted in <figref idrefs="f0006">FIGURE 8</figref>, multiple elemental hologram may be simultaneously printed.</p><p id="p0054" num="0054">An embodiment of the present invention in which the variation in voxel size is controlled is illustrated by <figref idrefs="f0007">FIGUREs 9</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0008">10</figref>. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0007">FIGUREs 9</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0008">10</figref>, this control is accomplished by placing a voxel-control lens 500 in the path of an object beam 20 between SLM 90 and<!-- EPO <DP n="23"> --> holographic recording material 70. The voxel-control lens 500 may be placed in close proximity to holographic recording material 70. The voxel-control lens 500 may be capable of making an SLM or a projected image of a SLM seen from the viewpoint of an elemental hologram 110 appear at a greater apparent distance relative to the holographic recording material 70 during recording, so that a sample image point 100 on the SLM 90 surface is reconstructed at a greater distance away from the holographic recording material 70. <figref idrefs="f0008">FIGURE 10(a)</figref> illustrates how an image 505 of a SLM may appear to an elemental hologram 110 in a printer without a voxel-control lens. <figref idrefs="f0008">FIGURE 10(b)</figref> illustrates how an image 505 of a SLM may appear to an elemental hologram in a printer with a voxel-control lens 500. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0008">FIGURE 10</figref>, the voxel control lens magnifies the image 505 of a SLM, such that the angle  subtended by the image does not change but the angle  subtended by an elemental hologram decreases to  when a voxel control lens is used. The distance between the image 505 of a SLM and the holographic recording material 70 may be varied by varying the focal length of the voxel-control lens 500 or its position between the holographic recording surface 70 and the converging lens 55 or other optical systems, including simple diffuser or HOEs, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0001 f0002 f0003">Figures 1-3</figref>, used in the prior art to converge light onto the holographic recording material 70. In some embodiments, the voxel control lens 500 may be part of the object beam unit 700.</p><p id="p0055" num="0055">In one particular embodiment of this invention, it is possible to make the voxel sizes fairly constant over a wide range of distances from a holographic recording material 70. This is accomplished by choosing a voxel-control lens 500 with a focal length equal to the distance between the voxel-control lens 500 and the actual location of the SLM or the location of a projected image of the SLM<!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --> as seen by an elemental hologram in a printer without a voxel-control lens. Such a voxel-control lens 500 and geometrical layout will effectively reconstruct the SLM 120 at an infinite distance relative to holographic recording material 70. If the size of the pixels 95 on a SLM 90 are small compared to the size of the elemental holograms 110, the voxel 140 boundary lines for such an embodiment will no longer intersect close to the holographic recording material 70 as depicted in <figref idrefs="f0004">FIGURE 6</figref>, but instead become approximately parallel lines which extend out to a great distance without intersecting as shown in <figref idrefs="f0007">Figure 11</figref>.</p><p id="p0056" num="0056">Although the characteristics of a voxel-control lens 500 may depend on the desired results, typically it is desirable for the voxel-control lens 500 to be achromatic and have an f-number of around 3.0 or lower. In one particular embodiment, the voxel-control lens may be achromatic and have an f-number of 2.4. In other embodiments, the voxel-control lens may have lower f-numbers, such as 0.5. Lower f-numbers are desirable because they allow for a wider angle of view. In yet other embodiments, the voxel-control lens may be monochromatic.</p><p id="p0057" num="0057"><figref idrefs="f0009">Figure 12</figref> depicts yet another embodiment of the present invention. Referring to <figref idrefs="f0009 f0010 f0011 f0012 f0013">Figures 12-16</figref>, a reference beam-steering system, generally 400, may use a beam-steering mirror system 450 to direct a reference beam 25, through a first beam-steering lens 410 and a second beam-steering lens 405 to an elemental hologram 110 on a holographic recording material 70 which, if desired, may be inclined with respect to the normal to the center axis 420.</p><p id="p0058" num="0058">The beam-steering mirror system, generally 450, may be embodied in various ways. One particular embodiment is depicted in <figref idrefs="f0012">Figure 15</figref>. In <figref idrefs="f0012">Figure 15</figref>, a deflection mirror 460 is fixedly mounted to a first rotatable mount 465, such that when the first rotatable mount 465 rotates, the<!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --> deflection mirror 460 rotates about a first axis 451 which passes through center point 461 of the deflection mirror 460. A motor for the first rotatable mount 470, which is controlled by a motor controller 455, rotates the first rotatable mount 465. The motor for the first rotatable mount 470 is fixedly attached to a support 475. First rotatable mount 465 is rotatably mounted to a support 475 with bearings or bushings to allow the first rotatable mount 465 to rotate about the first axis 451. Support 475 is fixedly mounted by an attaching device on a second rotatable mount 480 such that when the second rotatable mount 480 rotates, the deflection mirror 460 rotates about a second axis 452 which passes through the center point 461 of the deflection mirror 460 and which is orthogonal to the first axis 451. A motor for the second rotatable mount 485, which is controlled by a motor controller 455, rotates the second rotatable mount 480. The motor for the second rotatable mount may be fixedly attached to a vibration isolation table 80. The motors for the first and second rotatable mounts, 470 and 485, may be, but are not limited to, stepper motors or DC servo motors. The same or a separate motor controller 455 controlled by computer 230 may control the motors for the first and second rotatable mounts 470 and 480.</p><p id="p0059" num="0059">Another suitable a beam-steering mirror system 450 is a deflection mirror attached to a gimbal mount. In <figref idrefs="f0013">Figure 16</figref>, a deflection mirror 460 is fixedly mounted to a first axle 490 such that the deflection mirror 460 rotates about a first axis 451 which passes through the center point 461 of the deflection mirror 460. First axle 490 is rotated by a motor 491 for the first axle which is controlled by a motor controller 455. The motor 491 for the first axle is fixedly attached to a first gimbal mount 494. First axle 490 is rotatably mounted by bearing or<!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> bushing to the first gimbal mount 494. The first gimbal mount 494 is fixedly mounted by an attaching device to a second axle 492 at the opposite ends of a diameter of the first gimbal mount 494 that coincides with a second axis 452. Second axle 492 is rotated by a motor 493 for the second axle and is controlled by a motor controller 455. The deflection mirror 460 rotates about the second axis 452 which passes through the center point 461 of the deflection mirror 460 and which is orthogonal to the first axis 451. Second axle 492 is rotatably mounted by bearing or bushing to a second gimbal mount 496. The motors 491 and 493, for the first and second axles, 491 and 493, may be, but are not limited to, stepper motors or DC servo motors. The same or separate motor controllers 455, controlled by a computer 230, may control the motors for the first and second axles, 491 and 493.</p><p id="p0060" num="0060">As shown in <figref idrefs="f0009 f0010 f0011 f0012 f0013">Figures 12-16</figref>, the center axis 420 of the beam-steering lenses 405, 410 intersects the first axis 451 and the second axis 452 and passes through the center of an elemental hologram. A reference beam 25 may be directed at the center point 461 of the deflection mirror 460. A computer 230 controls the mirror system motor controller or controllers 455 of the beam-steering mirror system 450, such that a reference beam 25 reflected off the deflection mirror 460 hits an elemental hologram 110 on a holographic recording material 70 at a desired angle. The deflection mirror 460 may be placed at a distance of one focal length 411 of the first beam-steering lens away from a first beam-steering lens 410. The first beam-steering lens 410 may be placed at a distance of the sum of the focal length 411 of the first beam-steering lens and the focal length 406 of the second beam-steering lens away from the second beam-steering lens 405. The second beam-steering lens 405 may be placed at a distance of one focal length 406 of the<!-- EPO <DP n="27"> --> second beam-steering lens, away from the holographic recording material 70. The beam-steering system 400 used in the present invention allows the reference beam 25 to be steered to intersect with elemental hologram 110 at different angles.</p><p id="p0061" num="0061">In another embodiment, depicted in <figref idrefs="f0010">Figure 13</figref>, the beam-steering system 400 may include a reference-beam converging lens 415 which may be achromatic or monochromatic. After a reference beam 25 passes through the reference-beam converging lens 415, the reference beam 25 is reflected by a beam-steering mirror system 450 before passing through beam-steering lenses 410 and 405. The first and second beam-steering lenses 410, 405 are placed such that the reference beam 25 that passes through the converging lens and the first beam-steering lens 410 converges in the focal plane 425 of the second beam-steering lens 405. In addition, the center point 461 shown in <figref idrefs="f0012">Figures 15</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0013">16</figref> of a deflection mirror 460 are shown in <figref idrefs="f0012">Figures 15</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0013">16</figref> is located at a distance of one focal length 411 of the first beam-steering lens from the first beam-steering lens 410. Furthermore, the elemental hologram 110 to be exposed is located at a distance of one focal length of the second beam-steering lens 406 away from the second beam-steering lens 305.</p><p id="p0062" num="0062">In another embodiment, depicted in <figref idrefs="f0011">Figure 14</figref>, the beam- steering system 400 may include a beam-steering aperture 430 which eliminates the need to have a reference beam masking plate. In an embodiment, a reference beam 25 passes through a beam-steering aperture 430 that has the aperture of the area of the elemental hologram 110 to be exposed. If the reference beam passes through lenses that magnify or minify it, then the beam-steering aperture 430 should be sized such that the cross-section of the reference beam that intersects the<!-- EPO <DP n="28"> --> elemental hologram to be exposed has the same size and shape of the elemental hologram. The reference beam 25 then passes through two aperture relay lenses 435, is reflected off of a deflection mirror 460 (shown in <figref idrefs="f0012">Figures 15</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0013">16</figref>) of the beam-steering mirror system 450, passes through the first beam-steering lens 410, passes through the second beam-steering lens 405, and then intersects the elemental hologram 110 to be exposed. The beam-steering aperture 430 is placed at a distance of one focal length 436 of the aperture relay lenses from one aperture relay lens 435. The aperture relay lenses 435 are located two focal lengths 436 of the aperture relay lens away from each other. Then the center point 461 (shown in <figref idrefs="f0012">Figures 15</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0013">16</figref>) of the deflection mirror 460 (shown in <figref idrefs="f0012">Figures 15</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0013">16</figref>) is located at a distance of one focal length 436 of the aperture relay lens away from the second aperture lens 435 that the reference beam passes through.</p><p id="p0063" num="0063">Another embodiment of a reference beam-steering system 400 is illustrated by <figref idrefs="f0014">Figures 17</figref>, <figref idrefs="f0015">18</figref>, and <figref idrefs="f0018">21</figref>. In this embodiment, an optical coupler lens 670 channels a reference beam 25 that has just passed through a beam shutter to the fiber optic end 660 of a fiber optic cable 650. The fiber optic cable 650 delivers the reference beam 25 to a fiber optic tip 655 which is placed in the focal plane 425 of a second beam-steering lens 405. The reference beam 25 passes through a beam-steering lens 405 to an elemental hologram 110. The beam-steering lens 405 is located at a distance of one focal length 406 of the second beam-steering lens from the elemental hologram 110 being exposed. The fiber optic tip 655 is translated by a translation system, generally 600.</p><p id="p0064" num="0064"><figref idrefs="f0016">Figure 19</figref> illustrates another embodiment of the reference beam-steering system 400. In this embodiment, three reference beams 25 which may each be a different<!-- EPO <DP n="29"> --> color are channeled by three optical coupler lenses 670 toward three fiber optic ends 660 of three fiber optic cables 650. The fiber optic cables 650 deliver the reference beams 25 to fiber optic tips 655 to direct the reference beams 25 into optical combiner unit 640. Optical combiner unit 640 may have two dichroic combiners 215, which may combine the three reference beams 25 into a single reference beam 25, other suitable optical combiners. The optical combiner unit 640 is placed in the focal plane 425 (shown in <figref idrefs="f0014">Figure 17</figref>) of a beam-steering lens 405. The single reference beam 25 from the optical combiner unit 640 passes through the beam-steering lens 405 to an elemental hologram 110. The beam-steering lens 405 is located at a distance of one focal length 406 of the beam-steering lens from the elemental hologram 110 being exposed. The optical combiner unit 640 is fixedly mounted to a platform 630 which is fixedly mounted to a second movable support 622.</p><p id="p0065" num="0065">In another embodiment, three reference beams 25 are transmitted by fiber optic cables 650 to a optical combiner unit 640. The single reference beam 25 that is output from the optical combiner unit 640 is channeled by an optical coupler lens 670 into a single fiber optic cable 650 which is attached to and carried by an attaching device to a translation system 600. The fiber optic tip 655 of the single fiber optic cable 650 is located in a focal plane 425 of a beam-steering lens 405.</p><p id="p0066" num="0066">In still another embodiment, the three reference beams 25 are transmitted by fiber optic cables 650 to a optical combiner unit 640. The single reference beam 25 that is output from the optical combiner unit 640 passes through a beam shutter 225 before it is channeled by an optical coupler lens 670 into a single fiber optic cable 650 which is fixedly attached to a translation system 600. The fiber<!-- EPO <DP n="30"> --> optic tip 655 of the fiber optic cable 650 is located in a focal plane 425 of a beam-steering lens 405.</p><p id="p0067" num="0067">The translation system 600, as depicted in <figref idrefs="f0015">Figure 18</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0016">Figure 19</figref>, is able to translate in two orthogonal directions. The translation system includes a x-translation stage and y-translation stage.</p><p id="p0068" num="0068">One illustrative embodiment of a x-translation stage 680 includes a first lead screw 602 which is rotatably mounted by bushing, bearing, or other rotatable means to first end plates 608, and which may be rotated about the axis 601 of the first lead screw by a motor 604 for the first lead screw which is fixedly mounted to one of the first end plates 608. Two first guide bars 610 are fixedly mounted to the first end plates 608 such that the first guide bars 610 lie parallel to the axis of the first lead screw 601. The two first guide bars 610 pass through two holes in a first movable support 612. The first lead screw 602 is threaded through a hole in the first movable support 612. Thus, in this embodiment of the x-translation stage 680, when the first lead screw 602 is rotated by the motor 604 for the first lead screw, the first movable support 612 will move along the axis 601 of the first lead screw.</p><p id="p0069" num="0069">One illustrative embodiment of a y-translation stage 690 includes a second lead screw 618 which is rotatably mounted by bushing, bearing, or other rotatable means to second end plates 614, and which may be rotated about the axis 617 of the second lead screw 618 by a motor 620 for the second lead screw which is mounted to one of the second end plates 614. The other of the second end plates 614 is mounted to the first movable support 612 such that the axis 617 of the second lead screw is orthogonal to the axis 601 of the first lead screw. Two second guide bars 616 are fixedly mounted to the second end plates 614 such that the second guide bars 616 lie parallel to the axis 617 of the<!-- EPO <DP n="31"> --> second lead screw. The two second guide bars 616 pass through two holes in a second movable support 622. The second lead screw 618 is threaded through a hole in the second movable support 622. Thus, in this embodiment of the y-translation device 690, when the second lead screw 618 is rotated by the motor for the second lead screw 620, the second movable support 622 will move along the axis 617 of the second lead screw.</p><p id="p0070" num="0070">The motors 604 and 620, for the first and second lead screws which may be, but are not limited to stepper, DC servo or linear motors, may be controlled by a motor controller 606 for the motors for the lead screws which may be controlled by computer 230.</p><p id="p0071" num="0071">Although the types, focal lengths, and number of beam-steering lenses may be varied, for some embodiments, it may be desirable for the beam-steering lenses to be achromatic and have f-numbers of around 3.0 or less. In other embodiments, it may be desirable for the beam-steering lenses to be achromatic, confocal, f- lenses, which are also known as flat-field laser-scan lenses. In some embodiments, it may also be desirable to have lenses of lower f-number to allow for a wider range of reference beams. In one particular embodiment, it may be desirable to have the beam-steering lenses be achromatic and have f-numbers of around 1.0. In addition, the beam-steering lenses may be monochromatic in other embodiments.</p><p id="p0072" num="0072">The beam-steering system used in the present invention may be utilized to create holographic stereograms that display a particular image when illuminated by an illumination source from one angle, but display another image when illuminated by an illumination source from another angle. For instance, after exposing an elemental hologram with an object beam conditioned with a particular image on an SLM and a reference beam at a particular angle, the elemental<!-- EPO <DP n="32"> --> hologram may then be exposed to an object beam conditioned with another image on the SLM and a reference beam at another angle. In addition, a set of elemental holograms on a holographic recording material may be exposed by a reference beam at a particular angle, while another set of elemental holograms may be exposed by a reference beam at another angle. Thus, a printer of this invention can create a holographic stereogram that displays a different image depending on the angle of the illumination source. Furthermore, the same printer with a beam-steering system may be used to create multiple holographic stereograms, each with a different reference angle, such that the images of each will only appear when illuminated by an illumination source at the correct angle. If such multiple holographic stereograms are mounted on top of each other, then different images may be displayed by simply changing the angle at which the illumination source intersects the holographic recording materials.</p><p id="p0073" num="0073">Another embodiment of the present invention, illustrated by <figref idrefs="f0017">Figure 20</figref>, utilizes multiple SLMs 90 to produce full-color holographic stereograms. In <figref idrefs="f0017">Figure 20</figref>, two dichroic combiners 215 in an "x" configuration, or other suitable optical combiners, may be used in combination with three object beams 20, one object beam being red light, the other green light, and the other blue light. The three object beams 20 may be directed through three separate gray-scale SLMs 90. In one embodiment of the present invention the SLMs are LCD panels of high resolution such as 1,280 x 1,024 pixels where the total size of the LCD panel is approximately 10cm x 10cm. However, smaller LCD panels may be used. For instance, LCD panels with the same or fewer number of pixels but that are around 2cm x 2cm in size or smaller may be used.<!-- EPO <DP n="33"> --></p><p id="p0074" num="0074">In an embodiment shown in <figref idrefs="f0017">Figure 20</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0018">Figure 21</figref>, after passing through beam shutters 225, object beams 20 are directed through optical coupler lenses 670 to converge at fiber optic ends 660. The object beam 20 are then transmitted by fiber optic cables 650 to the fiber optic tips 655 which are placed in the focal planes of singlet lenses 705. The object beams 20 may pass through the singlet lenses 705, if necessary, reflect off mirrors 40, and pass through SLMs 90 and band-limited diffusers 45, which may be color specific. The singlet lenses 705 expand and collimate the object beams 20 such that the object beams 20 may more evenly illuminate the SLMs 90. The object beams 20 are then directed through a optical combiner unit 640 that may use two dichroic combiners 215 in an "x" configuration, or other suitable optical combiners, to combine the three object beams 20 into a single beam. The single object beam 20 may then pass through a first projection lens 715 and a Fourier transform filter 710 that may remove undesired effects such as, but not limited to, high frequency image components such as pixel or grid artifacts that resulted from an SLM display with pixels. The object beam 20 may then pass through a second projection lens 720 and then a converging lens 55. The first projection lens 715 is located such that images of the SLMs all lie in the focal plane of the first projection lens. The Fourier transform filter 710 is located in the focal planes of both the first projection lens and the second projection lens. The converging lens 55 is located such that its focal plane intersects the holographic recording material 70 at the elemental hologram 110 to be exposed. In other embodiments of the object beam unit 700, the first and second projection lenses 715 and 720 and the Fourier transform filter 710 are not used. In still other embodiments of the object beam unit 700, a<!-- EPO <DP n="34"> --> voxel control lens 500 may be included in the object beam unit 700 and lie in close proximity to the holographic recording material 70.</p><p id="p0075" num="0075">In one embodiment of the present invention, a material holder, generally 300, may be used to translate holographic recording material 70. As depicted in <figref idrefs="f0019 f0020 f0021 f0022">Figures 22-25</figref>, a material holder 300 may include a frame 324 attached to a x-translation stage 680 that is attached to a y-translation stage 690.</p><p id="p0076" num="0076">In one embodiment, the y-translation stage 680, as depicted in <figref idrefs="f0019 f0020 f0021 f0022">Figures 22-25</figref>, may have first holder end plates 302 to which first holder guide rods 306 are fixedly attached. A first holder lead screw 308 and a first holder driven lead screw 309 are rotatably attached by bushing or bearing or other suitable means to the first holder end plates 302. The first holder lead screw 308 and the first holder guide rods 306 are parallel to the axis of the first holder driven lead screw 307. The first holder driven lead screw 309 may be rotated by a motor 310 for the first holder driven lead screw, which is controlled by holder motor controller 305, which is controlled by computer 230. The motor 310 may also drive both lead screws 308 and 309 with a timing belt or other linkage. In addition, two motors 310, each coupled to a lead screw, may drive the lead screws. The first holder driven lead screw 309 passes through a threaded hold in the a first holder movable support 312. The two first holder guide rods 306 in close proximity to the first holder driven lead screw 309 pass through holes in the same first holder movable support 312. The first holder lead screw 308 passes through a threaded hole in another first holder movable support 312, and the two first holder guide rods 306 in close proximity to the first holder lead screw 308 pass through holes in the same first holder movable support 312.<!-- EPO <DP n="35"> --></p><p id="p0077" num="0077">In another embodiment, the x-translation stage 680, as depicted in <figref idrefs="f0019 f0020 f0021 f0022 f0023">Figures 22-26</figref>, may have a second holder lead screw 318 and a first holder driven lead screw 319 rotatably attached by bushing or bearing or other suitable means to second holder end plates 314. The axis of the second holder driven lead screw 317 is orthogonal to the axis of the first holder driven lead screw 307. The second holder lead screw 318 and the second holder guide rods 316 are parallel to the axis of the second holder driven lead screw 317. The second holder driven lead screw 319 may be rotated by a motor 320, for the second holder driven lead screw which is controlled by holder motor controller 305, which is controlled by computer 230. The second holder driven lead screw 319 passes through a threaded hole in the a second holder movable support 322. The two second holder guide rods 316 in close proximity to the second holder driven lead screw 319 pass through holes in the same second holder movable support 322. The second holder lead screw 318 passes through a threaded hole in another second holder movable support 322, and the two second holder guide rods 316 in close proximity to the second holder lead screw 318 pass through holes in the same second holder movable support 322.</p><p id="p0078" num="0078">As depicted in <figref idrefs="f0019">FIGUREs 22</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0020">23</figref>, the x-translation stage 680 may be mounted to the y-translation stage 690. In one embodiment, the first holder movably supports 312 are fixedly mounted to the second holder end plages 314. The second holder movable supports 322 are fixedly attached to a frame 324. A second frame 324 may be clamped to a first frame 324 by detachable couplings 325 which may include, but are not limited to, clamps, snaps, screws, and bolts. A holographic recording material may be held in between two detachably coupled frames 324. In an alternative embodiment, the natural adhesive property of a<!-- EPO <DP n="36"> --> holographic recording material may hold the material on one side of a transparent plate that is secured to frames 324. The frames 324 may be composed of stress-relieved aluminum, titanium, composites, or other rigid, strong, and lightweight materials.</p><p id="p0079" num="0079">As illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0020">FIGURE 23</figref>, object beam units 700 and reference beam-steering systems 400 may be fixed to bases 326.</p><p id="p0080" num="0080">As illustrated in <figref idrefs="f0021">FIGUREs 24</figref> and <figref idrefs="f0022">25</figref>, one or more object beam units 700 may be fixedly mounted to unit mounts 328 which are fixedly mounted to second holder movable supports 322 of a x-translation stage 680. Similarly, one or more reference beam-steering systems 400 may be fixedly mounted to other second unit mounts 328 which are fixedly mounted to other holder movable supports 322 of another x-translation stage 680. In addition, in some embodiments, a frame 324 may be fixed to the first movable supports 312 of a y-translation stage 690. Thus, in some embodiments, the holographic recording material 70 clamped between two frames 324 may translate vertically, while the object beam units 700 and reference beam-steering systems 400 translate horizontally.</p><p id="p0081" num="0081">In the embodiment depicted in <figref idrefs="f0021">FIGURE 24</figref>, two motors 320, which are controlled by holder motor controller 305, drive the second holder driven lead screws 319 of the x-translation stages 680. In an alternative embodiment depicted in <figref idrefs="f0022">FIGURE 25</figref>, one motor 320, in combination with a timing belt 330 that is linked to a belt mount 332 that is fixedly attached to one of the second holder driven lead screws 319, drives both second holder driven lead screws 319 of the x-translation stages 680.</p><p id="p0082" num="0082">In another embodiment depicted in <figref idrefs="f0023">FIGURE 26</figref>, the object beam units 700 and reference beam-steering systems 400 are attached to unit mounts 328 which are attached to<!-- EPO <DP n="37"> --> the second holder movable supports 322 of x-translation stages 680. A holographic recording material 70 translates vertically by a y-axis roller system 350 with rollers 342 and 344. The holographic recording material 70 may be wrapped around a top roller 342 and a bottom roller 344. The top and bottom rollers 342 and 344 are rotatably mounted by bushing, bearing, or other suitable means between roller end plates 340. The top roller 342 may be rotated by a motor for the rollers 346, which is controlled by a motor controller 305 which is controlled by a computer 230.</p><p id="p0083" num="0083">The motors used in the translation systems of the various embodiments may be, but are not limited to stepper motors.</p><p id="p0084" num="0084">As depicted in <figref idrefs="f0020 f0021 f0022 f0023">FIGUREs 23-26</figref>, there may be simultaneous or parallel printing of elemental holograms. In some embodiments, the printer may include object beam units and reference beam-steering systems attached to translation systems with x-translation stages that are attached to y-translation stages. In such systems, the holographic recording material may be fixed, while the object beam units and reference beam-steering systems are moved by the translation system to record an array of elemental holograms.</p><p id="p0085" num="0085">In an alternative embodiment, multiple layers of holographic recording material 70 may be held in a material holder 300. In addition, each layer may be sensitive to a particular wavelength of light.</p><p id="p0086" num="0086">In another embodiment of the present invention, for a given object beam, a matched set of a band-limited diffusers 45 and a reference beam masking plate 65 may be configured to allow for even exposure of an elemental hologram 110 of a particular size or shape and to prevent exposing portions of the holographic recording material 70<!-- EPO <DP n="38"> --> that are not part of the elemental hologram 110 intended to be exposed. As illustrated by <figref idrefs="f0024">FIGUREs .27(a), (b), and (c)</figref>, matched sets of band-limited diffusers 45 and reference beam masking plates 65 can be constructed to allow the exposure of elemental holograms 110 of different sizes or shapes. If the sets of band-limited diffusers 45 and reference beam masking plates 65 are constructed such that the band-limited diffusers 45. of all the sets have the same outer dimensions and can be placed in the same position in a hologram printer, and such that the reference beam masking plates 65 of all the sets have the same outer dimensions and can be placed in the same position in a hologram printer, then sets can be conveniently switched to easily change the size of the elemental hologram printed. Thus, a matched set of a band-limited diffuser 45 and a reference beam masking plate 65 can be replaced with another set of a band-limited diffuser 45 and a reference beam masking plate 65 so as to allow printing of a larger, smaller, or differently shaped elemental hologram. As depicted in <figref idrefs="f0024">FIGURE 27(B)</figref>, a band-limited diffuser 45 may be mounted onto a plate 510 housed in a threaded frame 515. The plate 510 may be a sheet transparent sheet of glass with an anti-reflective coating. The threaded frame 515 may be threaded into positioning device 525 which has a base 526 and a threaded ring 520. The positioning device 520 may allow translational adjustment in three orthogonal directions by three adjustable screws 530. As depicted in <figref idrefs="f0024">FIGURE 27(c)</figref>, a reference beam masking plate 65 may be housed in a threaded plate frame 560. A threaded plate frame 560 may be threaded into a threaded positioning device 565.</p><p id="p0087" num="0087">Some examples of full-color embodiments of the present invention are depicted in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIGUREs 7</figref>, <figref idrefs="f0006">8</figref>, <figref idrefs="f0016">19</figref>, and <figref idrefs="f0018">21</figref>. Another embodiment of the present invention includes a<!-- EPO <DP n="39"> --> full-color print with three different colored lasers, optical combiners, such as but not limited to dichroic combiners, to combine the three beams from the lasers, a full-color SLM, and achromatic optics to print full-color holographic stereograms. Still another embodiment of the present invention includes a full-color printer with three different colored lasers, an object beam unit that combines three object beams using three beam-limited diffusers, three gray-scale SLMs, and an optical combiner, achromatic optics, such as achromatic lenses, to manipulate or condition the full-color beams produced by the printer, and an optical combiner to combine three reference beams into a combined, full-color, reference beam. Yet another embodiment of the present invention includes a full-color printer with three different colored lasers, an object beam unit with an HOE that combines three different colored object beams into one combined, full-color, object beam and that also evenly distributes the combined object beam over an elemental hologram, an optical combiner to combine three reference beams into a combined, full-color, reference beam, and achromatic optics to manipulate or condition the full-colored beams.</p><p id="p0088" num="0088">Another aspect of the present invention involves a method of creating animated, one-step, full-parallax, holographic stereograms. One embodiment involves using multiple or sub-divided viewing zones, which typically are not needed to produce static image, full-parallax holographic stereograms, to produce one-step, full-parallax, holographic stereograms that can display animated subjects or different images through different viewing zones. Viewing zones are typically planar areas located at a distance from the holographic recording material in which a viewer's eye looking through that plane could see the holographic image produced by an array of elemental<!-- EPO <DP n="40"> --> holograms. Thus, a viewing zone may be analogous to a window in front of a hologram. However, rather than being planar, viewing zones may also be constructed from a series of points. Unlike traditional techniques for producing one-step, full-parallax holographic stereograms in which the view of a three-dimensional object or a scene is determined for each elemental hologram, the present invention produces animated, one-stop, full-parallax holographic stereograms by determining the view of an object or scene that an observer would see in each viewing zone.</p><p id="p0089" num="0089">Referring to <figref idrefs="f0025 f0026 f0027">FIGUREs 28-31</figref>, and assuming that a voxel-control lens 500 is used such that the image 505 (shown in <figref idrefs="f0008">FIGURE 10(b)</figref>) of an SLM would appear at an infinite distance from the surface of the holographic recording material, the steps for producing a holographic element of an animated holographic stereogram or a holographic stereogram that displays different images in different viewing zones are as follows.
<ol><li>1) Select the size and shape of a holographic stereogram, and the size and shape of its elemental holograms.</li><li>2) Select the desired effect. One example of an effect is changing the orientation of an object or a scene (e.g., its position or rotation) when a viewer moves. Another example of an effect is changing the shape or color of an object or a scene when a view moves.</li><li>3) Select the reference illumination geometry for the final holographic stereogram.</li><li>4) Select the shape(s), size(s), and location(s) of the viewing zone or zones with respect to the holographic recording material. In the plane of the viewing zone, a viewer would see a sharper<!-- EPO <DP n="41"> --> transition between the different objects or scenes depicted by the holographic stereogram than a viewer not in the plane of the viewing zones. Thus, it may be desirable to select the location of the viewing zones to be at a distance from the holographic recording material where most viewers would be located.</li><li>5) Select the objects or scenes or the attributes of the objects or scenes to be displayed by the holographic stereogram.</li><li>6) Select the location and placement with respect to the holographic recording material of the holographic images of the objects that will be displayed by the holographic stereogram to be created (<i>i.e.</i> whether the image will be located in front of, in back of, or straddle the holographic recording material).</li><li>7) Using a computer 230, generate computer models and model attributes for each viewing zone using traditional computer graphic techniques and programs of the objects or scenes. For instance, generate a computer model of an object 'A' 835 which can only be seen from one viewing zone 805, and generate a computer model of an object 'B' 840 which can only be seen from another viewing zone 810.</li><li>8) Set up the hologram printer. For instance, put holographic recording material 70 (shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIGURE 7</figref>) into a material holder 300 (shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIGURE 7</figref>), calibrate and initialize beam shutters 225 (shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIGURE 7</figref>), motor controllers 305, 455 the SLM 90 (shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIGURE 7</figref>), the beam-steering system 400 (shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIGURE 7</figref>), and<!-- EPO <DP n="42"> --> initialize the computer graphics program, and the computer 230 (shown in <figref idrefs="f0005">FIGURE 7</figref>).</li><li>9) Using a computer 230, for each elemental hologram 110 in a holographic stereogram that may be one-step, full-parallax, holographic stereogram:
<ol><li>A) Project lines from the perimeter of the elemental hologram 110 through the perimeter of each of the view zones 805 and 810. Since in a typical printer, a SLM is usually centered in front of an elemental hologram when the elemental hologram is exposed, the virtual image of the SLM that an elemental hologram would see through a voxel-control lens is also usually centered in front of the elemental hologram, as shown in <figref idrefs="f0026">FIGURE 29</figref>. As depicted in <figref idrefs="f0026">FIGURE 30</figref>, the projected lines intersect a virtual two-dimensional image 505 (shown in <figref idrefs="f0008">FIGURE 10(b)</figref>) of a SLM image. The elemental hologram will only see the portion of the virtual image 505 of the SLM, such as 815 or 820, bounded by the projecting lines. As shown in <figref idrefs="f0026">FIGURE 30</figref>, the projected lines define mask volumes 825, 830, which may differ from one elemental hologram to another for a given viewing zone.</li><li>B) For a desired viewing zone mask volume, such as 825, for an elemental hologram 100, using traditional rendering techniques, such as but not limited to, ray-tracing or scan-line conversion, render the portion of the appropriate computer model of an object or scene 835 (shown in <figref idrefs="f0026">FIGURE 30</figref>) enclosed by the projected mask volume 825 to create a<!-- EPO <DP n="43"> --> complete two-dimensional image of a projection on the portion of the virtual image 505 of the SLM of the computer graphic models of the objects or scenes 835 or 840 from the perspective of an elemental hologram. For instance, if a person were to look at a particular elemental hologram from within a mask volume 825, only the 'A' object 835 is seen. From mask volume 825, the 'B' object 840 is not viewable. Thus, to a viewer in mask volume 825, the bottom of the virtual image of the SLM is not visible. Similarly, if a person were to look at the particular elemental hologram from within a mask volume 830, only the 'B' object 840 is seen. From mask volume 830, the 'A' object 835 is not viewable. Thus, to a viewer in mask volume 830, the top of the virtual image of the SLM is not visible.</li><li>C) When rendering is complete for all the viewing zones 805 and 810 for an elemental hologram, composite the rendered images for the viewing zones.</li><li>D) Display the composite rendered image for the viewing zones 805 and 810 on the SLM 70 and allow light to pass through the beam shutters 225 for the proper time period to expose the elemental hologram.</li><li>E) Translate the material holder such that another elemental hologram can be exposed.</li><li>F) Repeat steps A through E until all the elemental holograms have been exposed.</li></ol></li></ol></p><p id="p0090" num="0090">In an alternative embodiment, rendering for multiple elemental holograms may be completed before exposing any of<!-- EPO <DP n="44"> --> the elemental holograms on a holographic recording material.</p><p id="p0091" num="0091">In an alternative embodiment, the same method applied for creating holographic stereograms with changing views may be used to create a holographic optical element (HOE). For instance, if it is desirable to create a HOE that acts like a lens to a converge diverging white light to a point, then by using the same viewing zone method as described, but determining a view point located at where the light should be focused, rather than a view zone, a HOE may be created. Alternatively, such a HOE can be created by determining a white computer-graphic object with the exact size, shape, and position of a given voxel, and printing a holographic stereogram of such an object.</p><p id="p0092" num="0092">In one embodiment of the present invention, the same computer 230 may be programmed to control the motors controlling the beam shutters, the motor controllers for the beam-steering mirror system, the motor controllers for the translation systems, conducts the computer graphics creation and rendering, and controls the display of the SLM. In an alternative embodiment, the same computer may also conduct the computations necessary for animation. The computer 230 may be connected to the beam shutters, the motor controllers for the beam-steering mirror system, and the SLM, through cables connected at both ends to serial or parallel communication ports. One end of the cables may be connected to the communication ports of the computer and the other ends of the cables may be connected to the devices controlled by the computer. In other embodiments, multiple computers 230 may be used.</p><p id="p0093" num="0093">In an alternative arrangement, different combinations of lens<!-- EPO <DP n="45"> --> set-ups are used to create the same effect as the voxel-control lens or the beam-steering lenses described herein.</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980751" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="54"> --><claim id="c-de-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Mehrwellenlngen-Stereogrammen in einem Schritt, die Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>eine erste Lichtquelle (200), die dazu ausgebildet ist, einen ersten kohrenten Strahl zu erzeugen;</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Strahlteiler (205), der dazu ausgebildet ist, den ersten kohrenten Strahl in einen ersten Objektstr (20) und einen ersten Bezugsstrahl (25) zu teilen;</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Materialhalter (300), der dazu ausgebildet ist, ein holographisches Aufzeichnungsmaterial (70) mit Elementarhologrammen zu halten;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Objektstrahleinheit (700), umfassend mindestens einen rumlichen Lichtmodulator (90), wobei der rumliche Lichtmodulator dazu ausgebildet ist, ein gerendertes Bild anzuzeigen und den ersten Objektstrahl mit dem gerenderten Bild zu konditionieren, um an einem gewhlten Elementarhologramm mit dem ersten Bezugsstrahl zu interferieren;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine zweite Lichtquelle, die dazu ausgebildet ist, einen zweiten Objektstrahl und einen zweiten Bezugsstrahl zu erzeugen, wobei der zweite Objektstrahl eine von einer Wellenlnge des ersten Objektstrahls verschiedene Wellenlnge aufweist und zu dem rumlichen Lichtmodulator gelenkt wird;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine dritte Lichtquelle, die dazu ausgebildet ist, einen dritten Objektstrahl und einen dritten Bezugsstrahl zu erzeugen, wobei der dritte Objektstrahl eine von den Wellenlngen des ersten und des zweiten Objektstrahls verschiedene Wellenlnge aufweist und zu dem rumlichen Lichtmodulator gelenkt wird;<!-- EPO <DP n="55"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Bezugsstrahl-Ablenksystem (400), das dazu ausgebildet ist, den ersten Bezugsstrahl dazu zu lenken, an dem gewhlten Elementarhologramm mit dem ersten Objektstrahl zu interferieren, um den Bereich des gewhlten Elementarhologramms zu belichten, und dazu ausgebildet ist, den zweiten Bezugsstrahl dazu zu lenken, an dem gewhlten Elementarhologramm mit dem zweiten Objektstrahl zu interferieren,</claim-text>
<claim-text>um den Bereich des gewhlten Elementarhologramms zu belichten, und dazu ausgebildet ist, den dritten Bezugsstrahl dazu zu lenken, an dem gewhlten Elementarhologramm mit dem dritten Objektstrahl zu interferieren, um den Bereich des gewhlten Elementarhologramms zu belichten; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen Computer (230), der dazu programmiert ist, die Interferenz von jedem der Objektstrahlen mit einem entsprechenden Bezugsstrahl der Bezugsstrahlen an dem ausgewhlten Elementarhologramm und/oder das Zufhren des gerenderten Bilds zu der Objektstrahleinheit zu steuern.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 1, die weiter Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>einen ersten Strahlverschluss (225), der in den Weg des ersten Objektstrahls (20) platziert ist; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>einen zweiten Strahlverschluss (225), der in den Weg des ersten Bezugsstrahls (25) platziert ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 1, wobei die erste Lichtquelle (200) einen Laser umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 1, wobei jede der drei Lichtquellen (200) einen jeweiligen Laser umfasst.<!-- EPO <DP n="56"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 4, wobei ein Laser dazu ausgebildet ist, ein blaues Licht zu erzeugen, ein Laser dazu ausgebildet ist, ein rotes Licht zu erzeugen, und ein Laser dazu ausgebildet ist, ein grnes Licht zu erzeugen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 1, umfassend mehrere rumliche Lichtmodulatoren (90), wobei jeder der Objektstrahlen zu mindestens einem entsprechenden rumlichen Lichtmodulator hin gelenkt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Objektstrahleinheit (700) ein holographisches optisches Element (HOE, 115) im Weg des ersten Objektstrahls umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 7, wobei das HOE dazu ausgebildet ist, den ersten Objektstrahl (20) zu konvergieren und gleichmig ber dem gewhlten Elementarhologramm zu verteilen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Objektstrahleinheit (700) einen bandbegrenzten Diffusor (45) im Weg des ersten Objektstrahls (20) und eine Sammellinse (55) im Weg des ersten Objektstrahls umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Objektstrahleinheit (700) eine Lichtwellenleiterleitung umfasst, die dazu ausgebildet ist, den ersten Objektstrahl (20) zu bertragen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 10, wobei die Objektstrahleinheit (700) Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>mehrere Lichtwellenleiterleitungen (650), die jeweils dazu ausgebildet sind, einen jeweiligen Objektstrahl der Objektstrahlen zu bertragen;<!-- EPO <DP n="57"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>eine einzelne Linse (705), einen rumlichen Lichtmodulator (90) und einen bandbegrenzten Diffusor (45) im Weg von jedem Objektstrahl; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine optische Kombinatoreinheit (640) in dem Weg von jedem der Objektstrahlen,</claim-text>
<claim-text>wobei der optische Kombinator dazu ausgebildet ist, die Objektstrahlen zu einem kombinierten Objektstrahl zu kombinieren, der das gewhlte Elementarhologramm schneidet.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 11, wobei die Objektstrahleinheit (700) Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>eine Sammellinse (55) in dem Weg des kombinierten Objektstrahls; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Paar Projektionslinsen (715, 720), die sich in dem Weg des kombinierten Objektstrahls zwischen der optischen Kombinatoreinheit (640) und der Sammellinse (55) befinden.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 12, wobei die Objektstrahleinheit (700) einen Fouriertransformationsfilter (710) umfasst, der sich zwischen den zwei Projektionslinsen (715, 720) befindet.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 1, wobei die Objektstrahleinheit (700) eine Voxel-Steuerlinse (500) proximal zu dem holographischen Aufzeichnungsmaterial (70) umfasst, wobei die Voxel-Steuerlinse dazu ausgebildet ist, eine Auflsung des holographischen Stereogramms zu steuern.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 1, wobei der Computer (230) mindestens eine zentrale Verarbeitungseinheit umfasst.<!-- EPO <DP n="58"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0016" num="0016"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 15, wobei mindestens eine der zentralen Verarbeitungseinheiten dazu programmiert ist, das Bild zu rendern, das zu der Objektstrahleinheit (700) zugefhrt wird.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0017" num="0017"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 15, wobei der Computer (230) mindestens eine Speichervorrichtung umfasst, die arbeitet, um das gerenderte Bild von mindestens einer der zentralen Verarbeitungseinheiten zu empfangen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0018" num="0018"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 17, wobei die Objektstrahleinheit (700) mehrere rumliche Lichtmodulatoren (90) umfasst, wobei jeder rumliche Lichtmodulator dazu ausgebildet ist, ein gerendertes Bild von mindestens einer der Speichervorrichtungen zu empfangen.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0019" num="0019"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 1, wobei das Bezugsstrahl-Ablenksystem (400) ein Strahlablenk-Spiegelsystem (450) umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0020" num="0020"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 19, wobei das Strahlablenk-Spiegelsystem (450) Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>einen Spiegel (460) mit einem Mittelpunkt (461), einer ersten Achse (451), die durch den Mittelpunkt luft und einer zweiten Achse (452), die durch den Mittelpunkt luft und senkrecht zu der ersten Achse ist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine erste Halterung (494), die den Spiegel trgt und dazu ausgebildet ist, den Spiegel um die erste Achse zu drehen, und</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine zweite Halterung (496), die die erste Halterung trgt und dazu ausgebildet ist,</claim-text>
<claim-text>den Spiegel um die zweite Achse zu drehen.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="59"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0021" num="0021"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 20, wobei die erste Halterung (494) einen auf den Computer (230) ansprechenden ersten Motor (491) umfasst, der die Drehung des Spiegels (460) um die erste Achse (451) steuert.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0022" num="0022"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 20, wobei die zweite Halterung (496) einen auf den Computer (230) ansprechenden zweiten Motor (492) umfasst, der die Drehung des Spiegels (460) um die zweite Achse (452) steuert.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0023" num="0023"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 19, wobei das Bezugsstrahl-Ablenksystem (400) Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>eine erste Strahlablenklinse (410) in dem Weg des ersten Bezugsstrahls (25), und</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine zweite Strahlablenklinse (405) in dem Weg des ersten Bezugsstrahls.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0024" num="0024"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 23, wobei das Bezugsstrahl-Ablenksystem (400) eine Bezugsstrahl-Sammellinse (415) umfasst, die in einem Weg der in das Strahlablenk-Spiegelsystem eintretenden Bezugsstrahlen angeordnet ist.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0025" num="0025"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 23, wobei das Bezugsstrahl-Ablenksystem (400) eine Strahlablenkblende (430) und Blenden-Relaislinsen (435) umfasst, wobei das Bezugsstrahl-Ablenksystem dazu ausgebildet ist, die Bezugsstrahlen durch die Strahlablenkblende und die Blenden-Relaislinsen zu leiten, wenn die Bezugsstrahlen in das Strahlablenk-Spiegelsystem eintreten.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0026" num="0026"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 1, wobei das Bezugsstrahl-Ablenksystem (400) Folgendes umfasst:<!-- EPO <DP n="60"> -->
<claim-text>eine jeweilige Lichtwellenleiterleitung (650) zum bertragen von jedem der Bezugsstrahlen (25), wobei jede der jeweiligen Lichtwellenleiterleitungen ein Ausgangsende (655) aufweist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>ein Verschiebungssystem (600) zum Bewegen der Ausgangsenden; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>eine Strahlablenklinse (405) in dem Weg der Bezugsstrahlen.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0027" num="0027"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 26, wobei der Computer (230) dazu programmiert ist, die Bewegung des Verschiebungssystems (600) zu steuern.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0028" num="0028"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 26, wobei das Bezugsstrahl-Ablenksystem (400) eine Abdeckplatte (65) in dem Weg der Bezugsstrahlen (25) und proximal zu dem holographischen Aufzeichnungsmaterial (70) umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0029" num="0029"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 26, wobei das Verschiebungssystem (600) eine erste Achse (601) und eine zu der ersten Achse senkrechte zweite Achse (617) aufweist und ein Gestell (680) fr die erste Verschiebung zur Verschiebung entlang der ersten Achse und ein Gestell (690) fr die zweite Verschiebung zur Verschiebung entlang der zweiten Achse umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0030" num="0030"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 26, die Folgendes umfasst:
<claim-text>a) mehrere Lichtwellenleiterleitungen (650) zum bertragen von mehreren Bezugsstrahlen (25), wobei jede Lichtwellenleiterleitung ein Ausgangsende (655) aufweist; und<!-- EPO <DP n="61"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>b) eine optische Kombinatoreinheit (640), die an dem Verschiebungssystem (600) angebracht ist und auerdem an jedem Lichtwellenleiterleitungs-Ausgangsende angebracht ist.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0031" num="0031"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 1, wobei der Materialhalter (300) ein Gestell (680) fr die erste Verschiebung umfasst, das ansprechend auf den Computer (230) wirksam ist, um den Materialhalter entlang einer ersten Achse zu verschieben.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0032" num="0032"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 31, wobei der Materialhalter (300) ein Gestell (690) fr die zweite Verschiebung umfasst, das ansprechend auf den Computer (230) wirksam ist, um den Materialhalter entlang einer zu der ersten Achse senkrechten zweiten Achse zu verschieben.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0033" num="0033"><claim-text>Vorrichtung zum Drucken von holographischen Stereogrammen nach Anspruch 1, wobei:
<claim-text>der Materialhalter ein Gestell fr die erste Verschiebung und zwei Gestelle fr die zweite Verschiebung umfasst;</claim-text>
<claim-text>das holographische Aufzeichnungsmaterial eine Vorderseite und eine Rckseite aufweist, wobei das holographische Aufzeichnungsmaterial an dem Gestell fr die erste Verschiebung angebracht ist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>mindestens eine Objektstrahleinheit an einem der Gestelle fr die zweite Verschiebung befestigt ist und sich auf der Vorderseite des holographischen Aufzeichnungsmaterials befindet; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>mindestens ein Bezugsstrahl-Ablenksystem an den anderen Gestell fr die zweite Verschiebung befestigt ist und sich auf der Rckseite des holographischen Aufzeichnungsmaterials befindet.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="62"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0034" num="0034"><claim-text>Verfahren zum Drucken eines holographischen Mehrwellenlngen-Stereogramms mit Elementarhologrammen in einem Schritt, das Folgende Schritte umfasst:
<claim-text>Auswhlen eines Elementarhologramms;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Teilen eines ersten kohrenten Lichtstrahls in einen ersten Objektstrahl und einen ersten Bezugsstrahl;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Teilen eines zweiten kohrenten Lichtstrahls in einen zweiten Objektstrahl und einen zweiten Bezugsstrahl, wobei der zweite kohrente Lichtstrahl eine von einer Wellenlnge des ersten kohrenten Lichtstrahls verschiedene Wellenlnge aufweist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Teilen eines dritten kohrenten Lichtstrahls in einen dritten Objektstrahl und einen dritten Bezugsstrahl, wobei der dritte kohrente Lichtstrahl eine von den Wellenlngen des ersten und des zweiten kohrenten Lichtstrahls verschiedene Wellenlnge aufweist;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Rendem eines Bilds;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Konditionieren von jedem der Objektstrahlen mit dem an mindestens einem rumlichen Lichtmodulator angezeigten gerenderten Bild;</claim-text>
<claim-text>selektives Ablenken des ersten, des zweiten und des dritten Bezugsstrahls an dem ausgewhlten Elementarhologramm;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Lenken des zweiten Objektstrahls zu dem rumlichen Lichtmodulator;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Lenken des dritten Objektstrahls zu dem rumlichen Lichtmodulator; und<!-- EPO <DP n="63"> --></claim-text>
<claim-text>Interferieren von jedem der konditionierten Objektstrahlen mit einem entsprechenden Bezugsstrahl der Bezugsstrahlen an dem ausgewhlten Elementarhologramm und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Belichten des Bereichs des ausgewhlten Elementarhologramms.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0035" num="0035"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 34, das folgende Schritte umfasst:
<claim-text>Abschirmen des holographischen Aufzeichnungsmaterials von dem ersten Objektstrahl;</claim-text>
<claim-text>Abschirmen des holographischen Aufzeichnungsmaterials von dem ersten Bezugsstrahl; und</claim-text>
<claim-text>Verschieben des holographischen Materials in Bezug auf den ersten Objektstrahl, um ein anderes Elementarhologramm auszuwhlen.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0036" num="0036"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 34, wobei der Schritt des Konditionierens des ersten Objektstrahls den Schritt des gegenseitigen Beeinflussens des ersten Objektstrahls und des rumlichen Lichtmodulators umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0037" num="0037"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 34, wobei der Schritt des Konditionierens des ersten Objektstrahls den Schritt des gegenseitigen Beeinflussens des ersten Objektstrahls und einem oder mehreren der Folgenden umfasst:
<claim-text>einem bandbegrenzten Diffusor, oder</claim-text>
<claim-text>einem HOE.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0038" num="0038"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 34, wobei der Schritt des Konditionierens des ersten Objektstrahls Folgendes umfasst: gegenseitiges Beeinflussen des ersten Objektstrahls und eines HOE, wobei das gegenseitige Beeinflussen das Konvergieren des ersten Objektstrahls<!-- EPO <DP n="64"> --> und das gleichmige Verteilen des ersten Objektstrahls zu dem ausgewhlten Elementarhologramm umfasst.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-de-01-0039" num="0039"><claim-text>Verfahren nach Anspruch 34, wobei der Schritt des Konditionierens des ersten Objektstrahls den Schritt des Leitens des ersten Objektstrahls durch eine Voxel-Steuerlinse umfasst, wobei die Voxel-Steuerlinse dazu ausgebildet ist, eine Auflsung des holographischen Stereogramms zu steuern.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980752" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="46"> --><claim id="c-en-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>An apparatus for one-step printing of multi-wavelength holographic stereograms, comprising:
<claim-text>a first light source (200) configured to produce a first coherent beam;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a beam splitter (205) configured to split the first coherent beam into a first object<br/>
beam (20) and a first reference beam (25);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a material holder (300) configured to hold a holographic recording material (70) having<br/>
elemental holograms;</claim-text>
<claim-text>an object beam unit (700) including at least one spatial light modulator (90), wherein the<br/>
spatial light modulator is configured for displaying a rendered image and for conditioning the first object beam with the rendered image to interfere with the first reference beam at a chosen elemental hologram;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second light source configured to produce a second object beam and a second reference<br/>
beam, wherein the second object beam has a wavelength different from a wavelength of the first object beam, and is directed at the spatial light modulator;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a third light source configured to produce a third object beam and a third reference beam,<br/>
wherein the third object beam has a wavelength different from the wavelengths of the first and second object beams, and is directed at the spatial light modulator;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a reference beam steering system (400) configured to direct the first reference beam to<br/>
interfere with the first object beam at the chosen elemental hologram to expose the area of the chosen elemental hologram to expose the area of the chosen elemental hologram, and configured to direct the second reference beam to interfere with the second object beam at the chosen elemental hologram to expose the area of the chosen elemental hologram, and configured to direct the third reference beam to interfere with the third object beam at the chosen elemental hologram to expose the area of the chosen elemental hologram; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a computer (230) programmed to control at least one of<br/>
the interference of each of the object beams with a corresponding reference beam of the reference beams at the selected elemental hologram, and<br/>
the delivery of the rendered image to the object beam unit.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 1, further comprising:<!-- EPO <DP n="47"> -->
<claim-text>a first beam shutter (225) placed in the path of the first object beam (20); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second beam shutter (225) placed in the path of the first reference beam (25).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 1, wherein the first light source (200) comprises a laser.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 1, wherein each of the three light sources (200), comprises a respective laser.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 4, one laser configured to produce a blue light, one laser configured to produce a red light, and one laser configured to produce a green light.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 1, comprising multiple SLMs (90), each of the object beams directed towards at least one corresponding SLM.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 1 the object beam unit (700) including a holographic optical element (HOE, 115) in the path of the first object beam.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 7, the HOE configured to converge and evenly distribute the first object beam (20) over the chosen elemental hologram.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 1, the object beam unit (700) including a band-limited diffuser (45) in the path of the first object beam (20) and a converging lens (55) in the path of the first object beam.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 1, the object beam unit (700) comprising a fiber optic cable configured to transmit the first object beam (20).<!-- EPO <DP n="48"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 10, the object beam unit (700) comprising:
<claim-text>multiple fiber optic cables (650), each configured to transmit a respective object beam of<br/>
the object beams;</claim-text>
<claim-text>a single lens (705), a SLM (90), and a band-limited diffuser (45) in the path of each<br/>
object beam; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>an optical combiner unit (640) in the path of each of the object beams, the optical<br/>
combiner configured to combine the object beams into a combined object beam that intersects the chosen elemental hologram.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 11, the object beam unit (700) comprising:
<claim-text>a converging lens (55) in the path of the combined object beam; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a pair of projection lenses (715, 720) located in the path of the combined object beam<br/>
between the optical combiner unit (640) and the converging lens (55).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 12, the object beam unit (700) comprising a Fourier transform filter (710) located between the two projection lenses (715, 720).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 1, the object beam unit (700) comprising a voxel-control lens (500) proximate to the holographic recording material (70), wherein the voxel-control lens is configured to control a resolution of the holographic stereogram.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 1, the computer (230) comprising at least one central processing unit.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0016" num="0016"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 15, at least one of the central processing units programmed to render the image that is delivered to the object beam unit (700).<!-- EPO <DP n="49"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0017" num="0017"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 15, the computer (230) comprising at least one storage device operating to receive the rendered image from at least one of the central processing units.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0018" num="0018"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 17, the object beam unit (700) comprising multiple SLMs (90), each SLM configured to receive a rendered image from at least one of the storage devices.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0019" num="0019"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 1, the reference beam steering system (400) comprising a beam-steering mirror system (450).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0020" num="0020"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 19, the beam-steering mirror system (450) comprising;<br/>
a mirror (460) with a center point (461), a first axis (451) passing through the center<br/>
point, and a second axis (452) passing through the center point and orthogonal to the first axis;<br/>
a first mount (494) supporting the mirror and configured to rotate the mirror about the<br/>
first axis; and<br/>
a second mount (496) supporting the first mount and configured to rotate the mirror about<br/>
the second axis.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0021" num="0021"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 20, the first mount (494) including a first motor (491) responsive to the computer (230) that controls the rotation of the mirror (460) about the first axis (451).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0022" num="0022"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 20, the second mount (496) including a second motor (492) responsive to the computer (230) that controls the rotation of the mirror (460) about the second axis (452).<!-- EPO <DP n="50"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0023" num="0023"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 19, the reference beam steering system (400) comprising:
<claim-text>a first beam-steering lens (410) in the path of the first reference beam (25), and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a second beam-steering lens (405) in the path of the first reference beam.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0024" num="0024"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 23, the reference beam steering system (400) comprising a reference beam converging lens (415) disposed in a path of the reference beams entering the beam-steering mirror system.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0025" num="0025"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 23, the reference beam steering system (400) comprising a beam-steering aperture (430) and aperture relay lenses (435), wherein the reference beam steering system is configured to pass the reference beams through the beam-steering aperture and the aperture relay lenses as the reference beams enter the beam-steering mirror system.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0026" num="0026"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 1, the reference beam steering system (400) comprising:
<claim-text>a respective fiber optic cable (650) for transmitting each of the reference beams (25),<br/>
each of the respective fiber optic cables having an output end (655);</claim-text>
<claim-text>a translation system (600) for moving the output ends; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>a beam-steering lens (405) in the path of the reference beams.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0027" num="0027"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 26, wherein the computer (230) is programmed to control the movement of the translation system (600).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0028" num="0028"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 26, the reference beam steering system (400) comprising a masking plate (65) in the path of the reference beams (25) and proximate to the holographic recording material (70).<!-- EPO <DP n="51"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0029" num="0029"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 26, the translation system (600) having a first axis (601) and a second axis (617) orthogonal to the first axis and including a first-translation stage (680) for translation along the first axis and a second-translation stage (690) for translation along the second axis.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0030" num="0030"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 26, comprising:
<claim-text>a) multiple fiber optic cables (650) for transmitting multiple reference beams (25), each fiber optic cable having an output end (655); and</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) an optical combiner unit (640) attached to the translation system (600) and also attached to each fiber optic cable output end.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0031" num="0031"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 1, the material holder (300) comprising a first-translation stage (680) operable in response to the computer (230) to translate the material holder along a first axis.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0032" num="0032"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 31, the material holder (300) comprising a second-translation stage (690) operable in response to the computer (230) to translate the material holder along a second axis that is orthogonal to the first axis.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0033" num="0033"><claim-text>An apparatus for printing holographic stereograms as in claim 1, wherein:
<claim-text>the material holder includes a first-translation stage and two second-translation stages;</claim-text>
<claim-text>the holographic recording material has a front side and a back side, the holographic<br/>
recording material being attached to the first-translation stage;</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one object beam unit is fixed to one of the second-translation stages and is located<br/>
on the front side of the holographic recording material; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>at least one reference beam steering system is fixed to the other second-translation stage<br/>
and is located on the back side of the holographic recording material.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0034" num="0034"><claim-text>A method of one-step printing a multi-wavelength holographic stereogram with elemental holograms, comprising the steps of:<!-- EPO <DP n="52"> -->
<claim-text>selecting an elemental hologram;</claim-text>
<claim-text>splitting a first coherent light beam into a first object beam and a first reference beam;</claim-text>
<claim-text>splitting a second coherent light beam into a second object beam and a second reference<br/>
beam, wherein the second coherent light beam has a wavelength different from a wavelength of the first coherent light beam;</claim-text>
<claim-text>splitting a third coherent light beam into a third object beam and a third reference beam,<br/>
wherein the third coherent light beam has a wavelength different from the wavelengths of the first and second coherent light beams;</claim-text>
<claim-text>rendering an image;</claim-text>
<claim-text>conditioning each of the object beams with the rendered image displayed on at least one<br/>
spatial light modulator;</claim-text>
<claim-text>selectively steering the first, second, and third reference beams at the selected elemental<br/>
hologram;</claim-text>
<claim-text>directing the second object beam at the spatial light modulator;</claim-text>
<claim-text>directing the third object beam at the spatial light modulator; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>interfering each of the conditioned object beams with a corresponding reference beam of<br/>
the reference beams at the selected elemental hologram and expose the area of the selected elemental hologram.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0035" num="0035"><claim-text>The method of claim 34, comprising the steps of:
<claim-text>shielding the holographic recording material from the first object beam;</claim-text>
<claim-text>shielding the holographic recording material from the first reference beam; and</claim-text>
<claim-text>translating the holographic material relative to the first object beam to select another<br/>
elemental hologram.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0036" num="0036"><claim-text>The method of claim 34, the step of conditioning the first object beam comprising the step of interacting the first object beam with the spatial light modulator.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0037" num="0037"><claim-text>The method of claim 34, the step of conditioning the first object beam comprising the step of interacting the first object beam with one or more of:
<claim-text>a band-limited diffuser, or</claim-text>
<claim-text>a HOE.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="53"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0038" num="0038"><claim-text>The method of claim 34, the step of conditioning the first object beam comprising:
<claim-text>interacting the first object beam with a HOE, wherein the interacting comprises converging the first object beam, and evenly distributing the first object beam towards the selected elemental hologram.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-en-01-0039" num="0039"><claim-text>The method of claim 34, the step of conditioning the first object beam comprising the step of passing the first object beam through a voxel-control lens, wherein the voxel-control lens is configured to control a resolution of the holographic stereogram.</claim-text></claim></claims><claims mxw-id="PCLM56980753" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="65"> --><claim id="c-fr-01-0001" num="0001"><claim-text>Un appareil pour une impression en une seule passe de strogrammes holographiques multi-longueurs d'onde, comprenant :
<claim-text>une premire source lumineuse (200) configure de faon  produire un<br/>
premier faisceau cohrent,</claim-text>
<claim-text>un diviseur de faisceau (205) configur de faon  diviser le premier faisceau<br/>
cohrent en un premier faisceau objet (20) et un premier faisceau de rfrence (25),</claim-text>
<claim-text>un support de matriau (300) configur de faon  contenir un matriau<br/>
d'enregistrement holographique (70) possdant des hologrammes lmentaires,</claim-text>
<claim-text>une unit  faisceau objet (700) comprenant au moins un modulateur de<br/>
lumire spatial (SLM) (90), o le modulateur de lumire spatial est configur pour l'affichage d'une image rendue et pour le conditionnement du premier faisceau objet avec l'image rendue de faon  interfrer avec le premier faisceau de rfrence au niveau d'un hologramme lmentaire choisi,</claim-text>
<claim-text>une deuxime source lumineuse configure de faon  produire un deuxime<br/>
faisceau objet et un deuxime faisceau de rfrence, o le deuxime faisceau objet possde une longueur d'onde diffrente d'une longueur d'onde du premier faisceau objet et est orient vers le modulateur de lumire spatial,</claim-text>
<claim-text>une troisime source lumineuse configure de faon  produire un troisime<br/>
faisceau objet et un troisime faisceau de rfrence,</claim-text>
<claim-text>o le troisime faisceau objet possde une longueur d'onde diffrente des<br/>
longueurs d'onde des premier et deuxime faisceaux objets et est dirig vers le modulateur de lumire spatial,</claim-text>
<claim-text>un systme de guidage de faisceau de rfrence (400) configur de faon <br/>
diriger le premier faisceau de rfrence de faon  interfrer avec le premier faisceau objet au niveau de l'hologramme lmentaire choisi de<!-- EPO <DP n="66"> --> faon  exposer la zone de l'hologramme lmentaire choisi, et configur de faon  diriger le deuxime faisceau de rfrence de faon  interfrer avec le deuxime faisceau objet au niveau de l'hologramme lmentaire choisi, de faon  exposer la zone de l'hologramme lmentaire choisi et configur de faon  diriger le troisime faisceau de rfrence de faon  interfrer avec le troisime faisceau objet au niveau de l'hologramme lmentaire choisi de faon  exposer la zone de l'hologramme lmentaire choisi, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un ordinateur (230) programm de faon  commander au moins une opration<br/>
parmi</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'interfrence de chacun des faisceaux objets avec un faisceau de rfrence<br/>
correspondant des faisceaux de rfrence au niveau de l'hologramme lmentaire slectionn, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>la remise de l'image rendue  l'unit  faisceau objet.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0002" num="0002"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 1, comprenant en outre :
<claim-text>un premier obturateur de faisceau (225) plac dans la trajectoire du premier<br/>
faisceau objet (20), et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un deuxime obturateur de faisceau (225) plac dans la trajectoire du premier<br/>
faisceau de rfrence (25).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0003" num="0003"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 1, o la premire source lumineuse (200) comprend un laser.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0004" num="0004"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 1, o chacune des trois sources lumineuses (200) comprend un laser respectif.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0005" num="0005"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 4, un laser tant configur de faon  produire une lumire bleue, un laser tant configur de faon  produire une lumire rouge et un laser tant configur de faon  produire une lumire verte.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0006" num="0006"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 1, comprenant une pluralit de SLM (90), chacun des faisceaux objets<!-- EPO <DP n="67"> --> tant dirig vers au moins un SLM correspondant.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0007" num="0007"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 1, l'unit  faisceau objet (700) comprenant un lment optique holographique (HOE, 115) dans la trajectoire du premier faisceau objet.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0008" num="0008"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 7, le HOE tant configur de faon  converger et  rpartir de manire uniforme le premier faisceau objet (20) sur l'hologramme lmentaire choisi.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0009" num="0009"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 1, l'unit  faisceau objet (700) comprenant un diffuseur  bande limite (45) dans la trajectoire du premier faisceau objet (20) et une lentille convergente (55) dans la trajectoire du premier faisceau objet.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0010" num="0010"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 1, l'unit  faisceau objet (700) comprenant un cble  fibre optique configur de faon  transmettre le premier faisceau objet (20).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0011" num="0011"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 10, l'unit  faisceau objet (700) comprenant :
<claim-text>une pluralit de cbles  fibre optique (650), chacun d'eux tant configur de<br/>
faon  transmettre un faisceau objet respectif des faisceaux objets,</claim-text>
<claim-text>une lentille unique (705), un SLM (90) et un diffuseur  bande limite (45)<br/>
dans la trajectoire de chaque faisceau objet, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>une unit de combinateur optique (640) dans la trajectoire de chacun des<br/>
faisceaux objets configure de faon  combiner les faisceaux objets en un faisceau objet combin qui coupe l'hologramme lmentaire choisi.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0012" num="0012"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 11, l'unit  faisceau objet (700) comprenant en outre :
<claim-text>une lentille convergente (55) dans la trajectoire du faisceau objet combin, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>une paire de lentilles de projection (715, 720) situes dans la trajectoire du<br/>
faisceau objet combin entre l'unit de combinateur optique (640) et la lentille convergente (55).</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0013" num="0013"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la<!-- EPO <DP n="68"> --> Revendication 12, l'unit  faisceau objet (700) comprenant en outre un filtre de transforme de Fourier (710) situe entre les deux lentilles de projection (715, 720).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0014" num="0014"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 1, l'unit  faisceau objet (700) comprenant une lentille de commande de voxel (500) voisine du matriau d'enregistrement holographique (70), o la lentille de commande de voxel est configure de faon  commander une rsolution du strogramme holographique.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0015" num="0015"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 1, l'ordinateur (230) comprenant au moins une unit de traitement centrale.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0016" num="0016"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 15, au moins une des units de traitement centrales tant programme de faon  rendre l'image qui est remise  l'unit  faisceau objet (700).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0017" num="0017"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 15, l'ordinateur (230) comprenant au moins un dispositif  mmoire conu de faon  recevoir l'image rendue  partir d'au moins une des units de traitement centrales.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0018" num="0018"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 17, l'unit  faisceau objet (700) comprenant une pluralit de SLM (90), chaque SLM tant configur de faon  recevoir une image rendue  partir d'au moins un des dispositifs  mmoire.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0019" num="0019"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 1, le systme de guidage de faisceau de rfrence (400) comprenant un systme  miroir de guidage de faisceau (450).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0020" num="0020"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 19, le systme  miroir de guidage de faisceau (450) comprenant :
<claim-text>un miroir (460) avec un point central (461), un premier axe (451) passant au<br/>
travers du point central et un deuxime axe (452) passant au travers du point central et orthogonal au premier axe,</claim-text>
<claim-text>un premier support (494) soutenant le miroir et configur de faon  faire<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="69"> -->pivoter le miroir autour du premier axe, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>un deuxime support (496) soutenant le premier support et configur de faon <br/>
faire pivoter le miroir autour du deuxime axe.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0021" num="0021"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 20, le premier support (494) comprenant un premier moteur (491) ractif  l'ordinateur (230) qui commande la rotation du miroir (460) autour du premier axe (451).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0022" num="0022"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 20, le deuxime support (496) comprenant un deuxime moteur (492) ractif  l'ordinateur (230) qui commande la rotation du miroir (460) autour du deuxime axe (452).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0023" num="0023"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 19, le systme de guidage de faisceau de rfrence (400) comprenant :
<claim-text>une premire lentille de guidage de faisceau (410) dans la trajectoire du<br/>
premier faisceau de rfrence (25), et</claim-text>
<claim-text>une deuxime lentille de guidage de faisceau (405) dans la trajectoire du<br/>
premier faisceau de rfrence.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0024" num="0024"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 23, le systme de guidage de faisceau de rfrence (400) comprenant une lentille convergente de faisceau de rfrence (415) dispose dans une trajectoire des faisceaux de rfrence entrant dans le systme  miroir de guidage de faisceau.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0025" num="0025"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 23, le systme de guidage de faisceau de rfrence (400) comprenant une ouverture de guidage de faisceau (430) et des lentilles de relais d'ouverture (435), o le systme de guidage de faisceau de rfrence est configur de faon  faire passer les faisceaux de rfrence au travers de l'ouverture de guidage de faisceau et des lentilles de relais d'ouverture au moment o les faisceaux de rfrence entrent dans le systme  miroir de guidage de faisceau.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0026" num="0026"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 1, le systme de guidage de faisceau de rfrence (400) comprenant :
<claim-text>un cble  fibre optique respectif (650) pour la transmission de chacun des<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="70"> -->faisceaux de rfrence (25), chacun des cbles  fibre optique respectifs possdant une extrmit de sortie (655),</claim-text>
<claim-text>un systme de translation (600) destin  dplacer les extrmits de sortie, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>une lentille de guidage de faisceau (405) dans la trajectoire des faisceaux de<br/>
rfrence.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0027" num="0027"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 26, o l'ordinateur (230) est programm de faon  commander le dplacement du systme de translation (600).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0028" num="0028"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 26, le systme de guidage de faisceau de rfrence (400) comprenant une plaque de masquage (65) dans la trajectoire des faisceaux de rfrence (25) et voisine du matriau d'enregistrement holographique (70).</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0029" num="0029"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 26, le systme de translation (600) possdant un premier axe (601) et un deuxime axe (617) orthogonal au premier axe et comprenant un tage de premire translation (680) pour une translation le long du premier axe et un tage de deuxime translation (690) pour une translation le long du deuxime axe.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0030" num="0030"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 26, comprenant :
<claim-text>a) une pluralit de cbles  fibre optique (650) pour la transmission d'une pluralit de faisceaux de rfrence (25), chaque cble  fibre optique possdant une extrmit de sortie (655), et</claim-text>
<claim-text>b) une unit de combinateur optique (640) rattache au systme de translation (600) et galement rattache  chaque extrmit de sortie de cble  fibre optique.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0031" num="0031"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 1, le support de matriau (300) comprenant un tage de premire translation (680) actionnable en rponse  l'ordinateur (230) de faon  translater le support de matriau le long d'un premier axe.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0032" num="0032"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 31, le support de matriau (300) comprenant un tage de deuxime<!-- EPO <DP n="71"> --> translation (690) actionnable en rponse  l'ordinateur (230) de faon  translater le support de matriau le long d'un deuxime axe qui est orthogonal au premier axe.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0033" num="0033"><claim-text>Un appareil d'impression de strogrammes holographiques selon la Revendication 1, o :
<claim-text>le support de matriau comprend un tage de premire translation et deux<br/>
tages de deuxime translation,</claim-text>
<claim-text>le matriau d'enregistrement holographique possde un ct avant et un ct<br/>
arrire, le matriau d'enregistrement holographique tant fix  l'tage de premire translation,</claim-text>
<claim-text>au moins une unit  faisceau objet est fix  l'un des tages de deuxime<br/>
translation et se situe sur le ct avant du matriau d'enregistrement holographique, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>au moins un systme de guidage de faisceau de rfrence est fix  l'autre tage<br/>
de deuxime translation et se situe sur le ct arrire du matriau d'enregistrement holographique.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0034" num="0034"><claim-text>Un procd d'impression en une seule passe d'un strogramme holographique multi-longueur d'onde avec des hologrammes lmentaires, comprenant les oprations suivantes :
<claim-text>la slection d'un hologramme lmentaire,</claim-text>
<claim-text>la division d'un premier faisceau de lumire cohrente en un premier faisceau<br/>
objet et un premier faisceau de rfrence,</claim-text>
<claim-text>la division d'un deuxime faisceau de lumire cohrente en un deuxime<br/>
faisceau objet et un deuxime faisceau de rfrence, o le deuxime faisceau de lumire cohrente possde une longueur d'onde diffrente d'une longueur d'onde du premier faisceau de lumire cohrente,</claim-text>
<claim-text>la division d'un troisime faisceau de lumire cohrente en un troisime<br/>
faisceau objet et un troisime faisceau de rfrence, o le troisime faisceau de lumire cohrente possde une longueur d'onde diffrente des longueurs d'onde des premier et deuxime faisceaux de lumire cohrente,</claim-text>
<claim-text>le rendu d'une image,</claim-text>
<claim-text>le conditionnement de chacun des faisceaux objets avec l'image rendue<br/>
<!-- EPO <DP n="72"> -->affiche sur au moins un modulateur de lumire spatial,</claim-text>
<claim-text>le guidage slectif des premier, deuxime et troisime faisceaux de rfrence<br/>
au niveau de l'hologramme lmentaire slectionn,</claim-text>
<claim-text>la direction du deuxime faisceau objet au niveau du modulateur de lumire<br/>
spatial,</claim-text>
<claim-text>la direction du troisime faisceau objet au niveau du modulateur de lumire<br/>
spatial, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>l'interfrence de chacun des faisceaux objets conditionns avec un faisceau de<br/>
rfrence correspondant des faisceaux de rfrence au niveau de l'hologramme lmentaire slectionn, et l'exposition de la zone de l'hologramme lmentaire slectionn,</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0035" num="0035"><claim-text>Le procd selon la Revendication 34, comprenant les oprations suivantes :
<claim-text>la protection du matriau d'enregistrement holographique du premier faisceau<br/>
objet,</claim-text>
<claim-text>la protection du matriau d'enregistrement holographique du premier faisceau<br/>
de rfrence, et</claim-text>
<claim-text>la translation du matriau holographique par rapport au premier faisceau objet<br/>
de faon  slectionner un autre hologramme lmentaire.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0036" num="0036"><claim-text>Le procd selon la Revendication 34, l'opration de conditionnement du premier faisceau objet comprenant l'opration d'interaction du premier faisceau objet avec le modulateur de lumire spatial.</claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0037" num="0037"><claim-text>Le procd selon la Revendication 34, l'opration du conditionnement du premier faisceau objet comprenant l'opration d'interaction du premier faisceau objet avec un ou plusieurs lments parmi :
<claim-text>un diffuseur  bande limite, ou</claim-text>
<claim-text>un HOE.</claim-text></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0038" num="0038"><claim-text>Le procd selon la Revendication 34, l'opration de conditionnement du premier faisceau objet comprenant : l'interaction du premier faisceau objet avec un HOE, o l'interaction comprend la convergence du premier faisceau objet et la distribution uniforme du premier faisceau objet vers l'hologramme lmentaire slectionn.<!-- EPO <DP n="73"> --></claim-text></claim><claim id="c-fr-01-0039" num="0039"><claim-text>Le procd selon la Revendication 34, l'opration de conditionnement du premier faisceau objet comprenant l'opration de passage du premier faisceau objet au travers d'une lentille de commande de voxel, o la lentille de commande de voxel est configure de faon  commander une rsolution du strogramme holographique.</claim-text></claim></claims><drawings mxw-id="PDW16669252" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="74"> --><figure id="f0001" num="1a,1b"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="145" he="197" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="75"> --><figure id="f0002" num="2a,2b"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="165" he="228" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="76"> --><figure id="f0003" num="3,4"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="156" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="77"> --><figure id="f0004" num="5,6"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="165" he="230" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="78"> --><figure id="f0005" num="7"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="165" he="225" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="79"> --><figure id="f0006" num="8"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="165" he="227" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="80"> --><figure id="f0007" num="9,11"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="137" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="81"> --><figure id="f0008" num="10(a),10(b)"><img id="if0008" file="imgf0008.tif" wi="128" he="159" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="82"> --><figure id="f0009" num="12"><img id="if0009" file="imgf0009.tif" wi="165" he="214" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="83"> --><figure id="f0010" num="13"><img id="if0010" file="imgf0010.tif" wi="165" he="217" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="84"> --><figure id="f0011" num="14"><img id="if0011" file="imgf0011.tif" wi="162" he="190" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="85"> --><figure id="f0012" num="15"><img id="if0012" file="imgf0012.tif" wi="165" he="198" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="86"> --><figure id="f0013" num="16"><img id="if0013" file="imgf0013.tif" wi="165" he="196" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="87"> --><figure id="f0014" num="17"><img id="if0014" file="imgf0014.tif" wi="165" he="208" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="88"> --><figure id="f0015" num="18"><img id="if0015" file="imgf0015.tif" wi="165" he="201" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="89"> --><figure id="f0016" num="19"><img id="if0016" file="imgf0016.tif" wi="165" he="201" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="90"> --><figure id="f0017" num="20"><img id="if0017" file="imgf0017.tif" wi="141" he="221" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="91"> --><figure id="f0018" num="21"><img id="if0018" file="imgf0018.tif" wi="165" he="218" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="92"> --><figure id="f0019" num="22"><img id="if0019" file="imgf0019.tif" wi="165" he="212" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="93"> --><figure id="f0020" num="23"><img id="if0020" file="imgf0020.tif" wi="165" he="231" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="94"> --><figure id="f0021" num="24"><img id="if0021" file="imgf0021.tif" wi="165" he="223" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="95"> --><figure id="f0022" num="25"><img id="if0022" file="imgf0022.tif" wi="165" he="220" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="96"> --><figure id="f0023" num="26"><img id="if0023" file="imgf0023.tif" wi="165" he="206" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="97"> --><figure id="f0024" num="27a,27b,27c"><img id="if0024" file="imgf0024.tif" wi="165" he="208" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="98"> --><figure id="f0025" num="28"><img id="if0025" file="imgf0025.tif" wi="165" he="219" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="99"> --><figure id="f0026" num="29,30"><img id="if0026" file="imgf0026.tif" wi="153" he="233" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="100"> --><figure id="f0027" num="31"><img id="if0027" file="imgf0027.tif" wi="151" he="140" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif"/></figure></drawings><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
