<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<patent-document ucid="EP-2681801-A2" country="EP" doc-number="2681801" kind="A2" date="20140108" family-id="44476078" file-reference-id="318301" date-produced="20180822" status="corrected" lang="EN"><bibliographic-data><publication-reference fvid="146585703" ucid="EP-2681801-A2"><document-id><country>EP</country><doc-number>2681801</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20140108</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></publication-reference><application-reference ucid="EP-12751876-A" is-representative="NO"><document-id mxw-id="PAPP154847895" load-source="docdb" format="epo"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12751876</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20120221</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id><document-id mxw-id="PAPP220439950" load-source="docdb" format="original"><country>EP</country><doc-number>12751876.9</doc-number><date>20120221</date></document-id></application-reference><priority-claims><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140554822" ucid="US-201113039981-A" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>201113039981</doc-number><kind>A</kind><date>20110303</date></document-id></priority-claim><priority-claim mxw-id="PPC140551020" ucid="US-2012025952-W" linkage-type="W" load-source="docdb"><document-id format="epo"><country>US</country><doc-number>2012025952</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20120221</date></document-id></priority-claim></priority-claims><technical-data><classifications-ipcr><classification-ipcr mxw-id="PCL2100275117" load-source="docdb">H01Q   3/26        20060101AFI20140716BHEP        </classification-ipcr></classifications-ipcr><classifications-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989623657" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01Q  21/28        20130101 FI20130416BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989640428" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01Q   1/52        20130101 LI20130416BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989646076" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01Q  19/021       20130101 LI20130416BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989646811" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01Q   9/26        20130101 LI20130416BHEP        </classification-cpc><classification-cpc mxw-id="PCL1989648977" load-source="docdb" scheme="CPC">H01Q  17/00        20130101 LI20130416BHEP        </classification-cpc></classifications-cpc><invention-title mxw-id="PT132361742" lang="DE" load-source="patent-office">ANTENNENVORRICHTUNG UND VERFAHREN FÜR HINTERGRUNDRAUSCHVERMINDERUNG UND ERHÖHTE EMPFANGSEMPFINDLICHKEIT</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132361743" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office">ANTENNA APPARATUS AND METHOD FOR REDUCING BACKGROUND NOISE AND INCREASING RECEPTION SENSITIVITY</invention-title><invention-title mxw-id="PT132361744" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office">DISPOSITIF D'ANTENNE ET PROCÉDÉ PERMETTANT DE RÉDUIRE LE BRUIT DE FOND ET D'AUGMENTER LA SENSIBILITÉ DE RÉCEPTION</invention-title></technical-data><parties><applicants><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919529483" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>TANGITEK LLC</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919535967" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>TANGITEK, LLC</last-name></addressbook></applicant><applicant mxw-id="PPAR919015756" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Tangitek, LLC</last-name><iid>101336025</iid><address><street>1033 SW Yamhill Street, Suite 301</street><city>Portland, OR 97205-2539</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></applicant></applicants><inventors><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919545552" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>DONEKER ROBERT L</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919545278" load-source="docdb" sequence="1" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>DONEKER, Robert, L.</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919014037" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>DONEKER, Robert, L.</last-name><address><street>1033 SW Yamhill Street Suite 301</street><city>Portland OR 97205-2539</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919514810" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="epo"><addressbook><last-name>THOMPSON KENT G R</last-name><address><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919533859" load-source="docdb" sequence="2" format="intermediate"><addressbook><last-name>THOMPSON, Kent, G., R.</last-name></addressbook></inventor><inventor mxw-id="PPAR919006353" load-source="patent-office" sequence="2" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>THOMPSON, Kent, G., R.</last-name><address><street>1033 SW Yamhill Street Suite 301</street><city>Portland OR 97205-2539</city><country>US</country></address></addressbook></inventor></inventors><agents><agent mxw-id="PPAR919017021" load-source="patent-office" sequence="1" format="original"><addressbook><last-name>Fleuchaus, Michael A.</last-name><suffix>et al</suffix><iid>101252582</iid><address><street>Fleuchaus &amp; Gallo Partnerschaft Patent- und Rechtsanwälte Steinerstrasse 15/A</street><city>81369 München</city><country>DE</country></address></addressbook></agent></agents></parties><international-convention-data><pct-or-regional-filing-data ucid="US-2012025952-W"><document-id><country>US</country><doc-number>2012025952</doc-number><kind>W</kind><date>20120221</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-filing-data><pct-or-regional-publishing-data ucid="WO-2012118642-A2"><document-id><country>WO</country><doc-number>2012118642</doc-number><kind>A2</kind><date>20120907</date><lang>EN</lang></document-id></pct-or-regional-publishing-data><designated-states><ep-contracting-states><country mxw-id="DS549828839" load-source="docdb">AL</country><country mxw-id="DS549828437" load-source="docdb">AT</country><country mxw-id="DS549828840" load-source="docdb">BE</country><country mxw-id="DS549755482" load-source="docdb">BG</country><country mxw-id="DS549911386" load-source="docdb">CH</country><country mxw-id="DS549823225" load-source="docdb">CY</country><country mxw-id="DS549828442" load-source="docdb">CZ</country><country mxw-id="DS549828841" load-source="docdb">DE</country><country mxw-id="DS549823230" load-source="docdb">DK</country><country mxw-id="DS549823231" load-source="docdb">EE</country><country mxw-id="DS549751101" load-source="docdb">ES</country><country mxw-id="DS549755483" load-source="docdb">FI</country><country mxw-id="DS549755484" load-source="docdb">FR</country><country mxw-id="DS549828846" load-source="docdb">GB</country><country mxw-id="DS549823232" load-source="docdb">GR</country><country mxw-id="DS549828847" load-source="docdb">HR</country><country mxw-id="DS549828443" load-source="docdb">HU</country><country mxw-id="DS549911387" load-source="docdb">IE</country><country mxw-id="DS549828848" load-source="docdb">IS</country><country mxw-id="DS549755489" load-source="docdb">IT</country><country mxw-id="DS549823233" load-source="docdb">LI</country><country mxw-id="DS549834426" load-source="docdb">LT</country><country mxw-id="DS549828444" load-source="docdb">LU</country><country mxw-id="DS549834427" load-source="docdb">LV</country><country mxw-id="DS549834428" load-source="docdb">MC</country><country mxw-id="DS549752158" load-source="docdb">MK</country><country mxw-id="DS549752159" load-source="docdb">MT</country><country mxw-id="DS549751102" load-source="docdb">NL</country><country mxw-id="DS549755490" load-source="docdb">NO</country><country mxw-id="DS549752160" load-source="docdb">PL</country><country mxw-id="DS549911388" load-source="docdb">PT</country><country mxw-id="DS549751103" load-source="docdb">RO</country><country mxw-id="DS549911389" load-source="docdb">RS</country><country mxw-id="DS549751104" load-source="docdb">SE</country><country mxw-id="DS549911390" load-source="docdb">SI</country><country mxw-id="DS549755491" load-source="docdb">SK</country><country mxw-id="DS549752173" load-source="docdb">SM</country><country mxw-id="DS549823238" load-source="docdb">TR</country></ep-contracting-states></designated-states></international-convention-data><office-specific-data><eptags><ep-no-a-document-published>*</ep-no-a-document-published></eptags></office-specific-data></bibliographic-data><abstract mxw-id="PA99830448" ref-ucid="WO-2012118642-A2" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><p num="0000">An antenna apparatus includes an electrically conductive section having peripheral edges, an antenna element coupled to the electrically conductive section, which transmits or receives electromagnetic signals, and an electromagnetic absorbing carbon material component. The carbon material component is generally disposed adjacent to the electrically conductive section, and includes a border region extending beyond the peripheral edges of the electrically conductive section by a given distance based on λ, where λ corresponds to the maximum wavelength of the one or more electromagnetic signals capable of being transmitted or received using the antenna element. Also, a distance between a surface of the carbon material component and the electrically conductive section is less than or equal to a value determined by λ. The carbon material component is constructed and arranged to increase the effective signal to noise ratio of the antenna apparatus and enhances antenna performance without increasing the baseline power consumption level.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA100327276" ref-ucid="WO-2012118642-A2" lang="EN" source="national office" load-source="docdb"><p>An antenna apparatus includes an electrically conductive section having peripheral edges, an antenna element coupled to the electrically conductive section, which transmits or receives electromagnetic signals, and an electromagnetic absorbing carbon material component. The carbon material component is generally disposed adjacent to the electrically conductive section, and includes a border region extending beyond the peripheral edges of the electrically conductive section by a given distance based on ?, where ? corresponds to the maximum wavelength of the one or more electromagnetic signals capable of being transmitted or received using the antenna element. Also, a distance between a surface of the carbon material component and the electrically conductive section is less than or equal to a value determined by ?. The carbon material component is constructed and arranged to increase the effective signal to noise ratio of the antenna apparatus and enhances antenna performance without increasing the baseline power consumption level.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA99830449" ref-ucid="WO-2012118642-A2" lang="FR" load-source="patent-office"><p num="0000">La présente invention a trait à un dispositif d'antenne qui inclut une section électroconductrice qui est dotée de bords périphériques, un élément d'antenne qui est couplé à la section électroconductrice et qui émet ou reçoit des signaux électromagnétiques, et un composant de carbone absorbant électromagnétique. Le composant de carbone est en règle générale disposé de manière à être adjacent à la section électroconductrice, et inclut une région frontalière s'étendant au-delà des bords périphériques de la section électroconductrice sur une distance donnée basée sur λ, où λ correspond à la longueur d'onde maximale du ou des signaux électromagnétiques pouvant être émis ou reçus à l'aide de l'élément d'antenne. De même, la distance entre une surface du composant de carbone et la section électroconductrice est inférieure ou égale à la valeur déterminée par λ. Le composant de carbone est construit et conçu de manière à augmenter le rapport signal sur bruit effectif du dispositif d'antenne et améliore les performances de l'antenne sans augmenter le niveau de consommation d'énergie de base.</p></abstract><abstract mxw-id="PA100327277" ref-ucid="WO-2012118642-A2" lang="FR" source="national office" load-source="docdb"><p>La présente invention a trait à un dispositif d'antenne qui inclut une section électroconductrice qui est dotée de bords périphériques, un élément d'antenne qui est couplé à la section électroconductrice et qui émet ou reçoit des signaux électromagnétiques, et un composant de carbone absorbant électromagnétique. Le composant de carbone est en règle générale disposé de manière à être adjacent à la section électroconductrice, et inclut une région frontalière s'étendant au-delà des bords périphériques de la section électroconductrice sur une distance donnée basée sur ?, où ? correspond à la longueur d'onde maximale du ou des signaux électromagnétiques pouvant être émis ou reçus à l'aide de l'élément d'antenne. De même, la distance entre une surface du composant de carbone et la section électroconductrice est inférieure ou égale à la valeur déterminée par ?. Le composant de carbone est construit et conçu de manière à augmenter le rapport signal sur bruit effectif du dispositif d'antenne et améliore les performances de l'antenne sans augmenter le niveau de consommation d'énergie de base.</p></abstract><description mxw-id="PDES51232254" ref-ucid="WO-2012118642-A2" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><!-- EPO <DP n="2"/>--><p id="p0001" num="0001"> ANTENNA APPARATUS AND METHOD FOR REDUCING </p><p id="p0002" num="0002"> BACKGROUND NOISE AND INCREASING RECEPTION SENSITIVITY </p><p id="p0003" num="0003">TECHNICAL FIELD </p><p id="p0004" num="0004"> This disclosure relates to antennas, and, more particularly, to an apparatus and method for reducing unwanted electromagnetic interference and increasing the reception sensitivity of antennas. </p><p id="p0005" num="0005">BACKGROUND </p><p id="p0006" num="0006"> Electromagnetic signals are widely used to transmit or receive information through the air between antennas. Modern day communications are heavily reliant on such transmissions including vast networks of hand-held wireless devices, cellular towers, radios, satellites, global positioning systems, and so forth. Each of the devices associated with such networks include an antenna. The antenna can take various forms and can function in a variety of different ways. Importantly, it is the quality and configuration of the antenna that can make the difference between a strong and coherent signal and one that is compromised by unwanted </p><p id="p0007" num="0007">electromagnetic interference. </p><p id="p0008" num="0008"> Conventional approaches to reducing background noise and improving the function and efficiency of antennas include implementing specialized electronics to filter noise, boost the transmitting power, or implement frequency hopping protocols, and the like. Some have focused on the shape or construction of the antenna itself. Others have attempted to construct plastic moldings or metal fibers to help focus or enhance the signal. Still others have used carbon, plastics, metal meshes, and the like, to make certain components of the antenna more rigid, or to reflect or conduct signals. </p><p id="p0009" num="0009"> However, even in view of these attempts and advances, consumers, businesses and governments are still plagued by disconnected telephone calls, slow internet reception, faulty transmission of information, inaccurate signals, and so forth. Such unreliability, especially when considered with the additional power consumption by devices implementing some of the approaches mentioned above, presents significant problems for society at large. l 
<!-- EPO <DP n="3"/>-->
 Accordingly, a need remains for an improved antenna apparatus, which reduces background noise and increases reception sensitivity without increasing power usage of the antenna apparatus. BRIEF DESCRIPTION OF THE DRAWINGS</p><p id="p0010" num="0010">FIG. 1 illustrates a perspective view of an example of an antenna apparatus including electromagnetic absorbing carbon elements according to one embodiment of the present invention. </p><p id="p0011" num="0011"> FIG. 1A illustrates a side elevation view of the antenna apparatus of FIG. 1 in the direction of lines 1 A- 1 A. </p><p id="p0012" num="0012"> FIG. 2 illustrates a perspective view of another example of an antenna apparatus including electromagnetic absorbing elements according to another embodiment of the present invention. </p><p id="p0013" num="0013"> FIG. 2A illustrates a cross-sectional view of the antenna apparatus of FIG. 2 taken along lines 2A-2A. </p><p id="p0014" num="0014"> FIG. 3 illustrates a perspective view of yet another example of an antenna apparatus including electromagnetic absorbing elements according to yet another embodiment of the present invention. </p><p id="p0015" num="0015"> FIG. 3 A is a side elevation view of the antenna apparatus of FIG. 3 in the direction of lines 3 A-3 A. </p><p id="p0016" num="0016"> FIG. 3B is a front elevation view of the antenna apparatus of FIG. 3 in the direction of lines 3B-3B. </p><p id="p0017" num="0017"> FIG. 4 illustrates a perspective view of still another example of an antenna apparatus including electromagnetic absorbing elements according to still another embodiment of the present invention. </p><p id="p0018" num="0018"> FIG. 4A illustrates a pian view of the antenna apparatus of FIG. 4. </p><p id="p0019" num="0019"> FIG. 4B illustrates a cross-sectional view of the antenna apparatus of FIG. 4A taken along lines 4B-4B. </p><p id="p0020" num="0020"> FIG. 5 illustrates a perspective view of a hand-held wireless device including an antenna apparatus embedded therein, and including electromagnetic absorbing elements of one form associated with the wireless device. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="4"/>-->
 FIG. 5 A illustrates a side elevation view of the wireless device of FIG. 5 in the direction of lines 5A-5A. </p><p id="p0021" num="0021"> FIG. 6 illustrates a hand-held wireless device including an antenna apparatus embedded therein, and including electromagnetic absorbing elements of another form associated with the wireless device. </p><p id="p0022" num="0022"> FIG. 6 A illustrates a cross-sectional view of the wireless device of FIG. 6 taken along lines 6A-6A. </p><p id="p0023" num="0023"> FIG. 7 illustrates a perspective view of another example of an antenna apparatus including electromagnetic absorbing elements according to another embodiment of the present invention. </p><p id="p0024" num="0024"> FIG. 7A illustrates side elevation view of the antenna apparatus of FIG. 7 in the direction of lines 7A-7A. </p><p id="p0025" num="0025"> FIG. 7B illustrates a cross-sectional view of the antenna apparatus of FIG. 7 taken along lines 7B/C-7B/C. </p><p id="p0026" num="0026"> FIG. 7C illustrates a cross-sectional view of the antenna apparatus of FIG. 7 taken along lines 7B/C-7B/C. </p><p id="p0027" num="0027"> FIG. 8 illustrates a perspective view of yet another example of an antenna apparatus including electromagnetic absorbing elements according to yet another embodiment of the present invention. </p><p id="p0028" num="0028"> FIG. 8 A illustrates side elevation view of the antenna apparatus of FIG. 8 in the direction of lines 8A-8A. </p><p id="p0029" num="0029"> The foregoing and other features of the invention will become more readily apparent from the following detailed description, which proceeds with reference to the accompanying drawings. </p><p id="p0030" num="0030">DETAILED DESCRIPTION</p><p id="p0031" num="0031">FIG. 1 illustrates a perspective view of an example of an antenna apparatus 100 including electromagnetic absorbing carbon elements 120 according to one embodiment of the present invention. FIG. 1 A illustrates a side elevation view of the antenna apparatus 100 of FIG. 1 in the direction of lines 1A-1A. Reference is now made to FIGs. 1 and 1 A. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="5"/>-->
 The antenna apparatus 100 includes an electrically conductive section 105 having peripheral edges 110. The electrically conductive section 105 can be made of any suitable metallic or other conductive material. An antenna element 115 is coupled to the electrically conductive section 105 and can transmit or receive one or more electromagnetic signals 102 through the air. The electromagnetic signals 102 can take any one of a variety forms, with any suitable amplitude, frequency, wavelength, and so forth, and can include either analog or digital data. The antenna apparatus 100 includes a carbon material component 120 disposed adjacent to the electrically conductive section 105. The carbon material component includes a border region 125 extending beyond the peripheral edges 110 of the electrically conductive section 105. </p><p id="p0032" num="0032"> The border region 125 of the carbon material component extends beyond the peripheral edges 110 of the electrically conductive section by at least a distance 130 of λ divided by 4 (λ/4), where λ corresponds to the maximum wavelength of the one or more electromagnetic signals 102 capable of being transmitted or received using the antenna element 1 15. In some embodiments, the distance 130 can correspond to λ/2, λ, or 2λ, among other suitable values, greater than λ/4. It should be understood that while preferably the dimension of distance 130 is λ/4 or thereabout, other values mentioned herein can be used. </p><p id="p0033" num="0033"> Furthermore, a distance 140 between a surface of the carbon material component 120 and the electrically conductive section 105 is less than or equal to λ divided by 4 (λ/4), where λ corresponds to the maximum wavelength of the one or more electromagnetic signals 102 capable of being transmitted or received using the antenna element 1 15. In some embodiments, the distance 140 can correspond to λ/8, λ/16, or λ/32, among other suitable values, less than λ/4. It should be understood that while preferably the dimension of distance 140 is λ/4 or thereabout, other values mentioned herein can be used. </p><p id="p0034" num="0034"> More specifically, the electrically conductive section 105 is a substantially planar antenna ground plane 105 having at least a width dimension 145 and a length dimension 150. The antenna element 115 is a substantially cylindrical rod or beam antenna, which is arranged at a normal relative to the antenna ground plane 105. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="6"/>-->
 The carbon material component 120 is substantially planar and arranged parallel to the antenna ground plane 105. The carbon material component 120 includes a width dimension 155 greater than the width dimension 145 of the ground plane by at least a distance of λ divided by 2 (λ/2). The carbon material component 120 includes a length dimension 160 greater than the length dimension 150 of the ground plane by at least a distance of λ divided by 2 Q 2). </p><p id="p0035" num="0035"> The carbon material component 120 is structured to reduce background interference or noise 135 of the one or more electromagnetic signals transmitted or received by the antenna element 1 15. In other words, background interference or noise 135 is reduced so that the one or more electromagnetic signals is more effectively transmitted by the antenna element 1 15, and/or reception sensitivity of the antenna element 1 15 is enhanced. In this manner, the integrity and quality of signals transferred between antennas is improved. It should be understood that while the background interference 135 is illustrated in relation to the antenna apparatus 100 arriving from one particular angle or direction, the background interference can arrive from multiple locations and angles, some or all of which can be reduced or eliminated by the carbon material component 120. </p><p id="p0036" num="0036"> In some embodiments, the carbon material component 120 is disposed directly adjacent to and in contact with the electrically conductive ground plane 105. In some embodiments, the carbon material component 120 is adjacent to but not necessarily in contact with the electrically conductive ground plane 105. </p><p id="p0037" num="0037"> The carbon material preferably includes a resin impregnated carbon fiber fabric having a specific resistance of less than or equal to 100 ohms per centimeter squared (100 Ω/cm<sup>2</sup>). The carbon material component 120 is constructed and arranged to increase the effective signal to noise ratio of the antenna apparatus, as disclosed and illustrated herein. For example, the carbon material component 120 can increase the effective signal to noise ratio by a minimum of approximately three decibels. Moreover, the carbon material component 120 increases the reception range of the one or more electromagnetic signals 102 by up to 1.4 times with no additional power consumption of the antenna apparatus 100. In other words, for a given baseline power consumption level of the antenna apparatus 100 in which a 
<!-- EPO <DP n="7"/>-->
 certain level of reception performance is attained, the carbon material component 120 when constructed and arranged as set forth herein, significantly increases the reception performance without increasing the baseline power consumption level. </p><p id="p0038" num="0038"> In some embodiments, the carbon material component 120 is encapsulated with an insulation layer to electrically isolate the carbon material component from electrical contact with any other element of the antenna apparatus 100, and to electrically isolate the carbon material component 120 from earth ground. </p><p id="p0039" num="0039"> FIG. 2 illustrates a perspective view of another example of an antenna apparatus 200 including electromagnetic absorbing elements according to another embodiment of the present invention. FIG. 2A illustrates a cross-sectional view of the antenna apparatus 200 of FIG. 2 taken along lines 2A-2A. </p><p id="p0040" num="0040"> The antenna apparatus 200 includes an electrically conductive section 205 having peripheral edges 210. The electrically conductive section 205 can be made of any suitable metallic or other conductive material. The surfaces of section 205 need not be smooth surfaces, but can rather include a mesh surface, wire grill, or the like. An antenna element 215 is coupled to the electrically conductive section 205 and can transmit or receive one or more electromagnetic signals 202 through the air. The electromagnetic signals 202 can take any one of a variety forms, with any suitable amplitude, frequency, wavelength, and so forth, and can include either analog or digital data. The antenna apparatus 200 includes a carbon material component 220 disposed adjacent to the electrically conductive section 205. The carbon material component includes a border region 225 extending beyond the peripheral edges 210 of the electrically conductive section 205. </p><p id="p0041" num="0041"> The border region 225 of the carbon material component extends beyond the peripheral edges 210 of the electrically conductive section by at least a distance 230 of λ divided by 4 (λ/4), where λ corresponds to the maximum wavelength of the one or more electromagnetic signals 202 capable of being transmitted or received using the antenna element 215. In some embodiments, the distance 230 can correspond to λ/2, λ, or 2λ, among other suitable values, greater than λ/4. It should be understood that while preferably the dimension of distance 230 is λ/4 or thereabout, other values mentioned herein can be used. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="8"/>-->
 Furthermore, a distance 240 between a surface of the carbon material component 220 and the electrically conductive section 205 is less than or equal to λ divided by 4 (λ/4), where λ corresponds to the maximum wavelength of the one or more electromagnetic signals 202 capable of being transmitted or received using the antenna element 215. In some embodiments, the distance 240 can correspond to λ/8, λ/16, or λ/32, among other suitable values, less than λ/4. It should be understood that while preferably the dimension of distance 240 is λ/4 or thereabout, other values mentioned herein can be used. </p><p id="p0042" num="0042"> More specifically, the electrically conductive section 205 includes a substantially parabolic reflector surface 205 in which at least one cross section of the reflector surface corresponds to a parabola. The antenna element is a feed antenna 215 arranged to receive the one or more electromagnetic signals using the parabolic reflector surface 205. The carbon material component 220 includes a substantially parabolic surface 220 in which at least one cross section of the carbon material surface corresponds to a parabola. The border region 225 of the parabolic carbon material surface 220 extends beyond the peripheral edges 210 of the parabolic reflector surface 205 by at least a distance of λ divided by 4 (λ/4). </p><p id="p0043" num="0043"> The substantially parabolic reflector surface 205 can be dish-shaped and include size dimensions such as depth, width, and diameter of the dish. The substantially parabolic carbon material surface 220 is also dish-shaped and includes size dimensions that are generally larger than the size dimensions of the dish- shaped reflector surface. For example, the depth of the parabolic carbon material surface 220 can be larger than the depth of the parabolic reflector surface 205, and the edge portions 225 can extend further relative to the edge portions 210 of the reflector surface 205. The distance 240 between the dish-shaped parabolic reflector surface 205 and the dish-shaped carbon material surface 220 is less than or equal to λ divided by 4 (λ/4), as mentioned above. </p><p id="p0044" num="0044"> The parabolic carbon material component 220 is structured to reduce background interference or noise 235 of the one or more electromagnetic signals transmitted or received by the antenna element 215. In other words, background interference or noise 235 is reduced so that the one or more electromagnetic signals 
<!-- EPO <DP n="9"/>-->
 is more effectively transmitted by the antenna element 215, and/or reception sensitivity of the antenna element 215 is enhanced. In this manner, the integrity and quality of signals transferred between antennas is improved. </p><p id="p0045" num="0045"> In some embodiments, the parabolic carbon material component 220 is disposed directly adjacent to and in contact with the parabolic reflector surface 205. In some embodiments, the parabolic carbon material component 220 is adjacent to but not necessarily in contact with the parabolic reflector surface 205. </p><p id="p0046" num="0046"> The parabolic carbon material component 220 preferably includes a resin impregnated carbon fiber fabric having a specific resistance of less than or equal to 100 ohms per centimeter squared (100 Ω/cm<sup>2</sup>). The parabolic carbon material component 220 is constructed and arranged to increase the effective signal to noise ratio of the antenna apparatus, as disclosed and illustrated herein. For example, the parabolic carbon material component 220 can increase the effective signal to noise ratio by a minimum of approximately three decibels. Moreover, the parabolic carbon material component 220 increases the reception range of the one or more electromagnetic signals 202 by up to 1.4 times with no additional power consumption of the antenna apparatus 200. In other words, for a given baseline power consumption level of the antenna apparatus 200 in which a certain level of reception performance is attained, the carbon material component 220 when constructed and arranged as set forth herein, significantly increases the reception performance without increasing the baseline power consumption level. </p><p id="p0047" num="0047"> In some embodiments, the parabolic carbon material component 220 is encapsulated with an insulation layer to electrically isolate the carbon material component from electrical contact with any other element of the antenna apparatus 200, and to electrically isolate the carbon material component 220 from earth ground. </p><p id="p0048" num="0048"> FIG. 3 illustrates a perspective view of yet another example of an antenna apparatus including electromagnetic absorbing elements according to yet another embodiment of the present invention. FIG. 3 A is a side elevation view of the antenna apparatus of FIG. 3 in the direction of lines 3A-3A. FIG. 3B is a front 
<!-- EPO <DP n="10"/>-->
 elevation view of the antenna apparatus of FIG. 3 in the direction of lines 3B-3B. Reference is now made to FIGs. 3, 3A, and 3B. </p><p id="p0049" num="0049"> The antenna apparatus 300 includes a "YAGI" or "YAGI-UDA" type antenna element 305/310 defined by peripheral edges 330. The antenna element is structured to transmit or receive one or more electromagnetic signals 302. The antenna element 305/310 can be made of any suitable metallic or other conductive material. The electromagnetic signals 302 can take any one of a variety forms, with any suitable amplitude, frequency, wavelength, and so forth, and can include either analog or digital data. </p><p id="p0050" num="0050"> One or more carbon material components 337/340 can be disposed adjacent to the antenna element. The carbon material components include a border region (e.g., 355/345) extending beyond the peripheral edges 330 of the antenna element 305/310. The border region (e.g., 355/345) of the carbon material components extends beyond the peripheral edges 330 of the antenna element by at least a distance 336 of λ divided by 4 (λ/4), where λ corresponds to the maximum wavelength of the one or more electromagnetic signals 302 capable of being transmitted or received using the antenna element 305/310. In some embodiments, the distance 336 can correspond to λ/2, λ, or 2λ, among other suitable values, greater than^/4. It should be understood that while preferably the dimension of distance 336 is λ/4 or thereabout, other values mentioned herein can be used. </p><p id="p0051" num="0051"> Furthermore, a distance 332 between a surface of each of the carbon material components 337/340 and the antenna element 305/310 is less than or equal to λ divided by 4 (λ/4), where λ corresponds to the maximum wavelength of the one or more electromagnetic signals 302 capable of being transmitted or received using the antenna element 305/310. In addition, the distance 334 between the carbon material components 337/340 is less than or equal to λ divided by 2 (λ/2). In some embodiments, the distance 332 can correspond to λ/8, λ/16, or λ/32, among other suitable values, less than λ/4. It should be understood that while preferably the dimension of distance 332 is λ/4 or thereabout, other values mentioned herein can be used. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="11"/>-->
 More specifically, the antenna element 305/310 includes an electrically conductive boom 305 and electrically conductive perpendicular elements 310 arranged perpendicular to the boom 305 and parallel to one another. Each of the perpendicular elements 310 is coupled to the boom 305, and each includes a particular length. The particular length decreases for each perpendicular element 310 from one end 315 of the boom to the other end 320 of the boom. The boom 305 and the perpendicular elements 310 together correspond to the antenna element 305/310 of the antenna apparatus defined by a substantially trapezoidal shape 325 having peripheral edges 330. The antenna element 305/310 of the antenna apparatus 300 is arranged in a particular plane 3B-3B and is structured to transmit or receive one or more electromagnetic signals. </p><p id="p0052" num="0052"> A first trapezoidal shaped carbon material component 337 is disposed adjacent to the antenna element 305/310 to a first side thereof, in a plane parallel to the particular plane of the antenna element. The first carbon material component 337 includes a border region 355 extending beyond the peripheral edges 330 of the antenna element 305/310. </p><p id="p0053" num="0053"> A second trapezoidal shaped carbon material component 340 is disposed adjacent to the antenna element 305/310 to a second side thereof opposite the first side, in a plane parallel to the particular plane of the antenna. The second carbon material component 340 includes a border region 345 extending beyond the peripheral edges 330 of the antenna element 305/310. The border region 355/345 of each of the first and second carbon material components 337/340 extends beyond the peripheral edges 330 of the antenna element 305/310 by at least a distance of λ divided by 4 (λ/4), where λ corresponds to the maximum wavelength of the one or more electromagnetic signals 302 capable of being transmitted or received using the antenna element 305/310. </p><p id="p0054" num="0054"> The carbon material components 337/340 are structured to reduce background interference or noise 335 of the one or more electromagnetic signals transmitted or received by the antenna element 305/310. In other words, background interference or noise 335 is reduced so that the one or more </p><p id="p0055" num="0055">electromagnetic signals is more effectively transmitted by the antenna element 
<!-- EPO <DP n="12"/>-->
 305/310, and/or reception sensitivity of the antenna element 305/310 is enhanced. In this manner, the integrity and quality of signals transferred between antennas is improved. It should be understood that while the background interference 335 is illustrated in relation to the antenna apparatus 300 arriving from one particular angle or direction, the background interference can arrive from multiple locations and angles, some or all of which can be reduced or eliminated by the carbon material components 337/340. </p><p id="p0056" num="0056"> In some embodiments, the carbon material components 337/340 are disposed directly adjacent to and in contact with the antenna element 305/310. In some embodiments, the carbon material components 337/340 are adjacent to but not necessarily in contact with the antenna element 305/310. </p><p id="p0057" num="0057"> The carbon material preferably includes a resin impregnated carbon fiber fabric having a specific resistance of less than or equal to 100 ohms per centimeter squared (100 Ω/cm<sup>2</sup>). The carbon material components 337/340 are constructed and arranged to increase the effective signal to noise ratio of the antenna apparatus, as disclosed and illustrated herein. For example, the carbon material components 337/340 can increase the effective signal to noise ratio by a minimum of approximately three decibels. Moreover, the carbon material components 337/340 increase the reception range of the one or more electromagnetic signals 302 by up to 1.4 times with no additional power consumption of the antenna apparatus 300. In other words, for a given baseline power consumption level of the antenna apparatus 300 in which a certain level of reception performance is attained, the carbon material components 337/340 when constructed and arranged as set forth herein, significantly increases the reception performance without increasing the baseline power consumption level. </p><p id="p0058" num="0058"> In some embodiments, the carbon material components 337/340 are each encapsulated with an insulation layer to electrically isolate the carbon material component from electrical contact with any other element of the antenna apparatus 300, and to electrically isolate the carbon material components 337/340 from earth ground. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="13"/>-->
 FIG. 4 illustrates a perspective view of still another example of an antenna apparatus 400 including electromagnetic absorbing elements according to still another embodiment of the present invention. FIG. 4A illustrates a plan view of the antenna apparatus 400 of FIG. 4. FIG. 4B illustrates a cross-sectional view of the antenna apparatus 400 of FIG. 4A taken along lines 4B-4B. Reference is now made to FIGs. 4, 4A, and 4B. </p><p id="p0059" num="0059"> The antenna apparatus 400 includes an electrically conductive section 405 having peripheral edges 410. The electrically conductive section 405 can be made of any suitable metallic or other conductive material. An antenna element 415 is coupled to the electrically conductive section 405 and can transmit or receive one or more electromagnetic signals 402 through the air between, for example, satellite 404 and/or radio tower 403. The electromagnetic signals 402 can take any one of a variety forms, with any suitable amplitude, frequency, wavelength, and so forth, and can include either analog or digital data. The antenna apparatus 400 includes a carbon material component 420 disposed adjacent to the electrically conductive section 405. The carbon material component includes a border region 425 extending beyond the peripheral edges 410 of the electrically conductive section 405. </p><p id="p0060" num="0060"> The border region 425 of the carbon material component extends beyond the peripheral edges 410 of the electrically conductive section by at least a distance 430 of λ divided by 4 (λ/4), where λ corresponds to the maximum wavelength of the one or more electromagnetic signals 402 capable of being transmitted or received using the antenna element 415. In some embodiments, the distance 430 can correspond to λ/2, λ, or 2λ, among other suitable values, greater than λ/4. It should be understood that while preferably the dimension of distance 430 is λ/4 or thereabout, other values mentioned herein can be used. </p><p id="p0061" num="0061"> Furthermore, a distance 440 between a surface of the carbon material component 420 and the electrically conductive section 405 is less than or equal to λ divided by 4 (λ/4), where λ corresponds to the maximum wavelength of the one or more electromagnetic signals 402 capable of being transmitted or received using the antenna element 415. In some embodiments, the distance 440 can correspond to 
<!-- EPO <DP n="14"/>-->
 λ/8, λ/16, or λ/32, among other suitable values, less than λ/4. It should be understood that while preferably the dimension of distance 440 is λ/4 or thereabout, other values mentioned herein can be used. </p><p id="p0062" num="0062"> More specifically, the antenna apparatus 400 is a patch and/or microstrip antenna 400, in which the electrically conductive section 405 is a substantially planar antenna ground plane 405 having a width dimension 445 and a length dimension 450. The antenna element 415 is a substantially planar electrically conductive patch having a width dimension 455 less than the width dimension 445 of the ground plane 405 and a length dimension 460 less than the length dimension 450 of the ground plane 405. In addition, a substrate 465 can be disposed between the ground plane 405 and the electrically conductive patch 415 in which a first surface 470 of the ground plane 405 is adjacent to and in contact with the substrate 465. </p><p id="p0063" num="0063"> The carbon material component 420 is substantially planar and arranged parallel to a second surface 475 of the ground plane 405 opposite the first surface 470. The carbon material component 420 includes a width dimension 485 and a length dimension 490. The width dimension 485 of the carbon material component 420 is greater than the width dimension 445 of the ground plane 405 by at least a distance of λ divided by 2 (λ/2). The length dimension 490 of the carbon material component 420 is greater than the length dimension 450 of the ground plane 405 by at least a distance of λ divided by 2 (λ/2). </p><p id="p0064" num="0064"> The carbon material component 420 is structured to reduce background interference or noise 435 of the one or more electromagnetic signals transmitted or received by the antenna element 415. In other words, background interference or noise 435 is reduced so that the one or more electromagnetic signals is more effectively transmitted by the antenna element 415, and/or reception sensitivity of the antenna element 415 is enhanced. In this manner, the integrity and quality of signals transferred between antennas is improved. It should be understood that while the background interference 435 is illustrated in relation to the antenna apparatus 400 arriving from one particular angle or direction, the background 
<!-- EPO <DP n="15"/>-->
 interference can arrive from multiple locations and angles, some or all of which can be reduced or eliminated by the carbon material component 420. </p><p id="p0065" num="0065"> In some embodiments, the carbon material component 420 is disposed directly adjacent to and in contact with the electrically conductive ground plane 405. In some embodiments, the carbon material component 420 is adjacent to but not necessarily in contact with the electrically conductive ground plane 405. </p><p id="p0066" num="0066"> The carbon material preferably includes a resin impregnated carbon fiber fabric having a specific resistance of less than or equal to 100 ohms per centimeter squared (100 Ω/cm<sup>2</sup>). The carbon material component 420 is constructed and arranged to increase the effective signal to noise ratio of the antenna apparatus, as disclosed and illustrated herein. For example, the carbon material component 420 can increase the effective signal to noise ratio by a minimum of approximately three decibels. Moreover, the carbon material component 420 increases the reception range of the one or more electromagnetic signals 402 by up to 1.4 times with no additional power consumption of the antenna apparatus 400. In other words, for a given baseline power consumption level of the antenna apparatus 400 in which a certain level of reception performance is attained, the carbon material component 420 when constructed and arranged as set forth herein, significantly increases the reception performance without increasing the baseline power consumption level. </p><p id="p0067" num="0067"> In some embodiments, the carbon material component 420 is encapsulated with an insulation layer to electrically isolate the carbon material component from electrical contact with any other element of the antenna apparatus 400, and to electrically isolate the carbon material component 420 from earth ground. </p><p id="p0068" num="0068"> FIG. 5 illustrates a perspective view of a hand-held wireless device 500 including an antenna apparatus 530 embedded therein, and including </p><p id="p0069" num="0069">electromagnetic absorbing elements of one form associated with the wireless device. FIG. 5 A illustrates a side elevation view of the wireless device of FIG. 5 in the direction of lines 5A-5A. FIG. 6 illustrates the hand-held wireless device 500 including an antenna apparatus 530 embedded therein, and including </p><p id="p0070" num="0070">electromagnetic absorbing elements of another form associated with the wireless 
<!-- EPO <DP n="16"/>-->
 device. FIG. 6 A illustrates a cross-sectional view of the wireless device of FIG. 6 taken along lines 6A-6A. Reference is now made to FIGs. 5, 5A, 6, and 6A. </p><p id="p0071" num="0071"> The wireless device 500 includes a housing 505 having a display 510 to provide a user interface on a front side 515 thereof. The housing includes a reference plane 520 associated with a back side 520 of the housing 505. The reference plane 520 includes peripheral edges 525. A patch and/or microstrip antenna 530 can be embedded at least partially within the housing 505 and structured to transmit or receive one or more electromagnetic signals. It should be understood that while a patch and/or microstrip antenna is the preferred type of antenna embedded therein, other suitable antenna types can be used. </p><p id="p0072" num="0072"> A carbon material component 537 is disposed adjacent to the back side 520 of the housing 505. The carbon material component 537 includes a border region 540 extending beyond the peripheral edges 525 of the reference plane 520. The border region 540 of the carbon material component 537 extends beyond the peripheral edges 525 of the reference plane 520 by at least a distance 545 of λ divided by 4 (λ/4), where λ corresponds to the maximum wavelength of the one or more electromagnetic signals 502 capable of being transmitted or received using the patch and/or microstrip antenna 530. In some embodiments, the distance 545 can correspond to λ/2, λ, or 2λ, among other suitable values, greater than λ/4. It should be understood that while preferably the dimension of distance 545 is λ/4 or thereabout, other values mentioned herein can be used. </p><p id="p0073" num="0073"> Furthermore, a distance 550 between a surface 537 of the carbon material component 537 and a surface 520 of the reference plane 520 is less than or equal to λ divided by 4 (λ/4), where λ corresponds to the maximum wavelength of the one or more electromagnetic signals 502 capable of being transmitted or received using the antenna element 530. In some embodiments, the distance 550 can correspond to λ/8, λ/16, or λ/32, among other suitable values, less than λ/4. It should be understood that while preferably the dimension of distance 550 is XI or thereabout, other values mentioned herein can be used. </p><p id="p0074" num="0074"> The carbon material component 537 is structured to reduce background interference or noise 535 of the one or more electromagnetic signals transmitted or 
<!-- EPO <DP n="17"/>-->
 received by the antenna element 530. In other words, background interference or noise 535 is reduced so that the one or more electromagnetic signals is more effectively transmitted by the antenna element 530, and/or reception sensitivity of the antenna element 530 is enhanced. In this manner, the integrity and quality of signals transferred between antennas is improved. It should be understood that while the background interference 535 is illustrated in relation to the wireless device 500 arriving from one particular angle or direction, the background interference can arrive from multiple locations and angles, some or all of which can be reduced or eliminated by the carbon material component 537. </p><p id="p0075" num="0075"> In some embodiments, at least a first portion 552 of the carbon material component 537 is disposed directly adjacent to and parallel with a surface 520 of the reference plane 520 of the housing 505. Moreover, at least a second portion 555 of the carbon material component 537 is curve-shaped on the edges 540 for gripping thereof. The curvatures 540 in the carbon material component 537 also enhance blockage of unwanted electromagnetic interference 535, which can otherwise interfere with communication signals of the hand-held wireless device 500. </p><p id="p0076" num="0076"> The carbon material preferably includes a resin impregnated carbon fiber fabric having a specific resistance of less than or equal to 100 ohms per centimeter squared (100 Ω/cm<sup>2</sup>). The carbon material component 537 is constructed and arranged to increase the effective signal to noise ratio of the antenna apparatus, as disclosed and illustrated herein. For a given baseline power consumption level of the antenna apparatus 530 in which a certain level of reception performance is attained, the carbon material component 537 when constructed and arranged as set forth herein, significantly increases the reception performance without increasing the baseline power consumption level. </p><p id="p0077" num="0077"> In some embodiments, the carbon material component 537 is encapsulated with an insulation layer to electrically isolate the carbon material component from electrical contact with any other element of the hand-held wireless device 500, and to electrically isolate the carbon material component 537 from earth ground. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="18"/>-->
 FIG. 7 illustrates a perspective view of another example of an antenna apparatus 700 including electromagnetic absorbing elements according to another embodiment of the present invention. FIG. 7A illustrates side elevation view of the antenna apparatus 700 of FIG. 7 in the direction of lines 7A-7 A. FIG. 7B illustrates a cross-sectional view of the antenna apparatus 700 of FIG. 7 in one configuration taken along lines 7B/C-7B/C. FIG. 7C illustrates a cross-sectional view of the antenna apparatus 700 of FIG. 7 in another configuration taken along lines 7B/C- 7B/C. Reference is now made to FIGs. 7, 7A, 7B, and 7C. </p><p id="p0078" num="0078"> The antenna apparatus 700 includes a dipole or "rabbit ear" antenna element 715 having peripheral edges 760. The antenna element 715 is structured to transmit or receive one or more electromagnetic signals 702. The antenna element 715 can be made of any suitable metallic or other conductive material. The electromagnetic signals 702 can take any one of a variety forms, with any suitable amplitude, frequency, wavelength, and so forth, and can include either analog or digital data. </p><p id="p0079" num="0079"> A carbon material component 720 can be disposed adjacent to the antenna element 715. The carbon material component 720 includes a border region 755 extending beyond the peripheral edges 760 of the antenna element 715. The border region 755 of the carbon material component extends beyond the peripheral edges 760 of the antenna element by at least a distance 730 of λ divided by 4 (λ/4), where λ corresponds to the maximum wavelength of the one or more electromagnetic signals 702 capable of being transmitted or received using the antenna element 715. In some embodiments, the distance 730 can correspond to λ/2, λ, or 2λ, among other suitable values, greater than λ/4. It should be understood that while preferably the dimension of distance 730 is λ/4 or thereabout, other values mentioned herein can be used. </p><p id="p0080" num="0080"> Furthermore, a distance 740 between a surface of the carbon material component 720 and the antenna element 715 is less than or equal to λ divided by 4 (λ/4), where λ corresponds to the maximum wavelength of the one or more electromagnetic signals 702 capable of being transmitted or received using the antenna element 715. In some embodiments, the distance 740 can correspond to λ/8, λ/16, or λ/32, among other suitable values less than λ/4. It should be 
<!-- EPO <DP n="19"/>-->
 understood that while preferably the dimension of distance 740 is λ/4 or thereabout, other values mentioned herein can be used. </p><p id="p0081" num="0081"> The antenna element 715 is an adjustable antenna element structured to be maneuvered into one of a plurality of configurations. Further, the carbon material component 720 can be adjustable and maneuvered into one of a plurality of similar configurations. The carbon material component 720 and the antenna element 715 are structured to accommodate the λ divided by 4 (λ/4) distance relationship between the border region 755 of the carbon material component 720 and the peripheral edges 760 of the antenna element 715 in each configuration of the antenna element and the carbon material component. Both of the carbon material component 720 and the antenna element 715 can be bent, swiveled, or otherwise adjusted. For instance, as shown in FIG. 7C, when the antenna element 715 is adjusted in a V-type configuration, the carbon material component 720 can likewise be adjusted in a V-type configuration, and the distances 730 and/or 740 can be maintained. To maintain the distance relationship, the carbon material component 720 can be bent inwardly toward the antenna element 715 to maintain the distance 740 relationship, swiveled, and/or extended outwardly to maintain the distance 730 relationship, with the antenna element 715. </p><p id="p0082" num="0082"> The carbon material component 720 is structured to reduce background interference or noise 735 of the one or more electromagnetic signals transmitted or received by the antenna element 715. In other words, background interference or noise 735 is reduced so that the one or more electromagnetic signals is more effectively transmitted by the antenna element 715, and/or reception sensitivity of the antenna element 715 is enhanced. In this manner, the integrity and quality of signals transferred between antennas is improved. It should be understood that while the background interference 735 is illustrated in relation to the antenna apparatus 700 arriving from one particular angle or direction, the background interference can arrive from multiple locations and angles, some or all of which can be reduced or eliminated by the carbon material component 720. </p><p id="p0083" num="0083"> In some embodiments, the carbon material component 720 is disposed directly adjacent to and in contact with the antenna element 715. In some 
<!-- EPO <DP n="20"/>-->
 embodiments, the carbon material component 720 is adjacent to but not necessarily in contact with the antenna element 15. </p><p id="p0084" num="0084"> The carbon material preferably includes a resin impregnated carbon fiber fabric having a specific resistance of less than or equal to 100 ohms per centimeter squared (100 Ω/cm<sup>2</sup>). The carbon material component 720 is constructed and arranged to increase the effective signal to noise ratio of the antenna apparatus, as disclosed and illustrated herein. For example, the carbon material component 720 can increase the effective signal to noise ratio by a minimum of approximately three decibels. Moreover, the carbon material component 720 can increase the reception range of the one or more electromagnetic signals 702 by up to 1.4 times with no additional power consumption of the antenna apparatus 700. In other words, for a given baseline power consumption level of the antenna apparatus 700 in which a certain level of reception performance is attained, the carbon material component 720 when constructed and arranged as set forth herein, significantly increases the reception performance without increasing the baseline power consumption level. </p><p id="p0085" num="0085"> In some embodiments, the carbon material component 720 is encapsulated with an insulation layer to electrically isolate the carbon material component from electrical contact with any other element of the antenna apparatus 700, and to electrically isolate the carbon material component 720 from earth ground. </p><p id="p0086" num="0086"> FIG. 8 illustrates a perspective view of yet another example of an antenna apparatus 800 including electromagnetic absorbing elements according to yet another embodiment of the present invention. FIG. 8A illustrates side elevation view of the antenna apparatus 800 of FIG. 8 in the direction of lines 8A-8A. </p><p id="p0087" num="0087">Reference is now made to FIGs. 8 and 8 A. </p><p id="p0088" num="0088"> The antenna apparatus 800 includes a "loop" antenna element 815 having peripheral edges 860 and/or 870. The antenna element 815 is structured to transmit or receive one or more electromagnetic signals 802. The antenna element 815 can be made of any suitable metallic or other conductive material. The electromagnetic signals 802 can take any one of a variety of forms, with any suitable amplitude, frequency, wavelength, and so forth, and can include either analog or digital data. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="21"/>-->
 A carbon material component 820 can be disposed adjacent to the antenna element 815. The carbon material component 820 includes a border region 855 extending beyond the peripheral edges 860 and/or 870 of the antenna element 815. The border region 855 of the carbon material component extends beyond the peripheral edges 860 and/or 870 of the antenna element by at least a distance 830 of λ divided by 4 (λ/4), where λ corresponds to the maximum wavelength of the one or more electromagnetic signals 802 capable of being transmitted or received using the antenna element 815. In some embodiments, the distance 830 can correspond to λ/2, λ, or 2λ, among other suitable values, greater than λ/4. It should be understood that while preferably the dimension of distance 830 is λ/4 or thereabout, other values mentioned herein can be used. </p><p id="p0089" num="0089"> Furthermore, a distance 840 between a surface of the carbon material component 820 and the antenna element 815 is less than or equal to λ divided by 4 (λ/4), where λ corresponds to the maximum wavelength of the one or more electromagnetic signals 802 capable of being transmitted or received using the antenna element 815. In some embodiments, the distance 840 can correspond to λ/8, λ/16, or λ/32, among other suitable values less than XI . It should be understood that while preferably the dimension of distance 840 is λ/4 or thereabout, other values mentioned herein can be used. </p><p id="p0090" num="0090"> The carbon material component 820 is structured to reduce background interference or noise 835 of the one or more electromagnetic signals transmitted or received by the antenna element 815. In other words, background interference or noise 835 is reduced so that the one or more electromagnetic signals is more effectively transmitted by the antenna element 815, and/or reception sensitivity of the antenna element 815 is enhanced. In this manner, the integrity and quality of signals transferred between antennas is improved. It should be understood that while the background interference 835 is illustrated in relation to the antenna apparatus 800 arriving from one particular angle or direction, the background interference can arrive from multiple locations and angles, some or all of which can be reduced or eliminated by the carbon material component 820. 
<!-- EPO <DP n="22"/>-->
 In some embodiments, the carbon material component 820 is disposed directly adjacent to and in contact with the antenna element 815. In some embodiments, the carbon material component 820 is adjacent to but not necessarily in contact with the antenna element 815. </p><p id="p0091" num="0091"> The carbon material preferably includes a resin impregnated carbon fiber fabric having a specific resistance of less than or equal to 100 ohms per centimeter squared (100 Ω/cm<sup>2</sup>). The carbon material component 820 is constructed and arranged to increase the effective signal to noise ratio of the antenna apparatus, as disclosed and illustrated herein. For example, the carbon material component 820 can increase the effective signal to noise ratio by a minimum of approximately three decibels. Moreover, the carbon material component 820 can increase the reception range of the one or more electromagnetic signals 802 by up to 1.4 times with no additional power consumption of the antenna apparatus 800. In other words, for a given baseline power consumption level of the antenna apparatus 800 in which a certain level of reception performance is attained, the carbon material component 820 when constructed and arranged as set forth herein, significantly increases the reception performance without increasing the baseline power consumption level. </p><p id="p0092" num="0092"> In some embodiments, the carbon material component 820 is encapsulated with an insulation layer to electrically isolate the carbon material component from electrical contact with any other element of the antenna apparatus 800, and to electrically isolate the carbon material component 820 from earth ground. </p><p id="p0093" num="0093"> Although the foregoing discussion has focused on particular embodiments, other configurations are contemplated. In particular, even though expressions such as "according to an embodiment of the invention" or the like are used herein, these phrases are meant to generally reference embodiment possibilities, and are not intended to limit the invention to particular embodiment configurations. As used herein, these terms can reference the same or different embodiments that are combinable into other embodiments. </p><p id="p0094" num="0094"> Methods for using each of the embodiments of the antenna apparatus are also set forth. Using the carbon material component as a supplemental element in antenna design, thereby increasing the transmitted signal to noise ratio, and 
<!-- EPO <DP n="23"/>-->
 reducing background electromagnetically induced interference, is contemplated and herein disclosed. The addition of a layer of resin impregnated carbon fiber fabric or other carbon material, located behind the antenna ground plane, or adjacent to the antenna element, diminishes effects of unwanted electromagnetic radiation on signal quality. Much like holding a hand towel behind ones ears helps to reduce the sounds from behind, the carbon material component helps to act as a shielding agent, which absorbs at least a portion of the background noise from becoming introduced into the signal that is transmitted or received. Adding the dampening element can increase the effective signal to noise ratio by 3 decibels or more, which essentially doubles the effective signal field strength, thereby increasing the reception range by up to 1.4 times. This can be accomplished with no additional system power consumption. While some examples of antenna types and configurations are disclosed herein, persons with skill in the art will recognize that the inventive concepts disclosed herein can be implemented with a variety of different antenna types, shapes, and forms. </p><p id="p0095" num="0095"> Consequently, in view of the wide variety of permutations to the </p><p id="p0096" num="0096">embodiments described herein, this detailed description and accompanying material is intended to be illustrative only, and should not be taken as limiting the scope of the invention. 
</p></description><claims mxw-id="PCLM44851388" ref-ucid="WO-2012118642-A2" lang="EN" load-source="patent-office"><claim-statement><!-- EPO <DP n="24"/>-->CLAIMS: </claim-statement><claim id="clm-0001" num="1"><claim-text>1. An antenna apparatus, comprising: </claim-text><claim-text> an electrically conductive section including a plurality of peripheral edges; an antenna element coupled to the electrically conductive section and structured to transmit or receive one or more electromagnetic signals; </claim-text><claim-text> a carbon material component disposed adjacent to the electrically conductive section, the carbon material component including a border region extending beyond the plurality of peripheral edges of the electrically conductive section; </claim-text><claim-text> wherein the border region of the carbon material component extends beyond the peripheral edges of the electrically conductive section by at least a distance of λ divided by 4 (λ/4), wherein λ corresponds to the maximum wavelength of the one or more electromagnetic signals capable of being transmitted or received using the antenna element. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0002" num="2"><claim-text>2. The antenna apparatus of claim 1 , wherein the carbon material component is structured to reduce background interference of the one or more electromagnetic signals transmitted or received by the antenna element. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0003" num="3"><claim-text>3. The antenna apparatus of claim 1, wherein a distance between a surface of the carbon material component and the electrically conductive section is less than or equal to λ divided by 4 (λ/4). </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0004" num="4"><claim-text>4. The antenna apparatus of claim 3, wherein the carbon material component is disposed directly adjacent to and in contact with the electrically conductive section. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0005" num="5"><claim-text>5. The antenna apparatus of claim 1, wherein the carbon material component includes resin impregnated carbon fiber fabric. <!-- EPO <DP n="25"/>--> </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0006" num="6"><claim-text>6. The antenna apparatus of claim 5, wherein the resin impregnated carbon fiber fabric has a specific resistance of less than or equal to 100 ohms per centimeter squared (100 Ω/cm<sup>2</sup>). </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0007" num="7"><claim-text>7. The antenna apparatus of claim 1, wherein the carbon material component is structured to increase the effective signal to noise ratio of the antenna apparatus. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0008" num="8"><claim-text>8. The antenna apparatus of claim 7, wherein the carbon material component is structured to increase the effective signal to noise ratio by a minimum of approximately three decibels. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0009" num="9"><claim-text>9. The antenna apparatus of claim 1, wherein the carbon material component is structured to increase the reception range of the one or more electromagnetic signals by up to 1.4 times. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0010" num="10"><claim-text>10. The antenna apparatus of claim 9, wherein the carbon material component is structured to increase the reception range of the one or more electromagnetic signals by up to 1.4 times with no additional power consumption of the antenna apparatus. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0011" num="11"><claim-text>11. The antenna apparatus of claim 1, wherein the carbon material component is encapsulated with an insulation layer to electrically isolate the carbon material component from electrical contact with any other element of the antenna apparatus, and to electrically isolate the carbon material component from earth ground. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0012" num="12"><claim-text>12. The antenna apparatus of claim 1, wherein: </claim-text><claim-text> the electrically conductive section is a substantially planar antenna ground plane having at least a width dimension and a length dimension; <!-- EPO <DP n="26"/>--> the antenna element is substantially cylindrical and arranged at a normal relative to the antenna ground plane; and </claim-text><claim-text> the carbon material component is substantially planar and arranged parallel to the antenna ground plane; </claim-text><claim-text> wherein the carbon material component includes a width dimension greater than the width dimension of the ground plane by at least a distance of λ divided by 2 (7J2); and </claim-text><claim-text> wherein the carbon material component includes a length dimension greater than the length dimension of the ground plane by at least a distance of λ divided by 2 (λ/2). </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0013" num="13"><claim-text>13. The antenna apparatus of claim 1 , wherein: </claim-text><claim-text> the electrically conductive section includes a substantially parabolic reflector surface in which at least one cross section of the reflector surface corresponds to a parabola; </claim-text><claim-text> the antenna element is a feed antenna arranged to receive the one or more electromagnetic signals using the parabolic reflector surface; </claim-text><claim-text> the carbon material component includes a substantially parabolic surface in which at least one cross section of the carbon material surface corresponds to a parabola; and </claim-text><claim-text> the border region of the parabolic carbon material surface extends beyond the peripheral edges of the parabolic reflector surface by at least a distance of λ divided by 4 (λ/4). </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0014" num="14"><claim-text>14. The antenna apparatus of claim 13, wherein: </claim-text><claim-text> the substantially parabolic reflector surface is dish-shaped and includes a size dimension; </claim-text><claim-text> the substantially parabolic carbon material surface is dish-shaped and includes a size dimension greater than the size dimension of the dish-shaped reflector surface; and <!-- EPO <DP n="27"/>--> a distance between the dish-shaped parabolic reflector surface and the dish- shaped carbon material surface is less than or equal to λ divided by 4 (λ/4). </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0015" num="15"><claim-text>15. The antenna apparatus of claim 1 , further comprising: </claim-text><claim-text> a patch antenna, wherein: </claim-text><claim-text> the electrically conductive section is a substantially planar antenna ground plane of the patch antenna having a width dimension and a length dimension; </claim-text><claim-text> the antenna element is a substantially planar electrically conductive patch having a width dimension less than the width dimension of the ground plane and a length dimension less than the length dimension of the ground plane; </claim-text><claim-text> a substrate is disposed between the ground plane and the electrically conductive patch in which a first surface of the ground plane is adjacent to and in contact with the substrate; </claim-text><claim-text> the carbon material component is substantially planar and arranged parallel to a second surface of the ground plane opposite the first surface, wherein the carbon material component includes a width dimension and a length dimension; </claim-text><claim-text> the width dimension of the carbon material component is greater than the width dimension of the ground plane by at least a distance of λ divided by 2 (λ/2); and </claim-text><claim-text> the length dimension of the carbon material component is greater than the length dimension of the ground plane by at least a distance of λ divided by 2 QJ2). </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0016" num="16"><claim-text>16. A wireless communication device, comprising: </claim-text><claim-text> a housing including a display to provide a user interface on a front side thereof, wherein the housing includes: </claim-text><claim-text> a reference plane associated with a back side of the housing, the reference plane including a plurality of peripheral edges; and <!-- EPO <DP n="28"/>--> a patch antenna embedded at least partially within the housing and structured to transmit or receive one or more electromagnetic signals; and a carbon material component disposed adjacent to the back side of the housing, the carbon material component including a border region extending beyond the plurality of peripheral edges of the reference plane; </claim-text><claim-text> wherein the border region of the carbon material component extends beyond the peripheral edges of the reference plane by at least a distance of λ divided by 4 (λ/4), wherein λ corresponds to the maximum wavelength of the one or more electromagnetic signals capable of being transmitted or received using the patch antenna. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0017" num="17"><claim-text>17. The wireless communication device of claim 16, wherein a distance between a surface of the carbon material component and a surface of the reference plane is less than or equal to λ divided by 4 (λ/4). </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0018" num="18"><claim-text>18. The wireless communication device of claim 17, wherein: </claim-text><claim-text> at least a first portion of the carbon material component is disposed directly adjacent to and parallel with a surface of the reference plane of the housing; </claim-text><claim-text> at least a second portion of the carbon material component is curve-shaped on the edges for gripping thereof. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0019" num="19"><claim-text>19. An antenna apparatus, comprising: </claim-text><claim-text> an antenna element including a plurality of peripheral edges, the antenna element structured to transmit or receive one or more electromagnetic signals; a carbon material component disposed adjacent to the antenna element, the carbon material component including a border region extending beyond the plurality of peripheral edges of the antenna element; </claim-text><claim-text> wherein the border region of the carbon material component extends beyond the peripheral edges of the antenna element by at least a distance of λ divided by 4 (λ/4), wherein λ corresponds to the maximum wavelength of the one or more <!-- EPO <DP n="29"/>--> electromagnetic signals capable of being transmitted or received using the antenna element. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0020" num="20"><claim-text>20. The antenna apparatus of claim 19, wherein a distance between a surface of the carbon material component and the antenna element is less than or equal to λ divided by 4 (λ/4). </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0021" num="21"><claim-text>21. The antenna apparatus of claim 19, wherein: </claim-text><claim-text> the antenna element includes an electrically conductive boom and a plurality of electrically conductive perpendicular elements arranged perpendicular to the boom and parallel to one another; </claim-text><claim-text> each of the perpendicular elements is coupled to the boom; </claim-text><claim-text> each of the perpendicular elements includes a particular length; </claim-text><claim-text> the particular length decreases for each perpendicular element from one end of the boom to the other end of the boom; </claim-text><claim-text> the boom and the perpendicular elements together correspond to the antenna element of the antenna apparatus defined by a substantially trapezoidal shape having a plurality of peripheral edges; and </claim-text><claim-text> the antenna element of the antenna apparatus is arranged in a particular plane and is structured to transmit or receive one or more electromagnetic signals; the carbon material component further includes: </claim-text><claim-text> a first trapezoidal shaped carbon material component disposed adjacent to the antenna element to a first side thereof, in a plane parallel to the particular plane of the antenna element , the first carbon material component including a border region extending beyond the plurality of peripheral edges of the antenna element; and </claim-text><claim-text> a second trapezoidal shaped carbon material component disposed adjacent to the antenna element to a second side thereof opposite the first side, in a plane parallel to the particular plane of the antenna, the second carbon material component including a border region extending beyond the plurality of peripheral edges of the antenna element, <!-- EPO <DP n="30"/>--> wherein the border region of each of the first and second carbon material components extends beyond the peripheral edges of the antenna element by at least a distance of λ divided by 4 (λ/4), wherein λ corresponds to the maximum wavelength of the one or more electromagnetic signals capable of being transmitted or received using the antenna element. </claim-text></claim><claim id="clm-0022" num="22"><claim-text>22. The antenna apparatus of claim 19, wherein: </claim-text><claim-text> the antenna element is an adjustable antenna element structured to be maneuvered into one of a plurality of configurations; </claim-text><claim-text> the carbon material component is an adjustable carbon material component structured to be maneuvered into one of a plurality of configurations, </claim-text><claim-text> wherein the carbon material component and the antenna element are structured to accommodate the λ divided by 4 (λ/4) distance relationship between the border region of the carbon material component and the peripheral edges of the antenna element in the plurality of configurations of the antenna element and the carbon material component. </claim-text></claim></claims><copyright>User acknowledges that Fairview Research LLC and its third party providers retain all right, title and interest in and to this xml under applicable copyright laws.  User acquires no ownership rights to this xml including but not limited to its format.  User hereby accepts the terms and conditions of the Licence Agreement</copyright></patent-document>
